You know, Daddy,
this is my very best birthday.
But I haven't given you
your present yet.
- What is it? What is it?
- Now, close your eyes.
Oh, oh, oh... Oh, now...
No peeking now.
Oh, Daddy!
You made this just for me?
You're the most wonderful father
in the whole world!
- Who is that?
- I... I don't know!
Quickly, dear,
stay in here and don't come out.
- I got you, toy maker!
- Oh, no! Olivia!
Daddy, where are you?
Daddy,
where are you?
Daddy!
It was the eve
of our good queen's Diamond Jubilee,
and the year Her Majesty's government
came to the very brink of disaster.
She...
I... I... I'm getting ahead of myself.
My name is Dr. David Q. Dawson,
most recently of
the queen's 66th Regiment.
I had just arrived in London
after lengthy service in Afghanistan,
and was anxious to find a quiet place,
preferably dry, hmm...
where I could rest
and find a bit of peace.
Little did I know
that my life was
about to change forever.
Oh! Oh, my!
Are you all right, my dear?
Come now, come, come, come.
Here, here, dry your eyes.
Ah, yes. Ah, that's better.
Now, tell me,
what's troubling you, my dear?
I... I'm lost.
I... I... I'm trying to find
Basil of Baker Street.
Well, let me see here.
"Famous detective
solves baffling disappearance."
Mmm-hmm. Uh, but, uh...
Where are your mother and father?
That's why I must find Basil.
There, there, there, there.
Now, now, now, now.
Well, now, I don't know any Basil.
But I do remember
where Baker Street is.
Now, come with me.
We'll find this Basil chap together.
Good evening, madam. Is this
the residence of Basil of Baker Street?
I'm afraid it is.
He's not here at the moment,
but you're welcome to come in and wait.
Oh, I... I don't want to impose.
It's... it's just, the girl...
Oh, my!
You poor dear!
You must be chilled to the bone!
Oh.
But I know just the thing.
Let me fetch you a pot of tea
and some of my fresh cheese crumpets.
A-ha! The villain's slipped this time!
I shall have him!
Out of my way! Out of my way!
I say... Oh!
- Who are you?
- What? Oh.
Basil of Baker Street, my good fellow.
- Mr. Basil, I need your help. And...
- All in good time.
But you don't understand.
I'm in terrible trouble.
If you'll excuse me.
Now... Now see here!
This young lady is
in need of assistance.
- I think you ought to listen...
- Hold this, please, doctor.
Of course.
Wait just a moment.
How did you know I was a doctor?
A surgeon, to be exact.
Just returned from military duty
in Afghanistan, am I right?
Why...
Oh, yes. Major David Q. Dawson.
- Uh... But how could you possibly...
- Quite simple, really.
You've sewn your torn cuff together
with a Lembert stitch,
which, of course, only a surgeon uses.
And the thread is
a unique form of catgut
easily distinguished
by its peculiar pungency,
found only in the Afghan provinces.
- Amazing!
- Actually,
it's elementary, my dear Dawson.
What in heaven's name?
Oh! Oh... My...
My good pillows.
Mr. Basil!
- How many times have I told you...
- Mrs. Judson, it's quite all right.
Uh... Mmm.
I believe I smell some of those
delightful cheese crumpets of yours.
- Why don't you fetch our guests some?
- But...
Now,
I know that bullet's here somewhere.
- Thank you, Miss...
- Flaversham. Olivia Flaversham.
- Whatever.
- Yes, but you don't understand.
Yes.
Yes!
No!
Drat!
Another dead end.
He was within my grasp.
Now, will you please listen to me?
My daddy's gone, and I'm all alone.
Young lady, this is
a most inopportune time.
Surely your mother knows where he is.
I... I don't have a mother.
Well... Um...
Then perhaps...
See here, I simply have
no time for lost fathers.
I didn't lose him. He was taken by a bat.
- Did you say bat?
- Yes.
- Did he have a crippled wing?
- I don't know, but he had a peg leg!
I say, do you know him?
Know him? That bat,
one Fidget, by name,
is in the employ of the very fiend
who was the target of my experiment!
The horror of my every waking moment.
The nefarious Professor Ratigan!
- Uh... Ratigan?
- He's a genius, Dawson.
A genius twisted for evil.
The Napoleon of crime.
- As bad as all that, eh?
- Worse!
For years, I've tried to capture him,
and I've come close, so very close.
But each time,
he's narrowly evaded my grasp.
Not a corner of London's safe
while Ratigan's at large.
There's no evil scheme
he wouldn't concoct!
No depravity he wouldn't commit.
Who knows what dastardly scheme
that villain may be plotting,
even as we speak?
Quite an ingenious scheme,
eh, Flaversham?
And aren't you proud to be a part of it?
This whole thing is...
It... it's monstrous.
We will have our little device
ready by tomorrow evening, won't we?
You know what will happen if you fail.
I... I... I don't care!
You can do what you want with me.
I won't be a part of this... this...
...this evil any longer.
Very well, if that is your decision.
Oh, uh, by the way,
I'm taking the liberty
of having your daughter brought here.
- Olivia?
- Yes. Yes.
Yes. Yes.
I would spend many a sleepless night
if anything unfortunate
were to befall her.
You... you wouldn't.
Finish it, Flaversham!
Oh, I love it when I'm nasty.
Fidget.
Fidget!
Bright and alert as always.
Here's the list.
You know what to do, and no mistakes!
No mistakes, sir.
"Tools, gears, girl, uniforms..."
- Now, Fidget!
- I'm going! I'm going! I'm going!
My friends, we are
about to embark on the most odious,
the most evil, the most diabolical
scheme of my illustrious career.
A crime to top all crimes.
A crime that will live in infamy!
Tomorrow evening,
our beloved monarch
celebrates her Diamond Jubilee.
And with the enthusiastic help
of our good friend, Mr. Flaversham,
it promises to be a night
she will never forget.
Her last night, and my first
as supreme ruler of all mousedom!
From the brain that
brought you the Big Ben Caper
The head that made headlines
in every newspaper
And wondrous things like
the Tower Bridge Job
That cunning display
that made Londoners sob
Now comes the real tour de force
Tricky and wicked, of course
My earlier crimes
were fine for their times
But now that I'm at it again
An even grimmer plot
has been simmering
In my great criminal brain
Even meaner?
You mean it?
Worse than the widows
and orphans you drowned
You're the best of the worst around
Oh, Ratigan
The rest fall behind
To Ratigan
The world's greatest criminal mind
Thank you, thank you.
But it hasn't all been
champagne and caviar.
I've had my share of adversity,
thanks to that miserable
second-rate detective,
Basil of Baker Street.
For years, that insufferable pipsqueak
has interfered with my plans.
I haven't had
a moment's peace of mind.
Aww...
But all that's in the past!
This time nothing, not even Basil,
can stand in my way!
All will bow before me!
Oh, Ratigan
You're tops and that's that
To Ratigan
To Ratigan, the world's greatest rat
What was that?
What did you call me?
- He didn't mean it, professor.
- It was just a slip of the tongue.
I am not a rat!
- 'Course you're not. You're a mouse!
- That's right. A mouse.
- Yeah, a big mouse.
- Silence!
Oh, my dear Bartholomew,
I'm afraid that
you've gone and upset me.
You know what happens
when someone upsets me.
Oh, Ratigan
You're the tops and that's that
Oh, dear.
To Ratigan
The world's greatest...
Oh, Felicia, my precious, my baby.
Did Daddy's little honey bun
enjoy her tasty treat?
I trust there will be
no further interruptions.
And now,
as you were singing...
Even louder
We'll shout it
No one can doubt
what we know you can do
You're more evil than even you
Oh, Ratigan
- Oh, Ratigan
- Ah...
You're one of a kind
To Ratigan
Hey.
The world's greatest criminal
Mind
This case is most intriguing
with its multiplicity of elements,
its many twists and turns.
Now, you're certain
you've told me everything?
The slightest detail may be important.
It's just as I said.
And then my father was gone.
What do you make of it?
Ratigan's up to something.
A crime of the most
sinister nature, no doubt.
The question is...
What would he want with a toymaker?
Quickly, we've not a moment to lose!
I'm right behind you, Basil.
No... No sign
of the blackguard anywhere.
Not quite, Dawson.
He left some rather unusual footprints.
They belong to the same fiend
who abducted the girl's father.
- Ratigan's peg-legged lackey.
- Uh... Basil?
A-ha!
Excellent work, old man.
Now there's nothing
to be afraid of, my dear.
- The scoundrel's quite gone.
- But not for long, Miss Flamhammer.
- Flaversham!
- Whatever. Now...
We simply pursue
our peg-legged friend
until he leads us to the girl's father.
- Then you'll get my daddy back?
- Yes!
And quite soon, if I'm not mistaken.
Now, hurry along, Dawson.
We must be off to Toby's.
- Toby's?
- Oh, you must meet him.
- He's just the chap for this.
- You... You want me to come?
I should think
a stout-hearted army mouse like you
would leap at the chance for adventure.
- Well, I am rather curious.
- Wait for me! I'm coming too!
What? Certainly not!
This is no business for children.
Are we going to take a cab?
My dear, I don't think you understand.
It will be quite dangerous.
Oh! Why, you... Look what...
Young lady, you are most definitely
not accompanying us.
And that is final!
And not a word out of you.
- Is that clear? I...
- Shh!
I observe that there's a good deal
of German music on the program.
It is introspective,
and I want to introspect.
But, Holmes, that music
is so frightfully dull.
Come on.
Toby?
Who is Toby?
Well, my dear, Toby is, uh...
Well, he's, uh...
I say, Basil, who is this Toby chap?
Ah! Here he is now.
Dawson, Toby.
Charmed, I'm sure.
Now, Toby, stop that!
Toby, cease! Desist!
Frightfully sorry, old man.
He has the most splendid sense
of smell of any hound I've trained.
But he can be deucedly frisky.
Hello, Toby!
Silly doggy!
Would you like a crumpet?
Now, Toby? To the matter at hand.
I want you to...
Good, now, Toby...
Toby...
I want you to find this fiend.
Yes, you know his type. A villain.
A scoundrel!
Low brow. Close-set eyes. Broken wing.
He's a peg-legged bat
with a broken wing.
Yes! That's the spirit!
Got his scent? Good boy!
Good boy!
- Miss Flamchester!
- Flaversham!
Whatever. Your father
is as good as found.
Toby,
sic 'em!
A-ha! Yoinks! Tally-ho!
The thrill of the hunt, eh, Dawson?
A-ha!
Quite!
Hoo-hoo! Our peg-legged quarry
can't be far now.
"Get the following.
"Tools." Check. I got tools.
"Gears." Double-check. I got gears.
"Girl." No, didn't get girl. "Uniforms."
I got plenty uniforms.
Oh, no. I gotta hide. I gotta hide.
I gotta hide!
Splendid job, Toby!
Now, Toby, sit.
- Toby, sit.
- Sit, Toby.
Good boy. If you'll excuse me.
You be good now.
We're going to find my father.
Here is our friend's entrance.
But, Basil, how could he fit
in through such a tiny...
Observe, doctor.
Basil, you astound me!
Shh.
Oh. I... I beg your pardon...
Oh, my.
Upon my word,
I've never seen so many toys.
Behind any of which could lurk
a bloodthirsty assassin.
So please, doctor, be very careful.
Oh!
Please!
Quiet.
Don't let this girl
out of your sight.
Now, Olivia, dear, stay close.
Hmm...
Checkmate.
A-ha!
Evidence of our peg-legged adversary.
Mmm-hmm. Oh, oh, oh, oh.
- Hmm. How very odd.
- What is it, Basil?
Isn't it painfully obvious, doctor?
These dolls have been
stripped of their uniforms.
And not by any child, either.
Hello.
Someone has taken the liberty
of removing the clockwork mechanisms
from these toys.
- Basil.
- Please, I'm trying to concentrate.
But Basil, I...
- Olivia!
- Gotcha!
Quickly, doctor!
Look out!
Bye-bye. Bye-bye!
Stop, you fiend!
Help! Uncle Basil, help!
I got the gears, I got the tools
I got the uniforms
I got the girl
Basil! Basil!
Mama, Mama.
Mama.
- Basil! Olivia... Olivia, she's...
- Mama.
- Yes! She's gone, Dawson!
- Confound it!
- Mama.
- I told you to watch over the girl.
Now she's been spirited away
by that maniacal little monster.
Soon to be in the clutches of the most
depraved mind in all of London!
I should have known better than to...
Than to...
Eh... I... Uh... Dawson?
Dawson?
I say, Dawson, old chap?
Oh. Uh... Poor girl.
I should have watched her more closely.
Don't worry, old fellow.
It's not entirely hopeless.
We'll get her back.
Do... Do you think there's a chance?
There's always a chance, doctor,
as long as one can think.
Mmm.
"Get the following.
- "Tools, gears..."
- What?
- "...girl..."
- "Get the..."
Dawson, you've done it!
This list is precisely what we need.
- What?
- Quickly, back to Baker Street.
Mr. Flaversham...
Allow me to present
your charming daughter.
- Olivia!
- Father!
Ow! My foot! My only foot!
Oh, Father!
I thought I'd never find you.
There, there, my bairn. I'm all right.
I was so worried about my little girl.
Oh, how sweet.
Oh, I just love tearful reunions.
- Now, come along, my dear.
- Oh, please! Please!
- Olivia! Oh, please, professor!
- Father!
Now, now...
Fidget will take good care of her.
That is, as long
as we have no further delays.
Yes, yes, I'll finish it.
Oh, just don't hurt my daughter.
Remember, it must be ready tonight.
Stop! Let me go!
You ugly old thing!
- That ought to hold you!
- Help! Let me out! Let me out!
See how you like that.
Ah, the uniforms.
Fidget, I knew I could rely on you.
Now, you didn't forget anything?
No problem.
I took care of everything.
Everything on the list.
Uh-oh.
- What's wrong?
- The list, I know...
- Where is the list?
- The list, yeah, yeah, yeah.
You see, it was like this.
I was in the toy store
getting uniforms when I heard...
You're not coming through.
A dog came. I ran.
I had baby bonnet, girl in bag
and Basil chased me.
What? Basil on the case!
Why you gibbering little...
Oh, my dear Fidget. You have been
hanging upside down too long.
You mean, you're not mad?
I'm glad you're taking it so well.
Not me, you idiot.
No, stop you stupid fur ball!
Open up! Open up! Oh!
Ay! Ah! You're hurting my wings!
How dare that idiot Basil poke his nose
into my scheme and foul up everything!
Let me out! Let me out!
Help...
I can just see that insufferable grin
on his smug face.
Yes, yes, I can just see it.
- Felicia, release him.
- I'm too young to die!
Fidget, you delightful little maniac.
You've presented me
with a singular opportunity.
Poor Basil!
Oh, he is in for a little surprise.
Offhand, I can deduce very little.
Only that the words are written
with a broad-pointed quill pen
which has spattered, twice.
That the paper is of
native Mongolian manufacture,
no watermark.
And has been gummed,
if I'm not in error
by a bat who has
been drinking Rodent's Delight,
a cheap brandy sold only
in the seediest pubs.
- Hmm. Amazing.
- Oh, not really, doctor.
We still don't know where it came from.
Perhaps a closer inspection
will tell us something.
Mmm-hmm. Hmm.
Mmm-hmm.
Coal dust.
Clearly of the type used in sewer lamps.
- But Basil...
- Shh. Don't speak!
Excuse me, Dawson.
Steady hand.
Yes. Yes. Good.
Come along, come along, come along,
come along, come along.
Yes, yes.
Good, good. Mmm.
No, bad. Good, good. Go, yeah.
Come along. Come along, come on.
Don't go back up.
Yes. Come along. Come on.
Yes... Yes!
We've done it, old fellow!
This reaction
could only have been triggered
by the paper's extreme saturation
with distillation of sodium chloride.
Salt water? Great Scott.
It proves, beyond a doubt,
this list came from the riverfront area.
Now, steady on there, Basil.
No, no. Elementary, my dear Dawson.
We merely look
for a seedy pub at the only spot
where the sewer connects
to the waterfront.
Stay, Toby. Stay.
Basil?
- Come, come, Dawson.
- I feel utterly ridiculous.
Don't be absurd.
You look perfect.
- Perfect? Perfectly foolish.
- Shh, shh, shh, shh.
Dawson,
stay close and do as I do.
Oh, I do beg your pardon, madam.
Quite unintentional
I assure you.
How impertinent!
Remember, we're low-life ruffians.
I was until that...
Shh, shh.
Get off, you eight-legged bum!
What's your pleasure, mates?
I'll have a dry sherry
with, uh... Oh, perhaps a twist of...
Two pints
for me and my shipmate.
Oh, by the way, we just got into port.
We're looking for an old friend of mine.
Maybe you know him.
Goes by the name of Ratigan!
I... uh... never heard of him.
Boo!
Dearest friends
dear gentlemen
Listen to my song
Life down here's been hard for you
Life has made you strong
Let me lift the mood
With my attitude
Hey, fellas
The time is right
Get ready
Tonight's the night
Boys, what you're hoping for
will come true
Let me be good to you
You tough guys
You're feeling all alone
You rough guys
The best o' you sailors and bums
All o' my chums
So dream on
And drink your beer
Get cozy
Your baby's here
You won't be misunderstood
Let me be good to you
Hey, fellas
I'll take off all my blues
There's nothing I won't do
Just for you
There you are, boys.
It's, uh... on the house.
I say, how very generous.
Dawson,
these drinks have been drugged.
Has a rather
nice bite to it.
Jolly good, ladies. Jolly good.
Dawson, get a hold of yourself.
Oh, bravo! Bravo!
- So dream on
- Whoops!
And drink your beer
If it isn't
our peg-legged friend.
Dawson... Oh, what luck!
Dawson? Dawson!
Your baby's gonna come through
Let me be good
To you
Yeah!
- Dawson. Dawson!
- What? Wha... What!
- What in heaven's name is going on?
- I've spotted our peg-legged...
Come on, old fellow.
There's not a moment to lose.
Let me be good to you
So dream on and drink your beer
- Your baby's here
- Basil?
Basil?
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
Follow me.
Great Scott.
I can't see a thing.
Grab my coat and follow along.
No, no, no, not that way.
Dawson, look out for your...
Ow! Confound it!
Do you have any idea
where we're going?
But of course. Left turn.
Right turn here, doctor.
A-ha! Dawson! We found it!
Ratigan's secret lair.
And it's filthier than I imagined.
Dawson, the bottle!
- It's stuck.
- Olivia?
Surprise!
Bravo! Bravo!
A marvelous performance.
Though, frankly,
I expected you 15 minutes earlier.
Trouble with the chemistry set, old boy?
Ratigan, no one can have
a higher opinion of you than I have,
and I think you're a slimy,
contemptible sewer rat.
By the way, Basil,
I just love your disguise.
Really, one would hardly recognize you.
The greatest...
...detective in all mousedom!
Ratigan, so help me,
I'll see you behind bars yet!
You fool! Isn't it clear to you?
The superior mind has triumphed.
I've won!
Oh, I love it! I love it!
You don't know what
a delightful dilemma it was
trying to decide on the most
appropriate method for your demise.
I had so many ingenious ideas,
I didn't know which to choose.
So, I decided to use them all.
Marvelous, isn't it?
But here,
let me show you how it works.
Picture this.
First, a sprightly tune
I've recorded especially for you.
As the song plays, the cord tightens,
and when the song ends,
the metal ball is released,
rolling along its merry way until...
Snap!
Boom.
Twang.
Thunk.
Splat! And, so ends the short,
undistinguished career
of Basil of Baker Street.
- You're despicable!
- Yes.
- Everything's ready?
- All set, boss.
Oh, this is wicked!
So delightfully wicked.
Mr. Flaversham,
let me congratulate you
on a superb piece of craftsmanship.
See what you can do
with the proper motivation?
- You all know the plan.
- Right, professor.
It was my fond hope to stay
and witness your final scene,
but you were 15 minutes late,
and I do have an important engagement
at Buckingham Palace.
Now, you will remember
to smile for the camera, won't you?
Hmm?
Say, "cheese".
- You fiend!
- Sorry, chubby.
You should've chosen
your friends more carefully.
Goodbye so soon
And isn't this a crime
We know by now that time...
Adieu, auf wiedersehen,
arrivederci, farewell.
Bye, bye, Basil.
With time so short
I'll say so long
And go so soon
Goodbye
You followed me
I followed you
We were like each other's
shadows for a while
Now as you see
this game is through
So although it hurts
Wh... What did he mean,
an engagement at Buckingham Palace?
Haven't you
figured it out yet, doctor?
The queen's in danger,
and the Empire's doomed.
The queen?
Psst. Over here.
Come on. Over here.
Hmm.
- Come in.
- Begging Your Majesty's pardon.
A present has arrived
in honor of your jubilee.
A present? Oh, how wonderful!
I just adore jubilees.
Here you are, sweetheart.
Have you been with us long?
"To our beloved queen,
this gift we send
"as her 60 year reign
"comes to an end"?
How extraordinary!
Goodness gracious!
Amazing likeness, isn't it,
Your Majesty?
Professor Ratigan!
Guards! Seize this despicable creature!
- Guards, seize this...
- Despicable creature!
- Oh, how dare you!
- Take her away.
Let go of me, you ruffians!
- Move along, honey!
- You fiends!
Traitors!
So although it hurts
I'll try to smile as I say
Goodbye so soon
And isn't this...
Basil?
- Basil!
- Oh, how could I have been so blind?
We all make mistakes.
We can't let that stop us.
We have to...
Ratigan's proved
he's more clever than I.
He would never have walked into
such an obvious trap.
Oh, pull yourself together!
You can stop that villain! Why...
Why...
So long... So long... So long
Basil! The record!
Oh, it's finally happened.
I've been outwitted.
- Basil, please!
- Beaten! Duped!
Made a fool of! Oh, ridiculed!
- Belittled!
- That's enough!
Dash it all, Basil! The queen's
in danger. Olivia's counting on us.
We're about to be splattered, and all
you can do is feel sorry for yourself.
Well, I know you can save us.
But if you've given up, then
set it off now and be done with it.
We know by now
that time knows how to fly
Set it off now.
Yes. We...
- We'll set the trap off now!
- Basil! Wait!
I didn't mean that we ought...
Angle of the trajectory,
multiplied by the square root
of an isosceles triangle,
dividing Guttermeg's principle
of opposing forces in motion,
and adjusting for
the difference in equilibrium...
Dawson, at the exact moment I tell you,
we must release
the triggering mechanism.
- What?
- Get ready, Dawson.
Steady.
Now!
Thank you, Dawson.
Smile everyone!
On this most august occasion,
we are gathered here
not only to commemorate
my 60 years as queen,
but to honor one...
Of truly noble stature.
"I present to you
a statesman among mice.
"A gifted leader..."
A crusader for justice...
Over here, fatty. You're a ton, toots.
Here kitty, kitty. Time for mouse chow.
A majestic mountain of humility,
and my new royal consort,
Professor Ratigan.
Toby!
The game's afoot, Toby.
Our queen is in mortal danger.
To Buckingham Palace!
Thank you, Your Majesty.
And now, as your new royal consort,
I have a few slight suggestions.
Item one...
Stop it!
Open wide.
Bye-bye.
Down, kitty! Down!
Item 96...
"A heavy tax shall be levied
against all parasites and sponges,
"such as the elderly, the infirm,
"and especially little children."
That's ridiculous. You're insane.
Perhaps I haven't made myself clear.
I have the power!
- Of course you do.
- I am supreme.
- Only you.
- This is my kingdom!
That is, of course,
with Your Highness' permission.
Most assuredly,
- you insidious fiend.
- What?
- You're not my royal consort.
- What a sense of humor.
- You're a cheap fraud and impostor.
- Flaversham!
A corrupt, vicious, demented,
low-life scoundrel.
There's no evil scheme
you wouldn't concoct.
No depravity you wouldn't commit.
You, professor,
are none other than
a foul, stenchus rodentus,
commonly known as a...
- Don't say it!
- Sewer rat!
Arrest that fiend!
The girl! The girl!
Stay where you are, or the girl dies!
Hurry, Dawson!
There he goes!
Dawson! Flaversham!
Gather up those balloons.
Just wait! Basil's smarter than you!
He's going to put you in jail.
He's not afraid of a big old,
ugly rat like you.
Would you kindly sit down and shut up!
Let her go, chaps!
We have to lighten the load.
Oh, you want to lighten the load?
- Excellent idea.
- No!
No! Not me! I can't fly! I can't fly!
Steady!
Basil, look out!
Closer, Dawson!
Closer!
Daddy, I can't reach!
I can't reach!
Basil! Over here!
There's no escape this time, Basil!
I've won!
On the contrary!
The game's not over yet!
Oh!
- Hooray!
- Hooray! It's Basil!
- Good fellow!
- Jolly good!
To be thanked
by the queen herself.
Oh, how very thrilling.
- Hey, Basil?
- All in a day's work, doctor.
Oh, Dr. Dawson, you were wonderful.
Indeed.
Oh, my, we're late to catch our train.
- Come along, Olivia.
- Yes, Father.
Goodbye, Basil.
I... I'll never forget you.
Nor I you, Miss... Miss Flangerhanger.
Whatever.
- Goodbye, Dr. Dawson.
- Goodbye, my dear.
Goodbye.
Well, um...
- not a bad little girl, actually.
- Not at all.
Well, it's time I was on my way, too.
But...
- But I thought...
- Well, the case is over.
Perhaps it's...
Well, perhaps it's best
I found my own living quarters.
But... Now who can that be?
Is this the home of the famous
Basil of Baker Street?
Indeed it is, miss.
You look as if you're in some trouble.
Oh, I am! I am!
Then, you've come to precisely
the right place.
Allow me to introduce
my trusted associate, Dr. Dawson,
with whom I do all my cases.
Isn't that right, doctor?
Wha... What? Yes, yes!
By all means.
Mmm.
As you can see,
this young lady has just arrived
from the Hampstead District,
and is troubled
about the disappearance
of an emerald ring, missing from
the third finger of her right hand.
Now, tell me your story,
and pray, be precise.
From that time on,
Basil and I were a close team
and over the years,
we had many cases together.
But I shall always look back
on that first with the most fondness.
My introduction
to Basil of Baker Street,
the great mouse detective.