Chim chiminy chim chiminy
Chim chim cheree
A sweep is as lucky as lucky can be
Chim chiminy chim chiminy
Chim chim cheroo
Good luck will rub off
when he shakes hands with you
Chim chiminy chim chim cheree
Chim cheroo
All right, ladies and gents.
Comical poems
suitable for the occasion,
extemporised and thought up
before your very eyes.
All right, here we go.
(SINGING) Room here for everyone
Gather around
The constable's responstable.
Now, how does that sound?
Hmm...
Hello, Miss Lark
I got one for you
Miss Lark likes to walk in the park...
- Grrrr.
...with Andrew!
Arf! Arf!
- Hello, Andrew.
- Arf! Arf! Grrrr! Grrrr!
Ah, Mrs Cory
A story for you
Your daughters were shorter than you,
but they grew.
Dear Miss Persimmon...
Yes?
Wind's in the east
Mist comin' in
Like something is brewin'
About to begin
Can't put me finger
on what lies in store
But I feel what's to happen
All happened before
Arf! Arf! Grrrr!
I'm sorry. Where was I?
Thank you, one and all,
for your kind support.
Ah, Miss Lark, thank you.
Crikey.
Bless you, guv.
Generosity itself, that's what you are.
No charge.
Oh, it's you. Hello.
Number 17 Cherry Tree Lane, you say?
All right. Come with me.
This here's Cherry Tree Lane.
Nice little spot, you might say.
Number 17 is just down a bit.
Now this imposing edifice
what first greets the eye
is the home of Admiral Boom,
late of His Majesty's navy.
Likes his house shipshape
and Bristol fashion at all times.
(BLOWS BOS'N'S WHISTLE)
- Time gun ready?
- Ready and charged, sir.
- Three minutes and six seconds.
- Aye, aye, sir.
What he's famous for is punctuality.
The whole world
takes its time from Greenwich,
but Greenwich
takes its time from Admiral Boom.
What cheer, Admiral?
Good afternoon! Where are you bound?
Some parties want to see number 17.
- Enter that in the log.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Some advice, young man.
Storm signals are up at 17.
Heavy weather brewing there.
Thank you, sir. I'll keep an eye skinned.
Here we are.
Number 17 Cherry Tree Lane,
residence of George Banks, esquire.
(SHOUTING)
Hello, hello, hello. The admiral's right.
Heavy weather brewing at number 17,
and no mistake.
Leave her alone!
Don't you be trying to stop
the wretched creature!
Let her go and good riddance.
I never liked her from the moment
she set foot in the door.
But who'll get stuck with the children?
Me, that's who!
Her and her high and mighty ways.
And that face of her
that would stop a coal barge, it would.
Indeed, Mrs Brill!
I wouldn't stay in this house
another minute
for all the jewels in Christendom.
No, Katie Nanna, don't go!
Stand away from that door!
What'll I tell the master
about the children?
It's no concern of mine.
Those beasts ran away from me.
They must be somewhere.
Did you look around the zoo?
You think the lion got them?
They're fond of
hanging around the cage.
I've said my say.
I've done with this house forever.
Hip, hip, hooray!
Don't stumble on the way out.
No, no, Katie Nanna!
(SINGING)
Mrs Banks. She's home.
Our daughter's daughters will adore us
And we'll sing in grateful chorus
"Well done, Sister Suffragette"
Good evening, Katie Nanna and Ellen.
The meeting was glorious!
Mrs Whitbourne-Allen chained herself
to the prime minister's carriage.
You should have been there!
And Mrs Ainslie
was carried off to prison.
Singing and scattering pamphlets
all the way!
Madam, I've always given my best...
Thank you, Katie Nanna.
I knew you were one of us.
We're clearly soldiers in petticoats
And dauntless crusaders
for women's votes
Though we adore men individually
We agree that as a group
they're rather stupid
Mrs Banks...
Cast off the shackles of yesterday
Shoulder to shoulder into the fray
Our daughter's daughters will adore us
And they'll sing in grateful chorus
"Well done, Sister Suffragette"
I don't wish to offend, but...
From Kensington to Billingsgate
One hears the restless cries
From every corner of the land
Womankind, arise
Political equality
and equal rights with men
Take heart, for Mrs Pankhurst
has been clapped in irons again
No more the meek
and mild subservients we
We're fighting for our rights militantly
Never you fear
If I may have a word...
So cast off the shackles of yesterday
Shoulder to shoulder into the fray
Our daughter's daughters will adore us
And they'll sing in grateful chorus
"Well done"
Mrs Banks!
What is it, Katie Nanna?
I have something to say to you.
Where are the children?
The children, to be precise,
are not here.
They've disappeared again.
That's really careless of you.
That's the third time this week.
The fourth, madam.
I've had my fill.
I'm not one to speak ill of the children.
When do you expect them home?
I couldn't say.
If you'd compute my wages...
Oh, gracious! You're not leaving?
What will Mr Banks say?
He'll be cross
when he finds the children missing.
Put these away.
The cause infuriates Mr Banks.
I beseech you, please reconsider.
Think of the children.
Think of Mr Banks.
He was just getting used to you.
Posts, everyone!
4, 3, 2, 1...
Fire!
- I do beseech you...
- My wages, if you please.
Bit early tonight, Admiral?
Nonsense. Bang on the dot, as usual.
How's the world of finance?
Never better.
Money's sound,
credit rates are moving up,
- and the pound is admired everywhere.
- Good.
How about you?
Bit chancy, I'd say.
The wind's up. The glass is falling.
- Don't like it.
- Good. Good, good.
Banks, you're steering into
a nasty piece of weather.
Banks!
Do you hear me?
Hello, Katie Nanna.
That must be heavy. Allow me.
Hmph!
What a very pretty hat.
(SINGING)
I feel a surge of deep satisfaction
Much as a king astride his noble steed
Thank you.
When I return from daily strife
to hearth and wife
How pleasant is the life I lead
- Dear, the children...
- Yes, yes, yes.
I run my home precisely on schedule
At 6:01, I march through my door
My slippers, sherry, and pipe
are due at 6:02
Consistent is the life I lead
George, they're missing.
Splendid, splendid.
It's grand to be an Englishman in 1910
King Edward's on the throne
It's the age of men
I'm the lord of my castle
The sovereign, the liege
I treat my subjects
servants, children, wife
With a firm, but gentle hand
Noblesse oblige
It's 6:03, and the heirs to my dominion
are scrubbed and tubbed
And adequately fed
And so I'll pat them on the head
and send them off to bed
Ah, lordly is the life I lead
Winifred, where are the children?
They're not here, dear.
Of course they're here.
Where else would they be?
- I don't know.
- You don't know?
They're missing.
Katie Nanna has looked everywhere.
Very well. I'll deal with this at once.
The police station. Quickly, please.
We needn't bother the police.
The fact is...
Facts cloud the issue.
One fact alone is clear.
Katie Nanna's faltered.
She's disappointed us.
I shall bring her to book...
Oh.
- She's left us, hasn't she?
- Yes, only just.
- George Banks here.
- (DOORBELL RINGS)
17 Cherry Tree Lane.
It's a matter of some urgency.
Please send a policeman.
The policeman's here, George.
What? Oh. Very prompt.
Wonderful service.
Thank you so much. Good night.
Come in, constable.
While on duty across the park,
I noted some stray valuables.
- I believe they're yours.
- Valuables?
Come along now.
Jane.
Michael.
Winifred, don't be emotional.
I wouldn't be too hard on them, sir.
They've had a long, weary walk today.
Children, come here at once.
Well?
- Sorry we lost Katie Nanna, Father.
- It was windy...
And the kite was too strong.
The kite ran away, sir, not the children.
Thank you. I'll manage this.
It wasn't a good kite.
We made it ourselves.
Perhaps if you helped us...
That's the ticket.
Kites are skittish things.
Only last week...
I'm very grateful to you, constable.
The cook will
find you a plate of something.
I shall now return to my duties.
Thank you, constable.
Good night, miss. Good night, ma'am.
Good night, sir.
"Cook will find something."
I'm awfully sorry about this, George.
You'll want to discuss it.
I would, indeed.
Ellen, take the children upstairs.
Yes, sir.
I knew it.
Who bears the brunt of everything?
Me, that's who.
They don't want
an honest working girl here.
They need a ruddy zoo keeper.
Sorry.
When I chose Katie Nanna,
I thought she'd be firm.
She looked solemn, cross.
Never confuse efficiency
with a liver complaint.
I'll do better next time.
Next time? You've engaged six nannies.
They've all been unqualified disasters.
I quite agree.
Choosing a nanny is a delicate task,
requiring insight, balanced judgement,
and an ability to read character.
Under the circumstances,
it might be apropos
to select the next person myself.
Would you, George?
I'll do this properly.
I'll advertise in The Times.
- Take this down, please.
- Yes, of course.
Wanted... No, required...
Nanny.
Firm, respectable, no-nonsense.
(SINGING)
A British nanny must be a general
The future empire lies within her hands
And so the person that we need
to mould the breed
It is a nanny who can give commands
- Getting this, Winifred?
- Yes, every word.
A British bank is run with precision
A British home requires nothing less
Tradition, discipline, and rules
must be the tools
Without them
disorder, catastrophe, anarchy
In short, you have a ghastly mess
Splendid, George. Inspirational.
The Times will be so pleased.
- Father.
- Yes?
We've discussed everything,
and we're very sorry about today.
I should think so.
- It was wrong.
- Indeed.
We'll cooperate with the new nanny.
I'll be glad for your help.
That's why we wrote this advertisement.
Advertisement for what?
The new nanny.
- You wrote an...
- George, let's listen.
You wanted our help.
Oh, very well.
"Wanted, a nanny for
two adorable children."
"Adorable."
That's debatable, I must say.
(SINGING)
"If you want this choice position
"Have a cheery disposition"
Jane, I don't...
"Rosy cheeks, no warts
I wrote that.
"Play games, all sorts
"You must be kind
"You must be witty
"Very sweet and fairly pretty"
- That's...
- George, please.
"Take us on outings, give us treats
"Sing songs, bring sweets
"Never be cross or cruel
"Never give us castor oil or gruel
"Love us as a son and daughter
"And never smell of barley water"
I wrote that, too.
"If you won't scold and dominate us
"We will never give you
cause to hate us
"We won't hide your spectacles
so you can't see
"Put toads in your bed
or pepper in your tea
"Hurry, nanny
"Many thanks
"Sincerely
"Jane and Michael Banks"
Thank you. Most interesting.
We've had enough of this.
Please return to the nursery.
- They were only trying to help.
- I'm aware of that.
I congratulate myself on stepping in.
"Play games, sing songs, give treats."
Ridiculous.
No question in my mind.
Now is the time for action.
The Times, please.
I don't know the number.
Oh, George, you're always so forceful.
The Times?
George Banks, Cherry Tree Lane.
I wish to place an advertisement.
(BLOWS BOS'N'S WHISTLE)
- Time gun ready?
- Ready and charged, sir.
I'll take the report, Mr Binnacle.
Wind's coming from a new quarter.
So it is.
- Sir.
- What?
Something taking place
off the port bow.
Ghastly looking crew, I must say.
There's a queue of nannies outside.
Shall I show them in?
I said 8:00, and 8:00 it shall be.
12 seconds to go.
- 10, 9...
- Posts!
7, 6, 5, 4,
3, 2, 1.
(CANNON FIRES)
It is now 8:00.
Yes, sir.
I have told you repeatedly, Ellen,
I dislike being hurried into things.
I don't understand.
They're nothing like
what we advertised for.
Woof! Woof! Woof!
Michael, look!
- Perhaps it's a witch.
- Nonsense. Witches have brooms.
It's her. It's the person.
She's answered our advertisement.
Rosy cheeks and everything.
- Show them in, one at a time.
- Yes, sir.
- Come in, one at a time.
- Thank you.
You are the father of
Jane and Michael Banks?
I said, you are the father of
Yes, of course.
You brought your references?
I never give references.
I believe it very old-fashioned.
We'll see about that then.
Now then, the qualifications.
Item one, "A cheery disposition."
I am never cross.
Item two, "Rosy cheeks."
Obviously.
Item three, "Play games, all sorts."
They'll find my games
extremely diverting.
Where did you get this paper?
I tore it up.
Excuse me.
Item four, "You must be kind."
I am kind, but extremely firm.
Have you lost something?
That paper. I thought that I...
You are George Banks?
And you did advertise for a nanny?
George Banks.
Very well, then.
Tore it up, turned it over,
threw it in the...
Are you ill?
I hope not.
About my wages...
- The reference is obscure.
- Obscure.
We must be clear on that.
- I require every second Tuesday off.
- Every Tuesday.
Perhaps a trial period would be wise.
Hmm... I'll give you one week.
I'll know by then.
I'll see the children now.
Close your mouth. We are not codfish.
Don't stand there. Best foot forward.
Spit spot.
- George?
- Aah!
I thought you were
interviewing nannies.
I was, I was.
You've selected one already?
Yes, it's done.
- Where is she?
- In the nursery.
- I put her to work straight-away.
- How clever.
I'd have muddled everything.
Is she everything
that we hoped she'd be?
It all happened rather quickly.
I mean, I... I, uh...
Will she be firm and give commands?
Will she mould our young breed?
Winifred, I think she will.
I think she will!
In that case, perhaps
Ellen should dismiss the others.
The others?
- Ellen!
- Yes, sir?
Tell the others
the position's been filled.
- The others, sir?
- Yes, the others.
How many nannies
does this house need?
The position has been filled.
I'm afraid the nursery isn't very tidy.
Rather like a bear pit.
- That's a funny bag.
- Carpet.
- To carry carpets?
- No, made of.
Your room has a lovely view.
Hmm...
It's not exactly Buckingham Palace...
Still, it's clean.
Yes, it will be quite suitable.
Just needs a touch here and there.
First things first.
The place to hang a hat
is on a hat stand.
Oh!
This will never do.
I much prefer
seeing all of my face at once.
But there was nothing in it.
Never judge things
by their appearance, even carpetbags.
I never do.
"A thing of beauty is a joy forever."
Hmm... A little more light perhaps.
We'd better watch this one.
- She's tricky.
- She's wonderful.
Much better.
Now, let me see.
That's funny. I always carry it.
It must be here somewhere.
- What?
- My tape measure.
- What for?
- To see how you measure up.
That's the funniest thing I ever saw.
Ah ha ha ha. Here it is.
Good.
Come along, then. Quickly.
Head up, Michael. Don't slouch.
Just as I thought.
"Extremely stubborn and suspicious."
- I am not.
- See for yourself.
- "Extremely stubborn and susips..."
- Suspicious.
Now you, Jane.
"Rather inclined to giggle.
Doesn't put things away."
How about you?
Very well. Hold this for me.
As I expected.
"Mary Poppins,
practically perfect in every way."
Mary Poppins.
Is that your name? It's lovely.
I've always liked it.
Shall we move?
In your advertisement,
did you not request games?
Yes.
First we'll play
"Well Begun Is Half Done."
That sounds suspicious.
Otherwise entitled,
"Let's Tidy Up The Nursery."
I told you she was tricky.
Shall we begin?
It is a game, isn't it?
Depends on your viewpoint.
You see, in every job that must be done,
there is an element of fun.
You find the fun,
and snap, the job's a game.
(SINGING)
And every task you undertake
becomes a piece of cake
A lark, a spree
It's very clear to see
That a
spoonful of sugar
helps the medicine go down
The medicine go down
Medicine go down
Just a spoonful of sugar
helps the medicine go down
In a most delightful way
(BIRDS WHISTLE)
A robin feathering his nest
has very little time to rest
While gathering
his bits of twine and twig
Though quite intent in his pursuit
He has a merry tune to toot
He knows a song
Will move the job along
(WHISTLING)
For a spoonful of sugar
helps the medicine go down
The medicine go down
Medicine go down
Just a spoonful of sugar
helps the medicine go down
In a most delightful way
(WHISTLING)
(SNAP)
The honeybees that fetch the nectar
from the flowers to the comb
Never tire of ever buzzing to and fro
Because they take a little nip
from every flower that they sip
And hence
They find
Their task is not a grind
Aaah
Cheeky.
Don't be all day.
(SNAP)
Let me out! Let me out!
Let me out!
Well...
Thank you now.
When you've quite finished!
Thank you.
That's quite sufficient.
Hats and coats, please.
It's time for our outing.
Let's tidy up the nursery again.
Enough's as good as a feast.
You're not as well turned out as I'd like.
Still, there's time.
Spit spot.
And off we go!
(SINGING) For a spoonful of sugar
helps the medicine go down
The medicine go down
Medicine go down
Just a spoonful of sugar
helps the medicine go down
In the most delightful way
(SINGING) Chim chiminy chim chiminy
Chim chim cheroo
I does what I likes and I likes...
What I do
Hello, art lovers.
Today I'm a screever
And as you can see
A screever's an artist
Of highest degree
And it's all me own work
from me own memory
Not Royal Academy.
Still, they're not bad, are they?
Chim chiminy chim chiminy
Chim chim cheroo
I draws what I likes
and I likes what I drew
No remuneration do I ask of you
But me cap would be glad
of a copper or two
Me cap would be glad
Wait!
Don't move.
Don't move a muscle.
Stay right where you are.
I'd know that silhouette anywhere.
- Mary Poppins!
- Hello, Bert.
You know Jane and Michael.
Well, I've seen them here and about.
Chasing a kite last time, weren't it?
We're going to the park.
To the park?
Not if I know Mary Poppins.
Other nannies go to the park.
When you're with Mary Poppins,
quick as you can say,
"Bob's your uncle,"
the most unusual things happen.
What are you talking about?
It's not my place to say,
but she probably has in mind
a jolly holiday.
Something along these lines.
That's always good. Here we go.
(GURGLE)
(SCREECH POP)
How about a lovely circus?
Lions and tigers.
World famous artistes
performing death-defying feats
of dexterity and skill.
Ta-da!
Oh, that's lovely.
I'd much rather go there.
A typical English countryside
done by a loving hand.
Though you can't see it, there's
a little country fair down that road.
I don't see any road.
What? No road?
Just wants a bit of something here
and a bit of something there.
There.
A country road
suitable for travel and high adventure.
May we go, Mary Poppins, please?
Don't you think it's lovely,
Mary Poppins?
Now's the time. No one's looking.
Oh, please. Please.
I have no intention of making
a spectacle of myself.
All right. I'll do it myself.
Do what?
Bit of magic.
- Magic?
- It's easy.
Let's see.
You think.
You wink.
You do a double blink.
You close your eyes and jump.
Is something supposed to happen?
Bert, what utter nonsense.
Oh.
Why do you complicate things?
Give me your hand, Michael.
Don't slouch.
1, 2...
Mary Poppins, you look beautiful.
- Do you really think so?
- Cross my heart, you do.
You look fine, too, Bert.
Isn't there a fair?
Down the road and behind the hill.
I hear the merry-go-round.
- Tell them hello.
- Don't smudge the drawing.
(SINGING) Ain't it a glorious day
Right as a mornin' in May
I feel like I could fly
Now, Bert, none of your larking about.
Have you ever seen
the grass so green
Or a bluer sky
Oh, it's a jolly holiday with Mary
Mary makes your heart so light
You haven't changed.
When the day is grey and ordinary
Mary makes the sun shine bright
Oh, honestly.
Oh, happiness is bloomin'
all around her
The daffodils are smiling at the dove
When Mary holds your hand
You feel so grand
Your heart starts beatin'
like a big brass band
You are light-headed.
It's a jolly holiday with Mary
No wonder that it's Mary that we love
Oh, it's a jolly holiday with Mary
Mary makes your heart so light
When the day is grey and ordinary
Mary makes the sun shine bright
Oh, happiness is bloomin'
all around her
The daffodils are smiling
at the dove, oink, oink
When Mary holds your hand
You feel so grand
Your heart starts beatin'
like a big brass band
It's a jolly holiday with Mary
No wonder that it's Mary that we love
Thank you.
Our pleasure, Mary Poppins.
Oh, it's a jolly holiday with you, Bert
Gentlemen like you are few
A vanishing breed.
Though you're just
a diamond in the rough, Bert
Underneath your blood is blue
Common knowledge.
You'd never think
of pressing your advantage
Forbearance
is the hallmark of your creed
A lady needn't fear
when you are near
Your sweet gentility is crystal clear
Oh, it's a jolly holiday with you, Bert
A jolly, jolly holiday with you
Waiter! Waiter?
Now then, what would be nice?
We'll start with raspberry ice
And then some cakes and tea
Order what you will
There'll be no bill
It's complimentary
You're very kind.
Anything for you, Mary Poppins.
You're our favourite person.
Right you are.
It's true that...
Mavis and Sybil
have ways that are winning
And Prudence and Gwendolyn
set your heart spinnin'
Phoebe's delightful
Maude is disarming
Felicia, Janice and Lydia
Charming!
Cynthia's dashing, Vivian's sweet
Stephanie's smashing, Priscilla a treat
Veronica, Millicent, Agnes, and Jane
Convivial company, time and again
Dorcas and Phyllis and Glynis are sorts
I'll agree are three jolly good sports
But cream of the crop, tip of the top
is Mary Poppins and there we stop
When Mary holds your hand
You feel so grand
Your heart starts beatin'
like a big brass band
Woo!
It's a jolly holiday with Mary
No wonder that it's Mary that we love
Yahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo!
Our own private merry-go-round.
Nice. Very nice, indeed,
if you don't want to go nowhere.
Who says we're not going anywhere?
Oh, guard!
Righto, Mary Poppins.
Thank you.
They're off!
Mary Poppins leads by two lengths,
Jane's second by...
My horse is the fastest.
Hear that, mate?
Want to put up with that?
Is that the best you can do?
Hurry up, boy!
Not so fast, please. Michael.
Bert, you're just as bad.
Sorry. Whoa, boy. Whoa.
Easy, boy. Whoa. Whoa.
Just a bit of high spirits, Mary Poppins.
Please control yourself.
We're not on a racecourse.
Follow me, please.
- Good morning.
- Oh, yes, quite. What?
I say.
Have you...
Ever?
Never!
View halloo.
Oh, yes, definitely. A view halloo.
View halloo?
(PLAYING)
Faith and Begorra.
'Tis them redcoats again.
Oh, musha, musha.
Poor little bloke.
Let's give him a hand.
Saints preserve us.
Yikes!
Tally ho! Da-doo da-doo!
Up you go. Now hang on.
Would you look at this?
An elegant merry-go-round horse.
Come on, you dirty omadhauns.
I'll lick all of you.
Faster, me beauty. Faster!
Riders, would you be kind
and let me pass?
Certainly, ma'am.
- Thank you.
- Not at all, ma'am.
Excellent time, gentlemen.
- Quite.
- Perfect day for it.
Ahem.
Oh, how nice.
Hooray! Yay! Yay!
Hold still. Watch the dickie bird.
- How does it feel to win?
- Well...
- Gaining fame and fortune.
- Yes.
- Your picture in the newspaper.
- Actually...
Extreme good looks, may I say?
No words describe your emotion?
Gentlemen, on the contrary,
there's a very good word.
- Right?
- Tell them.
Right.
(SINGING)
It's supercalifragilisticexpialidocious
Even though the sound of it
is something quite atrocious
If you say it loud enough
You'll always sound precocious
Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious
Um diddle diddle diddle
um diddle ay
'Cause I was afraid to speak
when I was just a lad
Me father gave me nose a tweak
and told me I was bad
But then one day I learnt a word
that saved me aching nose
The biggest word you ever heard
and this is how it goes
Oh, supercalifragilisticexpialidocious
Even though the sound of it
is something quite atrocious
If you say it loud enough
You'll always sound precocious
Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious
Um diddle diddle diddle
um diddle ay
He travelled all around the world
And everywhere he went
He'd use his word and all would say,
"There goes a clever gent"
When dukes and maharajas
pass the time of day with me
I say me special word
and then they ask me out to tea
Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious
Even though the sound of it
is something quite atrocious
If you say it loud enough
You'll always sound precocious
Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious
Um diddle diddle diddle um diddle ay
You can say it backwards...
Dociousaliexpiistifragicalirupes.
- Bit too much?
- Indubitably.
So when the cat has got your tongue
There's no need for dismay
Just summon up this word
and then you've got a lot to say
But better use it carefully
or it could change your life
For example, I said it to me girl.
Now me girl's me wife.
And a lovely thing she is.
She's supercalifragilisticexpialidocious
Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious
(THUNDER)
Jane, Michael!
Stay close now.
Oh, Bert, all your fine drawings.
There's more where they came from.
Meantime, I'm changing businesses.
This is hot chestnut weather.
Come along, children.
- Bye, Bert.
- Bye-bye.
- Bye.
- Bye, Jane and Michael.
Chim chiminy, chim chiminy
Chim chim cheroo
La dum da da dum
Da da da da dum
No, I won't take your nasty medicine!
Do we have to, Mary Poppins?
People with wet feet
must take their medicine.
I don't want it.
Oh!
Lime cordial! Delicious!
Strawberry! Mmm!
Rum punch.
Quite satisfactory. (HICCUP)
You won't ever leave us, will you?
Do you have a handkerchief?
Will you stay if we're good?
A pie crust promise.
Easily made, easily broken.
Whatever would we do without you?
I'll stay until the wind changes.
How long will that be?
It's time to go to sleep.
We couldn't possibly go to sleep.
So many lovely things happened today!
Did they?
We jumped into Bert's picture.
The horses fled the carousel.
And we went riding!
Tally ho! Tchunga! Tally ho! Yoicks!
Really?
Don't you remember?
You won the race.
A respectable person like me?
How dare you.
I saw you do it.
Another word
and I'll summon a policeman.
I saw it happen!
- Go to sleep.
- I don't want to.
We're much too excited.
Very well. Suit yourselves.
(SINGING) Stay awake
Don't rest your head
Don't lie down
Upon your bed
While the moon
Drifts in the skies
Stay awake
Don't close
Your eyes
Though the world
Is fast asleep
Though your pillow's
Soft and deep
You're not sleepy
As you seem
Stay awake
Don't nod and dream
Don't nod
And dream
Glorious day, Mr Binnacle, glorious.
Nobody sleeps this morning.
Put in double powder.
A double charge? Aye, sir.
Shake things up a bit, what?
- Lovely, lovely morning, Ellen.
- Indeed it is, ma'am.
- You packed the spoiled eggs?
- Yes.
After our meeting, we're all going
to throw things at the prime minister.
How distinguished you look today.
What's all that fearful caterwauling?
It's cook singing.
- What's wrong with her?
- She's happy as a cricket.
Since you hired Mary Poppins,
the most extraordinary thing
has come over the household.
- Ellen hasn't broken a dish all morning.
- That is extraordinary.
She and cook fight
like cats and dogs, but today...
- I'll hold the door.
- Thanks ever so.
(HUMMING)
Ellen, stop making that offensive noise.
(CHIRPING)
And shut the window.
That bird's giving me a headache.
Yes, sir.
Quiet!
You're giving the master a headache.
I'm sorry you're unwell.
Who said I'm unwell?
I just don't understand why
everyone's so confoundedly cheerful.
(SINGING)
Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious
How lovely. Thank you, my darling.
Stop, stop, stop!
- Good morning, Father.
- Morning.
Mary Poppins taught us...
Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious
What are you talking about? Supercali...
Whatever it is.
It's something to say when
you don't know what to say.
Yes, well, I always know what to say.
- Yes, hurry along, please.
- Yes, Father.
Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious
Winifred, will you explain
this unseemly hullabaloo?
I don't think there's anything to explain.
The children just came in
to make you feel better.
I should like to be quite clear.
I am not out of sorts.
I'm in a perfectly equable mood.
I do not require
being made to feel better!
You're always saying you want
a cheerful and pleasant household.
I should like to make a differentiation
between cheerful and...
Excuse me, dear.
Posts, everyone, please!
I have no objection to cheerfulness.
I expect certain decorum.
I don't propose standing idly by
and letting Poppins
undermine the discipline...
(CANNON FIRES)
There's something extremely odd
about this household
since that woman arrived,
and I've noticed it.
Yes, dear.
One thing more.
Yes, dear?
Have this piano repaired.
I like to have it in tune.
But, George, you don't play.
That is entirely beside the point!
Now, let me see.
We must go to the piano tuners,
then to Mrs Cory's shop
for some gingerbread,
then to the fishmonger's
for dover sole and prawns.
Michael, stop stravaging along behind.
Ahoy, there!
Ahoy!
- Good day to you.
- Good morning, Admiral.
What fine adventure
are we off upon today?
Going to fight the Hottentots?
Dig for buried treasure?
We're going to buy fish.
Very good. Proceed at flank speed.
Aye, aye, sir.
Let's put our backs into it.
More spit and polish.
That's what's wanted.
(DOG BARKS)
Andrew.
Woof! Woof! Woof!
Slow down. I can't understand a word.
Again?
The poor man.
Woof! Woof! Woof!
Woof! Ah-choo!
Bless you.
Woof! Woof! Woof!
Why, yes, certainly.
I'll go straight-away.
- Thank you very much.
- Woof!
- What did he say?
- "You're welcome."
- And?
- He didn't say anything.
You know best.
I thought we were buying fish.
There's been a change of plans.
Come along, please. Don't straggle.
(WHIMPERING)
Andrew, worrying won't help anyone.
You should go home and rest.
Woof!
- Bert, I'm glad you're here.
- I came right away.
How is he?
He's never been worse.
How about them?
It's contagious, you know.
- We'll get spots?
- Unlikely.
Ohh! Hoo hoo hoo!
Oh, Uncle Albert.
Bless my soul.
It's Mary Poppins. I'm delight... Ha-ha!
I'm delighted to see you.
Uncle Albert, you promised.
Ha-ha! I know.
I tried, really, I did. I... Ho ho!
But I so enjoy laughing. Ah ha ha!
When I start, it's up with... Ha ha ha!
That's what happens.
I love to laugh! Ah ho ho!
Oh, my! I can't help it.
Ha ha ha!
I just like laughing.
Ha ha! Ha ha!
Don't you dare.
You'll only make him worse.
- It's quite serious.
- Keep a straight face.
Last time,
we took three days to get him down.
(SINGING) I love to laugh
Hoo hoo hoo hoo!
Loud and long and clear
Ha!
I love to laugh
Ha ha ha ha!
It's getting worse every year
Ha ha ha!
The more I laugh
Ho ho ho!
The more I fill with glee
You're no help!
The more the glee
Ha ha ha ha!
The more I'm a merrier me
Hoo hoo hoo!
It's embarrassing.
The more I'm a merrier me
Ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha ha!
Some people
laugh through their noses
Sounding something like this
Mmm-hmm hmm hmm!
Dreadful.
Sss-sss-sss!
Some people laugh through their teeth
Goodness sakes
Hissing and fizzing like snakes
Sss sss sss!
Not at all attractive.
Some laugh too fast
Hee hee hee hee!
Some only blast
Ha!
Others they twitter like birds
Hee hee hee hoo!
You're as bad as he is.
Then there's that kind
what can't make up their mind
Hmm hmm hmm, ha ha ha!
Hee hee hee, ho ho ho!
Hee ha ho huh?
When things strike me as funny
I can't hide it inside
And squeak, hee,
as the squeakelers do
Ha ha ha!
I've got to let go
With a ho ho ho ho
Ha ha ha ha!
And a ho ho ho, hoo!
How nice!
I was hoping you'd turn up.
We always have a jolly time.
We love to laugh
Ha ha ha ha!
Loud and long and clear
Hoo hoo hoo!
We love to laugh
Ha ha ha ha!
So everybody can hear
Ha ha ha!
The more you laugh
Don't you start. Come back here.
We fill with glee
Hee hee hee!
And the more the glee
Ha ha ha ha!
The more we're a merrier we
Welcome, children. Welcome.
Make yourselves comfortable.
Pull up a chair.
I say, you're a sight.
Speaking of sight,
it reminds me of me brother.
He works in a watch factory.
What's he do?
He stands about all day
and makes faces.
Makes faces in a watch factory!
You made that up.
That's good.
Such behaviour.
It's disgraceful
or my name isn't Mary Poppins.
I know a man
with a wooden leg named Smith.
What's the name of his other leg?
Wasn't that funny?
What's the name of...
Children, it's tea time.
I won't have schedule interruptions.
Please stay.
Look, I have tea ready for you.
And it's getting cold.
I had hoped that maybe you would...
Splendid! Thank you very much.
Mind the bread and butter.
Now watch, children.
I knew she'd do it... A proper tea.
I suppose you'll want me to pour.
If I must, I must.
But stop behaving
like laughing hyenas.
- Two lumps, Uncle Albert?
- Yes, please.
- Bert?
- None for me.
I'm glad you came.
It wouldn't be fun otherwise.
Pour some milk
for Michael and yourself.
- Nice weather we're having.
- Yes.
The other day when it was cold,
a friend bought long underwear.
The shopkeeper said,
"How long do you want it?"
My friend said,
"From September to March."
Jane! Control yourself!
Children, please sit up properly.
- Your tea, Uncle Albert.
- Thank you, dear.
I'm having fun.
I wish you could always stay here.
We'll have to. There's no way down.
Oh, there is a way.
I hate mentioning it because
you must think of something sad.
Do it, please.
Let me see.
I've got the very thing.
Yesterday, when my neighbour
answered the bell, a man was there.
The man said, "I'm terribly sorry.
I just ran over your cat."
- Oh, that's sad.
- The poor cat.
Then he said, "I'll replace your cat."
She said,
"Okay, but can you catch mice?"
I started out saying...
I try. Really, I do.
But everything ends up so hilarious.
I can't...
I can't help...
That will be enough of that.
It's time to go home.
Oh, that is sad. Oh, no.
That's the saddest thing I ever heard.
Come along, children.
Must you really go?
People come to see me all the time,
and we have such a lovely time.
Then they go home,
and I'm very, very sad about it.
Don't worry. We'll return soon.
It was lovely.
- Keep an eye on him, Bert.
- I'll stay a while.
Thank you.
Uncle Albert,
I got a jolly joke
I saved for just such an occasion.
- Want to hear it?
- I'd be so grateful.
Righto. It's about me granddad.
One night, he had a nightmare.
So scared he chewed his pillow to bits.
Next morning, I says,
"How do you feel?"
He says, "A little down in the mouth."
There's nothing like a good joke.
No, and that's nothing like a good joke.
Bit late tonight, aren't you?
I say, Banks!
Is anything the matter, Banks?
Banks!
We're so glad you're home!
We had the most wonderful afternoon.
I know a man
with a wooden leg named Smith.
We don't know anyone called Smith.
The second chap says,
"What's his other leg's name?"
And a party on the ceiling.
Children, be quiet.
Mary Poppins says we'll go again.
Oh?
Oh, Mary Poppins said that?
Please return to your room.
Mary Poppins, will you come with me?
As you wish.
Mary Poppins, I regret what I must say.
Good evening, George.
Is anything the matter?
I'm afraid so.
I have to dress for my rally.
- I'd rather you be present.
- Of course, George.
Mary Poppins,
I confess I'm disappointed in you.
She's for it. I've heard this before.
I don't deny I'm partially responsible
for allowing
the children's worthless frivolity.
But they must learn
the seriousness of life.
But they're only children.
In light of what's happened...
George, are you certain?
I believe I am.
(SINGING)
A British bank is run with precision
A British home requires nothing less
Tradition, discipline, and rules
must be the tools
Without them
disorder, chaos, moral disintegration
In short, you have a ghastly mess
I quite agree.
The children must be
moulded, shaped and taught
That life's a looming battle
to be faced and fought
I'm disturbed to hear my children
talking about popping into pictures,
consorting with racehorse persons,
fox hunting...
I don't mind that. It's tradition.
But parties on the ceiling?
Having tea parties on the ceiling?
And other highly questionable outings...
If they must go on outings
These outings ought to be fraught
with purpose, yes, and practicality
These silly words like
Superca...
Super...
Supercal...
Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious.
Yes, well done.
And popping through pictures
have little use, fulfil no basic need
They've got to learn the honest truth
Despite their youth
They must learn
About the life you lead
Exactly.
They must feel the thrill
of totting up a balanced book
A thousand ciphers neatly in a row
Quite right.
When gazing at a graph
that shows the profits up
Their little cup of joy should overflow
Precisely.
It's time they learnt
to walk in your footsteps
My footsteps.
To tread your straight
and narrow path with pride
With pride.
Tomorrow, just as you suggest
Pressed and dressed
Jane and Michael will be at your side
Splendid! You've hit the nail...
At my side? Where are we going?
To the bank.
- The bank?
- Yes.
Tomorrow's an important day.
I'll see they
have a proper night's sleep.
Did I say
I'd take the children to the bank?
It sounded that way.
And why not?
Capital idea.
Just the medicine they need for all this
sugary female thinking they get here.
Quite right. Good idea.
Quite right.
Mary Poppins, we won't let you go.
What do you mean?
Weren't you sacked?
Sacked? I am never sacked.
- Oh, Mary Poppins!
- Hooray!
Neither am I a maypole.
- But...
- Goats butt.
Birds fly.
Children going out with their father
get some sleep.
An outing with Father?
He's never taken us on an outing.
He's never taken us anywhere.
How did you manage it?
You gave him the idea.
How impertinent!
Me giving ideas to people? Really.
- Where's he taking us?
- The bank.
Michael, the city!
Father can point out the sights.
Most things he can.
Sometimes people, through no fault
of their own, can't see past their nose.
Past their nose?
Yes. Sometimes
a little thing is quite important.
Oh, look. The cathedral.
Father passes that every day.
(SINGING) Early each day
to the steps of St. Paul's
The little old bird woman comes
In her own special way
to the people she calls
Come buy my bags full of crumbs
Come feed the little birds
Show them you care
And you'll be glad if you do
Their young ones are hungry
Their nests are so bare
All it takes is tuppence
From you
Feed the birds
Tuppence a bag
Tuppence, tuppence
Feed the birds
That's what she cries
While overhead, her birds fill the skies
All around the cathedral
The saints and apostles
Look down as she sells her wares
Although you can't see it
You know they are smiling
Each time someone shows
That he cares
Though her words are simple and few
Listen, listen
She's calling to you
Feed the birds
Tuppence a bag
Tuppence, tuppence
Though her words are simple and few
Listen, listen
She's calling to you
Feed the birds
Tuppence a bag
Tuppence
Now, remember.
Be on your best behaviour.
Isn't it your bank?
As a younger officer, it is, sort of.
Michael, look.
It's her!
- Who? It's who?
- The bird woman.
Just like Mary Poppins said.
You see her?
Of course I can. Do you think
I can't see past the end of my nose?
Listen, she's saying it.
Feed the birds.
Tuppence a bag.
Of course she's saying it.
- May we feed the birds?
- Whatever for?
- I have tuppence.
- Just this once.
Waste your money on birds?
Certainly not.
But Mary Poppins...
I'm not interested in Mary Poppins
nor in hearing her name.
But it's my tuppence.
Michael, don't throw your money away!
At the bank, I'll show you what to do.
It's extremely interesting.
Hello, Banks. What's all this about?
My children.
Why are they here?
They're opening an account, sir.
How much money do you have?
Tuppence. I want it to feed the birds.
Tuppence!
Tuppence...
Precisely how I started.
That's the elder Mr Dawes,
a giant in the finance world.
A giant?
Father, these are Banks' children!
They want to open an account!
Do they, boy? Excellent. Excellent.
We can use more money
to put to work for the bank.
You have tuppence?
May I be permitted to see it?
It's for feeding the birds.
Feed the birds and what have you got?
Fat birds!
But...
(SINGING) If you invest your tuppence
wisely in the bank
Safe and sound
Soon that tuppence
Safely invested in the bank
Will compound
And you'll achieve
that sense of conquest
As your affluence expands
In the hands of the directors
Who invest
As propriety demands
- May I, sir?
- Carry on, Banks.
You see, Michael, you'll be part of
railways through Africa!
Exactly.
Dams across the Nile.
- Talk about the ships.
- Fleets of ocean greyhounds.
Tell them more.
Majestic self-amortizing canals.
It fires the imagination!
(SINGING) Plantations of ripening tea
All from
Tuppence
Prudently, thriftily, frugally
invested in the...
To be specific
In the Dawes, Tomes, Mousley, Grubbs
Fidelity Fiduciary bank
Give me the money, boy.
I want to feed the birds.
Banks!
Yes, sir. Now, Michael...
When you deposit
tuppence in a bank account
Go on!
Soon you'll see
Tell him more!
That it blooms
into credit of a generous amount
Semi-annually
And you'll achieve that sense of stature
As your influence expands
To the high financial strata
That established credit now commands
You can purchase
first and second trust deeds.
Imagine the foreclosures,
bonds, chattels, dividends, shares.
Bankruptcies.
Debtor sales.
Opportunities.
Private enterprise.
Shipyards.
- The mercantile.
- Collieries.
Tanneries.
Corporations, amalgamations.
Banks!
While stand the Banks of England,
England stands.
When fall the Banks of England,
England falls!
You see, Michael?
All for the lack of...
Tuppence
Patiently
Cautiously
Trustingly invested in the...
To be specific
In the Dawes, Tomes, Mousley, Grubbs
Fidelity Fiduciary Bank
Welcome to our joyful
family of investors.
Give it back!
Michael, behave...
Give it to him.
Give me back my money!
The bank won't
give someone their money.
I'm getting mine.
Come along, every penny!
And give me mine, too.
Stop all payments.
Give me my money!
Children, come back!
- Stop those children!
- Jane! Michael!
Come on!
Stop those children!
Aah!
Come with me.
Granny will hide you!
Aah!
Here, half a mo.
Leave my sister alone.
Your friend won't hurt you.
Bert, it's you.
In the flesh and at your service.
You're filthy.
Perhaps a smudge.
It so happens
today I'm a chimney sweep.
Oh, Bert, we're so frightened.
Don't take on so.
Bert will take care of you.
Like I was your own father.
Who's after you?
Father.
What?
We went to his bank.
We must have done
something dreadful.
The police and army were after us.
Michael, don't exaggerate.
There must be some mistake.
Your dad loves you.
No, not with the look he had on his face.
He doesn't like us.
That don't seem likely, does it?
It's true.
Let's sit down.
Begging your pardon,
but my heart goes out to your father.
There he is in that cold, heartless bank,
hemmed in by mounds
of cold, heartless money.
I don't like seeing
living things caged up.
Father in a cage?
Cages come in all sizes and shapes,
even bank-shaped.
Father's not in trouble, we are.
Sure about that, are you?
You've got your mother
to look after you,
and Mary Poppins
and Constable Jones and me.
Who looks after your father?
When something happens,
what does he do?
Fends for himself, he does.
Who does he tell?
No one.
Don't blab his troubles.
He pushes on at his job,
uncomplaining, alone, and silent.
He's not very silent.
Michael, be quiet.
Bert, does Father really need our help?
It's not my place to say.
But fathers can always do
with a bit of help.
I'll take you home.
(SINGING) Chim chiminy chim chiminy
Chim chim cheree
A sweep is as lucky as lucky can be
Chim chiminy chim chiminy
Chim chim cheroo
Good luck will rub off
when I shakes hands with you
Or blow me a kiss
And that's lucky, too
Now as the ladder of life
has been strung
You might think a sweep's
on the bottommost rung
Though I spends me time
in the ashes and smoke
In this whole wide world
there's no happier bloke
Chim chiminy chim chiminy
Chim chim cheree
A sweep is as lucky as lucky can be
Chim chiminy chim chiminy
Chim chim cheroo
Good luck will rub off
when I shakes hands with you
Chim chiminy chim chiminy
Chim chim cheree
A sweep is as lucky as lucky can be
Chim chiminy chim chiminy
Chim chim cheroo
Good luck will rub off
when I shakes hands with you
Ellen, whoever that is, send them away.
I'm dreadfully late.
Yes, mum.
I'll be leaving.
Please stay till Father comes home!
Father will feel better
if you shake hands with him.
It's the children, mum.
I thought they were with their father.
You haven't been running off,
have you?
They haven't exactly been
running away, mum.
They've been frightened
and should be looked after.
Oh, of course, Mary Poppins will...
Oh, no, it's her day off.
Ellen, would you...
No, mum. I haven't done me brasses.
Ask Mrs Brill...
Not for 100 quid.
It's baking day,
and you know how cook is.
What about you, sir?
You've been so kind.
Me, mum?
Lord mayor's got
a stopped-up chimney.
How clever of you to know.
Our drawing room chimney
is in the most ghastly condition.
Thank you so much.
Besides, it will amuse the children.
The lord mayor's going
to be terrible put out.
Thank you so much.
I do appreciate it.
I must hurry.
Our gallant ladies in prison
are waiting for me to lead them in song.
Good-bye, my darlings.
(SINGING)
I choose me bristles with pride, yes, I do
A broom for the shaft
And a brush for the flue
It's awfully dark and gloomy up there.
You see how wrong people can be?
That's a doorway
to a place of enchantment.
Up where the smoke
is all billowed and curled
'Tween pavement and stars
Is the chimney sweep world
When there's hardly no day
Nor hardly no night
There's things half in shadow
And halfway in light
On the rooftops of London
Coo, what a sight
I wish we could go up there.
I like chimneys.
Rightly so.
A chimney is a wondrous thing.
It's built tall up there on the roof.
The wind blows across her top
and draws the smoke right up the flue.
Feel the pull on the end of that brush.
It's like you've got a whale
at the end of the line, isn't it?
Michael, be careful.
Things happen around fireplaces.
Oh, bother.
JANE: Michael!
Michael, come back down here!
Michael, Michael, where are you?
That's a bit awkward.
Stop putting ideas in their heads.
There goes another one.
Shall I go after them?
They can't
gallivant up there like kangaroos.
Michael, everything's going to be...
Will you put your things on?
Hurry up. Spit spot.
Thought you'd left.
We didn't mean to.
No harm done.
Truth is, this is
a fortuitous circumstance.
Look there.
A trackless jungle
just waiting to be explored.
Why not, Mary Poppins?
Oh, please, Mary Poppins.
Oh, well... If we must, we must.
Fall in.
Look lively. Look lively.
Jump to it. Get in line.
Attention!
Slope arms!
Right turn!
Quick march!
Hello there!
It's just good clean soot, Michael.
Far as we go, right?
Not at all.
What did I tell you?
The world's at your feet,
and who sees it but the birds,
the stars, and the chimney sweeps?
Quite nice,
but we've had enough night air.
Follow me, please.
(SINGING) Chim chiminy chim chiminy
Chim chim cheree
When you're with a sweep
You're in glad company
Nowhere is there a more happier crew
Than them what sings
Chim chim cheree, chim cheroo
Chim chiminy chim chim
Cheree chim cheroo
Cheroo!
Cheroo! Cheroo!
It's all me pals!
Step in time!
Step in time! Step in time!
Come on, mateys, step in time!
Step in time!
(SINGING) Step in time, step in time
Step in time, step in time
Never need a reason
Never need a rhyme
Step in time, we step in time
Kick your knees up!
Kick your knees up, step in time
Never need a reason
Never need a rhyme
Kick your knees up, step in time
Round the chimney!
Round the chimney, step in time
Never need a reason
Never need a rhyme
Round the chimney, step in time
Flap like a birdie!
Flap like a birdie, step in time
Never need a reason
Never need a rhyme
Flap like a birdie, in time
Up on the railing!
Up on the railing, step in time
Never need a reason
Never need a rhyme
Up on the railing, step in time
Over the rooftops!
Over the rooftops, step in time
Never need a reason
Never need a rhyme
Step in time
Over the rooftops, over the rooftops
Link your elbows!
Link your elbows, step in time
Link your elbows, link your elbows
Link your elbows
Step in time, step in time
Never need a reason
Never need a rhyme
When you step in time
You step in time
Mary Poppins, step in time!
There you go, Mary Poppins!
Lucky old Bert!
Come on, Mary Poppins!
Here we go!
Ain't she marvellous?
Ain't she beautiful?
Lovely. Tell your mum.
Hello, hello, hello!
- More! More!
- Mary, do it again!
Here we go.
We're being attacked by Hottentots!
Aye, aye, sir.
Cheeky devils! Give them what for!
Empty the shot lockers!
Aye, aye, sir!
Move along, Mr Binnacle.
Teach the beggars a lesson!
Gun ready, sir.
Stand by.
Fire!
Well hit, sir!
Very well hit!
Aah! They're at it again!
They're at it again, step in time
At it again, step in time
Ow!
Ow! Step in time
Never need a reason
Never need a rhyme
Whoa!
Step in time
Oh, Ellen, when you're free...
Votes for women, step in time
Not at the moment.
Votes for women
Votes for women!
It's the master!
It's the master, step in time
It's the master
What's all this?
What's all this, what's all this
What's all this
Link your elbows, step in time
What's all this? What's all this?
Kick your knees up
Kick your knees up...
Bert.
(WHISTLES)
Good luck, guv'nor.
Lovely time.
Had an elegant time, guv'nor.
Good luck, guv'nor.
Father, every sweep shook your hand.
You'll be so lucky!
Come along, children. Spit spot.
One moment, Mary Poppins.
What's the meaning of this?
I beg your pardon?
Will you explain all this?
I'd like to make one thing clear.
Yes.
I never explain anything.
(TELEPHONE RINGS)
(RING)
Yes? Banks here.
Mr Dawes...
I'm dreadfully sorry
about what happened today.
I can assure you that...
Tonight, sir?
Yes. We'll expect you at 9:00 precisely.
Without fail.
Why, yes, Banks.
It's extremely serious.
We regret this action.
You've been with us many years...
As was your father.
Yes, Mr Dawes.
I shall be there at 9:00.
A man has dreams
of walking with giants.
To carve his niche in the edifice of time.
(SINGING) Before the mortar of his zeal
Has a chance to congeal
The cup's dashed from his lips.
The flame's snuffed aborning.
He's brought to wrack
and ruin in his prime.
Life's a rum go, guv'nor.
That's the truth.
I think it's Mary Poppins.
Since she's come,
things have happened to me.
Mary Poppins?
Yes, of course!
My world was calm
Well ordered...
Exemplary.
Then came this person
With chaos in her wake
And now my life's ambitions go
With one fell blow
It's quite a bitter pill
To take
That Poppins woman did it!
I know the person... Mary Poppins.
She's the one what sings...
A spoonful of sugar
That is all it takes
It changes bread and water into
Tea and cakes
That's it exactly!
Changing bread into cakes, indeed.
No wonder
everything's higgledy-piggledy.
A spoonful of sugar
Goes a long, long way
Have yourself a healthy helpin'
Every day
A healthy helpin' of trouble.
You know what she did? I realise it now.
She tricked me
into taking
Jane and Michael to the bank.
That's how the trouble started.
Tricked you into that?
Outrageous!
A man as important as you?
Shameful!
You're a man of high position,
esteemed by your peers.
And when your little tykes are cryin'
You haven't time to dry their tears
And see them grateful little faces
Smilin' up at you
Because their dad
He always knows just what to do
I mean, look...
Like you say, guv'nor...
You've got to grind, grind, grind
At that grindstone
Though childhood slips
Like sand
Through a sieve
And all too soon
They've up and grown
And then they've flown
And it's too late for you to give
Just that spoonful of sugar
To help the medicine
Go down
The medicine go down
Medicine go down
Well, goodbye, guv'nor.
Sorry to have troubled you.
(WHISTLING)
Father.
We're sorry about the tuppence.
We didn't know it would
cause you so much trouble.
Here, Father.
You can have the tuppence.
Will that make everything all right?
Thank you.
(DOORBELL CHIMES)
Come in!
Take your hat off, Banks.
Good evening, gentlemen.
Get on with it. Go on.
Yes, Father.
In 1773, an official of this bank
unwisely loaned a large sum of money
to finance a shipment of tea
to the American colonies.
Do you know what happened?
I do. As the ship lay in Boston Harbour,
colonists dressed as Red Indians
boarded, behaved rudely,
and threw the tea overboard.
This made the tea
unsuitable for drinking,
even for Americans.
Precisely.
The loan was defaulted.
Panic ensued within these walls.
There was a run on the bank.
From that time to this,
there has not been a run on this bank.
Until today!
A run, sir, caused by
the disgraceful conduct
of your son.
Do you deny it?
No, sir.
I shall gladly assume
responsibility for my son.
Why are you waiting?
Get on with it.
Yes, Father.
No, not that!
Steady on.
Do you have anything to say?
Sir, they do say
that when there's nothing to say,
all you can say...
Confound it, Banks!
Do you have anything to say?
Just one word, sir.
Yes?
Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious.
What?
Mary Poppins was right.
It does make you feel better.
There's no such word.
It is a perfectly good word.
Do you know
what there's no such thing as?
With due respect,
there's no such thing as you!
Impertinence, sir!
Would you
like to hear a marvellous joke?
A real snapper.
Joke? Snapper?
Jane and Michael
meet one day on the street.
Jane says, "I know a man
with a wooden leg named Smith."
Michael says,
"What's the name of his other leg?"
The man's gone mad. Call the guard!
Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious.
I'm feeling better!
Don't strike my father!
There's the tuppence,
the wonderful, fateful,
supercalifragilisticexpialidocious
tuppence.
Guard it well. Good-bye!
Where are you going?
I might pop through
a chalk pavement picture
or seize a horse off a merry-go-round
or fly a kite.
Only Poppins knows.
- Poppins?
- My nanny.
She sings that ridiculous song.
(SINGING) A spoonful of sugar
Makes the medicine go down
The medicine go down
The medicine...
Mad as a March hare.
A wooden leg named Smith.
A wooden le...
Father.
Father!
Father, come down!
Daddy!
Daddy, come back!
Wind's come around,
blowing dead on from the west.
She doesn't care what happens to us.
She only promised to stay
till the wind changed, right?
Bring my hat stand, please.
Mary Poppins, don't you love us?
What would happen to me
if I loved all the children
I said goodbye to?
That's right. George W. Banks,
17 Cherry Tree Lane.
About 6'1 ", I'd say.
Yes, we rang up his bank first thing.
We discovered he'd
been discharged last night.
No telling what he'll do
in a fit of despondency.
Wouldn't hurt to drag the river.
There's a spot popular with jumpers.
Really, Ellen!
He seemed to have been
a fine, stable gentleman.
No hanky-panky.
Regular habits, as far as anyone knows.
(SINGING) The medicine go down
Just a spoonful...
It's him!
Or something similar.
A little less noise on the premises.
I can't understand the inspector.
Just a spoonful of sugar
Makes the medicine go down
You didn't jump in the river.
How sensible of you.
It's all right, sir.
He's been found.
No, alive,
or so I presume.
He's kissing Mrs Banks.
What happened at the bank?
I've been sacked, flung into the street.
A spoonful of sugar
Makes the medicine go down
Gone off his crumpet,
that's what he's done.
Dotty as you please.
What were you doing in the cellar?
First, where are the children?
Jane! Michael!
Your father's calling.
It doesn't sound like Father.
Jane! Michael!
Run along. Spit spot.
You won't go, Mary Poppins, will you?
Spit spot.
He mended it!
It's wonderful!
However did you manage it?
(SINGING)
With tuppence for paper and strings
You can have your own set of wings
With your feet on the ground
You're a bird in flight
With your fist holding tight
To the string of your kite
Oh, oh, oh
Let's go fly a kite
Up to the highest height
And send it soaring
Up through the atmosphere
Up where the air is clear
Oh, let's go fly a kite
A proper kite needs a proper tail.
That's what I said.
Go fly a kite.
No, sir. I don't mean you personally.
Let's go fly a kite
Up to the highest height
And send it soaring
Up through the atmosphere
Up where the air is clear
Oh, let's go fly a kite
When you send it flying up there
All at once you're lighter than air
You can dance on the breeze
Over houses and trees
With your fist holding tight
To the string of your kite
Oh, oh, oh
Let's go fly a kite
Up to the highest height
And send it soaring
There you are, Banks.
Congratulations.
Capital bit of humour.
"Wooden leg named Smith,"
or Jones, whatever it was.
Father died laughing.
Oh, I'm so sorry, sir.
Nonsense. Nothing to be sorry about.
Never seen him happier.
He left an opening for a new partner.
Congratulations.
Thank you very much indeed, sir.
Up through the atmosphere
Up where the air is clear
Oh, let's go
Fly a kite
Awk! That's gratitude for you.
Didn't even say goodbye.
No, they didn't.
Look at them.
They think more
of their father than of you.
That's as it should be.
Don't you care?
Practically perfect people
never permit sentiment
to muddle their thinking.
Is that so?
Mary Poppins, you don't fool me.
Really?
Really. I know how you feel.
If you think
I'm keeping my mouth shut...
That will be quite enough, thank you.
Goodbye, Mary Poppins.
Don't stay away too long.
Oh, oh, oh
Let's go fly a kite
Up to the highest height
And send it soaring
Up through the atmosphere
Up where the air is clear
Oh, let's go
Fly a kite