[Barking]
[Clock Chiming]
My story begins
in London...
not so very long ago.
Yet so much has happened since then,
that it seems like an eternity.
At that time,
I lived with my pet...
- in a bachelor flat
just off Regents Park.
- [Piano]
It was a
beautiful spring day,
a tedious time of the year
for bachelors.
Oh... that's my pet,
Roger Radcliff,
a musician of sorts.
I'm the one
with the spots.
My name's Pongo.
As far as I could see,
the old notion that
a bachelor's life was so...
glamorous and carefree
was all nonsense.
It was downright dull.
[Sigh]
It was plain to see that
my old pet needed someone.
But if it were left up to Roger,
we'd be bachelors forever.
He was married to his work,
writing songs.
Songs about romance...
of all things,
something he knew
absolutely nothing about.
Oh, he's intelligent enough,
as humans go.
And I think you could say, Roger is
a rather handsome animal in his way.
I could see no reason
why my pet...
didn't deserve
an attractive mate.
At least I was determined
to do my best.
Of course, dogs are a pretty
poor judge of human beauty.
But I had
a rough idea...
of what
to look for.
Hmm!
Unusual breed.
[Chuckle]
Very unusual.
Hmm!
Oh, surely not.
Well now,
what have we here?
Hmm.
Well, a little...
too short coupled.
Nope!
I say!
Well, I do say!
Now there's
a fancy breed.
Hmm.
Perhaps a little too fancy.
Yes, much too fancy.
Too old.
Too young.
It was a problem,
a real problem.
Well, now that's
a bit more like it!
The most beautiful creature
on four legs!
Now if only the girl...
Well!
She's very lovely too.
It was almost too good
to be true.
I'd never find another pair
like that,
not if I looked
for 100 years.
Ah, they're heading
for the park.
A perfect meeting place...
if I can only arrange it.
Uh-oh... but Roger never
stopped work 'til after 5:00.
That would be
too late.
[Barking]
After 5:00 already.
- Fancy that.
- [Barking]
All right, Pongo.
All right, boy.
[Barking]
[Yipping]
Pongo, boy,
take it easy!
What's all
the hurry?
[Barking]
Pongo, boy,
slow down.
I was afraid we'd missed them.
Perhaps they passed on by the park.
Then suddenly...
I spotted them.
It was a perfect situation
if I planned it right.
I couldn't depend on Roger.
I knew what he'd do.
He'd settle on the grass, puff
his pipe and that would be it.
No, it was all
up to me.
Well.
At first I had
no particular plan,
just anything
to attract attention.
You know,
stir things up a bit.
Pongo,
you silly old thing!
C'mon!
C'mon, let's have it, boy.
- Pongo!
- [Yipping]
Pongo!
[Barking]
[Pongo] For awhile,
it seemed to work.
At least they
had seen one another.
Things were going along
first-rate.
But for some strange reason
they left!
C'mon, you old renegade.
We're going home.
[Pongo]
But I wasn't giving up.
I was determined that somehow
they just had to meet.
- Oh!
- Ohhh!
I beg your pardon.
Please excuse me.
I must say,
what on earth!
- Oh, really. Good heavens.
- Oh, dear.
- Ohh!
- Ahh, ahh!
Oh, oh.
[Gasping]
Oh, my new spring suit
and my new hat!
[Roger] Ah, ah...
I'm terribly sorry.
Please let me
help you.
I'm so sorry.
I don't know
what's come over him.
I'm so sorry. He's never
acted this way before.
Please, just go away.
You've done enough.
Please?
Oh.
Oh, I say.
Here, take mine.
Oh.
[Laughing]
Wilt thou love her,
comfort her,
honor and keep her
in sickness and in health;
and forsaking
all others,
keep thee only unto her
so long as ye both shall live?
[Roger]
I will.
[Pongo] For the first
six months or so...
we lived in a small house
near the park,
a modest little place...
but just right for two couples
who were just starting out.
[Piano]
Perdita, darling,
are you all right?
[Chuckle]
Oh, of course, dear.
After all, dogs were having
puppies long before our time.
[Chuckle]
[Pongo] Oh, that's Nanny,
a wonderful cook and housekeeper.
She's such a kind,
understanding soul.
You know,
at times she seems
almost canine.
Roger, dear,
tea time.
Tea time!
[Roger]
Be down in a minute
Ta tum ti ta tum
Do you like my new song
Such clever lyrics.
[Chuckle]
Melody first, my dear.
And then the lyrics,
hmm?
[Car Horn]
Oh, Pongo... it's her.
It's that devil woman.
[Car Horn]
[Roger] Oh, must be Cruella, your
dearly devoted old schoolmate.
Cruella de Vil.
That's it!
Cruella de Vil
If she doesn't scare you
no evil thing will
- Oh, Roger.
- To see her is to take
a sudden chill
Ohh!
Cruella... Cruella
She's like a spider
waiting for the... kill
Roger,
she'll hear you.
Look out for
Cruella de Vil
Let her in, Nanny.
- Anita, darling!
- How are you?
Miserable as usual.
Perfectly wretched!
Where are they?
For heaven sakes,
where are they?
- Who, Cruella?
- The puppies! The puppies.
No time for games.
Where are the little brutes?
[Trumpet]
Lt'll be at least three weeks.
No rushing these things.
[Chuckle]
Anita, you're such a wit.
Here, dog, here.
- Here, dog.
- [Growling]
Cruella, isn't that
a new fur coat?
My only true love,
darling.
I live for furs.
I worship furs!
Is there a woman in this
wretched world who doesn't?
Oh, I'd like a nice fur,
but there are many other thing...
Sweet, simple Anita.
[Chuckle]
I know, I know!
This horrid little house
is your dream castle.
And poor Roger is your
bold and fearless Sir Galahad!
Oh, Cruella.
Then of course you have
your little spotted friends.
Oh yes,
I must say... such perfectly
beautiful coats.
- Won't you have some tea?
- I've got to run.
Let me know when
the puppies arrive.
- You will, won't you, dear?
- Yes, Cruella.
Don't forget, it's a promise.
See you in three weeks.
Cheerio, darling.
Ohh!
At first you think
Cruella is a devil
But after time
has worn away the shock
You come
to realize
You've seen
her kind of eyes
Watching you from
underneath a rock
- You're no help.
- This vampire bat
This inhuman beast
She ought to be locked up
and never released
The world was such
a wholesome place until
Cruella
Cruella de Vil
Roger,
you are an idiot!
[Laughter]
- Perdy?
- That witch. That devil woman.
She wants our puppies.
That's all she's after.
Don't worry, Perdy.
They're on to her.
- Nothing's going to happen
to our puppies.
- What does she want with them?
She can't possibly
love them.
Oh, Pongo.
I was so happy at first,
but now l...
[Crying]
Oh, l...
I wish we weren't
having any.
[Thunder]
[Pongo] Poor Perdita.
Of course, she had no choice.
The puppies arrived
right on schedule...
one wild and stormy night
in October.
[Footsteps]
Ohh!
Steady, boy.
[Nanny]
The puppies are here!
Oh... the puppies
are here!
H-H-How many?
- Eight.
- Eight?
[Barking]
By George, Pongo!
Eight puppies.
Ten.
- [Anita] Eleven.
- Eleven.
Eleven?
Eleven puppies, Pongo.
Wait a minute now,
wait a minute... thirteen!
No, no, no.
Fourteen.
- Ohh... fifteen!
- Fifteen?
And the mother's
doing fine, love.
You ducky thing, you.
Fifteen puppies?
Why, Pongo,
that's marvelous!
It's fabulous!
Why, you old rascal!
Fourteen.
Just fourteen.
We lost one.
Poor little thing.
Oh, Pongo, boy.
It's just one
of those things.
And yet?
And yet I wonder.
[Thunder]
Look, Pongo.
Anita!
Nanny.
Fifteen!
We still have
fifteen!
Oh, Roger, he's all right!
Thank heaven.
See? He's just
as good as new.
Can you imagine, Roger,
fifteen puppies!
Fifteen.
Fifteen puppies!
How marvelous.
How marvelous,
how perfectly... ugh!
The devil take it.
They're mongrels... no spots!
No spots at all.
What a horrid little white rat.
They're not mongrels!
They'll get their spots.
Just wait and see.
That's right. They'll have
their spots in a few weeks.
Oh, well, in that case I'll
take them all. The whole litter.
Just name your price, dear.
I'm afraid
we can't give them up.
- Poor Perdita, she'd be heartbroken.
- Anita, don't be ridiculous.
You can't afford to keep them.
You can scarcely feed yourselves.
I'm sure
we'll get along.
[Chuckle]
Yes, I know. I know!
Roger's...
Roger's songs!
[Laughing]
Enough of this nonsense. I'll pay you
twice what they're worth.
I'm being
more than generous.
Blast this pen.
Blast this wretched,
wretched pen!
When can the puppies
leave their mother?
Two weeks?
Three weeks?
[Roger] Never.
- What?
- We're n-n-not selling the puppies.
Not a single one.
Do you understand?
Anita, is he serious?
I really
don't know Roger.
- Cruella, he...
- Surely he must be joking!
No, no, no.
I-I-I mean it.
You're not getting one.
N-N-Not one.
And that's... final.
Why, you horrid man!
You... you...
All right, keep the little
beasts for all I care.
Do as you like with them.
Drown them!
But I warn you, Anita,
I'm through with all of you!
I'll get even.
Just wait.
You'll be sorry,
you fools!
You... you idiots!
[Door Slams]
[Barking]
Oh, Roger!
You were magnificent, darling.
He was a bloomin' hero,
ma'am!
Indeed he was.
A bloomin' hero!
Perdy?
Perdy, darling?
We're keeping the puppies,
every single one of them.
My ol' pet Roger, he told
that devil woman off.
He told her off, Perdy.
She's gone.
- Darling, she's gone for good.
- Oh, Pongo.
- C'mon, Thunderbolt.
Go get him, Thunder.
After him, boy.
He'll get that
dirty ol' horse thief.
Old Thunderbolt's the greatest
dog in the whole world.
He's even better
than Dad.
No dog's better
What's he going to do,
Dad?
Shh, shh.
Let's just wait and see.
[Puppy] Look at him run,
the old coward.
That old dirty Dawson!
The yellow-livered
old skunk!
I'd like to tear
his gizzard out.
[Perdy] Why, Patch, where did
you ever hear such talk?
Certainly not
from your mother.
- Watch out, Thunder.
- Don't worry, Penny.
He'll get that
yellow-livered...
Well, he'll get him,
all right.
Lucky, get down.
We can't see.
Mother,
make him get down.
C'mon, Lucky.
Down, dear.
Missed him.
Missed him by a mile.
I'm hungry, mother.
I'm hungry.
Rolly, you've just had
your dinner.
But I am,
just the same.
I'm so hungry I could eat...
a whole elephant.
Shh!
[Puppy] There he is,
behind that rock.
[Gunshot]
Oh, dear.
He shot poor Thunder.
He missed him. OI' Thunder's
pretending... I think.
[Wicked Laugh]
See? What did I tell you?
That's one of his tricks.
- Lucky, get down.
- Ha-ha-ha!
[Whimpering, Yipping]
I'm hungry, Mother.
I really am.
[TV] Don't miss next week's episode.
Who will triumph?
OI' Thunder
always wins!
And speaking of champions,
friends,
Kanine Krunchies is the
champion of all dog biscuits.
Kanine Krunchies
can't be beat
They make each meal
a special treat
Happy dogs are those who eat
nutritious Kanine Krunchies
Perdy, we better get these
little nippers off to bed...
if we're going for a...
w-a-l-k.
- We want to go too, Mother.
- Can we, Mother?
We never
get to go.
Come along, children.
Bedtime.
But we're not a...
[Yawn]... bit sleepy.
We want to go
for a walk in the park.
- Dad, can we?
- Better do as your mother says.
[Pongo] One, two,
three, four...
five, six...
seven...
eight, nine, ten, eleven,
twelve, thirteen...
I'm not sleepy.
I'm hungry.
Fourteen.
Hmm?
So do what all
the smart dogs do
And you'll feel great
the whole day through
You can be a champion too
if you eat Kanine Krunchies
Remember, friends,
just send five...
Lucky, you little rascal,
let's go.
There they go,
Horace, me lad,
out for their
evening constitutional.
A lovely pair
of turtledoves.
Around the corner
and off to the park.
Yeah, I don't like it,
Jasper.
One more pinch and
they'll throw the keys away.
Come off it, Horace.
We're getting plenty of boodle.
Yes, but...
I've been thinkin'.
You've been thinkin'?
I warned you about thinkin'.
I've got the knob for this job,
so let's get on with it.
Ah, nobody home
but the little ol' cook.
You just leave her
to ol' Jasper.
He can handle her
real diplomatic-like.
Yeah, but I still
don't like it.
Here, here.
Patch, you settle down.
[Chuckle]
Oh, dear.
Go to sleep now.
Close your little eyes.
That's a good
little one.
[Ringing]
Who do you suppose?
Good evening, ma'am.
We're here to inspect
the wiring and the switches.
- We're from the gas company.
- Electric, electric.
Electric company.
But we didn't call
for any inspection.
There's a new act
just been passed in Parliament.
Comes under the heading
of "Defense of the Realm Act."
It's for your own safety,
ma'am.
I don't care
whatever it says.
You're not coming in here
with the Mister and Missus gone.
Come off it, Ducky.
We got no time to palaver.
We got a job to do.
Excuse me!
What's the matter
with you two?
You got cloth ears?
You're not coming in!
She's a regular little tartar,
ain't she, Horace?
Don't you dare go up there,
you long-legged lummox!
Now I mean it.
If you don't get out
of this house...
I'll call the police,
I will.
Now be off with you,
you big weasel!
Now you've been
gone and done it.
You've cut me
to the quick, lady.
Why, I wouldn't stay here
if you asked me.
Not even
for a cup of tea.
Horace, me lad, I've got a sneaky
suspicion we're not welcome here.
Pack up.
We're leaving.
Sharp's the word
and quick's the action.
Let me out!
Help!
I'll call the police.
Good night, Ducky.
Ta-ta!
Those good-for-nothing
hoodlums!
Electric company.
Hmph!
They're nothing but common
sneak thieves.
I'll bet they made off
with the good silver.
Why, I bet they took
every last...
The puppies!
They're gone!
Patch? Lucky? Rolly?
They took
the puppies!
Oh...
Whatever will I do?
Those scoundrels!
They stole the puppies.
Police? Help!
The puppies.
Police!
Somebody help me!
Help! Help! Help!
"Dognapping!"
Can you imagine such a thing?
"15 puppies stolen."
They are darling little things.
Anita...
and her bashful Beethoven!
Pipe and all!
Oh, Roger,
you are a fool!
[Phone Ringing]
Hello?
Jasper!
Jasper, you idiot!
- How dare you call here.
- We don't want no more of this,
we want our boodle!
We'll settle
for half!
Not one schilling
'til the job's done.
Jasper! Jasper!
It's in the blinkin' papers,
pictures and all!
Hang the papers!
Lt'll be forgotten tomorrow.
- I don't like it.
- Shut up, you idiot!
What?
Not you, miss.
I mean Horace!
Why, you imbecile!
[Phone Ringing]
[Roger]
Maybe it's Scotland Yard.
Maybe they found something.
Hello, Inspector?
- Is Anita there?
- Who?
- Anita!
- Uh... it's for you.
Hello?
[Cruella] Anita, darling.
What a dreadful thing.
I just saw the papers.
I couldn't believe it.
Yes, Cruella.
It was quite a shock.
- Is she calling to confess?
- Roger, please!
- She's a sly one.
- We're doing everything possible.
- [Cruella] Have you
called the police?
- Yes, Scotland Yard.
- But I'm afraid...
- Where are they?
You idiot!
- Anita!
- Sorry, Cruella.
[Anita] If there's any news,
we'll let you know.
Thank you, Cruella.
Roger, I admit she's eccentric,
but she's not a thief.
Well, she's still number one
suspect in my book!
She's been investigated
by Scotland Yard.
- What more do you want?
- I don't know, darling.
I don't know.
Oh, Roger.
What'll we do?
Perdy, I'm afraid
it's all up to us.
Oh, Pongo.
Isn't there any hope?
Well, yes.
There's the twilight bark.
The twilight bark?
That's only a gossip chain.
Darling, it's the very
fastest way to send news.
If our puppies are anywhere
in the city, the London dogs will know.
We'll send the word tonight when
our pets take us for a walk in the park.
[Barking]
There's no one out tonight.
I'm afraid it's too cold.
We've got to keep
trying, Perdy.
[Barking]
[Distant Barking]
Perdy,
we're in luck!
It's the great dane
at Hampstead.
[Barking]
Quiet, boy!
Do you want to stir up
the whole neighborhood?
- Perdy, come on!
- Let's go.
- [Barking]
- Pongo, you old idiot!
[Howling]
Come on, now.
We're going home!
[Pongo Howling]
[Barking]
[Distant Barking]
[Yipping]
What is it, Danny?
Who's on the telegraph?
It's Pongo, Regents Park!
It's an all-dog alert.
What's it all about?
Tell me, tell me!
Wait a minute,
wait a minute.
[Distant Barking]
Well, now...
Hmm, that is something.
What, Danny?
What's something?
15 dalmatian puppies,
stolen!
Have they called the police?
Scotland Yard?
The humans tried everything. Now it's
up to us dogs and the twilight bark.
I'll sound the alert!
[Yipping]
Woof! Woof!
[Howling]
Ahh!
[Barking]
Prissy,
come in here!
[Barking]
[Yipping And Howling]
- [Barking]
- Coco!
Be quiet now!
[Many Dogs Barking]
[Man]
Aw, shut up!
Quiet!
[Barking Continues]
Will you be quiet!
[Distant Barking]
[Barking]
[Howling]
Towser,
what's going on?
What is it?
What's all the gossip?
'Taint no gossip, Lucy.
It be all the way from London.
- You don't say!
- 15 puppies stolen.
There's no puppies around here,
not since Nellie's last litter.
Well, then, we'd best
send the word along.
It be up to me
to reach the Colonel!
He be the only one
in barking range.
You'll never reach him
at this hour!
Well, I can try!
I'll bark all night
if I have to.
Ahem!
[Barking]
[Distant Barking]
Hmm-hmm-hmm.
Hmm... sounds like
old Towser.
It's an alert.
Sergeant!
Sergeant Tibs!
I say, Sergeant!
[Neighing]
Oh, yes, Captain!
Barking signal. It's an alert.
Report to the Colonel at once.
Righto, sir.
Right away, sir!
Colonel?
I say, Colonel!
Colonel, sir?
- Colonel?
- What? Who goes there?
Sergeant Tibs
reporting, sir.
Tibs? Tibs?
Oh, yes, Sergeant Tibs!
Look here, Tibs. What's the idea
of barging in at this hour?
But Colonel...
- Hold on, Sergeant. You hear that?
- [Barking]
- Sounds like an alert.
- Yes, Colonel.
- We'd better look into it.
Come along, on the double.
- Righto, sir.
- It's old Towser down
at Withermarsh, sir.
- [Barking]
By Jove, yes!
So it is.
Well, I'll see
what he wants.
Ahem!
Woof, woof, woof!
It be the Colonel.
The old boy himself!
He wants the message.
You'd better make it loud
or he'll never get it.
[Barking]
One long howl,
two short.
- One yip and a woof.
- Two yips, sir.
- What's the word?
- It's from London.
- It must be important.
- Yes, I'll get the rest of it.
Ahem!
Woof, woof, woof!
[Distant Barking]
Sounds like a number.
Three fives is 13.
- That's 15, sir.
- Of course, 15.
[Barking]
Yes... Dot, Spot...
Spotted puddings.
Poodles.
- No, puddles!
- Puddles, sir?
15 spotted puddles stolen?
Oh, balderdash!
- Better double-check it, Colonel.
- [Grumbling]
Oh, yes,
I suppose I'd better.
Woof, woof, woof!
[Barking]
Two woofs,
one yip and a woof.
- It sounds like "puppies"!
- Of course, puppies!
I just remembered.
Two nights past, I heard
puppy barking at Hell Hall.
The old de Vil place?
Nonsense, Tibs!
No one's lived there
for years.
Hold on! There's smoke
coming from the chimney!
[Colonel] By Jove, that's strange...
strange indeed.
I suppose
we'd better investigate.
I'll send word for
ol' Towser to stand by.
Roof! Roo-roo-roof!
Please... stand... by.
- What's he mean by that?
- I don't know.
Oh... maybe the ol' boy's
found something!
Oh, I do hope so.
They say the ol' place is haunted or
bewitched or some such fiddle faddle.
Fiddle faddle
and rot, sir.
Just the same, Sergeant,
use extreme caution.
No telling what sort of
hocus pocus you might run into.
[Gulps]
Blast it all, Tibs.
On the double, man.
- On the double.
- Yes, sir. Right away, sir.
Psst!
- [Whispering] Rover! Spotty!
- Hmm. What?
Are you one of
the 15 stolen puppies?
We're not stolen.
We're bought and paid for.
There's 99 of us
all together.
Ninety-nine!
How 'bout that bunch
of little ones?
They have names and colors.
They're not from the pet shops.
- Fifteen of 'em?
- We never counted them.
They're over there
by the tv.
- I'd better count 'em.
- Watch out for the baduns.
Baduns?
Those two blokes,
Horace and Jasper.
They're mean ones,
they are.
[TV]
Hey, look, Horace!
Watch me pot His Lordship
smack on the conk.
Ha-ha-ha-ha.
How's that for callin' 'em, eh?
Ha-ha-ha-ha!
[Whispering]
One... two...
- three, four, five, six...
- Hey, Jasper.
[Mumbling]
Give us a swig,
- just a short one.
- Now, Horace,
this hogwash ain't fit
for a fancy bloke like yourself.
Besides, you'd get crumbs in it,
you cabbage head!
All right.
Guzzle the whole works. I hope it
gives you colly wobbles, that's what.
Hey, Jasper.
Did you...
Six, seven, eight,
nine, ten, eleven...
Hey, get down, you runt!
And stay down!
[Yipping]
Go on, get out of here...
or I'll black
your other peeper.
Where was I?
Nine...
Nine... three more.
Twelve and... one, two, three.
That's fifteen!
They're the ones!
- [Screeching]
- Blimey!
- [Barking]
- What the...
Horace, look what we got!
A tabby cat!
[Yipping]
Ha-ha-ha!
Ho-ho-ho!
How'd you like
a tabby cat stew?
Or a cat casserole?
A la mode!
[Howling]
[Chiming]
[Howling And Barking]
- What is it, Pongo? What is it?
- It's the great dane.
He has news for us.
He'll meet us at Primrose Hill.
- How'll we get out?
- The back bedroom window.
It's always open
a wee bit. C'mon.
- Woof! Woof!
- [Barking]
Pongos, you've made it.
Good.
- What's the word? What's the news?
- Have they found our puppies?
They've been located
somewhere north of here...
- in Suffolk.
- Oh, thank heaven.
- Can you leave tonight?
- We can leave right away.
I'll go along as far as Camden Road
and give you instructions.
[Dane] When you reach
Withermarsh, contact old Towser.
He'll direct you to the Colonel
and the Colonel will take you...
to your puppies
at the de Vil place.
- De Vil!
- The de Vil place!
Oh, Pongo,
it was her!
- Oh, someone you know?
- There's no time to explain.
I hope we're
not too late.
Good luck, Pongo.
If you lose your way,
contact the barking chain.
They'll be
standing by!
[Honking]
Any news, Colonel?
Not a blasted thing.
They're lost or captured,
or something or other.
- Who knows what.
- Colonel, here comes a car.
Come now, Tibs.
Don't be ridiculous.
- They wouldn't be driving.
- Yes, I know, sir.
But it's heading
for Hell Hall.
It... It's stopping
at the gate!
It is?
Blast it all!
Better see what's up.
- On the double, man. On the double!
- Yes, sir.
Take over, Captain.
Righto, sir.
[TV Quiz Master] I'm sorry,
Mr. Simpkins. The answer is no, no, no.
Six down, four to go.
I've got no time to argue.
It's got to be done tonight.
It must be a yes
or no question.
Do you understand?
Tonight!
[Horace]
But they ain't big enough.
You couldn't get half a dozen coats
out of the whole caboodle.
Coats!
Dog-skin coats?
We'll settle for half a dozen!
We can't wait.
The police are everywhere.
I want the job done tonight!
How're we gonna do it?
Any way you like.
Poison them, drown them.
Bash them in the head.
You got any chloroform?
- Not a drop.
- And no ether, "ee-ther."
"Eye-ther"!
I don't care how you kill the little
beasts, but do it... and do it now!
Aw, please, miss.
Have pity.
Can't we see the rest
of the show first?
[Horace] We want to see
"What's My Crime?"
[Explosion]
Listen, you idiots!
I'll be back in the morning.
The job better be done...
or I'll...
I'll call the police!
Do you understand?
I think she means it.
Ah...
We'll get on with it...
as soon as
the show's over.
Will you please
sign in, sir?
You'd better get out of here
if you want to save your skins.
- But how?
- Shh.
There's a hole in the wall
there by the door.
C'mon, shake a leg.
Psst.
Kids, follow me.
[Horace] Hey, Jasper, look!
Ha-ha-ha-ha.
It's old Meathead.
Yeah, what do you know...
old Meathead Fauncewater.
C'mon,
don't crowd.
One at a time.
One at a time!
For our last contestant,
meet Mr. Percival Fauncewater.
If the panel fails to guess your
unusual crime in ten questions,
you will receive two weeks vacation
at a seaside resort,
all expenses paid.
[Quiz Master] That is, after
you've paid your debt to society.
Who will take the first
question? Inspector?
Could your crime
be classified as larceny?
- A theft, burglary?
- Straighten out!
Form a queue... along the wall.
Snap it up.
[Quiz Master] Mr. Fauncewater
is a burglar by trade,
but in this case,
his crime was not burglary.
- The answer is no.
- [Laughing]
One down, nine to go.
Miss Birdwell?
If your crime
wasn't robbery, did you...
Oh, dear,
what I mean is...
Do something of
a violent nature, that is...
Come, Miss Birdwell,
we're running short of time.
[Miss Birdwell] So sorry.
- Did you do someone in?
- Oh!
[Quiz Master] I'm sorry.
The answer is no.
Two down,
eight to go.
- Mr. Simpkins?
- Psst.
Hey, kid, let's go.
[Mr. Simpkins] Could it be
a violation of a city ordinance?
No.
Hey, get out of the way,
you little runt!
[Quiz Master] Three down,
seven to go. Inspector?
[Inspector] Very confusing,
I must say.
Surely,
this crime could...
- [Buzzer]
- I'm terribly sorry.
- We've run out of time.
- [Horace] Ain't that always the way!
Would it be possible for
Mr. Fauncewater to come back next week?
Then we could finish
our little game.
Good night, audience.
See you next week at this same time...
on "What's My Crime?"
Ah, oh well.
C'mon, Horace.
Let's get on with it.
I'll pop 'em on the head,
you do the skinnin'.
No you don't, Jasper!
I'll pop 'em off and
you do the skinnin'.
Horace, look!
They're gone.
They flew the coop...
right out through this hole.
Here, grab a torch.
We'll run 'em down before
you can say "Bob's your uncle."
[Whimpering]
There they go, Horace,
up the stairs.
[Whistling]
Here puppies.
Here, puppies!
C'mon now.
Don't go hiding from
ol' Uncle Jasper.
I ain't gonna hurt ya.
I thought we was
gonna pop 'em off.
Shut up.
Take a squint in there.
I'll check these
other two rooms.
[Whistling]
Here, puppies.
Come on out.
Come out wherever you are.
[Screeching]
Horace! Oh!
[Jasper] It's that mangy tabby cat.
He's the ringleader.
Head 'em off.
Head 'em...
[Yipping]
You bungling blockhead!
Back here!
Shh.
Here they come.
Double-crossin' little twerps,
pullin' a snitch on us!
After we took care of 'em.
There's gratitude for you.
It ain't fair, Jasper.
- [Whining]
- Horace, there they go!
Sergeant?
I say, Sergeant.
No time to explain.
Busy, sir.
Shut that door!
We'll close in on 'em.
Enough of this "Ring Around the Rosy."
Oh, Pongo,
I'm afraid we're lost.
It can't be far.
[Barking]
By Jove!
It can't be the Pongos.
[Barking]
Grrr...
[Howling]
It's the Colonel.
This way.
[Barking And Howling]
Colonel?
Are you the Colonel?
Oh, Pingo!
Uh... Uh... Pongo?
Our puppies,
are they all right?
No time to explain.
There's trouble.
A big hullabaloo.
Come along!
Follow me!
Ah, ha-ha-ha!
Now we've got 'em, Horace.
They've run out of room.
What have we got here?
A couple of spotted hyenas?
C'mon, Horace.
Give 'em what for.
I'm right
behind ya, lad.
Uh... oh!
You clumsy clod!
I'll knock the spots off you.
Let go!
[Barking]
Well, by George!
[Whimpering]
You mangy mongrel!
I'll knock your
blinkin' block off.
Yeow!
Blast 'em, Tibs.
Give 'em what for.
No, Colonel.
Retreat, retreat!
Yes. Yes, of course.
Retreat!
Retreat, on the double!
Help, Jasper!
Get me out of here!
Horace, they're
fighting dirty!
Oh, oh, oh!
Jasper!
Horace!
[Groaning]
C'mon, Perdy.
Let's go.
I'll skin every one
of them spotted hyenas...
if it's
the last thing I do.
[Puppies]
Dad! Mother!
- I missed you, Mommy.
- Here we are, Mommy.
Oh, my darlings...
my darlings!
- How'd you find us?
- Lucky, Patch, Pepper!
[Laughing]
Oh, Daddy.
- And Rolly, you rascal!
- Did you bring me anything to eat?
Everybody here?
All 15?
Twice that many, Dad.
Now there's 99 of us!
What?
Nine... 99?
[Pongo] Where did they
all come from?
[Perdy] What would she want
with so many?
She's gonna make
coats out of us.
- She couldn't!
- That's right, dog-skin coats.
Oh, dog-skin coats!
Come now, Tibs!
But it's true, sir.
Horace and Jasper were gonna
pop us off and... skin us!
She's a devil, a witch!
What'll we do?
We have to get back
to London somehow.
What about the others?
What'll they do?
Perdy, we'll take them
home with us... all of them.
Our pets would
never turn them out.
Colonel, sir,
lights on the road.
It's a truck
headin' this way.
[Tibs] It's the baduns,
Horace and Jasper.
They're following
our tracks.
We've got 'em
outnumbered, Tibs.
When I give the signal,
we'll attack.
Sir, I'm afraid that
would be disastrous.
Ahem!
Oh, think so?
We'd better
run for it.
Out the back,
across the pasture.
Thank you sergeant,
Colonel, Captain.
- Bless you all.
- How can we ever repay you?
Ahem! Nothing at all.
All in the line of duty.
That's right, sir...
routine.
Better be off.
Here they come.
C'mon, kids, hurry.
- Good luck, Pongos.
- [Colonel] And never fear.
We'll hold them off
'til the bitter end.
[Neighing]
Now, what's this?
Out of my way,
you barkin' haystack.
Or I'll knock your
blinkin' block off!
[Barking And Growling]
They ain't in here.
[Jasper] They're hiding
in the hay.
Give me a match.
We'll burn 'em out.
Ready, Captain.
Aim,
fire one.
Fire two.
Hey, there they go,
the little sneaks.
C'mon, back to the truck.
We'll head 'em off in half a mile.
They gotta be around
here somewhere.
- I've been thinkin'.
- Now, Horace.
What if they went down
the froze-up creek...
so's not to leave
their tracks?
Horace, you idiot!
- Dogs ain't that smart.
- [Sighs]
[Truck Engine]
All clear, Perdy.
- All clear.
- We gave 'em the slip!
Didn't we, Dad?
They didn't even
see us, Patch!
[Perdy] Shh, children.
Children, shh.
My feet are slippery.
I wish we could
walk on the snow.
No, son, we can't
leave tracks.
[Honking, Tires Screeching]
Well, any sign
of them?
Not so much as
one bloomin' footprint.
And we've been up and down
every road in the county.
- We're froze stiff. We're givin' up.
- Oh, no, you don't!
We'll find the little mongrels
if it takes 'til next Christmas.
Now get going!
Watch your driving!
Do you wanna get
nabbed by the police?
[Engine Revving]
Ninety-three,
ninety-four,
ninety-five, ninety-six,
ninety-seven,
ninety-eight...
Oh, Lucky!
C'mon, Lucky boy.
We can't give up now.
I'm tired and I'm hungry
and my tail's froze...
and my nose is froze
and my ears are froze.
- And my toes are froze.
- [Barking]
Pongo!
Pongo! Pongo!
We'd just about lost hope.
We have shelter for you...
at the dairy barn
across the road.
Oh, thank goodness.
Perdy! Perdy!
This way, Perdy.
- The dairy barn across the road.
- C'mon, kids.
It's not far.
C'mon, this way.
[Pongo] Follow the collie.
Just look, Queenie.
- Have you ever seen so many puppies?
- Aren't they adorable!
- Perfectly darling.
- The poor dears.
They're completely worn out
and half frozen!
- They all here, Pongo?
- Yes, dear. All 99 accounted for.
The famous Pongos.
We were so worried about you.
Been trying to reach you.
Afraid you'd been captured.
How did you make it
all this way?
- And in such dreadful weather.
- With all those little ones.
I'm hungry, Mother.
I'm hungry.
- I'm hungry too.
- Mother, we're hungry.
- We're all hungry.
- I'm sorry, children.
Do they like warm milk?
It's fresh.
- Where is it?
- Where is the milk?
Come and get it, kids.
It's on the house.
This way, children.
Around this way.
[Perdy] Don't crowd.
You'll have to take turns.
[Perdy] Rolly, wait your turn, dear.
Don't worry, kids.
There's plenty for all.
Ooh!
The little darlings.
Pongo, a few scraps
I saved...
- for you and the missus.
- Oh, thank you.
It's not much, but it might
hold you as far as Dinsford.
Huh?
Dinsford?
There's a Labrador there.
- His pet is a grocer.
- Oh, l... I'm sorry.
Quite all right.
Get some rest and don't worry.
I'll be standing watch.
I don't know what
we'd have done if...
- We're honored to be of service.
- We're sorry we can't do more.
[Duchess] Anyone who would think
of hurting these puppies...
- Shh! Duchess!
- They're so dear.
I wish they could stay
with us for always.
[Queenie] Princess, shh.
Quiet, everyone.
Let them sleep,
the poor things.
They're so exhausted and they
still have such a long way to go.
[Honking]
Hurry, kids. Hurry!
[Screeching]
Well now,
what have we here?
Well... so they thought
they could outwit Cruella.
- Ha-ha-ha-ha!
- [Honking]
Jasper!
Horace!
Here's their tracks
heading for the village.
Blimey!
It's them, all right.
Work your way south on the side roads.
I'll take the main road.
[Cruella]
See you in Dinsford!
[Barking]
Pongo, I've got
a ride home for you.
A ride home?
Perdy, did you hear that?
- For all of us?
- You mean we don't have to
walk anymore?
If we can manage it.
We'd better hurry.
We've got a ride home!
C'mon, children.
See the van
down the street?
[Labrador] It's going to London
as soon as the engine's repaired.
And there's room
for all of you.
[Perdy]
Pongo, there's Cruella.
Yes...
and Jasper and Horace.
- How will we get to the van?
- I don't know, Perdy.
- But somehow we've got to.
- Mother, Dad,
- Patch pushed me in the fireplace.
- Lucky pushed me first.
- Did not. Did not.
- Did too. Did too.
Did not!
- Please, children, don't quarrel.
- Say...
Perdy, I've got an idea.
Pongo,
- what on earth...
- Look, I'm a Labrador!
We'll all roll in soot.
We'll be Labradors.
Say, that is an idea!
C'mon, kids!
Roll in the soot.
You mean, you want
us to get dirty?
Did you hear that, Freckles?
Dad wants us to get dirty.
- Mother, should we?
- Do as your father says.
- This'll be fun.
- I always wanted to get good and dirty.
[Giggling]
[Pongo] That's the stuff.
The blacker the better.
- I'm ready.
- Me too.
- How's this, Dad?
- Wait. That's enough.
Not too many at a time.
Uh-oh. Rolly, hold on.
You're only half done.
Now, stay right with me.
We're gonna fool
the ol' mad lady.
Pongo...
I'm so afraid.
Jasper, do you suppose
they disguised themselves?
Say now, Horace.
That's just what they did.
Dogs is always paintin'
themselves black!
You idiot!
Well, so far
so good.
C'mon, Perdy.
Better get on your makeup.
I'll go ahead
with the next bunch.
[Cruella]
Jasper! Horace!
- Well?
- Be reasonable, miss.
[Horace] We're froze to our bones.
We've been out all night
and all day, with nothin' to eat.
They're somewhere in this village,
and we're going to find them.
Now get going!
- Do you think they've seen us?
- [Engine]
No, but we're
running out of time.
Try 'er again, mate.
Hurry, Perdy.
The van's about to leave.
Better hurry.
I'll get the rest.
That ought to do.
She'll get you back to London.
Better get aboard, miss.
Hey, Jasper.
[Whimpering]
C'mon, Horace.
Hurry, kids!
C'mon, kids.
Run on ahead.
- She's watching us, Dad.
- Keep going.
It can't be!
It's impossible!
[Labrador] Run for it!
- Jasper! Horace!
- [Honking]
Jasper!
[Cruella] There they go...
in the van.
After them! After them!
[Barking And Growling]
Pongo!
There she is... Cruella.
Hey, lady,
what in thunder
are you tryin' to do?
Crazy woman driver!
[Engine Revving]
- Pongo, look!
- Jasper!
Ain't nothin' to it.
I'll give him a nudge
and shove him in the dirt.
Perdy, watch out!
- Jasper!
- Horace!
You idiots!
You fools!
[Sobbing]
You imbeciles!
- Ah, shut up!
- [Sobbing]
[Radio]
You've seen her kind of eyes
Watchin' you from underneath a rock
Cruella de Vil
Cruella de...
Roger, after all,
that's your first big hit.
It's made more money
than we ever dreamed of.
Yes, I know.
I still can't believe...
that Pongo and Perdy
would run away.
Here's a bit of
Christmas cheer for you,
If there's anything
to be cheerful about.
Oh, those dear
little things.
Sometimes at night
I can hear them barking,
- [Barking]
- But it always turns out I'm dreaming.
[Barking]
[Anita] Roger, what on earth...
[Roger] They're labradors.
No, no.
They're covered with soot.
Look, here's Lucky!
Pongo, boy,
is that you?
Oh, Pongo, Pongo!
Ho-ho, it's Pongo!
And Perdy,
my darling.
And Patch, and Rolly,
and Penny, and Freckles.
They're all here,
the little dears.
- It's a miracle!
- What a wonderful Christmas present!
And look...
there's a whole lot more!
- Look, Anita, puppies everywhere.
- There must be 100!
One, two, three and
four... is seven.
Two, four, six, and three
is nine, plus two is eleven.
- 36 over here.
- 36 and 11, that's 47!
- Eighteen, Roger.
- That's 65!
Ten, eleven,
twelve, thirteen!
- Wait... six more.
- Let's see, that's 84.
And fifteen plus two...
a hundred and one!
A hundred and one?
Where did they come from?
Oh, Pongo,
you old rascal!
- What'll we do with them?
- We'll keep 'em.
- In this little house?
- We'll buy a big place in the country.
We'll have a plantation...
a dalmatian plantation.
Roger, that's truly
an inspiration.
It'll be a sensation!
We'll have
a dalmatian plantation.
A dalmatian plantation,
I say.
We'll have a dalmatian plantation
- Where our population can roam
- I'm hungry.
Our whole aggregation
will love our plantation home
Woo-woo-woo-woo
Oo-oo-oo
[Yipping]
Dalmatian plantation home
[Barking And Yipping]