September 21, 1945.
That was the night I died.
Disgusting.
- Hey, watch it!
- Sorry.
Is he dead?
The Americans'll be arriving
any day now.
These bums are a disgrace.
Mama...!
Tell me. What day is it?
Setsuko...
Another one.
What is this stuff?
Oh, what does it matter?
Just dump it!
This one's a goner, too.
You can see it in their eyes.
Sakuma's
Drops
GRAVE OF THE FIREFLIES
Production Designer and
Executive Producer
Ryoichi Sato
Original Story by
Akiyuki Nosaka
Character Design
Yoshifumi Kondo
Art Director
Nizo Yamamoto
Music
Michio Mamiya
Layout
Yoshiyuki Momose
Character Color Design
Michiyo Yasuda
Director of Photography
Nobuo Koyama
Sound Design
Yasuo Urakami
Producer
Toru Hara
Written and
Directed by
Isao Takahata
Air raid! Get to the shelters!
Quickly!
We're in for a big
one this time!
The shelter behind the firehouse
should be safest!
It's hot!
Be a good girl.
Try to be patient.
Well, I guess I had better
get over to the shelter.
So be careful , Seita, and get
over there as soon as you can.
Setsuko, be a good girl
and listen to your brother.
Mom, never mind us!
Get to the shelter!
Yes, yes.
Mom, do you have your medicine with you?
I have it right here.
Don't worry.
I hate the shelter!
Well, you'll be sorry
if you get blown up by a bomb.
Now get on.
My doll! My doll!
Air raid!
Seita!
Get down!
Seita! Seita!
Seita!
Hurry! Let's go! Let's go!
Clear the way, people!
Move the damn cart, will you?
Oh god!
Take whatever you can carry.
Long live the Emperor!
We're safe here. Don't worry, OK.
Where's Mama? I want Mama.
She is in the shelter.
The firehouse shelter can take
a hit from a 250-kilo bomb easy.
Don't worry about her.
She'll probably go to
Niponmatsu station to find us.
When things calm down,
we will meet her there.
Let's just rest a bit.
Are you okay, Setsuko?
I lost one of my shoes.
Don't worry. I'll
buy better ones.
I have some money.
Open this.
Wow Setsuko, you're rich.
It's black rain, from
all of the bombing.
Look...
It's all gone!
That was the civic hall.
We ate lunch there, once.
Seita, Is our house gone too?
Probably.
What'll we do?
Dad'll make them pay for this!
Mother! Mother!
Well, it's not like I was
the only one who lost his house.
We're all in the same boat.
Well, at least we're still alive.
There were two direct hits.
The fires are impossible to put out!
When you try to smother them,
it just spreads the oil around.
It's not her.
She's not down here!
Seita, I have to pee.
- OK.
Attention all residents of
Ichirizuka and Kaminishi!
Please report to the elementary
school for first aid services!
What's wrong?
My eye hurts.
Don't rub it.
We'll get it washed out
at the school.
Where's Mama?
She'll be there.
At School...?
Yes. Let's go.
Oh Seita! Come with me.
Have you seen your mother yet?
She's been injured. Go to her.
I'll watch your sister.
My goodness. wasn't
that scary, Setsuko?
Seita has to go somewhere.
We'll wait for him together.
Seita. I am glad you are here.
Are you okay?
My mom...?
This way.
This is your mother's, isn't it?
In here.
She's finally fallen asleep.
Your Mother really should be in a
proper hospital. We can't do much here.
I don't think they have hit
Kaisei hospital in Nishinomiya.
My mother-My mother has heart trouble.
Can she get her medicine?
I'll find out.
I'll be around, son.
Mom, are you...
You saw her?
Yes.
I am so sorry.
I'm thirsty.
If there's anything I can do,
just ask.
Did you get your ration?
Let me. I'll get it for you!
Keep this ring safe in your purse.
Don't lose it, OK?
Mom's been hurt, Setsuko.
But she'll get better soon.
Where is Mama?
In the hospital. In Nishinomiya.
We'll stay here
at the school tonight.
Then tomorrow, we'll go to stay at our
Aunt's house near the hospital, OK?
Setsuko?
Understand?
We're all staying on the second floor.
Why don't you stop by later?
Thank you for all your kindness. We will.
See you later then. Bye now.
Want some?
I want to see Mama.
Maybe tomorrow.
It's too late now.
Setsuko, watch me, I'm good at this!
I haven't unbandaged her. Believe
me, you don't want to see the body.
With this heat we're having,
she'll have to go on the truck today.
Where's your sister?
In Nishinomiya.
We have a distant aunt there.
I think she'll take care of us.
I see. Lucky for you.
I'd better get back to work.
Good luck to you.
Mama!
Where is Mama?
What's the matter?
Is she still sick?
Yeah. Yeah, she is still sick.
Welcome back.
How's your mother?
Is she at Kaisei?
Yeah...
Lucky your dad's in the Navy.
You get to have a truck
help move you over here!
I've laid out futons and
mosquito netting in your room.
Thank you.
I don't understand. Doesn't
Mama need her ring?
Did she give it to
me to keep for her?
Just be careful
you don't lose it.
Setsuko...
When Mom's a little better,
I'll take you to see her.
Time for bed. OK?
Dried bonito, herring, some
dried potato, pickled plums.
And I do believe this is butter!
All of these things are so
hard to come by nowadays.
It's soldiers' families
always get the best.
Anyway, did you stop
by the hospital today?
I'd like to tell your mother all the
things that have been happening.
And I could take Setsuko along
to visit her.
How bad?!
My Mom passed away while she
was still at the school.
What?! She's dead?
Then, why didn't you tell me?
Why were you hiding it?!
Answer me, child.
I didn't want Setsuko to know.
So, she is dead...
How awful!
Well, you'd best write your father
and tell him!
Seita!
Look!
She bought me new shoes!
Good for you, Setsuko.
Hello there!
Wacth this.
Don't be too long.
What was making that noise?
Bullfrogs. There is
nothing to be scared of.
Firefly!
Ready? Come on, catch it.
Aww, you squashed it.
It smells!
Don't squeeze so hard next time.
There're millions of them!
Hey Setsuko, close your eyes
and say "ah."
Why should I?
Come on. Just do it. "Ah."
Fruit drop!
Orange and cherry
and lemon and lime!
I am eating my candy
and taking my time!
That was close. I
almost swallowed it.
We're home.
Where were you two?
Did you thank the lady?
Yes, ma'am.
That food looks good.
Seita. why aren't you up?
Shouldn't you be going to school?
Or something?
Yeah, but the steelworks they had me
working in was bombed the other day.
And my school burned down.
There's no place to go.
Well, I hope
you've written to your father.
I did that. I sent it
through the Naval Office.
When?
Just after we came here. I guess
it was about 10 days ago.
That seems strange.
There should have been
a reply by now.
Return the scissors when you've
finished with them, Setsuko.
Any news on the war?
It's beginning to look hopeless.
It seems that the more factories we lose,
the harder the others have to work.
The War efforts is eating
up all of our supplies.
You're right. That's why food's
getting so hard to find.
Our soldiers aren't the only ones
who are suffering.
You work for our country's
defense too, young lady.
Eat up and work
as hard as you can!
Not again.
So you've taken in
a couple of homeless children?
Poor things, losing their
mother when they're so young.
What's wrong? You got an itch?
It's hot. I hate shelters!
Just hang on. We'll be
out of here soon enough.
Hey, you wanna go to the beach?
Yeah! Yeah! Let's go! Let's go.
Wow. It's all vegetable fields now.
What're they doing?
They are making sea salt.
It's all the salt and
soy sauce is rationed.
Alright. Hurry up, Setsuko!
It might be a little cold.
It is cold!
Feels good, right?
You won't itch now.
It's a big bath!
I'm gonna eat you!
Here I come!
Snippy... Snippy... Snippy Crab.
Snippy... Snippy...
Snippy...Snip.
What's wrong?
Is he sleeping?
Don't look at that.
When it gets a little warmer,
I'll teach you how to swim.
Let's swim, then we can eat.
We'll swim,
and that'll make us hungry.
Seita!
Setsuko!
You're hungry, aren't you?
There's food here for you here.
Come on now. Time to eat.
Mother! How are you?
Are you alright, my daughter?
I'm fine, really!
They're very nice here.
I'm hungry.
Let's get home before we're
caught in the next air raid.
I'm tired. Please carry me.
Air raid!
I am afraid these are no use. Your
mother won't be needing kimonos anymore.
Why don't you trade them
for rice?
I've been trading off my things
Little by little for food we need.
You can probably get
a full toh of rice for them.
That much?
You need your nourishment, you know.
I mean, how can you be a soldier
if you don't grow up healthy?
A whole toh of rice.
Your mother would be glad that you
didn't just let them just go to waste.
Why don't I take
them for you?
No!
Have you been awake
this whole time?
They're Mama's!
No, they're Mama's!
Don't take them!
No! No! No!
- Setsuko. Let them go.
Setsuko!
No.
Mama!
No!
It's fine rice.
- Yes...
We'll have a proper
rice dinner tonight, Setsuko.
Here, this is your share.
White rice, Setsuko!
Here you go.
With my daughter and our lodger
working so hard...
I've felt just terrible about
not having rice to give them.
It's great, huh?
Real white rice.
More please!
Sure.
You're just gobbling it down
tonight, aren't you, Setsuko?
Uh-huh. It's very good!
What's wrong?
I don't want rice porridge!
I don't suppose we have any
more of those pickled plums?
No, we finished
those off ages ago.
Here's your lunch.
Thanks. I'd better get going.
Bye, mom.
- Take care.
We'll have rice balls for lunch.
Just hold on until then.
You stop that! You'll have
porridge for lunch too!
Do you think
a lazy slug like you deserves...
the same as people who are
working so hard for our nation?!
Really, Seita. You're certainly old enough to
know now that everyone has got to cooperate.
You keep saying you want rice, but do you
do anything to earn this rice you want?
No, you don't!
I even give you some rice,
and you still complain!
But it was our rice in the first place.
Oh, so now
I'm cheating you, am I?
How dare you say that!
After I take you two into my home!
Fine!
Here is a new rule. From now on,
we will make our own dinners.
How do you like that?
Tell me Seita. You have other relatives
in Tokyo, don't you?
Some people on your mother's
side of the family?
Why not write to them?
We could be bombed any day.
I don't know where to find them.
Let's go home, Mommy.
Uh-huh. Daddy's waiting for us.
Frogs are singing,
it's time to go home
Sorry you had to wait so long.
What's wrong?
I'm really hungry.
And thirsty too.
OK.
Here. It's a fruit drop.
Mom has 7000 yen in the bank.
7000. That's more than enough for us
to live on, so don't you worry, OK?
I'm telling Dad to write back soon, because
Setsuko's waiting. Write your name
You're in luck.
You can't buy a stove like this easily
nowadays. You know what I mean?
It's almost impossible to find
any hardware to sell.
And of this quality.
I'll take that comb, and...
Do you have an umbrella?
An umbrella... Oh, yes!
It's raining cats and dogs.
But I have a raincoat and
my big red rubber clods.
Drip-drop, plip-plop
Down comes the rain!
And that should do it!
Be careful with that fire.
Right.
What are they up to?
They're doing their own cooking.
Well, good for them! It's about time.
More, please.
Mom, did you ever
scold them again?
Yes, and they refuse to apologize.
And that boy even bought a stove.
Just to spite me!
Finished!
Don't do that.
That's bad manners.
We can sit any way we want to.
Doesn't matter.
There. Rice for two.
That's it?
Yep. Next ration will be in July.
Let me!
Ready?
Here.
Do you like it?
It's all different tastes!
Grape, strawberry, mint, melon.
All the flavors are in there.
Now, drink it all up, OK?
It's all gone.
Great. They left the
dishes for me to do.
So selfish.
Honestly! Those little brats are two
of the worst children in the world.
Not again!
Seita please, that man and my daughter work
hard for our nation all day long.
We can't have her crying
keeping them awake.
We're having enough trouble getting
any sleep with all of these air raids!
Attention! Attention! Report
from Central Military Division.
Several waves of
enemy bombers are approaching.
Going to the shelter again, Seita?
You're old enough to
help fight the fires, aren't you?
I want to go home.
I hate living with her!
We don't have a house
to go back to.
With a great big streamer shaped
like a carp in the wind...
Go.
With a great big streamer shaped
like a carp in the wind...
The big one's Papa, and
the little one's the kids.
Stop it!
Don't you realize that
there's a war going on?!
You two are nothing
but trouble for me!
A couple of pests,
that's what you are!
You're no help during the raids.Take!
Take! Take!
You could go live in that
shelter for all I care!
That's it.
We can live here.
No one seems to be using it.
It seems sturdy enough.
And we can live
just like we want to.
Can we live here really?!
We've bothered you long enough.
We should be leaving now.
You are leaving? For where?
Haven't really decided yet.
Well then, you two, bye bye.
Take care of yourselves.
And this'll be the kitchen!
And this'll be the front door!
But where's the bathroom, Seita?
That can be anywhere.
You wanna go somewhere with me?
Thanks a lot. Where do
you want the wagon?
Just leave it right there.
Do you think you can sell my
sister and I a little bit of food,
and maybe a bail of straw?
I guess so.
There's not much left, though.
- It smells so good!
- Let's eat.
Well, I guess we can always
eat frogs if we have to.
Frogs?
Yeah. They taste great.
You'd better get under
the mosquito net now.
What's wrong?
I forgot my toothbrush.
One night without it
won't matter.
It's getting pretty buggy out here.
You'd better go get under the net.
It's dark in there. I'm scared.
I have to pee, Setsuko.
How about you?
Look, a kamikaze.
Looks like a firefly.
Yeah.
Hey, let's catch some.
Okay, get in.
Ready?
I can see you!
I can see you, too.
A hair clip.
Hey, let's get
as many as we can!
Did I ever tell you I went to see a naval
review one time, just before you were born.
Naval review?
Yeah. Dad's naval cruiser
was named the Maya.
It was in formation with the
fleet in the harbor.
Mighty fortresses
floating on the seas!
Defending our homeland
from invaders near and far!
Enemy plane!
I wonder where Dad is
fighting right about now.
Get off of me, Seita...
Whatcha doing?
Making a grave.
Mama's in a grave too.
Auntie told me about it.
She said that Mama died, and
that she's in a grave now.
We'll go and visit
her grave sometime.
Do you remember the graveyard, Setsuko?
That really pretty one out near Nunobiki?
That's where she is now. Resting
peacefully Under a big camphor tree.
Why do fireflies
have to die so soon?
Wow, looks like someone
is living in here.
They probably lost their house.
Maybe it's some crazy hermit.
It's a swing.
Hey, a kid lives here.
What's this?
Rest in Peace! Rest in Peace!
I wish it was real food.
It says "Setsuko".
Who's Setsuko?
Look guys! Dried out frog guts!
Who'd wanna eat that?!
Nobody I know
would ever eat this stuff!
Ground soybeans!
And I thought
the food I got was bad!
A ghost! A ghost!
Wait up! hey! Wait up!
I've traded everything for rice.
Even my mom's kimono.
There's nothing left to trade.
Please, I can pay you
good money for the rice.
Sorry. I can't trade
or sell anything to you.
I'm a farmer, but I'm afraid even
I don't have any rice to share.
Don't you have other
relatives to help you?
I don't know how to
contact any of them.
Then take my advice and just go
back to the woman in the village.
Look, everything's rationed now.
Can't survive outside
of the system.
Just swallow your pride
and apologize to her.
Thanks, anyway. I'll just
go and ask someone else.
You're the son of a navy man, aren't you?
So, try to be brave.
Look out!
Is it good?
Oh no!
It doesn't matter
if you like it or not.
You have to eat!
You need to, so you
can grow up strong!
Seita...
I feel-My insides
feel really funny.
Are you cold?
I've been having diarrhea.
Hey you...!
Hey! Sorry!
Sorry! I didn't mean to!
Forgive me!
My sister's sick. I just wanted
to get her some sugar! I'm sorry.
Yeah, sure! Stealing food's
a serious crime in wartime!
You god damned...!
Come back here!
What the hell?!
Potatoes too?!
So, you're the one who's
been stealing my crops!
- I'm sorry!
- Seita...
I'll never do it again, I swear!
I promise you will
never see me again.
Tell that to the cops!
I'll take you there myself!
Now walk! I hope they lock you
up for the rest of the war!
Seita...
- Please, she's sick!
Seita!
- She needs me! No!
Move!
Seita!
Seita...
Based on what you both told me, the
nature of the crime is very clear.
So I thank you for the information, sir.
I will take care of this. You may go now.
But, officer...
You've knocked
this poor kid around enough.
I'm even tempted to call it...
...assault!
I... er... Thank you, sir!
I suppose you have heard
about the latest attack.
Would you like a glass
of water or something,son?
Setsuko.
Seita!
Seita.
Should I get a doctor for you, Seita?
What parts hurt? I can help you.
Setsuko!
I have to go to the bathroom..
Can it wait a little bit?
Hop on.
Daddy is gone to the mountain
to bring back some firewood...
Hurry! Come on!
Setsuko. Dinner.
This pumpkin's great.
Tastes like sweet bean jelly.
I don't like that stuff.
Look, if you don't eat,
Dad' will blame me for it.
Come on, ready? I'll even help you, OK?
Now come on. Cheer up and eat!
Once you are better, I'll take you to
the beach again, Setsuko.I promise.
Yeah! Yeah!
Now I'll really get you
something good to eat, Setsuko!
Seita...
So, you are telling me these
were your mother's? Oh, please.
Try to pawn your garbage off on me?
Get out of here.
Setsuko.
Setsuko!
Seita... Water...
Yeah...
Breathe in.
And out.
She's been having diarrhea
for a while now.
Prickly heat and rashes
all over her body.
And her skin seems very
sensitive to any salt water.
Weakening from malnutrition. It's typical.
Probably due to the diarrhea.
Next patient?
Can you give her
medicine or a shot?
Don't wanna shot.
Please, doctor, you have to help her!
Medicine, please.
GIve her some medicine? All this child
needs is some food. A good meal.
She needs food...
How can I help you?
Where am I supposed
to get food?!
I am so hungry. What
do you want to eat?
Tempura, sashimi, jelly...
Anything else?
Ice cream.
And also...
I want fruit drops.
Fruit drops? Okay!
I'll withdraw all the money and
buy you all the food you need.
I don't want anything.
You can have it.
Don't go! Stay with me!
Don't leave me alone!
I don't want you
to worry, Setsuko.
I am going to go buy you some
good nourishing food, OK?
And I'll never... I will never
ever leave you again. Never, ever.
I promise.
3000 yen.
There's a typhoon coming?
That's just typical, isn't it?
We get our "divine
wind" after we surrender. Figures...
Surrender? Are you saying
we've lost the war?!
So, you haven't
heard, young man?
You are telling me Japan's lost the war?
The Great Japanese Empire?
Yeah.
Surrendered unconditionally.
But what about the fleet?
Are they...
All gone.
The whole fleet's been sent to the
bottom of the sea. Not one left afloat.
What?!
Was my Dad's ship sunk, too?! Do you know?
Please tell me. Is that why
he hasn't written me back?
How the hell should I know?
Crazy kid.
Damn him.
God damn him.
I'm so hungry.
Daddy.
Now Dad's gone too.
He's dead too.
Dad...
I'm sorry that I'm so late, Setsuko. I'll
go ahead and start making up some rice.
Up they go.
And down again.
Oh. The firefly's stopped.
I bought us some chicken
and I got a few eggs.
And I also have...
Setsuko, what's in your mouth?
This is a marble.
It isn't a drop!
I brought you something really special.
I know that you are goning to like it.
Seita...Have one.
One what, Setsuko?
Rice balls.
I made them for you.
Here...
Here, have- have one.
You don't want them?
Setsuko!
Look here. Watermelon.
And I didn't steal it.
Here, eat it.
It's good...
Hold on to this and I'll go make
us some rice gruel with eggs.
I'll leave the melon here for you.
OK?
Seita...
Thank you.
She never woke up.
There you go.
Charcoal for the cremation.
Now, since it's a little child, you
really should do it at a temple.
About the body, it should be lightly
dressed and use beanstalks for a good fire.
In spite of it all,
it's a lovely day.
It's so good to be home!
It hasn't changed a bit.
The old phonograph.
I've missed this view.
Come back soon!
The next morning,
I put some of Setsuko's ashes into...
...the candy tin,
and then climbed down the hill.
I never went back to the shelter.
Seita...
Time for bed. OK?