Hello, everyone.
I have my friend Chris Renaud on my right.
And I have my friend Pierre Coffin on my left.
And we're both the directors
of Despicable Me 2.
Well, we haven't much to say, right,
about this?
That's right.
We had nothing to do with that logo.
- Although it's nice rendering.
- Pretty cool. Nice flare there.
Yes. Well, I don't know
what to say about that.
We started off doing them on the first one,
and then they got branded.
It helped brand Illumination, I guess.
Yeah, they've sort of taken on
a life of their own.
I think the first idea we had
was with an evil minion in there.
Yes, I get it.
We jumped ahead. I think I ruined something.
- Damn!
- Can't say that. Roll that out.
I was gonna say the other word, but...
To get into the movie,
one of the things we talked about,
what the opening scene would be.
And for us,
one of the big inspirations in this movie,
maybe even more than the first one,
was James Bond.
Where there would be some kind of
big action opening thing
that felt, actually, not disconnected,
but felt like it was in a different world,
a different environment.
So, compared to the first movie,
where we start in Egypt,
we thought a cool thing to try
would be the Antarctic.
Scale and mystery, basically.
Yeah. We needed a crime to occur
that nobody witnessed.
So we could keep it top secret.
The original version of this scene, actually,
we were playing with setting it in Paris.
I remember, with all these Paris clichés,
and you almost got hanged in France.
- I decided I'd like to go for a Russian lab.
- Exactly.
Also, from a narrative point of view,
we knew we needed something
that not a lot of people could witness.
So the Antarctic worked great.
- All these guys are speaking Russian, right?
- Yes, that's actual Russian.
Although maybe not in Russia itself,
probably be something else.
- And here it is.
- Oh, my God! What is that?
Here's our big reveal of our magnet ship,
which was designed by Eric Guillon
to look like a giant magnet.
We even colored it like a big cartoon magnet.
It's red and silver.
But in this sequence,
it was just slightly different
than the one from the first Despicable Me.
We went for more of an action tone.
Also hoping to find some bits of comedy.
But truly it's more like, as Pierre said before,
just a sense of scale and action.
Again, try to build some mystery as to
who could be behind this masterful heist.
I've got nothing to say about this shot.
I tried to find something intelligent,
but I can't.
Yeah, that's right. It's extremely tasteful.
But anyway, here, just sort of
setting up the Despicable Me world,
trying to punctuate with comedy
even in an action scene.
And then we come and...
This was one of the main concepts of the
movie, which was the Anti-Villain League,
who, much like as we always talk
about Terminator 2,
what could we do with Gru in a second film?
And it seemed pretty clear that he
wasn't a villain by the end of the first movie.
So we thought maybe it'd be fun
to have him recruited by the good guys.
But before we get to that, we wanted to see
what Gru's doing with his kids.
Here in this scene, we see him prepping
to try to put together the perfect...
I guess it's six, right?
Agnes is turning six, is what we figured.
- Yeah.
- A 6-year-old birthday party.
It's a good opportunity
to sort of reintroduce all the characters.
Here's Edith dressed as a ninja.
I think originally,
didn't we say Batman, I think?
Yeah, a pink Batman.
But we weren't sure if we'd get the rights.
We're like, "Let's try a ninja.
It's public domain."
Actually, in a lot of ways,
it felt more appropriate for Edith.
Yeah. We did try to find some little
evolutions, obviously, for all the girls.
We knew that we didn't want them to be
five years older than the first one
or four years older.
So we tried to find those little differences
that made these characters
a little bit different from the first movie.
So, there they are, the minions.
I just want to mention, this is one of
the funny things with these characters
as they've evolved across the two movies
and a couple of shorts.
Originally, our concept was
they would never appear in the daylight.
Or if they did, in other words,
outside of Gru's underground lab,
they always had to be disguised.
Which, in this movie, gave us
an opportunity for a lot of disguises.
But I think there is one scene, actually,
if they are noticed by anyone,
it's only children.
So, anyway,
those are just a couple of little things.
You find as you do these things and
you create more stories for these characters,
you sort of have to bend or break your rules
as you go.
Break almost.
We try to be subtle about breaking,
but sometimes we were not.
So, in this moment, Gru's found out
that his entertainment he's booked
for the party is not gonna show.
For us, this was a great opportunity
to show the lengths that he's gone to
to make sure
that his daughters have a great life.
In other words, what he'll do as a father
to ensure their happiness.
And in our initial conversations
about this scene,
I have to admit
there's some autobiographical elements,
since my wife has asked me to appear
as a shark, Darth Vader.
- And a fairy princess?
- Not a fairy princess.
I had been something pink, though.
Some kind of creature that was
in some TV show. I don't remember now.
- Have you ever dressed up as a woman?
- No. I haven't had to go that far.
But anyway, Gru has.
That's a nice indication of how far
he'll go to make sure Agnes has a great day.
Just to come back to Gru,
Gru is a great character in the sense
that since he thinks himself
as being sort of mean
and really dominant about things,
it's always cool showing these characters
in very demeaning situations.
Like dressed up
as this fairy princess right now.
I think when Pierre and I and the writers,
and Chris Meledandri and Janet Healy
and all of us sort of talk about this character,
there's a lot of elements
that I think do come from our lives.
I always say in some ways, Gru right here
is a good example, is about bad parenting,
which I think a lot of people can relate to,
some of those choices you make
in the heat of the moment that
you maybe regret or wish you'd done better.
But in the end,
hopefully your kids still love you.
I know it's really you, Gru.
I'm just pretending for the other kids.
Anyway, one of our early conversations
was about how to keep Gru Gru,
now if he's more of a dad
and eventually working for the good guys.
And this character was... Not this one.
The one before, Jillian, his neighbor.
Was a good opportunity
to sort of let Gru be Gru.
That's what we did, is set up
other characters, you'll see some later,
that he can react to, that kept him true
to who we established in the first film.
No, Jills, that is not happening.
In the previous shot, you saw
some background animation that we love.
Like stuff that doesn't really
come in front of the foreground action.
A lot of things happen in the background
that are really funny sometimes,
so we'll try pointing those out.
Yeah, especially with some of
the minion scenes that are coming up.
You'll see what Pierre
and the animation team,
they always put a lot of good stuff there.
We saw Kyle, the dog, earlier,
and this is where we start to establish
our new character, Lucy Wilde,
played by Kristen Wiig,
who eventually through the film,
she's sent to recruit Gru,
but she also becomes his love interest
later in the film.
Again, this is the prime example
of romantic comedy dynamics,
where these two characters at first,
certainly their personalities
don't seem like they're going to mesh at all.
Lucy's very bright and optimistic.
In fact, her design is based on a sketch
from Eric Guillon.
He did this great drawing of her
almost like a shaft of sunlight
surrounded by all these dark villains.
Really that became the basis of her character.
Do you want to talk about that
as the animation test?
Yeah. When I read that line of description
in the script,
I thought it was a great animation test to do.
Like how would Lucy try to put Gru
into the trunk of a car?
We did, I think, a test
that lasted maybe a minute long
where Gru was really tortured
very slowly, painfully,
just to get him into that trunk.
Obviously, that didn't make it into the movie,
but we kept the essence of it.
And very often what happens
as the movie is developed
is we start with the script
from Cinco Paul and Ken Daurio,
but there's also animation work
being done simultaneously,
which very often also becomes a big part
of the scenes, certainly the characters,
so the movie sort of develops
in parallel paths
in both script and character animation.
That sort of enriches itself at every level also.
It's very evolutionary.
We were talking about that as we came over,
from the script
to the storyboards to animation.
And sometimes something early,
like an animation test,
which is done very early in the process,
becomes part of the scene
or informs the scene,
defines it in a lot of ways.
And sometimes leads also to a whole plot.
I mean, with the minion thing.
Do you remember?
Yes.
In the first movie, we had talked about
trying to develop a minion subplot,
but for various narrative reasons,
we had difficulty making that work.
But we knew in this one that was something
that we really wanted to try to create,
that they were more of a driver
in the storytelling itself.
So this is a moment...
This is Pierre being right.
We had a few conversations
about Lucy's car.
I think one cool thing
about the car is it feels,
for lack of a better word, very European
and very sort of period.
And I think this was Eric's first design,
which Pierre really liked,
and I remember we did some investigations
on other kinds of cars,
more big SUV,
more of what would be typical, I guess,
for a secret agent to be driving.
But this one just had such appeal,
and frankly, it was very unique.
And I think even,
you'll hear in Heitor's composition,
this is Lucy's theme you're hearing here.
Her theme also has
an old world feel to it, too.
It has a Henry Mancini quality.
So anyway, these elements
came together nicely for this character.
What's that?
- I think it's a huge shark.
- That's right.
That was the implication
in the storyboards, that it was a huge shark,
but no, it's a sub.
I don't think we fooled anyone with that.
I guess you're right.
It's easier to fool people
with storyboards than actual rendering.
"Yeah, it looked like
a huge shark in the shadow."
Looks like a sub.
Still works, though, just because
you've got a sense of discovery and scale.
One of my favorite
little design things in this set
is that the windows
of the submarine spell out AVL,
which we realized if you're outside
the submarine, it would be backwards.
So, it only works from the inside.
Works for the crew.
That's right, the crew, everyone else outside
has no idea who they are.
So this is another new character,
Silas Ramsbottom, played by Steve Coogan,
in an M type character
from the James Bond films.
And he did a great job.
Steve came in
with a couple of ideas for voices,
and this one was instantly
the one that we both liked, Pierre and I.
It's just a classic stuffy Englishman, I guess.
Do you remember the butler?
Yes, I remember the butler.
He was the guy in the bathrooms
and in the gym.
Remember we also were doing a little,
not a subplot with him,
but remember we were
having some ideas with the butler?
In early days? Yeah.
- He was supposed to be everywhere, right?
- Yeah, yeah, exactly.
He was always gonna be with Silas,
was the idea.
So there's a lot of ideas as we develop
the movies that we discuss,
and a lot of them we throw out.
Yeah, yeah. But it's actually good.
We found those little secondary ideas,
like the butler following Silas around.
We managed to do that,
I think, with the minions,
with the minion jar,
the one that gets the jar stuck on his head.
You'll find him over the movie
up until the very end.
So sometimes we manage stuff,
sometimes we fail.
Yeah.
But also sometimes we just say
that it's not worth it.
Exactly, it's not worth pursuing.
A little Easter egg here.
Yes. The two scientists have
the nametags of our names,
Coffin and Renaud.
Pierre is the tall, slim one.
I'm the short, fat one.
I am not sure that was our decision, actually.
It's the guy from...
It's sort of accurate.
I take a little bit of offense, but...
Well, I'm the one that gets killed.
That's true. I guess it evens out.
So that is the demonstration of
what we call PX-41, which was...
When we had the earliest conversations
about the movie, we're trying to figure out,
okay, what's the narrative story
that is going to drive the action,
and trying to come up with
what was an idea that would be on par
with Gru's theft of the moon.
So, it was hard to come up with something
that would rival that in scale,
so instead of looking externally
to something else,
like the Eiffel Tower or Mount Rushmore,
we looked internally
and started looking at the minions.
And when we started the conversation,
we were thinking
that maybe somebody broke into Gru's lab
and stole his minion-making machine.
And we had some funny sketches
based on that.
- But then it sort of evolved from there.
- Yeah.
I'm sorry, I wasn't following.
Here, Pierre is just watching the movie.
It looks really good.
Attitude! That's right!
So anyway, from there we started talking
about the idea of our minions,
the yellow minions themselves
being minion-napped
and leading to something involving
this chemical PX-41,
which is obviously something
like a werewolf,
some sort of transformation, Incredible Hulk.
You want to talk about the...
I was just thinking about you telling
about a machine that makes minions.
We had this idea, actually, from the first DM
to explain where these guys came from.
And then we veered away from it,
then for DM 2, I think Eric Guillon,
the designer of the movie,
came up with the idea
that they all came from
the yellows of the eggs.
- Remember that machine?
- Yes.
It was a huge machine that would break
one egg, and then takes just the yellow out
and then makes a minion out of it eventually.
And we dropped that idea, and then...
Because I don't know
if it's unconscious or anything,
but it felt like maybe we were breaking
the mythology of the minions.
We felt we were giving too much information.
Where do they come from?
And the idea was somebody
would take that machine and then...
There, you were gonna mention
those drawings.
Pierre's son did those drawings.
So, the idea that this machine would be taken
and somebody would reprogram it
and create evil minions.
But again, it's like we were talking,
that idea is where it started,
and then it evolved into
what became the narrative driver here,
where we were talking about things,
like Hellboy's Golden Army,
like the desire to create the evil army.
And that became our driver
for villain versus the theft of the moon.
I don't know if you remember
all these drawings that Eric had done.
We were supposed
to come in inside the movie,
Gru was trying to find a job, I think,
and then the minions were actually sent off
to do other work
just because Gru didn't have
any work for them.
So you'd see them
working over at Santa Claus,
working over at
a hamburger stand or whatever.
And you'd see them, a few hundred of them
on a deserted island.
And it's funny to see that,
now in the movie, we've kept...
Yes, we've kept elements 'cause Pierre
and I, some of our early conversations
were like if Gru's not a villain anymore,
where are the minions, what are they doing?
Have they left? Are they there?
You sort of start having these conversations
theoretically about,
what would be fun to see?
And in fact, some of those early sketches,
we see Dr. Nefario showing up trying
to get the minions to come back home.
So that was some early ideas
that we had discussed.
I think, for me, I really like this scene,
'cause I think it defines a lot about parenting.
I think Cinco Paul and Ken Daurio, again,
they did a great job writing the scenes,
establishing the daughter who's growing up
and the one who's still young and innocent.
And then when
we were recording Steve Carell,
he threw in this line, "Never get older."
And for me that just so defined the moment.
It was a great way to end that scene.
Got to be stuff in
the background here, Pierre.
Plenty of back stuff. If you look closely
at the left, guys over there,
the one with the hammer
just hit that other guy.
Then you've got this whole little story
happening in the background left
that's totally independent
of what's happening in the foreground.
We love that, those elements,
just trying to bring it back to life.
Mouth-to-mouth, and then eventually...
We got those all over the place,
we love those.
And I think this scene, the jelly-making,
when I talked to the story artists,
I was thinking of a Warner Bros. cartoon
called Hillbilly Hare,
which is one of my favorites.
And where Bugs Bunny
sings a square dance,
and these guys get caught
in a hay baling machine.
So, originally we had
the whole minion in the jar,
but we got to the point that didn't feel
like that was gonna work,
so we just put his head in there.
And then that was
the one that Pierre was mentioning,
- you see him throughout the movie.
- Yeah.
We should have ended his arc, actually,
break the jar at the very end.
I know, that's true, we didn't.
He is an evil minion, though, he gets that far.
And you recognize him just because
he's got this jar on his head.
That would have been funny.
Someone with a hammer...
But I tried to find a place
where maybe we could hit,
have him get rid of that jar
ultimately at the end
and then have some sort of thing happening,
he gets another thing stuck.
Exactly. Exactly.
So, here is where we find
what Gru is doing now,
as far as his employment.
He's working to convert his lab equipment
to something useful,
in this case building a jelly factory.
Unfortunately, his employees, especially
Dr. Nefario here, aren't very good at it.
So, even though Gru is very hopeful,
Dr. Nefario in this scene
announces he's going to leave.
So, it was just kind of a fun opportunity,
even the stuff we saw as we talked about
the Lucille Ball show, with them
and the grapes with the minions up top
stomping on various fruits, and Pierre
had the idea of the Chiquita banana thing.
So, just a great opportunity to take what
we'd established in the first film
and repurpose it in a kind of a funny way
with the jelly manufacturing.
Bigger lab, more evil,
full dental.
Again, here we see
Dr. Nefario getting ready to leave, so...
And this was kind of a pivotal moment,
'cause we wanted it just a little bit like...
Basically the idea here was, why would Gru
decide to go work for the good guys?
And essentially, it's because his new
business... I should be quiet here, I guess.
Yeah, it's your gag. It's your joke.
That's Chris Renaud's joke.
It's Cinco Paul, actually, who
wrote the original version of that, but...
- But you fought to keep it inside the movie.
- Yes, I fought.
I fought and storyboarded the original
version, so I'm in there somewhere.
Anyway, we needed Gru
to have a reason to accept their offer.
There he goes.
I should point out in that animation,
that wide shot,
you've gotta watch that minion there,
'cause he actually does fart in the last one,
it's the best.
- Twenty-second?
- It's the best.
Yeah, it's probably hard to see on a TV,
but on a movie screen,
it's big enough that you can see it.
So anyway, we needed Gru to really have
everything fail so he'd accept their offer.
So, this is a little like
what we had in the first movie,
where you basically say, "Let's go."
And then, didn't go that far.
If we revisited jokes from the first film,
we tried to do what you just saw,
which is put a new spin on it versus...
It can be tempting to do that, but we really
tried to make this feel like its own movie.
And we didn't really do it
that many times, I think.
Now, that shadow, that actually is Dr. Nefario
who's casting that shadow.
Yeah, 'cause we had debates about it.
You'll see later,
you'll meet a character named El Macho,
but the actual model that's casting
that shadow is Dr. Nefario.
So, here is our first minion-napping,
and we talked about how they should evolve,
'cause this one we wanted
to be very low-tech,
like basically the classic,
somebody getting...
- Knocking at the door.
- Yeah, right, right, right.
Very low, exactly.
And then from there, they sort of
get more and more sophisticated.
- I like the little touch at the end.
- Exactly! Still at work.
Are you sure we should be doing this?
So, coming into this scene,
we wanted to start to establish Gru's
resistance to dating,
and although we saw that
in the flashback earlier,
but sort of the girls
trying to drive it a little bit.
Bruce Willis.
Who else did we have there?
Vin Diesel, I think.
- Vin Diesel, yeah.
- Channing Tatum.
- Channing Tatum, yeah.
- At one point.
Okay, what are you doing?
We're signing you up for online dating!
Coming into this scene, we knew
we wanted Gru to announce to the girls
the fact that he's changing jobs, and he's
gonna be a spy and try to save the world.
Now for the announcement.
I think originally in this scene,
we even had Gru's mom.
- Yeah.
But we felt, for this movie,
it gets tricky with sequels because
there's a lot of characters to service.
So you end up making the decision
where to put your energy,
for lack of a better word.
Because again, we have Lucy in this one,
we have Silas,
and so with all the new characters,
we had to make some decisions
about how to get through these scenes.
Here we go.
- Yeah.
- There's nothing to say about that.
- Indian food, the best.
- That's right.
That's right, listen,
for all the different food types
that are mentioned by the minions.
It's a whole language.
That's a gag that evolved from story.
It's funny how, again, the costumes
were started by a story artist,
a guy named Mark O'Hare at his storyboards.
And then that gag came from animation
and Pierre, where the dress gets caught,
and then it informed the scene before, so...
Again, it's all very evolutionary,
the whole process.
- And sometimes not very linear in that case.
- No, it isn't. Exactly.
They started by doing
that last sequence and then...
So, anyways, coming into this scene,
we tried to think of, where's the place
that Gru would like to work the least?
In a shopping mall, and a cupcake store
just felt like it was completely the opposite
of Gru, all pink and...
And so that's where
we set them up for surveillance.
And here he's surprised to find out
that he's being paired with Lucy.
That's the kind of thing that Kristen Wiig
would just throw in, and you just can't help
but love that kind of contrast in a character
and performance, both vocal and animated.
I'll let you get it.
Well, that's typically
the case where the contrast
actually helps the animation
just because you can enhance it,
so it becomes visual.
And this is a funny line from the guys,
from the writers,
and then Kristen took it
just singing that last part,
just really again informed what we could do,
and right there she dances offstage.
It seems that
because of your checkered past,
everyone else refused to work with you.
I love that little moment
that's about to come up.
Yes.
Yeah, this was something that...
I think we actually had it...
We have a little bit of it with Agnes later,
but remember we actually were gonna do
direct call backs to this fantasy
with Agnes and Gru.
Exactly, and this guy, Dave, was supposed to
- be in love with Lucy throughout the movie.
- Yes.
Yeah, we had that little moment
where he's giving her a rose.
Anyway, so what happened was, again,
it was a funny idea,
when Lucy first sees her...
I'm sorry, when Agnes first sees her,
she has a fantasy moment,
and then Gru towards the end of the movie
also has a fantasy moment.
The problem was that
Dave's was just the best,
so they didn't feel like an escalation,
so we sort of left...
Although we do have a little hint of it
when Agnes first meets Lucy later in the film.
We just kept it to Dave.
There's Pierre's
heart-shaped firework right there.
Earth to Dave!
That's one of my favorite shots
right there, personally.
So, we get into the surveillance
of the different...
And we had to sort of set up
what characters could...
We had this idea one time, remember?
Like a rogue's gallery in the mall.
- Literally like...
- Everyone was a bad guy.
Everyone sort of looked like a bad guy.
So, it was, again,
just a rogue's gallery of villains,
that each one ran a mall store.
But it just felt a little too unreal,
so we went the direction of Gru's dismissive,
until this guy walks in,
Eduardo, played by Benjamin Bratt.
A very gregarious guy, a restaurateur,
who comes and welcomes
Gru and Lucy to the mall.
And we see his necklace there,
which is an abstract "E" for Eduardo.
Which becomes important later
when it gets rotated.
90 degrees and becomes an "M,"
like El Macho.
It's very, very important.
Yes, a tiny detail.
That gag.
We had a couple of versions of that one.
And the best one was actually
when it was on the belly,
but some people wouldn't allow us to do it.
So, this guy, we were thinking,
he's so much similar to Gru
in a lot of ways in that
he's maybe retired from villainy,
we'll find out later that he's also a father.
But in this moment,
Gru thinks he recognizes him
as being a villain
from the past named El Macho.
That guy looks exactly like...
And in fact, it's funny
when we started with Eduardo,
he kind of looked like El Macho.
He looked like this, big and strong,
and we kind of realized, as much
as we liked the look of the character,
it sort of stretched believability
that he'd look basically exactly the same,
but with shorter hair
and nobody would recognize him,
so we really went the route
that he's a guy past his prime,
obviously made him fatter,
almost appearing shorter in a lot of ways.
In fact, we had to work that out.
Yeah, he's probably a bit of a cheat there.
And so, beyond the costume,
we really changed him physically
to sell the idea
that you may not recognize him.
It feels like we're killing a lot of animals
in this movie.
- We just killed a bird, now a shark.
- Yeah. That's true.
Comedically, though, comedically.
Always with love.
- We kill people with a smile.
- That's right.
That was a very Warner Bros. moment.
- Completely silly.
- Over the top.
Looney Tunes, I should say, I guess.
...was a pile of singed chest hair.
But that face! It has got to be El Macho!
I remember when we did this,
we restructured this scene a bit,
and it actually worked really nicely
where we end it
on Gru really being determined
to follow through on his conviction.
And originally we had
a nose-picking joke there, but a butt scratch.
- Which I think is better, actually.
- I think it is better.
It's weird, though,
that we would get criticized
for a nose pick and not an ass scratch.
I don't know.
I guess there's something slightly less gross.
It is weird, though.
But you said you'd help me practice...
This is one of those moments for me.
I love the way
Gru actually throws Edith into bed.
And even his reaction here.
What I like about it is it feels very real.
You know what I mean?
You're trying to get the kids to bed,
somebody's like, "I got to practice this."
You're like, "Come on," versus
sort of maybe more happy about it.
That was something else.
Yeah. What's great about Gru is that
even when he pretends, he can't.
Yeah. Exactly. He's very authentic.
Okay.
And that was one.
We played with different versions of the line.
But truthfully, Carell just made it so funny.
"Zombie." It just really works.
Okay, so how do we set up everybody?
Here, we were playing with the idea
of Agnes missing the fact that she has a mom
without making Gru feel bad.
That was the tricky balance,
that she just felt a little left out
because she was unsure about participating
in this Mother's Day program at school.
So Gru gives her a little bit of a pep talk here.
- Now we break the emotional moment.
- Completely!
A little of the evolution on this.
Originally, we'd started with just a handful
of minions at the bar downstairs.
Gru comes in, and they're having ice cream,
and it's a very sort of quiet moment,
he gets them
to accompany him on his mission.
- But...
- But... Take it from there, Pierre.
But I just didn't want to have
another small scene with the minions.
We found this song existing,
it's called Yet Another Irish Drinking Song,
- I think from Da Vinci's Notebook.
- Yeah.
Little group. I love this song.
So we thought it could be hilarious
having those guys, instead of drinking
obviously, having ice cream,
singing that drinking song.
We really play it that way,
even with their heads underneath the taps.
- Yeah.
- Just have fun with it.
- Everybody's half sick in the background.
- That's right.
- That's you singing. Wait, wait.
- There I am.
- And that's me.
- Actually, believe it or not, that's still me.
- It is?
- Yeah. I re-sang your part.
Damn you!
That's a source of constant battling.
It's the only thing that we battle on.
I've lost consistently.
So, here's our second minion-nap,
which we played with making it feel
like a UFO abduction.
Also... I'm sorry. Go ahead.
I want to say this is the first scene
that actually went into animation
before the other one.
I think it is.
One thing we quickly discovered with the
minions is that it's hard to tell them apart.
- So, in this movie, it was more...
- Central?
It was also important
to track certain minions.
So the costuming
became the way we did that.
And Kevin here, to the right,
dressed as a golfer,
he's kind of the minion,
along with the French maid and one later,
that we tracked through the little subplot.
He's the first one that's going
to get transformed, I think, right?
He's the second. The French maid is first
and then he's second.
Then the French maid
is the last one transformed back.
So, the costumes became a way for us to
track them individually when we needed to.
Those guys are singing
the drinking song again.
So, here's Gru and Lucy
looking to break into Eduardo's place
to hopefully find some evidence
that he is indeed El Macho.
Funny thing about this, that floor
is actually not even half a meter thick.
It's actually a second story.
So they're basically
dangling down the floor below them.
Yeah. You can see their legs hanging down.
Everything is full of cheats.
It's like this, the little cord
Gru is going to trip that isn't here.
- Obviously, because...
- They'd see it.
Yeah, if you can see it, it wouldn't be fun.
And all of a sudden,
it appears when he trips over it.
There are no booby traps.
Booby!
We're laughing right now, but it feels like
everybody's going to notice that.
But it seemed funny to have a low tech way
to summon this...
Do you want to talk about the chicken?
Why the chicken?
Well, the chicken started
with the design of the restaurant,
because we had actual chickens
in the restaurant.
- Do you remember when we started doing it?
- Yeah.
It sort of evolved from there.
I think it was Pierre who said, "Hey, what if
he had a pet chicken, Eduardo?"
So, we had live chickens
walking around the restaurant,
we thought, "Well, why not have one of them
be an actual guard dog? Yeah."
The scene was originally written
with a Chihuahua.
It just felt like we started investigating
in design and in animation this chicken.
I essentially called the two storyboard artists
and said, "Hey, what if we made that
Chihuahua a chicken? What could we do?"
We talked about some ideas
and this stuff with the alien homage.
Even where the chicken is on Gru's head
came from the storyboard artists
as we were developing the scene.
Okay, let's go.
There's some chicken scratches
on Gru's face that we never...
- That disappear.
- Yeah, they're gone.
- We use the Daffy Duck rules of cartoon.
- Yeah. We hide behind those a lot.
One thing we did with Lucy is
we wanted her to have just a lot of
cool technology, actually, and cool gadgets.
So, she had that whatever that is,
that's almost like a Spider-Man web-shooter.
The resin thing
that the chicken was encased in,
and then these goggles
that are X-ray goggles.
We wanted her to really feel like...
One of the fun things we always liked
about the Bond films were...
- The gadgets.
- The gadgets. Exactly.
But Gru, not to be outdone,
has this safe cracker here.
By the way, do you believe, like me,
that each time a new James Bond came out,
it got usually trashed
just because it had too much gadgets in it?
- Yeah.
- But I always thought, "Oh, man! It's cool!"
I know. I miss the gadgets.
'Cause now it seems like we went
in the opposite way, there are no gadgets.
Yeah. That's true.
So, Eduardo returns back to the restaurant
a bit early.
This scene we played with
a few different ways
to try to find the way
to create the most amount of tension.
So, we played with it editorially a few ways.
That was an idea from Janet Healy.
She threw it out in an editorial session.
One of our producers.
And it really worked.
So, again, from the way these things evolve,
ideas come from a lot of different places.
My eyes!
Gru, call one of your munchkins!
"Call one of your munchkins!"
- Where did that come from?
- I can't remember.
I think somebody wrote it,
but I don't remember who.
I actually don't remember.
So, anyway, thinking of
one of our inspirations
here was The Blues Brothers, actually.
Thinking, "Okay, what would the minions do
if they were called to come get us?"
We thought, "Well, you know what?
They'd drive right into the mall."
So that's what we played.
We played with the multiple levels.
Thank goodness
for Lucy's car being so small.
It really allowed us a lot of freedom.
There was a time that this scene
was much longer. Too long, one would say.
But sometimes
when we're putting these things together,
we're thinking, "Do we need more action?
Do we need more comedy?"
We're trying to find that balance.
We had a whole scene...
- I love this moment right here.
- Yeah.
We had a whole scene where El Macho
pursued them on a motorcycle.
- Shot the chicken at them.
- Yeah. I liked that, actually.
There was a narrative problem though,
is that El Macho couldn't recognize them.
It felt difficult given this long involved chase
that he wouldn't know who he was following.
So, that and for pacing reasons, we scaled it
way back. But it's still a lot of fun.
Love that sequence.
In this one, basically we needed an idea
to make it feel like a lot of minions were
being taken versus one and two at a time,
just to create the escalation.
This is the last beat where we see
the minions being kidnapped, right?
Exactly.
So, we had basically the ice cream truck,
was the thought,
queuing off their love
of ice cream from that song,
a moment we saw earlier.
It's actually Dr. Nefario
who's animated driving the truck,
even though you can't see him in there
with the blacked-out windows.
And watch out there,
you got a little Platoon moment
where this big guy
is trying to sacrifice himself.
There is the jar-headed minion.
So here we wound up
settling for the last minion.
I mentioned to
our storyboard artist, Didier,
to have a little hand come down,
and then Pierre said,
"Why doesn't he get his tongue stuck?"
And boom!
And that's how we ended the scene.
Which we'll see that minion again later
with the ice cream stuck to his tongue.
Again, that's how we identified him.
See if you can get closer.
So this is a character, Floyd Eaglesan,
played by Ken Jeong, and did a great job.
I can't remember who he'd said.
One of his relatives was who he
was thinking of for a little bit for this voice.
And there was a time when we had
a bit more of the character in the film,
'cause we were...
Again, we were trying
to set up multiple threats, who could it be
that committed this crime
that we saw at the beginning of the movie?
But again, we got to the point
where we just had to reduce it
and keep it more focused
on Gru's relationship with Lucy
and the coming rivalry with Eduardo.
I remember Floyd Eaglesan
used to have this magnet
- for Gru to make the hair grow.
- That's right.
Gru went to get a baldness treatment.
Yeah, the magnets...
One of the reasons they suspected him
is because he used magnets
to try to pull hair out of your scalp.
- Anyway... That's right.
- It's true.
So there you see Agnes,
that's her little fantasy moment.
We simplified it greatly, but still it really
serves its purpose nicely,
where we see how she instantly connects.
I love that little animation moment
where she waves to Lucy.
She instantly connects to her
and sees her as a good match for Gru.
Are you out of your gourd?
And then goes into the classic
Gru and Lucy sitting in a tree,
K-I-S-S-I-N-G, or a version of that, anyway.
Stop. This is a song of lies.
And I will be the flower girl!
I don't even like her. Now, go have fun!
And also, a moment like this is important
because it gives our character Lucy
an opportunity
to see a bit softer side of Gru.
And so you try to find these moments
so you can build some kind of affinity
between the two characters,
so when eventually they get together,
it feels a bit earned.
I love this line.
I am pretty fun.
Every dad would like to say that, I guess.
- That scene evolved a lot also.
- Yes, it did.
We had many versions of this.
Trying different ideas, like what's
the best version of a coin fountain gag?
How do we find the girls after they left Gru?
So, this is another character Antonio,
who we find out in a bit
is actually Eduardo's son.
But Margo doesn't care,
this is a budding crush on her behalf.
And it's a nice moment for Miranda,
Miranda Cosgrove who plays Margo,
to have some fun with this character.
And I love it, too, because it's such
a great thing for Gru as a dad to react to
and be totally thrown off by.
I was just going to get a cookie.
Care to join me?
Sure.
I'm Margo.
And then, the next moment,
you get an opportunity
to see how the other girls react to this,
where Edith wants nothing to do with it,
and a concerned Agnes.
Kind of a little thing there are the coins.
We animate the movie,
create the picture entirely in France,
and a lot of those coins, some of them
are silver and look like US money.
A lot of them are gold and look like the euro.
There's always little details like that.
So it feels like everywhere and nowhere,
although they're small, I guess.
We sort of based the mall actually
on the mall in Santa Monica, a little bit.
It doesn't have an enclosed ceiling,
but is in the round like that.
Welcome to Eagle Hair Club.
It's about time you showed up.
- Little James Bond reference there.
- Yes.
There's a little Ernst Blofeld,
except it's a toupee in this case.
When someone moves into the mall
who is folically-challenged...
And that eagle was thrown out there
by one of our board artists, Matt Nealon,
and we just thought it was funny,
so we built it.
- But it doesn't make any sense.
- No, it doesn't.
And we never see it again.
But sometimes those little details
make all the difference.
- Okay.
- With this scene,
one of our board artists, Didier,
we were trying to...
It was written in the script that
the sensor was on Gru's belt buckle.
So, he came to me with this idea of
how does... Basically, what you see here,
maybe not quite, maybe his version
was more graphic, actually.
But it's a funny idea based off
of this thing that's on Gru's belt buckle,
how would he use that,
and so this very physical comedy scene
grew out of something that was
just a description in the script.
So it reminds me of a lot of things
that Peter Sellers would do.
- Like John Cleese with the funny walk.
- Yes, yes.
- Or Mr. Bean.
- Mr. Bean, totally.
Those are our ultimate references.
And that's the great thing
that comes out of animation
is, again, it's this evolution of ideas.
And suddenly you've got something
that feels very fun.
So, Gru is heading off to see if he can find
Margo.
And he ends up seeing
that she is heading into
the restaurant with Antonio.
And again, this was the moment
where we wanted to,
this whole scene, in fact...
How would Gru react to his beloved daughter
dating a boy who we're sure he thinks
is not good enough for her?
So, for some reason,
they have cookies in a Mexican restaurant,
but that's... I suppose that's possible.
I don't know.
Margo.
We basically...
I forget where this line came from,
but we always really liked it,
sort of Gru's reaction.
"Me llama-lama ding-dong."
And then here's a chance to see...
This was, I think, one of the first boarded
scenes, might have been the second
of Eduardo, and dancing.
And it was just so great.
In fact, what we were talking before
about how Eduardo used
to look very big and muscular,
that was it, he was boarded that way.
But it was so much fun,
even when he got short and fat, we kept it.
It is weird that all these women would like...
Remember when we had
a man here for the third beat?
That would have been so good.
This is some great work from
some of the boarding, great animation, too,
from Eric Favela.
I think in our eyes, in a lot of ways,
it's a great way to reintroduce the character.
There's a lot of dancing in the movie,
you'll see.
- It's very musical, actually.
- Yeah, a lot of music and dancing,
which I think honestly is, for us,
a part of the appeal.
We really like doing the music-based scenes.
Look at you.
We try not to be serious about it,
that's why we...
- Yes.
- We like them.
I'm sorry. Pollito is usually very friendly.
So, yeah.
In animation, one of the things that we tried
was that the chicken
always felt like a chicken.
Except in that one moment
where he squints his eyes.
Again, it's a question of contrast.
We could have gone the easy route
and made him like a cartoon character,
but we thought the comedy
would come more out of the fact
that it's a real chicken than a comical one.
An anthropomorphized chicken.
And also the animation team,
I think Pierre is probably remembering
his own days of youth,
Antonio always is animated
with his mouth hanging open.
- That's the way I see teens.
- That's right.
So using that scene, it became a great way
in that last moment with Gru
to power into this scene where Gru now
is convinced more than ever
that Eduardo is El Macho.
But the funny part, and this was
where Steve Carell...
This is one of the first scenes
we animated, as well.
And his vocal performance in this,
I would just say I think
he really understood the moment.
Because this actually became our bar.
You know what I mean?
Just for Gru's character,
'cause he did such a great job in here,
where he just won't let go of the fact
that they should arrest the son.
Do you remember Chris Meledandri saying
that this was "the scene" of the movie,
just like the sleepy kitten
was "the scene" of the first movie?
It was character defining,
it was story defining.
It had everything in there.
- It had character and story...
- Intertwined.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, yeah.
Gru discovered traces of the serum
at Eagle Hair Club!
Interesting.
Unfortunately for Gru, though in Silas' eyes,
the fact that he's now connecting Eduardo
to his son undermines his case.
We wanted Gru leaving this scene
more determined than ever
to prove his hunch right.
Do you remember... I was gonna say...
We had another scene, actually,
with Silas that was on the submarine,
but we found that we just didn't need it.
It became more... You find that a lot.
Sometimes you think you need
more information than you do.
So, this is a scene I was inspired...
I was inspired...
Basically, we had a few things,
there were these sketches that Pierre
was mentioning before with Eric Guillon
with the minions at the beach,
that's right, but The Truman Show
and Happy Feet, where the penguin
wakes up in an enclosure
but he doesn't know he's in an enclosure.
We set up the way
we had this great beach scene.
We're like, "Good. Let's use it."
So we made that their...
And this is actually inspired by Jaws,
it's hard to believe.
- But...
- Butt, what?
No, when I pitched it to the board artist,
I said, "Ripping his clothes off
"like Jaws and running into the ocean."
Nobody gets eaten by a shark,
but the shots are similar.
Then we see that they're actually imprisoned.
And that's Dr. Nefario once again.
So, again, we were able to take some ideas
that really had nothing to do with that
moment and use them in a fun way.
This little moment, I'd say this is based
on my apartment right here.
Because my Wi-Fi always goes out.
Anyway, we had to create a moment where
Gru noticed that the minions are missing.
We didn't want to make too much of it
because we didn't want...
We felt if he notices minions are missing...
- He would do something about it.
- Exactly.
So, we make it a vacation joke.
But in a way, it kind of did its job.
I've got good news!
I have my friend Shannon here with me.
This is a scene also that was much longer
and was more about information.
But then we started talking
about a simplification,
Gru just basically
wanting to get out of the date
and using Agnes as somebody
who's misinterpreting his hand signals.
And we had a couple we didn't use,
jazz hands was one.
'Cause I was the only one
that was advocating jazz hands,
and I think the way the writers wrote it,
and the way it evolved in performance...
It really was a very funny
relatable moment for any parent
trying to use their kids as an excuse.
Particularly to arrive to this moment here.
And so, this is a bit of a tricky moment.
The wig!
We debated many times how to get into that.
And so we use Kyle, the dog,
to remind us about that trial wig
from the other scene,
'cause we wanted to lead right there
where she says phony,
and we see him wearing this toupee.
Well...
It serves two purposes.
It shows Gru's
lack of confidence in this situation,
the fact that he would even do this.
The more important was,
we needed, in a little bit later, you'll see...
Here you go.
You'll see that Lucy comes to Gru's defense
right here in a couple of moments.
And we really needed that to turn Gru's...
- Perception of Lucy?
- Perception of Lucy, exactly.
And I think in animation,
although we had stuff in boards,
the exercising in the restaurant
actually became much, much stronger
once it went to animation.
'Cause sometimes when you're in boards,
like, "God, is this gonna work?"
But you don't take into account
that next evolution. You know what I mean?
So, sometimes it can be,
even for us, difficult to sort of say...
You're like, "Well, it feels like it's right."
And then you take it to the next step
and then you're like, "Okay."
Well, that's the thing, right?
The way we work is that Chris,
you take care of storyboard
and mainly script discussions
and stuff like that, right?
- Yeah.
- And I take care of animation.
We focus each other
on our particular strength,
meaning that when Chris is happy
on the storyboard,
then we try to plus it, basically.
And so, it's fun, actually having that
canvas of a thing to start with and ends...
- Ideas come out of that simple situation.
- And even sometimes ideas,
'cause I think in this case,
they'd even started when
we were having discussions in rough layout.
And I was even thinking later in the movie,
sometimes we'll sort of ape an idea in
rough layout and then that could be helpful.
Although poor rough layout,
that can be a rough phase for the movie,
because it's sort of not storyboards
and not animation,
so it can be tough to visualize.
Shall we take her home?
From here, I can't remember
what was here before,
but I remember our conversation
and I think that it was Cinco Paul
that first mentioned this idea.
Where were we? Weekend at Bernie's.
A little bit.
But there was something here before that
I can't quite remember that just didn't work.
You know what we find
when we develop the movie,
there's a couple of cases,
is that we need an idea,
a comedic idea that drives it.
It can't just be, "It's serving a story point."
Orit's, "We have to get this information out."
And so, once we knew,
obviously we needed Lucy
to come to Gru's defense,
but once it became about taking
this unconscious woman home,
it suddenly became something more
and funnier and really had an idea behind it.
Very often when we start, it's very basic,
"Okay, we need to deliver this information."
And then when we go into our reviews
with Chris Meledandri
and the writers, then it's like,
"Well, okay, we got the information across,
but how do we make it good?"
So that becomes the discussion
and we all chip in to,
or pitch in to evolve those sequences.
This was fun.
Yes. Surprisingly, it was.
There's this thing of the debate
about the kiss.
To kiss or not to kiss.
But that used to not be in, and now it is in,
and I think it's really good.
- I do.
- Yeah.
I remember, sometimes we...
And we worked very hard
to avoid the cliché, I'll say,
but sometimes the cliché is what works,
and I think in the case here,
we weren't quite feeling the connection,
and I remember even having
a discussion at editorial,
if you really want to feel the connection,
a little kiss on the cheek,
and I think somebody,
I can't remember,
I know it came from another place, too.
And then that again informs the process.
I just want to mention quickly,
Pharrell Williams,
who wrote some terrific songs,
this, I think, is my favorite.
And we knew we wanted Gru after that
little kiss to be happy, essentially,
and Pharrell really quite literally wrote that.
But it's great, it's such a nice moment.
This is "the shot."
I want to say to everyone
that we're sorry for the...
- Sorry for that transition?
- Yeah.
We thought it would be better.
It just defines how Gru feels at this moment,
and it's such a nice contrast, so you think
of the first movie when it's Despicable Me,
and he spends the whole time
walking with his hands behind his back.
- Little animation moment here.
- Yeah, great moment there.
And she keeps going.
Originally, we had the classic,
this is where it was good to go
beyond the cliché
where he was twirling a woman
and he dropped her.
Got who?
Floyd Eaglesan!
Our agents located a secret room...
So, this is where
we sort of set up the idea that
Gru's mission's over, basically,
and he and Lucy are going to separate.
You start to get the couple together
and then,
through circumstances beyond their control,
they have to separate.
- It's the end of the second act, usually, right?
- Exactly. Exactly.
Floyd Eaglesan there
has been framed by we know not who.
But in the eyes of the Anti-Villain League,
the case is closed,
so they're gonna send Lucy off to Australia.
Yes.
But thank you for everything.
I think it's a nice moment narratively
where Gru is so happy just a moment ago,
and then it all comes crashing down
as he learns that she's gonna leave.
This is the thing we have coming up here,
is Lucy's lipstick taser, which, again,
you find these elements
that you can track through the movie,
which are very helpful.
When the lipstick taser started,
it was really just a gadget at the beginning.
And then we used it here
as a memento of the first time they met,
and then it sort of tracks
through the movie from there.
It becomes what Gru looks at when he's sad.
And actually, we even used it
in the third act action.
So, it's always cool when you sort of like,
"Wait, we've got this piece
and how can we use it more effectively?"
Thank you, Lucy.
Agent Wilde.
And both actors here did a great job.
'Cause I remember we talked at one point
about re-writing the dialogue,
but actually, it was more
about how the dialogue was performed,
and it wasn't about what they were saying
but how they were saying it.
And they both did a terrific job.
This, we thought, was very cool.
Like having that happy moment
and then mirror that happy moment with...
- But his change of mind, basically.
- Yeah.
Feels like the old Gru, actually.
Maybe a little meaner than the old Gru,
I'm not sure.
So, this again,
this is another one of those scenes
that evolved in many, many different ways,
and again, certainly
from the versions we discussed,
this was absolutely the strongest,
and it became a nice little moment
between Gru and Agnes.
Agnes is such a great character, as played
by Elsie Fisher, to balance against Gru.
I mean, she's a pure innocent. She's a child.
The scenes between her and Gru are, I think,
a great thing for particularly Gru's character.
And we try, obviously, in animation also,
not to push those moments
where they feel tacky or overly emotional,
just because the situation and the words
are actually carrying the heavy weight.
To quickly mention, also,
Yarrow Cheney and the lighting team.
I think the lighting in that scene
really was quite beautiful.
Very cheated, but excellent.
...and you're leaving for Australia
and all, but...
This, I think for Pierre and I,
is one of our favorite scenes.
- And it's...
- No.
- How dare you.
- No. It's good.
Just because it's so weird.
- Just this shot is weird.
- Yeah.
Remember we debated that joke
over and over, how to play that joke?
It makes no sense, that joke,
but I don't know why,
at the end of the day, we felt it worked.
- We used to have a jury in there, didn't we?
- Yeah. There were numbers.
Then it was,
"He wouldn't be holding the phone
"because that's not how you would do it."
You remember all those conversations?
One nice thing here,
we got some great boards,
but also it was very nicely edited
by Greg Perler.
And I think that, in a lot of ways,
there was potential,
just because of the music.
Like using this phone
as the object of his discontent.
And then, you know...
Who came up with that idea
of the firemen arriving?
- Matt Nealon. Yeah.
- The boarder.
So, just having them play...
Actually, you know what? I'm not sure.
He came up with the way it is.
But it might have been mentioned
in the script. I don't remember, to be honest.
I have to do this.
All the "beados" were done by Chris.
The scream was Pierre.
So, then we're back to the beach.
- With Kevin.
- That's right.
They were drinking alcohol at one point.
Remember we had to do an alcohol pass and
cut down how many drink references we had.
So, they were eating bananas,
which is probably truer to form.
So, this is when we first get an opportunity
to see what exactly is going on
with these minion-nappings.
I love that.
That's one of my favorite vocals right there.
So, then we see the French maid,
who was the first minion taken.
We get to see what the PX-41 actually does.
With the evil minions,
we talked about several things, but we knew
that we wanted them to be a different color.
Because things that are different colors
always seem to be appealing.
So, we had some sketches from Eric.
I think some of them had black hair,
and then Yarrow did some with purple hair.
We're like, "Okay, that's it."
We did a couple of things
like lengthen their arms, their teeth.
They have an undercut jaw.
We even, at one point,
talked about one version having three eyes,
but we ended up not doing that,
just felt too far off the mark.
So, just sort of making them feel like
a werewolf version of our regular minions.
Edith, try not to kill anyone.
Margo!
Hello, Mr. Gru.
Okay.
I love this kind of a gag where a character
can seemingly move, defy actual physics.
- What do you mean? Like here?
- Yeah.
"Wait. What?"
You are a funny man.
There are no rules, señor. It's Cinco de Mayo.
And just expressing Gru's frustration.
Should I mention this next moment?
Yeah. This moment came from
an animation test that Christophe Delisle,
one of our greatest animators,
that Mac Guff did.
And that moment had to last just about
a minute long, I think, or something like that.
Basically what you see
is the structure of what he did.
- A little bit shorter.
- Yeah, we had it longer,
but actually ended up
going back to the original animation test.
One thing about the animation test,
to talk about process,
is with Antonio's character,
we were trying different things.
And in truth, that animation test
informed who he became.
Someone who would defy Gru.
This is Matt Nealon again. Chip hat.
We ended up realizing
that he couldn't be too nice.
It made it difficult
to let Gru really cut loose on him.
We didn't want him to be sympathetic,
I guess, at the end of the day.
But we did try that at the beginning.
He was more of a romantic.
This is an example, I think, where
the storyboarding process in concert
with the script really is great and very cool.
Because this was really
these two characters talking,
and our board artist
pitched out this idea of a chip hat,
which doesn't exist, but feels like it could,
if you know what I mean.
And instantly the conversation has, again,
each scene, each moment needing an idea.
It needs something more
than just the words that are being spoken.
And this used to be the place, also,
where the whole rhythm sort of fell down.
- Yes.
- We used to give a lot of explanation
- as to what El Macho was after.
- That's right.
The reason why he became evil, and
we cut that all out just because of rhythm.
'Cause it was really a place where
we were starting to get bored a little bit.
Yeah, that's the danger.
You have to balance, again, the amount
of information the audience needs
versus the entertainment.
You don't want anyone lost, but you also
don't want to bog them down in exposition.
So it's a discovery process.
It's funny, because as talky as it was before,
this particular sequence
that we're seeing right now didn't exist.
Yeah. We sort of got to a place where, "Gosh,
we need something that pushes the mystery,
"is a little bit action-driven, not big."
We started talking about ways
for Gru to follow Eduardo down to his lab.
This is obviously heavily inspired
by Raiders of the Lost Ark, the first one.
I always forget the name
of that video game. Dance Dance?
It's the one
where you jump on the colored tiles,
and also Billie Jean,
the Michael Jackson video.
So we thought we'd combine those elements
along with a musical cue
to get Gru down into El Macho's laboratory.
Here, again, this scene,
we knew we wanted Lucy missing Gru,
but how could we have fun with that?
So we started playing with the idea
of her seeing him everywhere.
It was your idea.
I remember you pitching it out in editorial.
I don't know.
I try to remember how these things evolve.
I can tell you, I was there.
I wasn't saying a word,
then you came up with that.
I thought, "Damn, how does he do that?"
It's really good.
We had her looking around.
We recorded Steve Carell saying,
"I just did a boom boom,"
I'm still laughing thinking about it,
for another scene, actually.
He was an adult Gru disguised as a baby
doing the mall surveillance.
Greg remembered it, and pitched it slightly,
and put it as the button to this scene,
and it made all the difference.
We had the baby. I think
when the guys wrote it, the baby was there.
And we went from...
Using that little bit
that we remembered from Carell
created a nice button on the scene.
I'm not sure you're going to be able
to see that sequence in the plane.
Yeah. That's right. It's a little scary.
We had to figure out a way
how to get those off of Gru's face.
So that was what we came up with.
From a set design point of view, we were
really thinking of Raiders of the Lost Ark.
Even the Last Crusade, that long bridge
that Indiana Jones has to cross.
Basically, we wanted it to be
a distinct underground laboratory,
knowing that Gru has his own
that's covered in steel.
So, this one being carved from rock
felt like a Mayan temple or something.
It felt like a nice contrast.
More warm in its tones.
Dr. Nefario?
So, this was our big reveal.
Now we know where Nefario went.
Although, my son did notice
that it was Nefario.
We didn't fool him! That's not good.
- No. He's only eight, right, is he? Is he nine?
- I think he's two.
All right. So, here's Kevin again,
you can see his golf hat.
And we wanted to do
this demonstration scene, basically,
that would really, in structure...
What do we say?
A little like the animation of Bill Plympton.
Totally Bill Plympton. Yes.
Pierre and I both,
particularly for these movies,
what we call sort of a graphic presentation
for particularly cartoon comedy.
It's very presentational, straight on.
It just always plays funnier that way.
It feels like that scene in Time Bandits.
But I remember Pierre was looking for
what could the minions be in
that would feel unique.
And so these cages came about
from a sketch from Eric.
And very graphic, too, just because
you could use those cages
to help you frame the shot a little bit better.
Their city gets eaten!
Why don't they eat out of the cages?
I never figured that out.
- Some gray kryptonite.
- That's right.
Great performance by Benjamin Bratt here.
And you can see now his necklace is an "M."
So, yeah. See.
We would be unstoppable!
Every detail has been given
months and months of thought.
There's no mistake in this movie.
- That's right.
- Not one.
I love that popper.
Again, I think that was originally
a bottle of champagne. We got rid of it.
I just need to get some things off my plate
before we start taking over the world,
that's all.
- Again, a great performance.
- Yeah.
One hundred percent! I am in!
Yeah, I mean, this is a nice moment
from the writers and then augmented
by the animation.
And then we did do, again,
some work to find the perfect length,
for lack of a better word,
and I think it works nicely.
And then where El Macho still thinks
that maybe Gru isn't being entirely truthful.
This, I love. This is like AI Capone in...
- The Untouchables.
They should have made those confetti red.
I know, that's right. The confetti.
So, this was again another
one of those moments
that we tried many versions of,
including Margo almost having
her first kiss. Or actually having?
I think almost, we never, with Antonio.
But again, it wasn't helping us.
And it made Gru seem a little too mean.
So we brought back the chip hat.
For anyone who is lonely, they get a chip hat.
And then gave Gru a nice moment
to freeze this Antonio guy.
- And to become Gru again.
- That's right.
Who's not too nice a guy.
Short, sweet and really
solved the narrative issue nicely.
That is one hand glider, boy, I don't know...
I don't know if you've noticed,
we've just totally cheated the time of day,
'cause when Lucy was on the plane,
it was during the day,
and then she shows up there, it's night.
We figured she's halfway on her way
to Australia, so it's a different time zone.
That was our theory.
Pollito, what's the matter?
Hey, Eduardo!
Lucia, I apologize.
Pollito, he's usually not like this.
Well, we didn't know
how to show the chicken
just because he had to hold that bag
and not bring attention to himself,
so we left it like...
Literally just facing
the wrong way the whole time.
Yeah, so there was, I remember...
Gosh, where was that used?
Anyway, I can't remember,
but I remember another character
holding a chicken reversed like that.
- He's still reversed.
- Of course.
He's about to reveal
something very important.
For instance, he never mentioned
that you were both working
for the Anti-Villain League!
So this is the moment where we put Lucy
in jeopardy, kind of start driving.
There is Nefario.
There's no reason for Gru to arrive
with such violence.
He's not sure,
he's suspicious something bad is coming.
...knew it was him all along,
so if anyone's cool, it's me!
I feel like this moment
went through some changes.
I remember when we talked about,
when it was in layout,
we talked about the minions
playing video games, which was funny.
'Cause we were talking like,
"What would kids be doing?"
Which is how we often talk
about the minions,
like, "What would children be doing?"
'Cause that's sort of their attitude
about a lot of things.
Nefario?
Sorry, gotta go!
He's got Lucy?
And then this is what gets Gru
going into his Gru cycle.
Which we're certainly
gonna use in the next movie.
Again, the fun of this, really,
when creating a sequel
is always trying to create something
new and different
that you haven't experienced before,
so we thought it would be cool.
And also that little house
was always on the lawn,
so it felt neat to say that that little house,
the little girl's dollhouse,
not dollhouse, but playhouse,
serves a purpose.
It's covering that little ramp
for that motorcycle.
So, we really wanted this
to be a sense of grandeur
and sort of frankly like Darth Vader
assembling his troops.
All the rockets have
a different city painted on them.
There's Paris and New York.
The one you're about to see is our joke on
Hoboken, which I lived in for several years.
That's a city? I always wondered.
Yeah, it's actually a city in New Jersey.
But we've got Tokyo and Beijing.
So, that's his plan coming to fruition.
He's about to launch
the minions all over the globe.
- We spent a lot of time on this shot.
- Yes, we did.
Just because of the reflections,
we didn't know how the shadows were,
if the shadows were gonna be well-placed.
How much of the limbs we should see
from that evil minion?
So all that had to be dosed.
One of our big influences,
actually, were video games,
like first-person shooters.
Seeing the limbs a bit, but playing with that
particularly because it's in 3D.
What was that?
So this is the moment, actually, which
is probably the scariest in the movie,
and we designed it that way.
'Cause we wanted the evil minions
to be not really evil,
but they did have to be
a bit of a threat in some moments.
So this is really
where they are the most threatening.
Obviously, 'cause partly because
it's the girls that are in danger,
and it's more intimate 'cause it's one-on-one.
This is something that the writers threw in,
which was great,
which is Agnes having this superpower.
And it was a great moment.
'Cause how do we get
these little kids away from this guy?
So, his glasses break, and then he's blinded
and can't see where he's going.
So they go down, this is where we find...
'Cause we had a lot of discussions,
where is Edith?
'Cause there was a time
when Edith accompanied Gru.
- Remember she snuck away?
- That's right, yeah.
She snuck away with Gru
to help him try to rescue Lucy.
So, when we got rid of that idea,
we needed, "Okay, where's Edith gonna be?"
So we put her downstairs playing Ping-Pong.
- With nunchucks.
It's a Bruce Lee reference.
You notice there that the minion
is now wearing black overalls,
'cause El Macho changed them.
He's got a little "M" on him.
And then Nefario has returned
with a rather convenient antidote.
We went back and forth on this.
I believe the idea was originally pitched
by Eric Guillon a long time ago
about the jelly.
Whether the jelly itself was the antidote
or do you put the antidote in it?
So we ended up putting the antidote in it,
which is what made the most sense.
This third act evolved quite a bit over time,
and the idea started with the writers.
I always think of it as the Death Star moment
with Han and Luke dressed as Stormtroopers
taking Chewbacca into the detention center.
Anyways, so painting our yellow guys purple
felt like a great idea.
Comedically, it was rich with opportunities.
And then this is one of Pierre's
favorite things is the... sound.
And in my discussions with the board artists
and sending him
some of the animation tests,
what you'll see is this little showdown,
which is basically a... showdown.
Fight.
- We do that now.
- That's right.
- Between us.
I even talked to Bruno Chauffard,
our CG Sup, about creating spit.
'Cause we didn't have it originally.
I was like, "Well, we've got to see spit."
I love those discussions.
You don't feel serious.
Yeah, you have to take it seriously.
So, yes, basically this became a spit fight
that eventually reveals our Dave there
to actually be painted.
We talked about the evil minions a little bit
in this moment you're about to see,
very much like
the Invasion of the Body Snatchers,
when he does his "bah" and there's a scream.
- He looks like Donald Sutherland there.
- He does, exactly.
And one of our influences here was...
- World War Z?
- Yes.
We saw a trailer for World War Z
and obviously
we're like, "That's cool."
So we just tried to create
a swarm of these evil minions
to sort of behave like a wave.
Yeah, like water simulation.
And I think in this moment,
really it was fun to create a sense of scale
with the odds against Gru
and then these two little guys.
And this was something I worked
with the board artists on the evolution.
The fun part about doing something like this
is the staging of the action.
And like, "Okay, what do we do?"
And we had this set and we had this rooftop
at the end of the set.
It felt like a great place to get them stuck.
So, the jelly now is the antidote.
Yeah, we know.
And we do know also
that all these jelly things aren't
properly aimed at the mouth of the minions.
- Yeah, that's right.
- Yeah.
I put an antidote in the jelly.
It works, at least visually.
- Yeah.
- Don't question it.
So, the second time Dr. Nefario
saves the day in that ship.
Hi!
- You brought the girls?
- Yes!
For me, I really liked this moment,
it's like a parenting thing.
'Cause movies, I think, very often
just make that assumption
that the girls would be in the third act action
without acknowledging it,
but I like blaming it on Dr. Nefario.
A deluded old guy who thinks it's okay.
Gru?
So, in here, we really wanted to...
We talked about this a few ways,
like how the action evolves
and making sure that we kept Gru's focus
on finding Lucy,
just again to keep that character drive
versus the other things,
which probably in some ways...
I guess our feeling was when you start
developing a story about saving the world,
ironically, it starts to feel a little abstract.
So, in the designing of the jelly guns,
we actually made it so the jars of jelly
themselves are the magazines.
So we can easily identify...
There's the French maid.
It's over, El Macho.
So the first minion's
the last minion transformed.
Again, we tried to design those things
that run through the movie.
And here's another one!
So, for some reason,
El Macho has tied Lucy to a shark.
You said earlier about killing a lot of animals.
Here goes another one.
Of course, they're just animated.
That one will suffer
more than the others, actually.
- That's true.
- Like a sushi shop.
Was that Didier's idea? The sushi thing?
No, that was me. No, that was me.
- You're cruel.
- Yeah.
Tallyho!
What did we have there before?
I can't remember, with El Macho.
There was something
and then we changed it to the minion.
- I don't remember.
- I don't, either.
I think it was Gru grabbed it,
they were in a fight.
Yeah, that's right, cat fight. Yeah.
Yeah, we had a whole wrestling match
between Gru and El Macho
when El Macho was human.
It just was too long.
Remember we had the minions cheering?
They had foam fingers and they were
rooting for Gru versus helping.
Actually, we didn't have that moment of
- El Macho transforming with the PX-41.
- That's right.
We actually had the idea very early on,
and I can't remember in what form that was.
I remember Eric did sketches of this
a long time ago.
And then when we started boarding this,
our board artist said,
"He really should drink that stuff."
And I was like, "You know what? We had
that. I don't remember what happened."
So we actually went back to the idea,
and it just felt like a nice evolution.
But again, playing it comedically
where he evolves,
- but then his belly...
- Drops down.
And so here again sort of thinking
about what do we...
How do we track something
through the movie?
Particularly something relating
to Gru and Lucy, who are the main storyline.
So the lipstick taser. Here we go.
The same ridiculous dance that Gru does.
Isn't that Gangnam Style a little?
It is.
- Loosely is.
- Yes.
So, then we had a lot of talks
about how to end El Macho.
I don't know if this is
the most elegant ending.
But we thought it was the funniest.
So, we just ended him here with the fart gun.
Although it's funny, I think,
that we did this little thing
with the big game hunter
and Dr. Nefario posing for a photo
that I think, at the end of the day,
buttons it nicely.
We had an idea at one point about El Macho
ending up in the zoo in the gorilla cage.
We never pursued it.
Don't worry, I will get you out of this.
What I like about this with the chicken is that
that's actually what a chicken could do,
is just hit that button.
Innocently, but he does it
with a bad feeling in mind.
And you remember also we wanted to make
him pay and have him at the very end of...
We were gonna serve him
- at the restaurant.
- The feast at the restaurant.
- That would have been good.
- That would have been funny.
I thought no one would be upset
with a chicken getting eaten.
Yeah, here's the sushi bit.
We had something. It was a fisherman.
- Remember?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
The shark ate the fisherman
and then it just didn't work.
- It wasn't funny.
So, then we went with the sushi bit.
It's always good
when you're trying to think of comedy,
you have to think of those
unexpected consequences,
but that gives something,
it's hard to describe but...
Better make it quick.
When you do something visually
and you put it together and you're like,
"Oh, boy!
That didn't work as well as we'd hoped.
"Back to the drawing board."
So here we had to sort of build the tension
as Gru finally gets the courage
to ask Lucy on a date.
And originally we had them
hanging in the volcano. Remember that?
- Yeah.
- They were slipping.
And we played this idea
that they were slipping, slipping, slipping,
and then we cut to their funeral
or we thought it was their funeral.
- A couple of coffins.
- Caskets.
- Don't say "coffins."
- That's right, it's caskets.
But it ended up just being
a little hard to understand,
so we moved the tension back
to when they're riding the rocket.
And we added those guys
from the beginning.
We really like doing call backs, don't we?
That's right, that's right. Always feels fun.
So, this was an idea
that started with, I believe,
it was Ken Daurio who mentioned it.
And we talked about
a lot of things for this ending.
But I think, certainly in my mind, a wedding
was gonna give us the best opportunity
to get our characters together
and land the right tone.
Because, from the first film,
we sort of end with a celebration,
and there's always dancing and music,
and it just felt like a rich opportunity.
So, Pierre did a version of this song, I Swear,
and the first version, it was just minionese.
And then we talked about it and...
- We needed some ridiculous words.
- Yeah, but I said,
"It would be great if we could do a word."
And Pierre goes, "What about underwear?"
And I said, "Yeah."
And he goes, "I don't know if that'll fit."
And so I think we sang it back and forth
and then that was it.
Do you think people
recognize that word though?
- I think they do. Yeah, yeah.
- Yeah?
- So...
- Animation test again.
Yeah, that's right.
How would these two characters,
with each of their graphic elements
being so strong, be able to kiss,
and we played off of it, basically.
And we talked about it with the board artists,
and layout contributed, too,
just really playing it
like one of those videos from the '90s,
one of those boy bands,
and that's really what we pursued.
Love those guys in the background
with that little heart.
And so here again, we had...
These kinds of moments are challenging
to discover, to say the least.
But what we ended up doing is going back
to what we'd set up in the earlier sequence
with Agnes.
- Mother's Day?
- Yeah, Mother's Day.
And her finally getting the chance
to say it to her new mom.
And do it successfully,
so we play her a little bit timid here.
And it's always nice
when you've got this piece in place
and then you're able to pay it off.
Which was what we were shooting for here.
And again, we try to be true,
as opposed to illustrating
the moment a little bit too much.
And my new mom, Lucy, is beyond compare.
Even Lucy's reaction here is very true.
Yeah, it sort of has a nice authentic quality.
And then we have the other girls join
and it feels like just...
I think that's the theme
of the movie in a lot of ways.
We were just thinking of extending this nice
family that we established in the first film.
Now, for the very end, I should probably
just let it play and stop talking.
- But...
- We should sing.
Yeah, right. But really what happened was
the I Swear moment was playing so nicely,
we just had a conversation.
Gosh, we've got them singing
and knowing what weddings are about
and those archetypal songs
that work just great.
Y.M.C.I... Y.M.C.I.
- Y.M.C.A.
- Where'd that come from?
I don't know. Felt like it was something
the minions could sing wonderfully
and would just be a lot of fun.
You said it all.
Do you remember that character?
Who is she?
What was the...
- They drove off into the sunset.
- Yeah, yeah.
But this was a better opportunity...
I think Cinco threw this out.
- That was your idea.
- Yeah.
To do the photographs
as a great way to collect our characters.
And in the end credit sequence, we really,
really wanted to have fun with the 3D.
Within the movie itself,
we don't have that many moments
where we have the freedom to do it
without actually killing either the emotion
or taking the people
out of the story the movie's telling.
And so, the end credits is a chance
for us to overplay the 3D a little bit more
and have fun with it in the literal sense.
Meaning, play around with the black bars,
with stuff like cutting it, going beyond it.
And also, we sort of noticed
that against black, 3D works the greatest.
Yeah.
It's fun, too,
'cause one of our big influences, I think,
I speak for both of us,
are the Looney Tunes cartoons.
And what's fun about this
is a lot of that stuff, even the 3D...
You'll see in a moment,
the guy with the giant piece of dynamite,
and they smash into the steel and the saw,
all those little fun cartoon things.
This gives us a chance, even a moment
like that, to play with those things in 3D.
And the added benefit
is that the three characters that you see
are actually gonna be the stars
of the next movie.
Exactly. So it felt like a great opportunity
to set them up.
So we talked about the black bars,
that became the concept
of keeping them open.
And a musical element, too.
This is another song by Pharrell Williams,
which is great, with CeeLo Green singing.
So, there are attempts
to perform as an audition.
It's a very elusive concept
that strings it together.
But I think it makes way more sense
than the first ending credits
we did on the first DM,
which were total nonsense and very abstract.
At least this one
has something you can grasp.
I like that you think
this one actually makes more sense.
Does it not?
Also, the things we talked about were,
particularly in Europe,
some of the 3D advertisements
that appear before the films
with candy floating in mid-air.
They're really a lot of fun.
And when you go with your kids,
they reach out and try to grab them.
So, really just,
particularly those bubbles, taking advantage
of what really works so well in 3D.
But the irony of it all is actually
that those commercials
can permit themselves
to go beyond
what the eye sometimes permits,
just because they don't care
about storyline or anything.
- Exactly.
- And so...
We've also freed ourselves
of those constraints.
We don't have any storyline whatsoever.
We just have characters
interacting with each other.
That probably is the way we make
too many of our decisions.
I wonder what people will think of this
when they watch it in 2D.
They won't understand what they went for.
So that's it.
That's great. Here we go.
We don't talk through all this, do we?
No. Let's go eat.
Sorry, it's just our lunchtime.
- Shall we go?
- I think so, yeah.
- Guys, what do you think?
- Okay, yeah.
Goodbye, everyone. Bye-bye.
Thank you so much. Hope you enjoyed it.