Illumination...
Illumination!
Places, everyone.
Once there was a way
To get back homeward
To get back home
Sleep, pretty darling
Do not cry
And I will sing a lullaby
This was it.
The moment it all began.
The moment an ordinary little guy
fell in love with the theater.
Everything about it.
The lights,
the way the scenery moved,
even the smell.
He was only six years old,
but his plans to become
the first koala bear in space
were suddenly toast.
Some folks may have said
he grew up to be the greatest
showman the city has ever seen.
Some called him a visionary,
a maverick.
Sure, some folks said he was
as crazy as he was stubborn,
but I say wonder and magic
don't come easy, pal.
And, oh, there would never be
any doubt,
the name Buster Moon would go down
in entertainment history.
And I should know...
- Because I am Buster...
- Moon!
Open this door!
Good morning, Mr. Moon.
Miss Crawly. What...
What's going on?
You got a lot of animals
waiting to see you, Mr. Moon.
I do?
Holy moly, I really do.
Yeah, it's the stage crew
from your last show.
They say their paychecks bounced.
Tell 'em I'll call up the bank
and make sure
they're paid tout de suite.
Oh, I got Judith from the bank
holding on line two right now, sir.
Actually, I'm gonna have
to call her back.
What should I tell her this time?
Tell her Buster Moon is out to lunch.
Moon! Open this door!
Come on, Moon!
I know you're in there!
Moon! Open this door!
Hey!
Well, my temperature is rising
And my feet on the floor,
crazy people knocking
'Cause they're wanting some more
Let me in, baby
I don't know what you've got
But you'd better take it easy,
this place is hot
And I'm so glad
We made it
So glad we made it
You got to gimme some lovin'
Gimme, gimme some lovin'
Gimme some lovin'
Every day...
In your mind
Could you ever be
really close to me?
I can tell the way you smile
If I feel that I could be
certain then
I would say the things
I want to say to...
Hmm, thought I heard
someone singing there.
Ah, whatever.
Guys, listen.
Stay where you are.
The cops are here in...
What are you...?
- Hold it right there!
- Yeah, I'll get him!
Go, go, go!
Johnny, you were supposed
to be keeping a lookout!
Sorry, Dad.
And where's your mask?
Do you ever feel
Like a plastic bag
Drifting through the wind
Wanting to start again?
Do you ever feel
Feel so paper thin...
Look at me. I'm Mommy!
Caspar, get off the table.
Rosita, have you seen my car keys?
Norman, would you please tell them
what a good singer I am?
Oh, yeah, you were great, honey.
By the way, the bathroom sink
is blocked again.
Bye, honey!
Like the Fourth of July
'Cause, baby, you're a...
One, two, one, two, three, four!
- I don't wanna talk to ya
- Nothing to say
- I don't wanna walk with ya
- Outta my way
- I'm not gonna play for ya
- Don't want to play
- I don't need anyone else
- Yeah, yeah
I live my life by myself,
yeah, yeah
I can't stand the things
that you say
I'm not listening any...
Oh, my gosh.
I thought you guys said
you were musicians.
Ash, babe,
I'm the lead singer, okay?
Just stick to the backing vocals.
Sorry, I get carried away.
Yeah, I know, right?
It just kind of ruins my song,
you know?
Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday
Dear Grandpa
Happy birthday to you
What?
Come on, make your wish.
I wish you'd join a choir.
A local band or something.
I tried.
Hey, hey, Dad, we've been over this.
So she's a little shy.
So what?
If I had a voice like Meena's,
I'd be a superstar by now!
Just singing... Ooh, yeah.
- I said ooh, yeah...
- Sure you would, Grandpa.
Now blow out your candles.
A penny?
How dare you!
I happen to have studied
at the Lincoln School of Music.
Sorry, it's all I got right now.
Oh, is that so?
- All right, prove it, pal.
- What?
- Empty your pockets right now.
- Trying to find...
- What is this you got here?
- Just trying to find...
What do you smoke out of this?
That's my inhaler.
Aha! I knew it!
You all saw it.
You all saw it right here.
The monkey lied.
I forgot I had that.
And next time, pick on someone
your own size!
Bully!
Take care of her, will you?
She may look old and rusty,
but she is a classic.
Okay, listen.
We both know that my theater
has been going through
some pretty rough times lately,
but as the saying goes,
for every cloud, a silver lining.
We've got...
Hold on right there, Buster.
My dad, he heard I was
gonna see you today,
and he was all like,
Eddie, you tell that koala
I'm not funding any more
of those shows.
And that's final.
Those were his words.
Well, your dad's right.
Those shows were the problem.
War of Attrition.
Rosie Takes a Bow.
I mean, nobody wants to see
that stuff anymore.
So, what do I do?
- Quit?
- No.
I give 'em a show they cannot
resist, which is gonna be...
Just one more minute,
s'il vous plaît.
Merci.
Don't speak French.
They speak English here.
Now, my next show is gonna be...
Drumroll, please...
A singing competition.
A singing competition?
Who wants to see another one of those?
Everyone!
Just think.
Your neighbor,
the grocery store manager,
that chicken... right there!
Everyone in this city gets a shot
at being a star live on my stage.
Buster, this is a terrible idea.
Oh, no, it's not.
Real talent from real life.
That's what audiences want,
and I'm gonna give it to 'em!
All right, well...
Can we please just get out of here?
Don't you want to eat?
Yeah, but we can't afford any of this.
Yes, I know, and that's why...
I brought sandwiches.
That's not allowed.
What, you don't like
peanut butter and jelly?
- Excuse me, sir.
- Okay, look.
I got cream cheese, I got banana...
- You okay?
- Yep. Never better.
Miss Crawly?
Hello?
Who is it?
It's me.
Your boss, Mr. Moon.
- Oh, hello, Mr. Moon.
- There we go.
Now, I need you to add
the following information
- to our publicity flyers.
- Yes, sir.
The winner of the singing contest
will receive a grand prize of...
$935.
Gonna need more than that.
Just a second.
There.
There!
$1,000.
- You got that?
- $1,000...
Print 'em up on every single sheet
of paper we have left
and let's spread the word
right away, okay?
Yes, uh, yes, sir.
Oh, okay.
Come on out of there.
Ah, the winds of change.
Yep, when this show's a hit,
I'm gonna get you a fresh coat of paint.
How are we doing
with those flyers, Miss Crawly?
Oh, yes, sir.
We're all good to go here.
Miss Crawly, no!
No, no, no, no, no, no!
Oopsie-daisy.
Oh, well, I guess that's
one way to spread the word.
Hey, Lance, look at this.
Ash, babe, hey!
- You make a withdrawal!
- Yeah.
Meena!
Hey, hey, hey!
What do you think you...?
Yeah.
Let's go to work.
And cue the crazy old lizard.
Good morning, Mr. Moon.
Indeed it is, Miss Crawly.
Top of the morning to you.
I made you some coffee.
You did? Where is it?
Oh, I got a little thirsty
on the way up those stairs.
- Shall I go open the doors now?
- The doors?
Well, you've got a lot
of animals waiting in line
to audition, Mr. Moon.
I do?
Holy moly, I really do.
I swear to you, Eddie, this is no joke.
Look, just get down here
and see for yourself.
I gotta go.
This is it, Miss Crawly.
Get your scaly tail downstairs
and throw those doors open wide.
Okay, one at a time, please.
Calm down.
Got me looking so crazy right now
Your love's got me
looking so crazy right now
Got me looking so crazy right now
Your touch has got me
looking so crazy right now...
Rah, rah, ah-ah-ah
Roma, ma-ma-ma
Gaga, ooh-la-la
Want your bad romance...
- Jump!
- Jump, jump, jump
Might as well jump...
Bye, Iggy.
Bye, Perry. Bye, Carla.
Bye, Gail.
Bye, Rory. Bye, Mickey.
Bye, Moe. Bye, Nelson.
Bye, Hannah.
Bye, Tess.
Bye-bye, Caspar.
Baaa-by...
I compare you to a kiss
from a rose...
L-U-C-K
L-U-C-K...
I love my shoes, I love my shoes...
Come, my lady, come, come, my lady
You're my butterfly sugar baby...
Let's hear from a few more
of the folks in line.
- What about you, sir?
- Well, Bob, I'm a lab technician
for a leading pharmaceutical company,
but I was born with a gift.
And that gift is to sing.
Oh, my gosh, look at her butt
Oh, my gosh, look at her...
- I live my life by myself
- Yeah, yeah
- I can't stand the things that you say
I'm not listening anyway...
Yeah...
Lollipop, lollipop,
ooh-lolli, lolli, lolli
ooh-lolli, lolli...
Oi, Dad. Just going out.
Well, don't be long.
I got the gang coming over.
Lollipop, lollipop,
ooh-lolli, lolli, lolli
ooh-lolli...
Well, look, I mean,
I'm sure you're gonna get a lot
of namby-pamby animals in here
saying things like...
Oh, it's not winning.
It's the taking part that counts.
Yeah, yeah. Not me, pal.
I'm here to win.
That prize, it's mine.
People say, yo, Humpty,
you're really funny-looking
That's all right
'cause I get things cookin'...
Working 9:00 to 5:00...
We can dance if we want to...
Aserejé ja de jé, de jebe tu de...
Ride like the wind
Ride like the...
Ben, the two of us
Need look no more...
This ain't love
It's clear to see
But, darling, stay with me
Wow! Thank you, Johnny.
Okay, next up...
- We have Meena.
- Good luck out there.
All right, come on. Here we go.
Come on, you can do it.
You can do it. Okay...
Oh, I'm s...
Oh, I'm sorry...
Okay. Hey, it's all right.
You know, it's all right.
Take it away, Meena.
Okay...
Anytime, now.
Do you want to start over?
All right, enough of that.
That's quite enough of that.
That's it. Come on.
Off the stage, Helga.
Go on. You're useless.
Thanks.
Right. Here we go.
Hit it!
Every time it rains, it rains
Pennies from heaven
Don't you know each cloud contains
Pennies from heaven...
You've just got ignite
The light
And let it shine
Just own the night
Like the Fourth of July
'Cause, baby, you're a firework
Come on, show 'em what...
Okay, that's everyone, Mr. Moon.
All right, call everyone
back to stage, Miss Crawly,
and let's get...
Hello!
Can I have everybody back
to stage, please?
Everyone come back to stage
for selection.
Okay.
Thank you, Miss Crawly.
You're welcome, Mr. Moon.
All right.
Let's see, now.
I'll take...
- you guys.
- Yes!
And which one of you is the girl?
Very funny.
Loud and horrible,
but shows promise.
Welcome to the show.
Cool.
I guess we could hang.
No, no.
I just want her, not you.
What?
All right, the rest of the group acts,
thank you so much.
Oh, don't feel bad, folks.
There will be a ten percent discount
on tickets for everyone.
Yeah, sure, thanks a lot.
Let's get out of here, Ash.
Ash?
Yeah...
Yeah, let's go.
Okay, soloists.
Johnny, Mike, Pete, Richard,
Daniel and Ray.
Mike!
I've gotta have you in my show.
Oh, I... if you insist.
And I'll take Pete...
Ooh, yeah!
And one more.
Let me see, now.
Oh, my gosh, I am so sorry.
Oh, what is wrong with me?
Thanks for coming, Richard.
Oh, my... Ray!
Are you all right?
Just hang in there, Ray.
I got you.
Okay, then I'll take...
Daniel.
Thank you, Johnny.
Daniel, can you hear me?
You're in the show!
What?
Are you talking to me?
Yes.
I was saying that you are in...
Oh, geez, this is gonna drive me nuts.
Johnny, get back here.
You're in.
Thank you, Daniel. Good-bye.
Yes!
Okay. That's everyone on my list.
Wait a second.
Rosita.
- Is Rosita still here?
- Oh, yes.
Yes, I'm here.
Rosita, Rosita, Rosita.
Great set of pipes, but boring to watch.
I knew it.
So, what should I do?
I could partner you up with Gunter.
Gunter! Where are you?
Ja! Ja! This is me.
Ja!
It's gonna spice things up on stage.
Wait. You want us to sing together?
Ja! The two of us together,
you joking me?
We're going to be spicy, no?
That koala's a fool, Sherry-Anne.
You are going to be a star one day!
Auditions are over, pal.
- Show's already been cast.
- Okay...
you are my chosen few.
Yes!
This is it, folks.
A defining moment in all of our lives.
No. No, no, no, not you guys.
I dismissed all
of the group acts already.
You... You can go home.
Look, look, look, I'm really sorry,
but all of the slots are filled.
No, no, no, no, listen.
No in show.
Good-bye-bye.
Miss Crawly!
Come on, you guys, out of here.
Come on, off the stage.
- Thank you so much.
- Hey, Moon.
What's the story? Is the prize
really inside this thing?
The prize? Oh, sure.
Yes, it's all in there.
Well, open it, will you?
I want to see what $100,000 looks like.
- Yeah, come on. - Me too.
- Let's have a look. - Open it.
Yeah, yeah, go on.
Open it, Mr. Moon.
For sure, I'll open it.
Wait. What did you say?
He said $100,000.
A hundred...
I forgot my keys.
Koala be right back.
For the last time, Miss Crawly,
I'm not going to fire you.
Now, would you pull yourself together,
and please blow that nose of yours.
No, no, no, not in here.
- Blow it outside.
- I'm sorry, Mr. Moon.
- Thank you.
- Buster, what do you expect?
- She's like 200 years old.
- Eddie, please, look.
If your folks could just
loan me the money until...
$100,000? Buster, come on.
I gotta think.
I've gotta think.
I've got to come up
- with a solution...
- Look, maybe it's time
to stop thinking
and it's time to just move on.
I mean, this theater of yours,
you could get some decent
money for it and...
I don't know, maybe we could
do something together.
What? What, sit around
playing video games?
Do you know what that is?
It's a bucket?
Yes, and do you know why
I have this bucket?
'Cause the roof is leaking?
No, that's the bucket for the leak.
I have this one 'cause it
belonged to my father.
Every day for 30 years,
he worked his tail off
washing cars
just so I could buy this place.
Every day, Eddie.
Just for me.
Sounds like a great dad.
So, how do you want to handle this?
Oh, Mr. Moon,
I got Judith from the bank
holding on line two again.
Well, there's only one thing
I can do.
Okay, everybody, listen up.
I gotta send you all home.
Right now.
- What?
- Yep.
'Cause, like my dad used to say,
get a good night's sleep
and do a great day's work.
That's right.
Rehearsals begin first thing
tomorrow morning.
And if you want to become stars
and win 100 grand,
then you better be ready
to work harder
than you've ever worked
in your lives.
So get some sleep and dream
big dreams.
Miss Crawly!
Okay, come on.
That's enough now.
Come on, off the stage.
Please.
- Dream big dreams?
- I know, it's good, right?
What about the 100 grand?
Don't you worry, Eddie.
There's got to be a way to get it.
What? Buster, no, listen to me!
This show is not gonna
save your theater.
You're at rock bottom, pal.
Yep, and you know what's great
about hitting rock bottom, Eddie?
There's only one way left to go,
and that's up.
And you can see the lucky few
leaving the theater behind me.
Now back to you in the studio, John.
Oh, honey, please don't cry.
You are not a failure.
There'll be other chances.
- You just...
- The heck there will!
Dad, please.
Come on!
Don't you want this?
Well, sure, but I messed it up.
Then you gotta go back there
tomorrow and say,
Mr. Moon, I demand you let me
re-audition!
Be confident! Show 'em you
ain't gonna be pushed around!
You got that, Meena?
Good!
Now, go get my cocoa.
I won't sell out for nobody
Won't follow no fool...
Would you stop?
I'd only be doing it for us.
Oh, really?
Yes, really.
If I won that money, we could build
our own recording studio,
start our own label.
I mean, the whole world
would get to hear your songs.
I'm not listening to my girlfriend
'Cause she just wants to
Sell out
Hey! Just a min...
Oh, oh, wait. Wait!
Oh, look at...
I know Derek, the manager.
He'll vouch for me.
Come on!
Hey, Mario.
How's it going?
Oh, for crying out loud.
Oh, yeah, oh, let the bears in.
Let the bears in. Fine.
There he is!
I got a surprise for you, my son.
What's that?
- Tell him the plan.
- Right.
We've been told there's a ship
carrying 25 million in gold,
gonna dock at night right here.
With the usual guards
here and here.
But, lucky for us, there's
a sewer right under here.
So the getaway driver meets us here.
And that is gonna be you
this time, Johnny.
- What? You want me to drive?
- Yeah.
It's time my boy had
a proper role in the gang, eh?
Hang on, hang on, Dad.
Barry's always been our driver.
Barry don't mind.
Do you, Barry?
- No. No, that's fine.
- Yeah.
So, when exactly
is this ship coming in then?
We ain't got a date yet.
Probably won't be
for a while, though, will it?
What do you care? It's the last
job we ever need to do.
When it comes in, we go.
Right?
Great.
Can't wait.
Hi.
I saw your ad in the paper.
Yes, I need a nanny
just for a couple of weeks.
You can? Great.
Oh, the kids?
Yes, they're wonderful.
They... Yeah, I have 25.
No, I'm not joking.
But they're really no problem...
Hello? Hello?
Good night, Mommy.
Hey. How was the big meeting?
That bad, really?
Well, I have something
really exciting to tell you.
You make the best pie, honey.
Listen, Norman,
I know it's short notice,
but I could really use some help
with the kids tomorrow
because, well, you are not
gonna believe what I did today.
Norman, are you listening to me?
Rehearsals begin
first thing tomorrow morning,
so get some sleep and dream
big dreams.
Good morning, everybody.
Now, I want you all dressed
before breakfast.
Breakfast!
Rosita, have you seen
my car keys?
Don't forget, your keys
are in your coat pocket.
Oh, I found 'em.
- Bye, honey.
- Bye, Norman.
Time for school.
Bye, Iggy.
Bye, Perry. Bye, Carla.
Bye, Gail. Bye, Rory.
Bye, Mickey. Bye, Moe.
Bye, Nelson. Bye, Hannah.
Bye, Tess. Bye, Kelly.
Bye, George. Bye, Andy.
Bye, Freddy.
Bye-bye, Caspar.
This contest is war.
This stage is the battlefield.
Your song is your weapon.
Now, you only get one shot
to blow that audience away,
so choose carefully
from the list of songs
I've selected for each of you.
Ah, talked some sense
into that boyfriend of yours.
Lance is an artist,
but I wouldn't expect you
to understand that.
You're right.
I don't understand that at all.
Now, you'll notice each list
also includes my costume
and performance suggestions.
Okay? Miss Crawly will show you
to your rehearsal spaces.
Now, let's get to work.
Excuse me, Mr. Moon?
For some reason, it says here
that I should be playing the piano?
Yes, just imagine...
big, soulful guy like you
tenderly playing the keys.
There'll be goose bumps everywhere.
Well, I haven't played piano
since I was a kid.
Miss Crawly, we're gonna need
some piano lessons over here.
Yes, sir! Up the stairs.
I'll be right along.
And, Pete, you're in here.
You got it, Mr. Moon.
- Check your ego, man.
- Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
- Break it up, break it up, break it up.
- Oh, yeah?
Tell Ricki. He started it.
That's right.
Just like I started this band.
My band, Howie.
Oh, forgive me, Your Highness.
Guys, come on.
No, no, no, no, no.
Hey, hey. Out. Get out of here.
Look, just calm down
and pick a song.
I think we'll probably have
a better chance of winning
if I do the singing part
and leave the dancing part to you.
Bah! Are you joking me?
You are just in need of, like,
a super cool warm-up.
Come on, let's take off
these clothes.
That is not necessary.
That is a lot of skin.
Ah, don't you look so worried face.
I've got one for you too.
Hey, Porky!
- Keep it down, will you?
- Sorry.
Hey, Moon, you gave me the wrong list.
Cheesy pop's not exactly my style.
Style.
I'm glad you brought that up.
Now, let's see.
There.
Isn't this a great color for you?
I can't tell.
It's melting my eyes.
- You got anything in black?
- Black?
What, you want everyone to think
you're going to a funeral?
You think you're some kind
of artsy-fartsy type?
No, no, no, no, no.
Bingo! Pop star princess!
Is this part of the competition?
Okay, everybody, don't panic.
- Don't panic.
- What's going on?
Talk to me, Crawly.
When did we last pay
the power company, Mr. Moon?
Oh, for Pete's sake.
Okay, don't worry, everybody.
I will take care of this.
In the meantime, you will continue
to rehearse in the dark.
- What?
- But I can't see anything.
Don't you worry, Rosita.
I have glow sticks.
Great.
Use this time to shake off
those first-day inhibitions,
and I'll be right back.
- You gotta be kidding me.
- Okay, you heard him.
Back to work now.
Come on, everybody.
Sorry, old girl.
I'll fix that.
Mr. Moon?
You probably don't remember me,
but I auditioned yesterday,
and I...
Hey, listen.
Do you think maybe you could
reach the ledge?
That ledge?
Whoa, that's a heck of a trunk
you've got there.
Thanks a lot, kid.
Mr. Moon?
My name is Meena,
and I baked a cake for you,
and I was wondering
if you'd maybe give me
- a second chance to...
- Just a moment, please.
Be right with you.
Yay! It's about time.
Johnny...
Yep, mind your head here.
Hey, can you pull up
that scenic cable?
- You mean this?
- Yes, that's it.
Great!
And the house lights?
Ah, I know.
Beautiful, isn't she?
You know what, kid?
How would you like to be
a part of this show?
Really? Wait.
Oh, my gosh, I was just
gonna ask about that.
Great. 'Cause I could
really use a stagehand.
Stagehand?
- But...
- Don't worry about it.
You're gonna pick it up in no time.
I'll teach you everything
I know. Follow me.
These are the rehearsal spaces
and dressing rooms,
and up here we got workshops
and the main office.
Up in the air!
Touch your toes!
Awesome.
Awesome?
Yeah, I think the word
you're after is awful.
And that's me restraining myself.
There's not an ounce of talent
between 'em.
Not an ounce.
In fact, you know what?
I think that prize
is as good as mine already.
Yes, indeed,
I am about to come
into a very,
very large sum of money.
$100,000 to be precise.
Well, is that so?
In that case, sir, you'll be
wanting our platinum card.
Gas so high,
got 'em riding on E
Daddy needs shoes
and kids gotta eat
They can have every
last penny on me
Me and Swizzy rollin'
in the Lambo
Sit back reminiscing
when I never had no
I think I might give away
a million bucks...
Well, well, well, hello again.
'Cause I feel good,
yeah, I feel good
'Cause I feel good
I think I might take...
Oh, man, these are like
the cheesiest songs of all time.
I know, right?
I mean, I was even thinking
of writing my own song instead.
Wait, what?
- Your own song?
- Well, yeah.
Look, if you want to win that money,
just do what the koala says.
Why? You think I can't
write my own song?
I'm just saying,
not everyone can write
songs, okay?
I know I make it look
easy, babe,
but it's not.
Oh, here she is.
Quiet down, everybody.
So, Meena, are you in the show?
Well, yeah, kind of, but...
She did it!
Oh, I'm so proud of you,
I could pop!
That's my birthday wish
coming true right there!
- Way to go, Meena!
- Oh, Meena, we love you!
Mom...
- What the heck?
- Wait a minute, wait a minute.
Don't be mad, okay?
It was your grandma.
She told the whole street
about your audition.
- Mom, no, wait.
- Shush, baby.
You need to save
that singing voice of yours.
So, from now on,
just nod or shake
your head, okay?
How was that, Dad?
You're still too soft
on them corners, Johnny.
You got to attack 'em.
And you're crunching the gears.
I told you, you got
to be gentle with the...
Look, turn that down.
Oi!
Listen to your father!
Too soft on the corners, Johnny.
You're not doing it right, Johnny.
Speed up, Johnny.
Do it like I showed you.
I know exactly who you...
Dad?
Oh, no.
I've run over my dad.
Now, that is more like it.
And the three little pigs
lived happily ever after.
Good night, my dears.
Norman, are you awake?
How was your day, honey?
Same as always.
It was?
I don't know how you
do it all, honey.
- Good night.
All creatures great and small,
welcome to the Moon Theater!
Mr. Moon?
- I have Judith from the bank.
- What?
Whoa, no, no, no. Tell her I'll
call her back in the morning.
Oh, I can't.
She's right here.
Judith! Hello.
I work for a bank, not a charity,
and if your accounts are not settled
- by the end of the month...
- Okay, Judith...
I personally guarantee,
by the end of this month,
this show is going to be
the biggest hit this city
has ever seen.
Mr. Moon, none of your shows
have ever worked.
None of them!
You've had your chances.
Now, settle your accounts,
or we will repossess this property.
Okay. Toodle-oo.
What are you going to do,
Mr. Moon?
Honestly...
I have no idea.
I listen to the wind,
to the wind of my soul
Where I'll end up,
well, I think
Only God really knows
I've sat upon the...
Are you wearing a Speedo, Eddie?
What... What are you...?
Eddie?
Is everything all right?
Yeah, just doing my laps, Ma!
So, what, you live
in the pool house now?
Yeah, my folks want me to be more,
you know, independent, I guess.
They even hooked me up
with this life coach dude.
- Life coach?
- Yeah.
I guess he's gonna help me
find my purpose in life.
I thought I had one,
but it turns out
it wasn't the right one
or something.
I don't know.
Anyway, he's got me
on this whole schedule thing.
It's, like, Mondays,
take out the recycling.
Tuesdays, mow the lawn.
Wednesdays, go visit Nana.
Thursdays, clean the pool.
It's like, don't we have people
to do all of this stuff?
Back up.
Your nana is still alive?
Oh, yeah.
And she's rich, right?
She's loaded.
But trust me, you don't want
to go near my nana.
She is one mean sheep.
There may be trouble ahead
But while there's moonlight
And music and love and romance
- Now, fade up the spot.
- Let's face the music
And dance
Good. Lower the moon.
- Coffee?
- Thank you, Miss Crawly.
Okay, that's normal.
Just needs a knock.
See? You're getting it.
And while we've still
Got a chance...
Anyone seen my glass eye?
The darn thing keeps popping out.
Soon...
You almost killed me, Jumbo!
- It wasn't me.
- Oh, is that so?
Pete?
Pete!
You're gonna be all right.
Okay, just...
Just hang in there, buddy.
Ricki? Kai?
Why aren't you guys rehearsing?
We're through.
They said
I'm an intolerable egomaniac.
I don't even know
what that means.
All right.
We're two acts down.
Give me some good news,
Miss Crawly.
Oh, it's not as bad
as it looks.
Oopsie-daisy.
Meena, how would you like
to re-audition for the show?
Really? Well, yeah.
- Great.
- I mean, no.
What?
I mean, yes, I can sing.
But no, I get so nervous,
and I can't do it.
I mean, I would totally do it,
but... no, I... no.
I'm gonna take that as a maybe.
Great! Look, they're back.
We're gonna come back
to this, Meena.
Listen, guys,
forget what I said before.
You are very talented.
Please, join the show, okay?
Yes? No?
Here.
What? Hey, no, no, no.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Don't go, don't go!
Oh, what is this for?
Now, we use this
to follow the steps.
Goddess on a mountaintop
Burnin' like a silver flame
The summit of beauty and love
And...
Caspar! Caspar, no!
How about this?
Come on. What did I tell you?
I'm so sorry.
He had a fever,
and it was too late
to get a sitter, so...
Well, you seem fine now.
Well, I'm your Venus
- Stop! You're messing it up!
- I'm your fire
- At your desire.
- Hey!
I am not singing this.
What's not to like?
You're a female,
and you're a teenager.
This song was made for you.
Wow, it's like you can
see inside my tiny
teenage mind.
I know, right?
You just gotta add some moves
and a little bit of...
Hey, I just met you
And this is crazy
But here's my number
So call me maybe
- Go for it!
- Oh, you mean like this?
Try to chase me
But here's my number
So call me maybe.
There you go.
You're a natural.
Yes, that was very bad.
Johnny.
Come in. Over.
Oh, Johnny, your jacket's talking.
Johnny, where are you?
Dad, what's going on? Over.
What do you mean,
you gotta leave now?
I know.
I'm... I'm so sorry.
It's just, I've got
this family business thing.
Do I need to start worrying
about your commitment
here, Johnny?
- Tell me no.
- No. Absolutely not.
I promise it won't
happen again.
- It better not.
- Thank you, Mr. Moon.
I want love to forget
- That you offended me
- Baby, I'm back.
Or how you had defended me
When everybody tore me down
Yeah, I want love to change
my friends to enemies
- Change my...
- What is going on here?
Hi. I'm Becky.
Becky?
Hey, what did you expect?
You're never around anymore.
I did it for us, Lance!
You and me!
Oh, sweetie, I'm sorry.
I think I left my sunglasses
in there.
Come on, Becky.
Let's get out of here.
Jackpot, baby!
Well, I say we call it
a night there, fellas.
Hey, put the cash in my car,
will you, Derek?
Well, you're one great
card player, Mike.
Not so bad yourself.
Except I still can't tell
how you cheated.
Cheated? Cheated?
Oh, I am offended.
Come on, baby,
let's cut some rug.
What the...?
How did that get there?
- Run for it, baby!
- Hey!
Get him!
Excuse me.
Don't let him get away!
- Thanks, Derek.
- Out of the way.
So long, suckers!
Good morning, Buster.
- Hey, Eddie. How are you?
- Good.
- How's the show going?
- Ah, it's going great.
Hey, that's a sharp jacket
you've got on today.
Oh, thanks.
Wait.
What are you doing here?
Eddie, you can't come
visit your nana
without bringing her
some flowers.
- Here.
- What? No!
Buster, no! Don't go in there!
Yes, can I help...?
- Buster!
- Ah, Nana!
Just look at you, dear.
You don't look a day over 90.
Oh, my gosh.
Buster Moon.
We met at Eddie's graduation.
Oh, lucky me.
A visit from my useless grandson
and his ghastly little
theater friend.
Look at that,
she remembers me.
Okay, Nana...
How would you like to be
the sponsor
for a very prestigious prize?
Not for that singing contest
I saw on the news.
That's the one.
Oh, I see.
You don't have the money, do you?
Well, we don't quite have it
all locked in...
Well, you'll not get a cent
out of me.
Nana, please, just listen to me
- for one second, okay?
- No, absolutely not.
- Don't listen to him, Nana.
- I'm not listening
- to either of you.
- Just wait one second.
Lapsang souchong, no sugar,
and be quick about it.
Nana, I don't know
how to make tea.
I saw this show
when I was a kid.
Nana, you were absolutely
amazing.
Please, this flattery is futile.
I have no intention
of bailing you out.
Your pathetic shows
are the reason
that theater no longer
has an audience.
Oh, but this show is gonna...
gonna pack 'em in
like it did in the
good old days.
They were not good old days,
Mr. Moon.
They were magnificent.
And that theater of yours,
it was a palace of wonder
and magic.
But, Nana, it still is.
Yeah, right.
I can recall the ushers
in their velvet suits.
Queues a mile long just
to get a ticket.
The curtain rising
over that glorious stage.
Music and light bringing
dreams to life?
Precisely.
Well, it's just like
you remember it.
In fact, I've made it
even more spectacular.
No, you haven't.
Come see for yourself.
A special performance
just for you.
What do you say, Nana?
I say...
you are a liar, Mr. Moon.
Okay, well, we're done now.
Thank you, Nana.
But anything's better
than spending another evening
playing checkers with
this old fart.
What?
Great.
It's gonna blow you away, Nana.
And that is no lie.
Now, listen up.
Tomorrow we are going to have
a full preview of the show,
and our audience will be none
other than Miss Nana Noodleman.
- Nana Noodleman?
- Wow, Nana Noodleman.
She's still alive?
Oh, yes, and believe me,
she's got some pretty
high standards.
All right? So, today,
we're going to have
a full dress rehearsal,
and I want to see you
light up the stage, folks.
- Well, that's cool.
- Meena? Miss Crawly?
What do you think?
Wow, it's so ambitious.
Yeah, are you sure about this?
I promised Nana
something spectacular.
And this...
It's gonna blow her away.
- Oh, yes.
- Two minutes, everybody.
Johnny.
Johnny, where are you?
Johnny,
answer the walkie-talkie.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, Dad.
I'm here. I'm here.
- What's wrong?
- We got the call.
Shipment's coming in.
- Tonight?
- Not tonight. Now.
Meet us on the corner
of Hector Street in two minutes.
Stay here.
We'll be back in exactly 37...
Yeah, 37 minutes. Yep.
You've told me repeatedly.
I can make it.
Bravo, Mike.
Nana is gonna love that.
Oh, you're...
you're too kind, Mr. Moon.
And I myself am loving
the new suit, sir.
Okay, can we see Ash
next, please?
Ash, let's get you out here.
Oh, stand back.
Moody teenager coming through.
Good luck, Ash.
I threw a wish in the well
Don't ask me, I'll never tell
I looked to you as it fell
And now you're in my way
Your stare was holding
Ripped jeans, skin was showing
Hot night, wind was blowing
Where do you think
you're going, baby?
I just met you
This is crazy
Here's my number,
so call me maybe...
Okay, enough of that.
Cut it, cut it, cut it, cut it.
I don't think anyone's
gonna call her after that.
Okay, Ash...
Hey, come on, Ash.
What is it? Do you...
Do you not like the dress?
Ash, what's wrong?
Well, it sounds to me like you
are way better off
without that... that...
That total super-jerk
dinkleschplatt!
Exactly.
Total super-jerk dinkleschplatt.
Rosita! Gunter!
- You're on next.
- Yeah, okay, here.
There should be some gum or
some candy in there somewhere.
Just help yourself.
Rosita, Rosita, Rosita.
Wait, wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait.
Can I take your place, please?
- Sure, Johnny. Go ahead.
- Okay, get ready,
'cause I'm warning you...
this stage is about to explode
with major piggy power.
I am so sorry.
I have no control.
Yeah!
Okay, come on, you can do this.
I stay out too late
Got nothing in my brain...
Are you okay?
Oh, yes, I'm fine, thank you.
- How are you?
- Okay.
Johnny, let's get you out here!
And, you guys, you've gotta
work on that routine.
Take it away, Johnny!
What would I do
without your smart mouth
Drawing me in
and you kicking me out
You got my head spinning...
You can't just sing it.
You've got to show
the fire und desire.
The fire went out
a long time ago.
What?
Look, I can't even
keep count of the steps.
Counting schmounting!
She sings too much
with her head, right?
Ja, ja, see?
Forget the steps
and just, like,
let the music take control
of your body parts.
My body parts are not
responding, okay?
It's never gonna happen.
I should just be getting groceries.
- Rosita, no. - Rosita, come on.
- What? Rosita, please.
Like, don't go.
Psst! Hey! Hey!
Down here.
Have you seen three
nasty-looking bears out there?
No.
Oh, great. Hey, by the way,
I love your act.
Seriously, the part where you fall
flat on your face?
Oh, that...
that cracks me up, every time.
See you around, Porky.
And you give me
All of you
Ah, man.
Johnny, I know
I'm asking a lot of you...
Mr. Moon, I'm really trying,
I promise.
What about your backup song?
Have you practiced that?
Well, not yet.
Well, why don't we go back
and work on that one, okay?
I mean, look,
if you play like that
in front of Nana Noodleman...
Johnny?
Hey!
We are set for life now, boys!
What's going on?
Where's Johnny?
He's not here.
Run!
Oh, I'm dead.
Finally see
It's not just a dream
When you set it all
Free, free...
Okay, wait, let me see.
When you set it all free,
all free, all free...
No, Mom, I have not made
any friends.
What do you think this is,
kindergarten?
If you hadn't squealed to the cops,
I wouldn't be in here right now.
Honey, when are you getting out?
I'm only gonna be in here
for a few years.
Well, where'd you hide the money?
Where were you?
Well, thing is, I went
- to get gas, and...
- Don't lie to me!
I was at a rehearsal.
Rehearsal? For what?
I was at a singing contest.
Look, Dad, I'm... I'm sorry.
I just don't want to be
in your gang.
- I want to be a singer.
- Singer?
Look, Dad, no, it's okay,
it's okay.
I can get the bail money.
There's a prize, it's $100,000.
How did I end up
with a son like you, eh?
You're nothing like me.
You never were,
and you never will be.
I'll get you out!
Dad, wait!
I'll get the money!
I promise!
Johnny! Oh!
You...
You gave me a fright there.
Sorry. I didn't mean to.
I just...
Well, I know it's late,
but I could really use
some extra piano lessons.
That's it.
That's good.
You're getting it.
True colors shining through
I see your true col...
Shoppers are reminded the store
will close in 15 minutes.
Thank you.
Ese amor llega así de esta manera
No tiene la culpa
Amor de compra y venta
Amor de en el pasado
Bamboleo, bambolea
Porque mi vida
yo la prefiero vivir así
Bamboleo, bambolea
Porque mi vida
yo la prefiero vivir así
Bamboleo, bambolea
Porque mi vida yo la prefiero
Vivir así
The lady in aisle six...
that was awesome.
All right.
Mr. Moon,
are you sure this is legal?
I don't know.
All right, but if you keep
asking questions,
we'll never get this done.
Now, hit it!
A little higher.
Just a little bit.
There it is. Thank you.
Hey!
Posters up.
- You!
- Now, run away!
Come back here, you vandals!
Rosita, have you seen my car?
Rosita, what the...?
What's going on?
Rosita!
Kids, where's Mommy?
How's that, Miss Crawly?
Hey.
Sorry.
Mr. Moon would like everyone
to meet backstage
before she arrives.
When you set it all free,
all free, all free
You set it all free
You wrote that?
Yeah.
Do you like it?
Are you kidding?
It's fantastic.
You've gotta sing that today.
Mike, you're on first.
Sure.
Just a second here.
Honey, I'm busy.
What? I can't hear you.
Rosita and Gunter,
you're on after Mike.
You got it, boss.
Rosita!
Super cool!
You've, like, totally come back.
Okay, Johnny, you follow them...
What?
Oh, oh, yeah, yeah, I'm ready.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Ash, you're...
After Johnny. I got it.
And, Meena, last chance, kid.
You want to... You want to join
these guys out there today?
I would.
I just get so scared.
Sure, you do.
All right, but...
you know how to get
over that, right?
No.
You just start singing.
Do what you love,
then you'll be great
'cause you won't be
afraid anymore
because you'll actually
be doing it, right?
Look, do you love to sing?
I mean,
do you really love it?
Of course I do.
Then you face this head-on,
Meena.
Because, like my dad always said,
don't let fear stop you
from doing the thing you love.
Okay, I'll do it.
- Great.
- Mr. Moon!
She's here.
Nana...!
Do not even think
of embracing me.
You got it.
Eddie, please show your Nana
to the royal box.
Oh, for heaven sakes,
I'm perfectly capable of walking.
You nervous?
Are you kidding?
I'm absolutely terrified.
Boss.
That's his car, isn't it?
Right there.
Pull over.
Lapsang souchong,
courtesy of Mr. Moo, Moo...
Wonderful.
Honey, honey, the show
is starting, all right?
I can't talk now.
I gotta go.
Of course I love you.
You think I'd buy you
diamond earrings if I didn't...
Where is my money?
Okay, okay, listen, listen,
I just...
I just maybe kind of
spent it all.
You know?
No, no, no, please, please, wait!
I'll give you the money.
I'll get you...
I'll get you $100,000!
Where are you
going to get that kind of money?
Moon! Okay?
Moon's got my money.
Who is this Moon?
All creatures great and small,
welcome to the Moon Theater.
I am your host,
Buster Moon, and...
Okay.
Behold!
The very first stage lit
entirely by...
squid power.
Flashing
Lights, lights, lights
Flashing...
Yeah!
Beautiful work, guys.
Now just follow me on the beat.
Flashing
Lights, lights, lights...
And as you can see,
this is no ordinary theater.
This is a palace of wonder and magic.
He's done it!
He's really done it, Nana!
Oh, goodness.
Now welcome our first contestant.
Which one of you is Moon?
Hey, hey, hey,
you can't just barge in here.
You know this guy?
- Mike?
- Right.
Mike here says you got his money
and it's in that box.
No, no, no, no, no,
just hold on a moment here.
That's prize money,
and it's not Mike's
unless he wins it fair and...
- Give him the money!
- Okay, okay.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, take it.
The whole chest.
It's yours, okay?
All right here.
Open it.
Open it? I... No. Me?
Open it!
Okay, no, I...
I just don't...
I don't have the keys,
so maybe you can come
back later?
Get out of the way!
No, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no.
Wait!
Hey, hey, there you go.
Big guy with a bat.
Who needs keys, right?
All right, well, let...
let's get this thing
squared up now.
What the...?
That's it?
That's all there is?
He lied.
- Moon lied to us all.
- Well, wait a second.
- I can explain. Okay?
- He's your problem, not me.
This is just a prop.
So, where's the $100,00?
You're kidding.
What's the big idea?
What a huge waste of everyone's...
This... This was just...
Buster, look out!
I'm stuck!
Buster, it's falling!
Let go!
Hey!
Okay, okay, okay, steady, girl.
Steady...
No, no, no, no...!
Is everyone okay?
Nana!
I'm so sorry. I just...
No, no, no, no, no, don't...
Don't go!
Has anyone seen my glass eye?
Oh, it...
it's right here, Miss Crawly.
I've got it.
Look out!
Once there was a way
To get back homeward
No.
Once there was a way
To get back home
Oh, Dad.
I'm so sorry.
Boy, you're gonna
- Carry that weight
- Where is Mike?
He must be dead.
- Carry that weight
- Come on, let's go!
A long time
Boy, you're gonna
- Carry that weight
- Mommy, where are you?
Carry that weight
Oh, my gosh.
- A long time
- Help! Help! - Hold on!
Mommy's here!
I'm standing
at the scene right now, Judy,
and I can tell you it is a miracle
anyone survived
this unbelievable disaster.
Golden slumbers
Fill your eyes
Sleep, pretty darling
Do not cry
And I will sing
A lullaby.
Yeah, Buster Moon certainly
brought down the house
once and for all today.
And, although Mr. Moon has not
been available for questions,
unconfirmed reports suggest
he was responsible
for building a water tank
that exploded
and flooded the building.
I've been told the 250 squid
who had been part of
Moon's display
are, in fact, employees...
- Eddie?
- of three-star restaurant Les Calmars.
There's someone at the door.
And that none of them were harmed
during the incident.
Whether they will be returning
to their usual work is not yet...
Oh, no.
Mr. Moon?
Come on, Moon,
you can't just hide out
in your buddy's pool house.
Yeah, we just want to make sure
you're all right, that's all.
- Hey, Mr. Moon.
- You okay?
Guys, look, I'm sorry
about what happened,
and the prize money and...
Oh, it's okay.
No, none of this is okay.
At least we're all in one piece.
Yeah, and you know what,
I bet we can find
some other place to put
the show on.
- Right?
- Yeah.
The show?
Guys, I'm done.
- Are you serious?
- What do you mean, done?
Come on!
Didn't you see this? Huh?
Look, it says
I'm a danger to society.
- What?
- Gah!
A deluded, washed-up charlatan
who never had a hit in his career.
Oh, come on,
you don't believe all that.
Yeah, I do.
Listen, you're not the only one
who lost something here.
- We all did.
- Ja!
I mean, I lost any chance
of ever speaking
to my dad again over this show.
- Sorry.
- Oh, Mr. Moon, don't...
Ah, forget about it.
What is this?
I don't understand.
Come on, let's get out of here.
Mr. Moon?
Meena, please.
I baked a cake for you
'cause, well,
I know you're sad right now
and probably afraid to try
again and...
Yeah, I am afraid.
I'm afraid that this...
this, me, right now,
this is who I am.
This is...
This is my lot for life...
That I'm not the guy
that my dad wanted me to be,
not by a million miles.
But you told me...
What? What? What did I say?
Well, you know,
don't let fear stop you
from doing the thing you love.
Ah, come... That's just
a bunch of stupid, corny...
- No, it's not.
- What, you really believe
that you're gonna be a singer?
Well, yeah, maybe.
Well, then you're just
as big a fool as I am!
Look, kid.
You and me, we're both afraid
for good reason.
Right, 'cause deep down
we know...
we just don't have what it takes.
- Wake me up
- I'm awake, I'm awake!
Before you go go,
'cause I'm not planning on...
- Hey, Buster.
- Hey, Eddie.
Man, where'd you go?
Are you okay?
Listen, could you meet me
at the corner
of Dinsdale and Lemington?
Now?
Yeah, please.
And could you...
could you bring me
a spare Speedo?
Speedo?
Hey, Miss Crawly.
Oh, hello, Eddie.
Hey.
Did you bring the Speedo?
- The... Oh, yeah, here.
- Great.
You're a real pal, Eddie.
Oh, our first customer.
Miss Crawly, fill the bucket.
Be right with you, sir.
Wait.
What are you doing?
The only other job I know.
Just glad my dad isn't here
to see this.
Miss Crawly, if you would...
Thanks.
Well, gotta go to work.
I'll see you around, Eddie.
Come on!
I ain't got all day!
Yeah, yeah...
Ah, forget it.
Too slow, dude.
One moment, please, sir.
Well, you know the good thing
about hitting rock bottom?
There's only one way left to go,
and that's up.
Come on.
You wash, I'll dry.
Thank you, Miss Crawly.
Hallelujah
Hallelujah...
I did my best,
it wasn't much
Buster, where are you going?
I couldn't feel,
so I tried to touch
I've told the truth
I didn't
Come to fool you
And even though
it all went wrong
I'll stand before
the Lord of Song
With nothing on my tongue
But hallelujah
Hallelujah
Hallelujah...
I...
Do you think you could
sing like that
in front of a real
audience?
I don't know, but I want to try.
Good.
'Cause I want to see it.
We are? Seriously?
Oh, my gosh! Okay.
Okay, yes, I'll be right over.
Hello?
Oh, hello, Mr. Moon.
Some say he's the worst showman
this city's ever seen.
Some say he's a walking disaster.
A loose cannon.
Well, tomorrow night,
the name Buster Moon will go down
in entertainment history
once and for all,
as he and this bunch
of bumbling amateurs
attempt to restage the show
that brought down his theater.
Pressure pushing down on me
Pressing down on you
No man ask for
Under pressure
That burns a building down
Splits a family in two,
puts people on streets
That's okay
It's the terror of knowing
what this world is about
Watching some good friends
screaming, let me out!
Pray tomorrow takes me higher
Pressure on people,
people on streets
Ah, don't you worry, Mike.
All is forgiven.
Just glad you're back
in one piece.
Oh, yeah, you're too kind,
Mr. Moon.
And the... the prize money?
It's... I mean, it's...
it's real this time, right?
There is no prize money,
'cause there's no competition.
Tonight you're singing
for yourselves.
Two minutes, everybody.
Final checks.
Singing for ourselves?
Unbelievable.
What, what, what is...?
Who's he...?
This is crazy.
I'm out of here.
Hello!
We're...
We're putting on a show here.
- Hey! - Come on.
- You all should come and see it.
You! Come on!
Come on, fella!
It's going to be really good.
Hey. How's our new stagehand
getting on?
- He's learning fast.
- All set and standing by!
I love this headset!
The audience are
in their seats, Mr. Moon.
Great!
- Caspar!
- That's all?
Get your pants back on, young man!
Please, you guys, please.
Please sit down!
Hey, put your shoes back on right now!
Zoe, I saw that! Stop it!
And, Leo, that is disgusting!
Well, John,
I've covered many disasters
for this network,
but this is sure to...
Oh, oh, they're about to start.
Okay, guys, listen up.
Look, I gotta tell you...
there's not much of an audience
out there tonight.
But you know what?
It doesn't matter.
It really doesn't.
'Cause tonight is our night.
And whatever happens,
I just want you all to know
how proud I am to be
a part of this with you.
Good luck, Mr. Moon.
Good luck, every...
Sorry.
Just jumped the cue there.
Don't worry.
I'm gonna get the hang of this.
Here we go.
All creatures great and small,
welcome to...
Oh, hello there.
Great.
Welcome to our newly
refurbished, open-air theater.
Yes, I am your host,
Buster Moon...
- You ready, big guy?
- Ja!
I'm, like, totally ready.
All right.
Let's do this.
Gunter and Rosita!
I stay out too late
Got nothing in my brain
That's what people say
I go on too many dates
But I can't make them stay
At least that's what people say
That's what people say
Are you getting this?
But I keep cruising
Can't stop, won't stop moving
It's like I got this music
In my mind saying,
it's gonna be all right
I never miss a beat
I'm lightning on my feet
And that's what they don't see
That's what they don't see
Ja, ja, ja
'Cause the players gonna play,
play, play, play, play
And the haters gonna hate,
hate, hate, hate, hate, baby
I'm just gonna shake,
shake, shake, shake, shake
I shake it off, I shake it off
Players gonna play,
play, play, play, play
And the haters gonna hate,
hate, hate, hate, hate...
Aren't they great?
What, are you kidding me?
It's like watching Jell-O
dancing around.
Like you could do
any better, pip-squeak.
All right, all right, all right.
Hey!
You want to see something great?
I'll show you great.
Heartbreakers gonna break
Fakers gonna fake
I'm just gonna shake
I shake it off, I shake it off
Shake it off, shake it off
I shake it off
- Yeah, Mommy!
- Gunter and Rosita!
Kids, no.
Back to your seats.
- The show's still...
- Okay, okay.
Norman!
All right! Piggy power!
That was great!
Well, it seems I'm not
the only one who actually
enjoyed that.
Crowds are beginning
to arrive at the scene.
Help!
I'm so sorry, Mr. Moon.
Johnny, you're on next.
You could never know what it's like
Your blood like winter
freezes just like ice
And there's a cold, lonely
light that shines from you
You'll wind up like the wreck
You hide behind that mask
you use
And did you think this fool
could never win?
What is that?
Turn it down, will you?
I got a taste of love
in a simple way...
Oi, didn't you hear me?
I said turn it...
- You just fade away
- Johnny?
Don't you know, I'm still standing
Better than I ever did
Looking like a true survivor
- Johnny.
- Feeling like a little kid
- It's Johnny! That's my son!
- And I'm still standing
After all this time
Picking up the pieces of my life
- My son.
- Without you on my mind
I'm still standing
Yeah, yeah, yeah
- What the...?
- Hey, hey!
Once I never could hope to win
- Hey, hey, hey!
- You starting down the road
Leaving me again
The threats you made
were meant to cut me down
And if our love was just a circus
You'd be a clown by now
Don't you know, I'm still standing
Better than I ever did
Looking like a true survivor
Feeling like a little kid
And I'm still standing
After all this time
Picking up the pieces of my life
Without you on my mind
I'm still standing
Yeah, yeah, yeah
What about that, huh?
Give it up for Johnny, folks.
Yeah!
Johnny! Johnny!
What's with the face?
You were great.
They loved you.
Yeah, thanks, Rosita.
All right.
Welcome to all you newcomers.
You are just in time
to meet a teenager
who was recently dumped
by her boyfriend.
I know, right?
But she's gonna chase
those blues away
with a song of her very own.
Allow me to introduce
the singing sensation, Ash.
Judith?
You are all trespassing
on private property.
- What?!
- And you will leave right now.
I didn't... No, no, no,
no, no, no, Judith...
All of you.
I followed my heart into the fire
Got burned,
got broken down by desire
I tried, I tried,
but the smoke in my eyes
Left me blurry
Blurry and blind
I picked all the pieces
Up off the ground
Got dirt on my fingers,
but that's gone now
- Got the glue in my hands
- I am calling the police.
I'm sticking to the plan,
sticking to the plan
That says I can do
anything at all
I can do anything at all
This is my kiss good-bye
You can stand alone
and watch me fly
'Cause nothing's
keeping me down
Gonna let it all out
Come on and say it right now,
right now, right now...
Seriously?
She's not even that good.
Yeah, yeah, totally.
This is my big hello
'Cause I'm here
and never letting go
I can finally see
It's not just a dream
When you set it all free,
all free, all free
You set it all free
This is my big hello
'Cause I'm here
and never letting go
I can finally see
it's not just a dream
When you set it all free,
all free, all free
You set it all free.
You guys okay?
Ash! Ash! Ash! Ash!
Ash! Ash! Ash!
What about that?
We just witnessed the birth
of a genuine rock star!
Moon, you...
you've got some stuck here.
He may be tiny,
but there is no denying
his enormous talent.
Would you please welcome
to the stage Mike.
What are you doing back here?
Relax, sweetheart.
Just came back
to show you bozos
how it's really done.
Now, watch this.
And now
The end is near
And so I face
The final curtain
My friend
I'll say it clear
And state my case
Of which I'm certain
I've lived
- A life that's full
- Boss! That is him!
That is Mike!
I've traveled each
And every highway
And more, much more than this
I did it
My way
Regrets
I've had a few
But then again
Too few to mention
I did
What I had to do
And saw it through
Without exemption
I'm so proud of you.
I planned
Each charted course
Each careful step
Along the byway
And more,
much more than this
I did it
My way
You gotta be kidding me.
For what is a mouse
What has he got
If not himself
Then he has not
To say the things
He truly feels
And not the words
Of one who kneels
The record shows
I took the blows
Negative.
I've lost sight of the suspect
and am terminating pursuit.
And did it
My way...
That pip-squeak really was great.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Oh, please.
You're too kind, really.
Look at me.
I'm turning red.
Stop. I can't take it.
Keep... Keep it coming.
Well, I better get back.
They'll be wondering
what happened to me.
You'll visit me though, yeah?
Yeah, course I will.
See you, son.
We have one final act
for you tonight.
Would you please welcome
to the stage
for her first ever
live appearance...
Meena.
Meena?
Is she coming out?
Meena, what's wrong?
Are you okay?
I can't move.
I'm... I'm terrified.
Give me your hand, kid.
Okay, deep breaths.
Deep breaths.
And remember what I told you.
You will not feel afraid anymore
if you just start singing.
Meena! Meena!
I can do it... Okay.
Oh! Oh, I'm so sorry.
Okay.
Sing.
Everybody's got a thing
But some don't know
How to handle it
Always reaching out
In vain
Accepting the things
Not worth having
But don't you worry
'Bout a thing
Don't you worry
'Bout a thing, mama
'Cause I'll be standing on
The side when
You check it out
They say your style
Of life's a drag
And that you must go
other places
Just don't you feel too bad
When you get fooled
by smiling faces
Don't you worry
'bout a thing
'bout a thing, baby
'Cause I'll be standing
on the side
When you check it
Out...
When you get off
Your trip...
Guys, guys, wait.
We can talk this over, right?
We're all reasonable
individuals here.
Get in! Quick!
Oh, thank you, sweetheart.
Whew! That was close.
Yeah.
Everybody needs a change
A chance to check out
the new, yeah
You're the only one who sees
The changes you take
yourself through
Don't you worry
'bout a thing
Come on!
Don't you worry
'bout a thing, mama
'Cause I'll be standing
I'll be standing
For you
Don't you worry
'bout a thing
- Meena! You did it! - She did it!
- That's my granddaughter!
Go, go!
Oh, Dad,
I wish you could see this.
Once there was a way
To get back homeward
To get back home
Sleep, pretty darling
Do not cry
And I will sing
A lullaby...
Everybody ready?
All creatures great and small,
welcome to the New Moon Theater.
See the girl
with the diamonds in her shoes
She walks around
like she's got nothing to lose
Yeah, she's a go-getter,
she's everybody's type
She's the queen of the city,
but she don't believe the hype
She's got her own elevation,
holy motivation
So I wrote some letters
out in big bold type
I got faith in you, baby
I got faith in you now
And you've been such a,
such a good friend to me
Know that I love you somehow
I met you, hallelujah
I got faith
See the boy with
the Stevie Wonder swag
Ain't got a clue
all the magic that he has
He's a go-getter,
he's everybody's type
Gonna make it my mission
make him feel all right
He's a twelve on a ten-point,
rockin' out to his joint
Just say the word
'cause I could sing all night
I got faith in you, baby
I got faith in you now
And you've been such a,
such a good friend to me
Know that I love you somehow
I met you, hallelujah
I got faith
I get her running
and my mind goes crazy
I think about you
morning, noon, night and day
I get her running
and my mind goes crazy
Crazy girl
I met you, hallelujah
I got faith
I got faith in you, baby
I got faith in you now
And you've been such a,
such a good friend to me
Know that I love you somehow
I met you, hallelujah
I got faith
Faith, faith, faith, baby
I got faith in you, baby
I got faith in you now
And you've been such a,
such a good friend to me
Know that I love you somehow,
I do
I met you, hallelujah
I got
Faith...
Faith!