Now it's always once upon a time
in New York City.
It's a big old, bad old, tough old town.
It's true.
But beginnings are contagious there.
They're always settin' stages there.
They're always turnin' pages there for you.
Ain't it great the way it all begins in New York City.
Let me have one. Please.
Right away you're makin' time.
And makin' friends.
No one cares where you were yesterday.
If they pick you out you're on your way.
To a once upon a time.
That never ends.
So, Oliver, don't be shy.
Get out there and go and try.
Believin' that you're the guy.
They're dyin' to see.
'Cause a dream's no crime.
Not once upon a time.
Once upon a time in New York City.
If it's always once upon a time in New York City.
Why does nightfall find ya feelin' so alone.
How could anyone stay starry-eyed.
When it's rainin' cats and dogs outside.
And the rain is saying "Now you're on your own".
So, Oliver, don't be scared.
Though yesterday no one cared.
They're gettin' your place prepared.
Where you wanna be.
Keep your dream alive.
Dreamin' is still how the strong survive.
Once upon a time in New York City.
Keep your dream alive.
Dreamin' is still how the strong survive.
Once upon a time in New York City.
Keep your dream alive.
Dreamin' is still how the strong survive.
Once upon a time in New York City.
And it's always once upon a time.
In New York City.
- Forty seconds.
- All right. Here we go.
You see the feet walkin'
down the street in the fast lane.
Walkin' on the street where they goin'.
Just makin' a move tryin' to survive.
Find a way or not to stay alive.
Cool cat in a cruel world knows
good from bad, his mind is in a swirl.
Got to look out and open your eyes.
If you're in a jam you got to realize.
- You're in the fast lane.
- Wait, wait, wait, wait a minute.
- In the fast lane.
- Wait, wait, wait.
- Hi. Sorry I'm late.
- That's all right.
Come on, sweetheart. We're late.
You can play with the kitty
some other time, honey. Come on.
Hey, 'scusa me.
Don't ya see I'm pushin'
somethin' here? Thank you.
Hey, come on, folks! Step right up.
Get your hot dogs.
The best hot dogs in New York.
Hey, it's a beautiful day, eh?
Come on, folks.
Step right up.
Hey! Go on. Get outta here. Shoo!
Get outta here. Go on, kitty.
Get your sausages.
All right, let's go, folks.
Step right up.
I got the hottest dogs in the Big Apple!
Hmm.
Psst. Psst.
Hiya.
- Hmph!
- Ooh. La-de-da.
Hey! Hey, get off of me!
- What's the matter with you?
- Well, well.
I said get outta here.
Looks like Louie's got a visitor.
Could be time for the Dodge to turn
this into a total "cat-astrophe."
Get off me! Get outta here. Go on! Shoo!
Ooh, you sure picked the wrong guy
to get hot dogs from, kid.
- Get away from me!
- Whoa! Chill out, man.
I don't eat cats. It's too much fur.
I've been watching you,
and I think you're in serious need
of some professional guidance.
Now what do ya say we team up
and change old Louie's mind
about sharing those hot dogs?
I'm not goin' back there again.
Hey. It'd be a snap, kid.
I'm an expert at these things.
All you gotta do is learn some moves.
- Moves?
- You know. Tempo.
Ooo-cha-ba. A rhythm.
This city's got a beat.
You gotta hook into it.
And once you got the beat, you can do anything.
- Loan?
- "Absitively posolutely."
The man you see before you
is affectionately known as "Old Louie."
A well-known enemy of the four-legged world.
Our mission, cat, is to liberate
those all-beef kosher franks
and hightail it outta here.
- Startin' to feel that rhythm?
- Well, uh...
Yeah! Yeah!
I do feel it! When are we gonna get
those hot dogs?
Right now.
Hey! Dog.-
Hey! Get outta here! Hey!
Hey! Hey. Get outta there!
I'll get you!
Kitty!
Hey, you really got that rhythm, kid.
Uh... Yeah?
We were good, huh?
So when are we gonna eat?
- We?
- Yeah. I'm starvin'.
Listen, kid. I hate to break it to ya,
but the dynamic duo is now the dynamic uno.
What do ya mean?
What I mean is,
our partnership is herewith dissolved.
But, wait! Wait. You're not being fair!
Fairs are for tourists, kid. Consider it
a free lesson in street savoir faire
from New York's coolest quadruped.
Check ya later.
Hey, wait! I helped you get those!
Half of those are mine!
Ya want 'em? Come and get 'em.
Uh-huh
But I'm warnin' ya, kid.
One minute I'm in Central Park
Then I'm down on Delancey Street
What the... Hey!
Say, from the Bowery to St. Mark's
There's a syncopated beat
Like I said Woo-hoo
Woo-hoo-oo
I'm street wise
I can improvise
Said ooo-hoo woo-hoo-oo
I'm street smart
I've got New York City heart
Why should I worry
Why should I care
I may not have a dime
But I got street savoir faire
Why should I worry
Why should I care
It's just be-bopulation
I got street savoir faire
Mmm-hmm
The rhythm of the city
Boy, once you get it down
Then you can own this town
You can wear the crown
Why should I worry
Tell me why should I care
Say, I may not have a dime
Oh, but I got street savoir faire
Why should I worry
Why should I care
It's just doo-wopulation
And I got street savoir faire
Everything goes, everything fits
They love me at the Chelsea
They adore me at the Ritz
Why should I worry
Why should I care Yeah
And even when I cross that line
I got street savoir faire
Woo-hoo
Said ooo-ooo woo-hoo-oo
Whoa!
Woo-hoo-hoo-hoo-oo
Woo-ooo woo-hoo-oo
Woo-hoo woo-ooo-oo
Come on. Where you goin'? No! No!
Woo-hoo woo-hoo-oo
Woo-hoo-woo-ooo-oo
Woo-hoo-woo-hoo-oo
Woo-hoo woo-hoo-oo
Huh?
Tito! Stop that racket!
I'm trying to watch this show.
There would have been a time for such a word.
Oh, tomorrow, tomorrow and tomorrow creeps...
In this petty pace from day to day
and all our yesterdays
have lighted fools the way to dusty death.
Hey, Frankie, whatcha watchin'?
Hey, does he get the girl? I mean, what happens?
Shut up, you little rodent.
Hey, man, this stuff is boring, man.
Come on, let's watch some boxing.
I wanna see some action.
Hey, Frankie. Que' peso'?
You're getting slow, man.
My name is Francis.
Francis. Not Frank.
Not Frankie. Francis.
No kidding, man? Hey, so what did
you bring in today, "Frahn-cees"?
It's none of your business,
you intrusive little pipsqueak.
Look what I got.
Oh, good show, Einstein.
Now all we need is the court and the net.
You think this place is big enough?
Hey, come on. What we need is
some good quality stuff, man.
- Check it out.
- Oh, shredded leather.
Shredded what? What you talkin' about,
man? That's a primo wallet, man.
- Rubbish, you mean.
- All right, that does it, Frankie, man!
You insulted my pride! That means death!
- Behold. The runt of the litter.
- Cut it out, you two.
- Frankie! Frankie!
- Arf!
Fagin's not gonna be too happy about this.
So, Francis, you got the food, right?
- Well, no. I...
- Ooh, Frankie.
Frankie. It was your turn to get the food today.
- It's newspaper burritos again!
- Hey.
Whoa. Whoa. Cool it, Dodger fans.
I'd like to introduce you to... Your dinner.
- Ia Dodger.
- Hot dogs! All right, Dodger man!
You remain our preeminent benefactor.
Yeah. And you're okay, too.
So how'd you do it this time, Dodgie baby?
Let me tell you, Rita. It was tough.
Only I could have done it.
Did you have to fight, man?
Did you fight? How many were there?
Picture the city.
Eighth and Broadway. The crowds hustling.
The traffic roaring. The hot dogs are sizzling.
I love a story with food in it.
Enter Dodger, one bad puppy.
Not just out for himself, but community minded.
But he's not the only one out there.
Enter the opposition.
A greedy, ugly, psychotic monster...
With razor-sharp claws, dripping fangs,
and nine lives, all of them hungry.
He comes at me, eyes burning.
I knew my time had come.
Suddenly...
Gang war! Gang war!
Watch out! Here comes a gang war!
- Help!
- Take cover!
Well, what is it?
Hey, man, check it out.
Ay, it's a alien!
Cool it, guys. It's just a cat.
- Mi madre, un gato!
- Felis domesticus!
Now, how'd you find this place, cat?
I followed this dog.
He's lying! He's lying! He's lying! He's lying!
Shut up, Tito!
- Why would a cat follow a dog?
- Yeah?
I... I just wanted some of the sausages
I helped him get.
He's a spy, man! Come on,
let's eat him. You're dead meat, kitty.
I... I saw him come down.
Hey! That's... Hey, that's him! Over there.
- Hmm?
- Hey, kitty. What took you so long?
Relax, kid.
Dodger, razor-sharp claws?
- Dripping fangs?
- I kind of like those burning eyes.
Hey, keep it down, guys. The game's on.
Oh, boy, Dodger.
Top dog has to get help from a cat.
Hey, Tito, cool it, man.
Come on. Let's see this big,
bad kitty fight in action.
Hey, Tito, look!
Oh, boy! Dog pile!
Oh, what a bunch of overgrown... Oof!
All right. That's it.
All right, all right, knock it off! Enough!
What's the matter with you guys?
Don't you understand?
Sykes will be here any minute.
And I don't have...
No, no, no, no, no!
No, no. Stop it.
No. No. No licking.
What a joke! All right, settle down.
Sykes!
All right, all right. I'm coming.
I'll be right there.
You guys, listen. Don't let me down.
What do you got? Let's see what you got.
It's worthless! What have you done?
Oh, how are we ever going
to pay Sykes off with a pussycat?
Oh.
Look who's here, kids.
Company. Nice doggies.
I was just on my way out.
You guys miss us?
Mr. Sykes. I, uh...
He's gonna kill me.
Hello. Oh, lovely evening.
I was just saying this to your two lovely
purebred Dobermans.
The money, Fagin.
Actually, I've got something
much better than money.
Some luxury items that should make
a considerable dent in my debt to you.
Oh, my! You waxed your car, didn't you?
Did they use the buffer on it,
because I can see myself.
Oh, boy. Oh, boy. Oh, boy.
I don't want your garbage, Fagin!
Oh, please, Sykes. Oh, please. Oh, please.
I don't think you grasp
the severity of the situation.
Oh, no! Oh, no, I did grasp it.
This is how I grasp. Look.
Accident.
Accident! Ooh-hoo-hoo!
- Mr.- Fagin!
- Sorry.
Now, I lent you money and I don't see it.
Do you know what happens when
I don't see my money, Fagin?
People get hurt.
People like you get hurt.
Do I make myself clear?
Clear! Perfectly clear!
Ya know, Rita, I can't figure out,
why you'd rather hang around a dump like this,
when you could be living uptown
with a class act like myself.
Isn't it rather dangerous to use one's
entire vocabulary in a single sentence?
Hey, Frankie, get down,
brother. You bad, man.
Hey, you got something to say to me, fat boy?
Come on, you guys don't scare me.
I'll kill you both.
Come on, let me at 'em!
I'll kill 'em! I'll kill 'em!
Go ahead. Let him go.
Why don't you pick on someone your own size?
- Like you, old man?
- Hey, Roscoe.
Roscoe, is this us losing our sense of humor?
Nah. I ain't lost my sense of humor.
See? I find that funny.
Oh, please.
Please. Oh, please!
Three sunrises. Three sunsets.
Three days, Fagin.
Three days. Three, three, three. That's nine.
- Nine?
- No, Fagin.
- Three.
- Three!
Oh, you mean, just three days?
Oh, my goodness!
Oh, I'm having a bad day!
Hey, hey, Roscoe. Look what I found.
Forget it, Desoto. We gotta go.
I like cats. I like to eat 'em.
Get out of my way, Dodger.
That's enough, Roscoe.
Run along, Roscoe.
Your master's calling.
Come on, Desoto.
We ain't finished, Dodger.
You guys are gonna pay for this,
starting with that cat.
Oh, yeah? You guys don't scare me!
Come on and say it to my face!
Come on, come on, come on, come on, come on!
Yeah, those creeps'll think twice
before hassling us, man.
All right, kid. What'd I tell you guys?
OI' Dodge can really pick 'em, huh?
Ooh, three days.
How am I ever gonna come up
with all that money?
What's the use? I'll never get out
from under that maniac.
My days are numbered
and the number is three.
It's hopeless.
Thanks, guys.
That reminds me.
I saw Desoto's nose. Who did that?
You? You.
That took a lot of guts.
We've never had a cat in the gang before.
We can use all the help we can get.
Ahhh. All right. Time for bed.
We've got a big day tomorrow.
Aww, no.
Oh, all right.
But just one chapter tonight.
Um, let's see.
Here we are. Here we are. Chapter 7.
"Sparky stopped
and he rolled in a field of wildflowers.
"The dandelions tickled his nose,
"till he laughed out loud.
"And then something caught his eye.
"It was Bumper the rabbit.
"Sparky jumped to his feet,
"and ran toward Bumper barking loudly."
Woof. Woof.
Well, you try it sometime.
Ruff! R-Ruff!
Well, that's because you're a dog.
"Sparky knew that Bumper would run
"and that he could chase him over the field.
"But Sparky would never catch him or hurt him
"because Sparky was not that kind of a dog."
This is the big one.
We've got two days to do or die.
Dodger, you keep an eye
on the new kid. Show him the ropes.
I don't wanna put any undue pressure on you,
but, as you march off to do your duty,
I want you to keep one thing in mind.
Dead men do not buy dog food!
So, big smiles and get out there,
and fetch!
All right. If Mr. Sykes don't see
some cold, hard cash soon,
we are Doberman chow.
Come on.
We'll start on Columbus Avenue.
- What kind of work do we do, anyway?
- Investment banking, man.
Didn't you read about us
in the Wall Street Journal?
- Really?
- Yes. Captains of industry.
Gosh! Can I be one too?
Hey, when you got your pals, you got all ya need.
Okay, Dodge.
We gotta clean you up, child,
and give you some on-the-job training.
Ooo, yeah Now listen up
You got a lot to learn
And if you don't learn you don't eat
But if you're tough and always use your head
You'll feel right at home on the street
When you got talent Everything is free
Watch how we do things Ooo, I guarantee
You're gonna see how the best survive
We make an art out of staying alive
If you do just as you're told
These are streets of gold
Every boulevard is a miracle mile
You'll take the town and you'll take it with style
If you play it brave and bold
These are streets of gold
Hello? What have we here?
- All right! A chauffeur shuffle!
- Listen up.
Einstein, gimme a fender bender at two lights.
Tito. You're in charge of electronics.
Rita and I'll work the crowd. Francis...
I know. My public awaits.
Hey, but what about me? What do I do?
You help Tito.
All right! Come on, gato.
Uncle Tito will show you how it's done.
Ready? Go!
Winston, listen to this.
"After a little sightseeing, we left Paris by car
"for the con, confer..."
- Conference, Jennifer.
- Oh, yes. Conference.
"In Rome on Wednesday.
"Jenny, I'm afraid your father
and I won't be able to make it..."
Is there anything wrong, Jenny?
Are your parents all right?
- They're staying longer.
- Oh, don't worry.
I'm sure they'll be home
for your birthday.
No.
- What was that?
- I... I don't know.
But... But now, don't be alarmed.
- I'll be right back.
- Run, Sparky. Go find Bumper.
Why me? Today of all days.
Hey, check it out, man. Beep, beep.
Hey, forget Fagin, man.
Let's take this baby to Atlantic City.
What have I done? Poor thing.
You oughta be ashamed of yourself!
I'm sure he's just fine.
Harming that poor...
Probably just a little stunned.
Run along, little fellow. Go on, now. Shoo.
- Hey, Tito. What can I do?
- Well, uh...
Why don't you be a lookout, man?
Yeah, that's it. Be a lookout.
Okay. What is a lookout?
Ay! Look, just look out the window.
Make sure it's still daylight, okay?
Hey. Hey, Tito. Tito, there's somethin' back there.
Hey, stop hasslin' me, man.
I only got one more wire, okay?
But... But...
What's goin' on here?
Let's get outta here!
Oh, you poor kitty. Here. Let me help you.
Jenny, are you all right?
Where's the kid?
He must still be in the car, man.
Oh, that poor little kid.
You were supposed to keep an eye on him, Tito!
Yeah.
Well, it's hard to watch anything
when you're getting barbecued, man.
What are we gonna do, Dodge?
Tito, come with me.
The rest of you, get back to Fagin.
Now, really, Jenny. We can't
just take in a stray off the street.
But look at the poor thing.
Winston, he's half starved.
Ah. I know you're growing attached
to the little fellow,
but do try to understand.
Your parents left me responsible for you.
They won't mind. Really.
Don't worry, kitty. I'll take care of you.
Georgette is not going to like this.
Rise and shine, Georgette. Your public awaits.
Girl, we've got work to do
Pass me the paint
And glue
Perfect isn't easy
But it's me
When one knows the world is watching
One does what one must
Some minor adjustments, darling
Not for my vanity but for humanity
Each little step a pose
See how the breeding shows Ooh!
Sometimes it's too much for even me
But when all the world says yes
Then who am I to say no
Don't ask a mutt to strut like a showgirl
No, girl, ya need a pro
Not a flea or a flaw
Take a peek at that paw
La-de-da-da
Perfection becomes me N' est-ce pas'?
Unrivaled, unruffled
I'm beauty unleashed, yeah
Jaws drop, hearts stop
So classic and classy We're not talkin' Lassie
Aaa...
Aaa... Ooo...
Ooo...
Though many covet my bone and bowl
They're barkin' up the wrong tree
You pretty pups all over the city
I have your hearts and you have my pity
Pretty is nice but still it's just pretty
Perfect, my dears
Is me
Ooo!
Wait till you taste this.
It's a secret recipe I just invented.
What on earth...
My goodness! Jenny!
Don't you think a tin of kitty chow
would have sufficed?
Nonsense. He'll love this.
Now, young lady.
I really think we should've waited
until your parents...
Ugh!
Oh, bother!
And for ze kitty, the house specialty.
Ia Jenny avec Cocoa Krispies.
Mmm.
- Jenny, it's your parents!
- Yeah! Wait till I tell 'em!
Oh, yes, sir. I do assure you
everything is absolutely hunky...
Georgette, I wouldn't go in there if I were you.
- Uh, everything's fine here.
- They're gonna be so excited.
Here she is now.
A cat!
What is the meaning of this?
Winston!
I guess I'll have to handle this myself.
- Hello.
I, um, hope you won't think me rude,
but do you happen to know
out of whose bowl you're eating?
- Yours?
- Ooh!
Aren't you a clever kitty?
And do you have any idea whose home this is?
I thought it was Jenny's.
Well, it may be Jenny's house,
but everything from the doorknobs down is mine!
Oh, Georgette. I see you've met Oliver.
Isn't he cute?
I've got great news. Mom and Dad
just said I could keep him.
I'm sure you two are gonna be the best of friends.
Now for $200..
- Where's the kid?
- We tailed him all the way up the park.
- We never had a chance.
- You should see this place.
There's gotta be maybe 200 people livin' there.
We can't let the kid take the heat for us.
Yeah, man. If we don't get him,
they're gonna torture that kid.
What in heaven's name are we waiting for?
But what about Fagin?
Alas, our beleaguered benefactor,
bearing the brunt of our futile endeavors.
Gimme a break. Speak English, Frankie.
Francis. Francis. Francis!
All right, cool it!
Now we got work to do.
First, we'll spring the kid.
Then we'll take care of the old man. All right?
Yeah! That's right, man! He's family. He's blood.
Hear, hear!
Okay, troops. Our mission begins at daybreak.
Einstein, go up to the door. Francis, you're our...
Oh, Jennifer. I don't hear any practicing!
All right, Winston. I gotta practice now, kitty.
Oh, you wanna practice too.
You and me together
Will be forever
You'll see
We two can be good company
You and me
Yes, together we two
Hmph!
Together that's you
Forever with me
We'll always be good company
You and me
Yes, together we'll be
You and me together
Will be forever
You'll see
We'll always be good company
You and me
Just wait and see
Good night, Oliver.
Bye, Winston. Good-bye, Oliver.
Hi, Jenny. Sit over here.
All right, listen up. We checked it out.
All we gotta do is...
Oh, man! He's dead meat now!
I'll handle that ruffian.
Body slam! Body slam! Oh, come on, you fool!
Hit him! Hit him! Oh, bother.
Einy. Get outta there!
Huh?
Yes? Who is it?
Oh, my-
You!
I'll show you, you, you...
Come back here!
What...
Miralo this place. Check it out.
Chagall. Matisse.
These are all masterpieces.
Huh, this place looks pretty nice.
I mean, how bad off could it be here?
Hey, man, if this is torture,
chain me to the wall.
Tito!
We're here for the kid, remember?
Now let's get him and go.
"I love you, Oliver. Play with Georgette."
I'd like to play with him, all right!
The little fur ball!
Ooh.
Who are you? What do you want? Winston!
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Calm down.
Ooh!
Don't come any closer!
I knew this would happen one day.
You're barkin' up the wrong tree.
It's not you I'm after.
It's not? It's not!
Well, why not?
What's the problem, Spot?
Not good enough for you?
I mean, do you even know who I am?
Fifty-six blue ribbons.
Fourteen regional trophies!
Six-time national champion!
Ooh, and we're all very impressed. Right, guys?
Very impressed.
Oh!
Allow me to introduce myself. I am
Ignacio Alonzo Julio Frederico de Tito.
Get away from me, you little bug-eyed creep!
Winston!
- Excuse me, uh, sister. Who's Rex?
- None of your business!
And you, tubby, off the bed!
Get away from there, you...
- All right! That does it!
You yo-yos clear out and I mean now!
Winston!
Relax, champ.
We'll leave as soon as we get our cat.
If you think I'm intimidated by a bunch
of flea-bitten, dog-pound rejects...
Your cat?
How stupid of me. You must be
the friends he keeps talking about.
- Yes.
- Georgette.
Something's not quite right here.
Shh. Quick. Before he comes back. Follow me.
Look at him, Dodger.
Honey, let's just forget the whole thing.
No, no, you can't do that! You don't understand.
- The poor dear's so traumatized.
- Georgette.
- Huh? What?
- What is going on here?
Now get going. Hurry. Use the fire escape.
Hey, there's no time for long good-byes,
but here's something to remember me by, baby.
Ooh, I think she likes me, man.
Ooh, I could've danced all night
I could've danced all night
- You were very good.
- What?
- Nice job, Dodger.
- Hey, wait. What's goin' on, you guys?
- Just the rescue of the century.
- Rescue?
Shoulda seen Frankie handle that butler.
I was rather good, wasn't I?
And how about Tito
and Miss Six-time National Champion?
Hey, hey, but, wait.
I don't understand you guys.
- You okay, kid?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
Hey, sure he is! He's back with his Uncle Tito.
I was happy there.
Why did you guys take me away?
We rescued you, kitty.
We... We brought you home.
But, well, I have another home now.
And someone who loves me.
What do you mean, kid? You're in the gang.
- But, but...
- The gang means family.
We risked a lot to get you outta there.
Look, I'm sorry, but all I ever wanted was...
What? This place is not good enough
for you anymore?
Don't wanna mix with the riffraff?
No, no. I like you. I mean, I like...
I like every one of you, but...
But there was a little girl. I just wanna go back.
We never should've took him, Dodger.
But, Dodger, please...
You wanna leave? Fine! There's the door.
- But he just got here.
- Go on. No one's stoppin' ya.
Hey, uh, Dodger, man, uh, lighten up.
You lighten up! If he doesn't like it, let him go.
Oh, it's hopeless.
What's this?
So that's where you've been!
Looks like you're doing
all right for yourself, Oliver.
Your owner probably spends
more money on catnip
than we do on food in a month.
He's probably worried sick about you.
All alone in that big house
with only his money to comfort him.
Only his millions and millions of dollars to...
That's it! We're saved!
Oh-ho-ho. What a plan! Ah, yes!
Uh, paper! Paper! Whoo, it's so great.
Dear Mr. Rich... Ah!
Mr. Very Rich.
- Bye, Jenny!
- Oliver!
Oliver? Oliver!
Feel it. That's it. Very good.
Oliver!
Two, four, five, six, seven, eight. Oh, you love it!
Oliver, I'm home.
That's funny.
Georgette, help me find Oliver.
Oliver! Oliver!
Oh, where could he be?
Oliver?
He's not here.
Where is he? Here, kitty, kitty, kitty, kitty.
Hmm.
"Dear Mr. Very Rich Cat-owner Person."
Whoops.
"And if you don't bring the money,
"you'll never see your cat again."
Oh, no.
Georgette, something terrible has happened.
They've kidnapped Oliver.
Oh, Georgette, you loved him too.
Don't worry. We're going to get him back.
This is an airtight plan, Sykes.
Sweet and simple.
I ransom the kitty,
and you get paid in full tomorrow.
I'll even toss in a little extra
for your patience.
Whaddya say? It's my final offer.
Take it or leave it.
Yeah, Who is it'?
Oh...
Fagin, it's you. Why didn't you say so?
Oh! Good question.
But listen, if you're busy,
we can drop by some other time.
Don't be silly. Just push the door.
I said, push!
Ooh!
What do you mean? You start with the knuckles.
Ahh, Fagin. Do come in. I'll be right with you.
Yeah.
No, you don't kill him yet.
Huh? Yeah.
And then, what's the last thing you do?
You put on the cement shoes.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, that's right.
Come on. Hey, don't worry about it.
So, Fagin.
Did we bring something green
and wrinkly to make me happy?
Sykes, I've got an airtight kitty... Plan... Plan!
It's sweet and simple, the plan.
- Oh, boy, oh, boy, oh, boy.
- Let's just take this from the top.
What am I gonna do with you, Fagin?
- I've got this kitty, you see...
- Fagin.
You don't got the money.
Oh, no! Oh, no!
Oh, no, no, no! Stop! Please, Sykes, please!
Sykes, I'm getting your money tonight!
It's coming tonight!
Please. It's from a rich cat... No, I mean,
a cat from a rich family's paying... Ow!
They're coming tonight with the money
I owe you, uh, to get the cat back!
{SNAPS) - ********************
Hey, I think there's hope for you yet.
Oh-ho! I'm proud of ya, Fagin.
Yeah, you're startin' to think big.
You've got 12 hours.
And, Fagin?
This is your last chance.
Turn left, right when you get to the big propeller.
Oh, Georgette, I can't read this.
No, that... No, that's not right. It's left.
Oh, Georgette, where are we?
I think we're lost.
Stick close, Georgette. It's creepy down here.
He's late. I drew a perfectly good map.
Well, there was a few smudges on it, okay.
I went outside the line with
the green crayon, but not that much.
- Oh, Dodge.
- A child could read that map.
Hey, Rita, they never laid a paw on me.
Ooh, wait. What if he comes
and he's huge and mean?
- Excuse me, sir.
- It's the FBI!
I didn't do it! I didn't do it! I was framed!
Oh-ho-ho! Whaa...
Listen, little girl, this is a tough neighborhood.
You'd better go home.
- Ugh!
- I can't.
- I'm lost.
- Aw, gee.
Lost. Well.
I'd help you, but I'm kind of busy right now.
What're you doin' down here anyway?
I came to find my kitty.
- Your kitty?
- Somebody stole him.
But... But, uh, are you sure?
Maybe you made a mistake.
No.
No, somebody stole him and sent me this note.
- Easy, boys.
- See? Now I'm lost. Look.
I even brought this to get him back.
Oh-ho-ho-ho-hoo! You brought a piggy bank.
- That's all I have.
- That's awful.
I know. And what kind of a person
would steal a poor little kitty?
But I... I mean, maybe he...
Maybe he was up against the wall,
at the end of his rope.
He must have been a poor, desperate man.
It's still wrong!
I'm so scared. I don't know what to do.
- I don't know what to do.
- Neither do I!
Hey! Guess what?
I found a little lost kitten.
I don't know, take a look. Maybe he's yours.
Oliver! Oliver! Oh, my Oliver!
Sykes.
Sykes! I was gonna... Yaaah!
- Hey! Hey, wait! What're you doing?
- Let go!
No! No, wait! You can't do this!
Keep your mouth shut.
Consider our account closed.
Stop! Stop! Time out!
DOGS BARKING)
- Wha... What happened?
- You okay, kid?
- Jenny... He took Jenny!
- Don't worry. We'll get her back.
You will?
Hey. "Absitively," kid.
Come on, man, let's go! Come on!
- Let's get him, man!
- All right... Let's do it.
Wait! Come back! Stay. Sit. Wait!
Come back!
- Oh, man. It don't look good.
- It's all locked up, Dodger.
All right. There's gotta be some way in.
Yeah. Francis.
Now, don't cry, little girl.
They only eat when I tell them to.
- Francis, you all set?
- Farewell, Dulcinea.
- Francis!
- Peasants.
Maestro?
- Ready, kid?
- Yeah.
Go!
Oof!
Roscoe. Desoto.
Come on, Desoto.
Hey, hey, hey! There is a lady present.
Well, it's nice to see
that one of you has some manners.
After you, my little croissant.
Good grief.
And remember, quiet.
Oh!
- I broke a nail.
- Oh, balderdash.
- What'd you call my woman, man?
- Freeze!
- Yo, Tito.
- Right. I'll check it out.
Yeah. Oh, that's funny, Mr. Winston.
But I don't think you really
appreciate the situation.
Somebody could get hurt.
Why not just get the old man on the phone
and tell him it's about his daughter...
Jenny.
Okay, listen up. Tito, Francis,
I want you...
You smell that?
Yeah. Heh-heh! It's party time.
What the...
Didn't order any pizza.
Go, go, go, go, 90, 90, 90, 90!
Where are those dogs?
Oh, Oliver!
I thought I'd never see you again.
- Ahem... Gentlemen.
- What's the occasion?
- Come to rescue your little friend?
- Say good-bye, Francis.
Oh, boys!
Whoopsy-dais-Y!
All right! What a woman!
Francis, you keep an eye
on the monitors. Rita, over here.
What is this, a slumber party?
Get goin', ya stupid mutts!
Francis, is the coast clear? Francis!
Goodness!
- What're we gonna do, Dodge?
- Yo, Tito, hot-wire.
Hey, no way, Dodger, man.
I've been barbecued too many times, man.
- Good luck, Alonzo.
- Huh?
I'll be waiting.
Hey! Heigh-ho, heigh-ho
It's off to work we go
What is this?
All right, girlie. Open the door.
Come on, now.
Girlie, I'm warnin' ya.
Come on, Tito.
You just... Back up. Desoto. Come on!
- Come on.
- Yaaah!
This has all been very entertaining.
But the party is over.
Ow-oh-oh-ow!
Uh! Come on! Come on, come on! Let's go!
Fagin!
Heh-heh! Hey, man, you're ugly!
And you're uglier than him!
And you're Ugly, Part 3!
Hey, you're Revenge of the Ugly!
Ooh-hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Whoo!
Yow! Ooh-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Uh!
Mr. Fagin! Mr. Fagin, help me!
All right! Check it out! Heh!
Uh!
Help me! Oh!
Ahhh! Save me! Save me, Alonzo!
Hey, get off my back, woman! I'm driving!
Let go! Jenny, jump!
Alonzo!
Oliver?
Oliver? Oliver!
Whew!
Whoo!
Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday, dear Jenny
Don't forget to make a wish, Jennifer.
And many more
All right, anybody want some cake?
Okay, Einstein. But not the whole thing.
You got it now, baby! Yeah, left foot, right foot.
All right! Check it out! There you go. Relax, hey.
Tito, you dance divinely.
- He's cheating!
- Body slam!
Come on, hit him again.
Murder him! Twist his arm!
- Whoa!
- Foxworth residence.
- Mr. Foxworth!
- Body slam him now!
Shh-shh-shh! My goodness.
You're back tomorrow?
Oh, she'll be so surprised to see you.
Yes, good-bye, sir.
All right. Get him! Get him!
- Hit him! Come on! Murder him!
- All right, you got him!
- Pick him up! Hold him there!
- Ta-da!
- I believe that's a 10 spot, old sport.
- Now, where...
Where is that check book? Oh, look at the time.
Well, heh-heh, we better be goin'.
Indeed.
Francis, Rita, Tito, vamonos!
The streets are calling!
Now, Jennifer,
have we forgotten anything?
Oh, yeah. Thanks, everyone. The gifts were great.
Bye, Mr. Fagin, and thank you.
Oh, bye-bye, Jenny.
Come on, boys!
It's time for us to go.
Alonzo, darling, could I see you
for a moment, privately?
Privately? Ooh!
Coming, Alonzo?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah! You guys beat it.
Uh, my baby and I, uh, we gotta talk.
You know, you're not so bad
for a bug-eyed little creep.
With a little grooming...
Grooming? Uh...
That's it! We'll start with a bath.
Bath?
Let's go!
- Bye-bye.
- Oh, Oliver, we shall meet again.
- Hey, see ya 'round, kid.
- Good-bye, you guys.
Boys! Let's go!
Listen, kid, ahh,
you just want to hang out or anything...
Nee-hed. Hey, Dodger, mar.
Do you see her anywhere'?
- Hey, whoa!
- Man! I can't keep this woman off me!
- Man, I gotta get away from that chick...
- Alonzo!
- Uh, good-bye, Oliver.
Hey, you guys, wait for me, man! Hey, wait up!
Alonzo Frederico Tito,
you come back here this minute!
Hey, whoa, kid. Do you think
you can handle the champ?
Sure.
Hey! You're okay... For a cat.
We'll keep a spot open for ya in the gang...
Vice president, uptown chapter.
Later, kid.
Why should I worry
Bye-bye! Bye!
Tell me why should I care
What a delightful scoundrel.
Say, I may not have a dime
Oh, but I got street savoir faire
Why should we worry
Why should we care
We may not have a dime
But we've got street savoir faire
Why should we worry
Why should we care
It's just be-bopulation
We got street savoir faire
- Uhh-uhh-uhh-umm
- Whoo-hoo-hoo
The rhythm of the city
Boy, once you get it down
Then you can own this town
You can wear the crown
Why should we worry
Why should we care
It's just doo-wopulation
We got street savoir faire
Why should we worry
Why should we care
And even when we cross that line
We got street savoir faire
Woo-ooo Woo-hoo-oo