The Tale of the Princess Kaguya
Executive Producer: Seiichiro Ujiie
Based on the Japanese Folktale
"The Tale of the Bamboo Cutter"
Original Concept: Isao Takahata
Screenplay: Isao Takahata, Riko Sakaguchi
Music: Joe Hisaishi
Theme Song: Kazumi Nikaido
Character Design and Directing Animator: Osamu Tanabe
Art Director: Kazuo Oga
Planning: Toshio Suzuki
Producer: Yoshiaki Nishimura
Director: Isao Takahata
Once upon a time long long ago now,
there lived an old bamboo cutter.
He would make his way into the mountain forest and cut wild
bamboo, from which he made all sorts of useful things...
His name was
Sanuki no Miyatsuko.
One day he noticed a light shining
from inside a bamboo stalk...
Curious the bamboo
cutter approached it.
As he approached it, the light
flowed into the ground...
creating something he had never
seen before.
What is this?
Bamboo shoot sprouting so early?
Even before the plums?
What is this?
Have mercy on me!
Hello...
May I ask please, who might
you be, my lady?
Oh my! She is such a
beautiful little princess!
It's a miracle! This must be a blessing
from Heaven, I'm sure of it!
You're back early.
Something wrong?
Ah! What a beautiful
little doll!
No quiet, you'll wake her.
She's sleeping.
Ah!
Shh. Shh.
She just appeared
to me in the grove.
Appeared?
Definetly a blessing
from Heaven!
Hey! Heaven gave it to me!
Oh? Well I'm the one
who'll raise her.
Raise her? She's already
a perfect little princess.
No no no! Don't be silly, there is
more to raising a child than you think.
Right?
Here let me take her...
Oh!
Don't just sit there! Go find a lenght of
cloth or something warm I can wrap her in!
Don't be upset, sweetheart. We're gonna
take very good care of you. I promise.
Will this work?
There, there! You're gonna be just fine.
That's a good girl!
What's happening?
What's going on?
Can't you see? She wants me to
be the person who raises her!
Bring me one of the
good baskets, please.
Alright! This is really strange, you know.
I mean think about it...
What if she's a woodland
spirit or something?
What does she look like to you?
A little baby, of course.
That's right!
But she was a beautiful
princess just a moment ago!
Well I have to believe thats Heaven showing us what a beautiful princess she's going to become someday when she's all grown up.
You're right!
Of course. So that means we have to raise
the baby properly right from the start.
Yes, that must be it.
I see
I'm glad you understand.
I'll be right there helping!
Wait! We have to find a breast for her.
That's why I'm taking
her to a wet nurse.
Yes, I heard there was a new baby
in the woodworker settlement.
Is that what this is for?
Yes, we had to bring a gift.
What's wrong?
Hey! Hey what are you doing?
Oh you poor thing!
I guess you were really hungry.
How did you do that?
You see? She's very content,
she's drinking it right down.
Yeah!
I can't begin to explain it,
but I have milk!
She's laughing!
Ah! I might be imagining it
but she feels heavier.
No! That can't be!
What's the matter?
She just got even heavier!
What?
Let me see.
She seems to be growing
right before our very eyes.
Look! The plum blossoms!
I think she's got
a little heavier!
You see?
She's certainly healthy!
And from that day forward
the Bamboo Cutter and his wife...
carefully raised this miraculous child,
as if she were their very own.
Careful! You do not want to touch those.
Look! There's a baby in there!
Can you make it?
Stop pushing!
See? There she is!
Hey! She's looking over here!
Yeah! She is!
No she's not!
What's the matter?
Oh!
Hey!
Princess!
She's standing!
She's begun to walk!
Oh!
Hey now!
Alright...
Hah! That kid's weird!
She can walk now!
Yeah! She was just crawling.
I think she just got bigger too!
She grows fast! Like bamboo!
That'll be her name! Little Bamboo!
That's perfect!
Little Bamboo!
What do you mean Little Bamboo?
She's Princess! Princess!
Little Bamboo!
Princess!
Come here!
Princess... come here!
Atta girl! Come here
Little Bamboo!
Be quiet!
Princess!
Come here!
Princess... come here!
Little Bamboo!
Princess, Princess... come here
...come here, Princess!
C'mon Princess!
Princess! Come here!
That's my girl!
Yeah!
You wanna come with me?
C'mon!
We'll have these bamboo
shoots for dinner.
Dinner! Dinner!
Bamboo shoot! Bamboo shoot!
Alright now!
Stand back Princess.
There's lots of them!
Yeah!
Come here!
Stupid! You don't mess
with wild boar piglets!
Huh?
You're really a strange kid!
It looks like you just got bigger!
That kid's weird, Sutemaru.
Woh! Look at her!
She's grown again!
She's just like
a bamboo shoot.
Yeah you're right!
Bamboo shoot!
For dinner!
Bamboo shoot! Little Bamboo!
* Go round, go round *
* Waterwheel, go round *
* Go round, and call Mr. Sun *
* Birds, bugs, beasts, grass, flowers and trees *
* Spring, summer, autumn, winter *
* bring 'em all on *
* Go round, go round *
* Waterwheel go round *
* Go round and call Mr. Sun *
* Spring, summer, autumn, winter *
* bring 'em all on *
Birds! Bugs! Beasts!
Grass! Flowers!
Flowers!
And trees!
* Go round and call Mr. Sun *
Hey! Tell me something?
How come you know this song?
I just know it!
* Go round, go round *
* Waterwheel go round *
* Distant time, come round *
* Oh distant time *
Come round,
call back my heart
Birds, bugs, beasts, grass, flowers...
...and trees
Teach people how to feel
If I hear that you pine for me...
I will want to return to you,
I will want to return to you...
Those aren't the words.
Hey! She's crying!
Yeah she is!
What's wrong?
I don't know.
She's so weird!
Look! That's where our houses are.
And that's your bamboo grove.
Yeah! Bamboo shoots!
It's time to go!
C'mon!
Princess!
Where are you?
Where... where are you?
Where could she have gone?
What is that?
What's this?
I'll be back later!
Be careful now!
I will!
I'm a little worried, those boys are rough.
She might get hurt playing with them.
They're fine, don't worry.
It's good for her.
Yeah, it's just that
up in the bamboo grove...
Ah... no, it's nothin'
No no, that's lacquer!
You'll get a rash!
Lacquer?
That smells good!
He's gonna make
bowls out of those.
Really?
That's my father, my brother
and my mother.
Goodbye! Bye!
Bring us a present!
Bye! Bring us back a present!
This is the Bamboo Cutter's daughter.
Little Bamboo.
Little Bamboo!
It's okay, c'mon jump!
It's really hot!
I'm thirsty.
I bet those... I bet those are so sweet.
They are?
Hey! Come back!
Let's go!
Someone's coming!
Leave it!
I'll save this for the others.
Delicious!
Then when I saw these beautiful robes
shooting up in the air, I finally realized...
what Heaven wishes to be done.
What Heaven wishes to be done?
Think of Princess a way of life, that is appropriate to this robe. Raise her as a Princess of noble rank.
That is what Heaven expects of us!
What are you saying?
With this gold I was given.
I am going to build the Princess a fine mansion in the capital.
You're taking her to the capital?
I must.
Out here in these mountains she's
nothing but a country girl.
Up in the capital she'll become a noble  princess...
She'll have the opportunity to meet other nobility...
And I believe she'll be happier.
Well, in any case,
that is the command of the Heavens.
I don't know about this...
Well I do.
Anyway, tomorrow I will travel
to the capital.
From the next day on,
the old Bamboo Cutter went to the capital city often...
with the front of his kimono filled with gold.
The summer season passed,
and the time of the autumn harvest came round.
* Blow wind, blow, blow *
* Blow, blow hard, oh wind *
Little Bamboo! Can you please take him?
Sure!
* Bring the fruit of the mountains *
* Chestnuts, chestnuts... *
* Mushrooms, mountain, mountain grapes *
Pick up! Pick up!
I'm gonna get this all over you!
Look! A pheasant!
It's heading for you! Little Bamboo!
Little Bamboo! Chase it to the left!
I got it!
It's coming your way Sutemaru!
You're not getting away!
Sutemaru!
Sutemaru! Sutemaru!
Sutemaru are you okay?
I got it.
I got it!
Yeah he got it!
That's awazing!
Are you okay?
I'm coming down to help you.
It wont hold!
Sutemaru! I'm really sorry!
Are you okay?
Stupid! Those rocks are too loose to climb!
I'm sorry.
Go find a long piece of ivy and bring it here!
Yeah okay!
Oh! Hey you're bleeding!
It's nothing a little bit of spit won't fix.
No! Wait!
There you go.
Little Bamboo...
Have you gotten bigger again?
Yeah? You think so?
I do. I have this feeling
you're gonna keep on growing...
and go somewhere different, and leave us behind.
I don't know why you would say that?
Your Little Bamboo will always be here with you,
forever and ever.
And I'll always be a part of your gang,
forever and ever, too.
Sutemaru!
Is this one alright?
Looks good.
Tie it to a tree!
We did!
Good!
Here.
Thanks.
Hey, look at this! There's mushrooms here!
Look, Sutemaru!
They look delicious!
There are so many of them growing here!
Tomorrow we can make stew for everyone!
Yeah! I'll get the pheasant ready!
Yeah! Pheasant stew!
Pheasant! Pheasant! Pheasant stew!
Sorry I'm late.
Sutemaru caught a pheasant.
And we found some mushrooms.
Oh, and mountain grapes!
Where are you going?
The capital.
The capital?
Me, too?
Right now?
Yes. Just leave the basket on the ground.
What? But we're making pheasant stew tomorrow.
I promised Sutemaru that we...
Just put it down.
Now, let's go.
Can we come back tomorrow in time for stew?
But for the Princess and for Sutemaru,
that tomorrow never came.
The young lady is awake.
Good morning, my lady.
If you please...
Ah! Well, well, Princess!
And can I ask you, if Your Highness' mood,
would you be in the best of spirituals today?
Is that you Momma?
And Papa?
You both look so funny!
Why are you dressed like that?
I suppose we aren't doing this right!
I am!
My Princess! Get yourself a change
of range. I mean, a range of chobes!
Sorry.
Get a change of robe!
All of these robes are yours,
Your Highness.
Wow!
These smell good!
They're beautiful!
They're like falling rainbows!
She's having a great time,
she seems to like them.
Well, of course!
As of today,
this will be our new home.
This mansion is ours?
That's right.
This is fantastic!
Poppa, I can swim in there...
can't I?
You most certainly
will not swim in there.
A noble princess would never frolic, nor even
consider part taking in such unlady like antics.
Your Highness...
I have thusly summoned Lady Sagami
here from the palace to educate you...
in the ways of nobility.
Her job is to make you a noble princess!
Noble princess?
From the palace?
My Lord! This child is clearly in
desperate need of my instruction.
Naturally, I would have liked to have started earlier but I,
Sagami, will mould her into a truely fine young lady.
And so the Princess,
under Lady Sagami's tutelage...
began to learn the heirs and
graces of a noble lady.
Watch this carefully.
Keep your back like so, as straight as an arrow.
Swish up perfectly, like this.
Swish?
That is approximately correct.
The truth is, a noble princess
stands only on rare occasions.
But... how do I move if I
want to pick up something?
Like this...
Come to a kneeling position and
schuffle your knees, to move gracefully.
Shuffle, shuffle, shuffle.
Notice nothing else moves.
Your Highness!
We are far from done!
Wow!
It is a beautiful scroll, is it not?
A proper way of looking at it,
is like this, so the story flows.
Look! Now it's really flowing!
How about a small reward?
Oh! It makes me so proud to see
you practicing your letters...
I'm happy to see my
teachings are reaching you.
Your Highness!
Yes! Now once more, together.
Hey, that was fun!
Your Highness!
How's practice coming along?
Is everything going smoothly?
Ah, My Lord!
I trust you are well, Father.
Oh, my!
You've become so elegant
I hardly recognize you.
How about the koto lessons,
are they coming along as well?
We've only just begun...
she only knows a few notes!
My, how beautiful!
It's very suspicious and I'm starting to wonder
if someone else has trained her before...
In front of you, she performs perfectly
but with me, she's all games!
Oh! That's right!
Her Highness' a being who has come
straight down from Heaven.
She was never supposed to stay in the
mountains like some kind of common girl.
With her father watching proudly,
the Princess devoted herself to Lady Sagami's training.
What is happening here?
Why are you still behaving like
some kind of a servant!
You are, if nothing else,
the mother to a noble princess.
But this is the only way I feel
at ease living in this house.
And it's because you feel that way
the princess never changes her...
Princess, what's wrong?
You're extremely quiet today.
Come over here and listen husband...
What? Really?
Yes.
That's wonderful news!
We'll have to hold a great banquet!
A banquet?
A celebration of your coming of age.
Well, of course! This is the
happiest of occasions!
If we're having a party,
can we can invite my friends?
I'd love to see them all!
Your friends from the village!
That would be wonderful for you.
Don't be stupid!
You don't understand anything!
Do you realize how important this is?
We live in a much different world than those
hillbillies back in our old village!
This banquet will make you
a truly noble princess!
So right after the new year we'll have a celebration!
With putting up with hair, and the naming ritual.
But Poppa...
Ah! This is wonderful!
I mean, it's wonderful!
Wait! I'll ask Inbe no Akita.
He'll serve as the name father.
Hello? Is anybody there?
Lady Sagami? Lady Sagami?
What a bore.
* Birds, bugs, beasts *
* Grass, flowers and trees *
* Teach people how to feel *
Momma, would you give a
part of the garden to me?
Why?
It would be fun to plant
some of the things I like.
Yes, yes of course
if it makes you happy.
You can do whatever
you want with it.
Thank you, Momma.
No! Get away!
You will never be a noble princess
looking as you do now.
Without eyebrows the
sweat will run into my eyes!
Don't be ridiculous. For a noble princess
there is nothing that will maker her perspire!
Come...
Why would I want black teeth?
I wouldn't open my mouth then!
And I won't be able to laugh anymore!
You won't have to worry about that!
For a noble princess does not open her mouth to laugh.
That's stupid!
Even a noble princess must sweat and
sometimes want to laugh out loud!
Surely they wanna cry,
or get mad and wanna scream!
Oh no! A noble princess
should never show...
Then a noble princess is not human!
Princess!
The poor thing was all tied up!
Your Highness!
This way, Lord Akita and
thank you for coming.
Princess!
This is extremely embarassing!
I'm afraid she's still but a child.
No... not at all.
She looks like an
adorable little princess.
She hasn't been properly made up yet.
I am truly ashamed and I must apologize to you!
No! Please don't give it another thought.
If I see her face as it really is...
the better I can divine of a truly
appropriate name for the Princess.
Those are very welcome words.
I have every confidence that you will
bestow upon the princess a very fine name.
Please Your Highness, come out and greet
this gentlemen who will give you your name.
How do you do, my lord?
It's an honor to meet you.
Your Highness, if you wouldn't mind, perhaps you
could perform something, on the koto for our esteemable guest.
Beautiful!
The Shining Princess
of the Supple Bamboo...
The Shining Princess...
of the Supple Bamboo?
Yes.
She has a form as graceful
as supple bamboo...
and a beauty that radiates out from her! Superb!
So then I add a name for
"Princess of the Shining Light"
And thus I suggest to you
the name "Princess Kaguya"
Yes! How beautiful!
I'm so proud, Lord Akita,
that is the most wonderful name I've ever heard!
Thank you very much.
As is the custom, the naming ceremony was followed
by putting up the hair and dawning the trailing skirt.
Soon after, large numbers were invited
to the great banquet...
to celebrate the naming
of Princess Kaguya.
Congratulations sir!
Princess Kaguya...
a truly fine name.
This is wonderful, right?
Just wonderful.
There are many good gentlemen
who have come to the banquet!
Then the purpose of this banquet is
to celebrate the taking of my name?
Of course it is, mam.
Yes, but... all I'm doing
is sitting here.
It's like...
I'm not even at my own party.
Thank you very much!
The banquet to celebrate the naming of Princess Kaguya,
went on for three days, and three nights.
Here to Princess Kaguya to celebrate
the putting up of her hair!
A fine thing!
Yes?
A fine thing! Yes?
Really my friend! This is all a
bit pretentious, don't you think?
What?
The Princess...
the so called Princess
C'mon you know what we mean?
Princess Kaguya or whoever...
Her flower of a face enshrined
behind that blind.
Clearly there wouldn't be any harm in allowing us
to see her if she's as beautiful as they say?
Yeah! Why not?
I agree!
No no! I'm afraid that
would be out of the question.
What's happening here? We've come to celebrate
her naming, and we don't even get to say hello?
I'm sorry! But that's just
the way things are done!
What do you mean?
The way things are done!
No wait!
There's no noble princess here!
Yeah!
You're right!
Who are you saying Her Highess is?
Her Highest? How much did it cost?
A naming ceremony for this Princess?
Who cares about that?
Atleast show her to us!
Maybe she looks like some kind of goblin!
Or worse!
Excuse me? Where did the people who
were living down below go?
I wouldn't know.
They packed themselves up...
Took off on a journey to find better wood.
Better wood?
They probably won't be back for ten years.
Ten years?
If you use up all the trees,
the mountain is ruined.
But if you leave the mountain
its power, and go on a journey...
it comes back to life. Trees need a good
ten years, then you can work them again!
It's like that for charcoal burning too.
I see... but the mountain
looks dead already.
The leaves used to be so
full and bright here...
Everything comes back eventually.
See for yourself.
The trees are already
getting ready for spring.
Getting ready?
So spring will come back again?
Sure it will.
It's like a circle, just when you
think one ends, another begins again.
You can always count on it.
So who might you be?
I've seen this before.
I've seen it.
From that day forward, it was
as if Princess Kaguya...
was another person,
devoting herself to her studies...
and passing her days in silence.
Hey look! Look at this
huge pile of gifts from the nobility!
The high born have now accepted you!
See? They obviously consider
you to be one of them!
You know what? This bird
deserves a much better space...
How about, for old time's sake, I weave
you a fine bamboo cage to keep him in?
Now what do you think about that, huh?
Thank you, Father.
Ha-ha! Wonderful!
It's wonderful!
I mean, wonderful!
Wonderful!
I'll just leave the
bird right here.
Thanks be to Heaven!
As time went on, rumours of
the Princess' beauty grew.
The streets outside the mansion
became cramped with people...
hoping to catch a glimpse,
of the mysterious Princess Kaguya.
Are you a servant
of Princess Kaguya?
If your are, give her this for me!
Give this to her!
No! You must give this to her!
First!
See that she gets this! Please!
She needs this gift!
You must take this to her,
right away!
There's another crowd of gentlemen
suitors in the streets.
They've were very persistant. They gave me all
these letters and demanded that I pass on to you.
And so I am, and since it
seems to be impossible for...
you to go outside the mansion, I thought
I'd bring you some cherry blossoms.
Thank you!
I hear you have summoned me,
Prince Ishitsukuri?
Yes, it's about that rich upstart's
daughter whom you named...
Oh! You're taking about Princess Kaguya?
Shh! Keep your voice down!
Did you say Princess Kaguya?
Woh! Princess Kaguya?
I've heard the rumours about her.
They say that she's very beautiful.
You fool! You had to raise
your voice didn't you?
But don't matter how beautiful they say she is...
she is still of humble birth.
So she is not a woman
appropriate for any of us.
Even you have to admit Akita, that
Princess Kaguya is a very presumptuous name...
to be given the likes of a commoners daughter.
No matter how much you paid for it.
Not so, Lord Minister.
This beautiful girl is not
Miyatsuko's true daughter.
She was found in a bamboo stalk.
What?
A bamboo stalk?
Now that's interesting!
She could be some kind of forest spirit!
After seeing her with my own eyes...
that is entirely possible, my Lord.
Really?
I must confess, that the moment I stood
before Princess Kaguya...
this old man's body began to tremble...
as if a dry fountain had
come flowing back to life!
Even remebering her now, words fail to express
her glimmering beauty, and my heart...
surges as I remember every moment
looking at her!
Out of the way!
I swear! I will win this race!
I must get to her first!
That glimmering beauty will be mine,
I tell you, nothing will stop me!
The one who will win her is me!
I swear!
She will be my wife!
Lady Sagami!
You have to see these!
What is it, my lord?
Just look at these!
Look at them all!
Five of the most high-born men in the land
have come calling for one simple reason...
they wanna marry the Princess!
Oh, my!
Oh! Wonderful! Wonderful!
All these princes are interested in her...
and even the Minister of the Right!
But how do we choose among them?
It's going to be a very difficult challenge!
And to make matters worse, they are all waiting
impatiently in formal dress even as we speak!
I will take care of this.
Leave Her Highness to me.
You go entertain them,
and whatever you do, keep them happy!
Alright, my lady!
Oh and thank you!
Thank you! Thank you!
Wonderful!
I just knew that banquet
was worth putting on!
These are five proposals
from five of the most...
important nobles in the land.
Whichever one you choose,
you cannot go wrong!
But I've never even met them!
Oh! Please don't worry!
This is very simple! You'll pick a proposal from one of these
noble gentlemen, and then you'll meet him on your wedding day.
It hardly matters because with any of these fine
princely men, you'll be happy forever... and ever!
I'm supposed to feel happy?
I have no intension of
marrying anyone yet.
Have you lost your mind!
Once you have become a noble princess,
you must marry a suitable gentleman as quickly as possible!
That is the very
defintion of happiness!
Why would you even think twice?
With any of these men, your happiness
would be completely guaranteed.
I do not want any of it!
So please tell those men to leave.
Do you really want to hurt
your father like this?
Do you understand that he is as happy for you,
as he would be for himself?
Everything has been made ready for you.
If you would be so kind to come this way...
Now please, express your proposal
to the Princess in order.
I am Prince Kuramochi.
Princess...
as you know my true feelings have been clearly stated
in the letter that has been given to you...
Your Highness, Princess Kaguya,
if I were so fortunate...
that you became my wife, it would be as if
I plucked a branch of the tree of jewels...
that grows on the Mountain of Horai...
whose trunk is of gold and it's
fruits are the whitest of pearls.
Princess Kaguya, you are an exquiste
treasure that is as unattainable...
precious as that...
I'm Prince Ishitsukuri! Princess Kaguya,
if you consent to be my wife...
I will worship you morning and night. My forehead
pressed to the ground in utter devotion...
you are a treasure I would revear as much as the
stone begging bowl of Lord Buddha himself.
You would worship her
as if she were some cold stone bowl?
Princess Kaguya, to me you are
as a robe of fire-rat fur.
From which when thrown in the fire,
all the impurities is burned away...
but which itself is not consumed, only shining
more brightly as the flames grow higher...
you are utterly rare. Untouched and innocent. As illusive
as this treasure about, which they speak of finding in China.
You have the goal to compare
Princess Kaguya to a rat-skin?
Princess, to me...
Councilor Otomo
you are a fine glistening jewel,
a jewel that shines intensly from above.
A gem with more radiance than the five colored
jewel that shines on the dragon's neck!
Oh! No, no, no!
For me, Princess Kaguya...
is something more precious and natural, like the warm
cowry shell amulets, swallows use as a charm...
for safe birth.
That is a true treasure!
A true treasure...
You think a boring everyday seashell
is a treasure? You must be crazy!
Well... well, a dragon's neck stinks you know!
It's on the neck!
What a beautiful sound!
She is truly gifted!
Gentlemen! I'm most grateful for
the sentiments you expressed...
to someone you have never seen or met.
Yet there is something
else I require...
These rare treasures that
are difficult to obtain...
I ask... that you bring them to me.
Then, and only then, will I be able to clearly and fully
understand how you treasure me in your hearts...
Prince Kuramochi, present to me
a jewel branch from Mount Horai.
Prince Ishitsukuri, the stone
begging bowl of Lord Buddha.
How? But...
Lord Minister of the Right Abe,
bring a robe made of fire-rat fur.
Excuse me?
Grand Counselor Otomo, obtain the
jewel from the great dragon's neck.
Middle Counselor Isonokami,
please bring me the swallow's cowry shell...
The amulet of easy child birth...
Wait! Wait... but that!
No, no no no...
All these items would be impossible
to find, even if they do exist!
Princess, these five gentlemen were
only using them as comparisons!
Yes.
All these gentlemen compared
me to very rare treasures.
Therefore, whomever can present
me the real treasure...
I will happily become that noble
gentleman's real treasure.
Gentlemen please, I humbely apologize!
My daughter knows nothing of
the ways of the world.
But she must be a beautiful princess.
Her voice, her music...
Indeed, I must say that melody was
quite out of this world.
The truth is, she is asking us to
achieve an impossible task...
Impossible!
It can't be done!
She'll remain a jewel
that no one can acquire.
This is terrible!
When the nobles left, so did all the other people
who were waiting in front of the mansion!
They disapperaed just
like the tide going out.
Exactly.
I thought I better let
you know right away.
Your Highness!
C'mon! Let's go!
Go? Where?
Outside!
Outside?
Yes! Let's go see the cherry blossoms!
You know what? we should ask father
and mother to come along with us!
I'm sorry, but there is no
longer anything I can do.
But, but...
The next time I'm sure
the Princess will try to, ah...
There will certainly be no next time!
She has burnt her last bridge.
I will take my leave of you!
Oh no, please don't go...
Squire, the cart the Princess requested has arrived.
They are just waiting for you sir.
Tell them to go on ahead without me!
I'm not going!
Oh, my!
Beautiful!
Stop here!
Oh, my! It's beautiful!
I'm very sorry, your Highness.
Please forgive us!
Let's go.
The cherry blossoms are
right at their peak.
I must say, they're certainly
splendid to experience.
Let's go home.
But...
Keep everyone back!
Stay back! Stay back!
Clear the space here!
There seems to have been an
accident up ahead.
Oh! Someone's running this way.
Sutemaru!
Sutemaru?
This way!
Better run little one!
It's Sutemaru!
Sutemaru!
What are you doing?!
C'mon! Let's get out of here!
We're going!
Little Bamboo!
Sutemaru!
Let's go.
Three years passed...
Go on.
It's a lovely day, isn't it?
The plants in the garden seem to be thriving!
Yes, but you know...
It looks completely
different from down here!
Well!
Yes!
See! It looks like the mountain, doesn't it?
You're right.
There's the forest and a hill...
Oh my! It is just like home!
That's right!
And see the cogan grass?
It looks just like the bamboo grove.
And the mugwort looks just like trees!
And Mr. Moon could rise up from right
behind those mountains, couldn't it?
Yes!
And look! We can go across that
bridge and climb over the hill...
Princess!
Where is the Princess?
You're in the kitchen again?
And what's wrong with
that once in a while?
It's not once in a while,
it's all the time!
Anyway...
I have news about Kuramochi!
What?
He brought back the jeweled
branch from Mount Horai!
It's quite an accomplishment!
Impossible!
Yes, yes! And I never thought
such a thing would happen, believe me...
he is true to his word!
An impossible task, and he pulled it off!
I wouldn't be surprised if he would had me!
But he really did what he said he'd do!
Now! After we recieve the gift, you must
prepare yourself quickly to be married to the Prince.
My heavens! I have to go!
I must prepare a bedchamber for
the Prince and Your Highness!
If only Lady Sagami were here!
I don't believe it!
Prepare a bedchamber...?
Where is the Princess?
Quickly where is Princess Kaguya?
Please wait, Your Highness!
Please wait!
Ah! Mr. Miyatsuko!
Please forgive my appearance.
I was so anxious to get here,
I didn't have time to change my traveling clothes!
Your Highness! Your presence is always welcome here!
This is most truly wonderful!
Please... come in!
I'll show you the way.
Splendid.
Without further ado,
I will present the promised object.
What can I say? It's dazzling!
It leaves me speechless! It's so... what the...
It is as you requested.
The jeweled branch of Mount Horai.
Princess Kaguya, can you see it?
Come closer!
Here! I will bring it closer to you.
One moment, please.
First, allow me to ask you how you found it.
It must be quite a story...
Oh! It is quite a story!
Three years ago I vowed to carry
out your Highness' wish...
I then set my plan in motion...
from the harbor at Naniwa I set
course for the Mountain of Horai.
We were tossed by fierce waves...
we nearly starved from lack of food...
and after a grueling, harrowing journey...
Behold!
What is that mountain,
so forbidding yet so very beautiful?
What is this?
It flows with water of gold and precious gems!
Look!
A maiden scoops water with a silver bowl!
Dear Maiden...
please tell me what is the
name of that mountain?
That is the Mountain of Horai.
And you are very brave to
have travelled so far!
Ah! I had finally arrived
at the Mountain of Horai!
Without a second glance at the lovely maiden,
I climbed the mountain.
Behold! Those precious, exquiste trees!
Silver branches, a trunk of gold
and fruit of pearls!
So beautiful! It takes my breath away...
Are these not the jeweled
branches of Horai...
the very thing that Princess Kaguya said she wished?
And thus, without haste, I snapped off
this branch to bring to your feet.
One look is worth a hundred stories.
Please, won't you see for
yourself Your Highness!
Stop! You shall not pass!
Move! Get out of my way!
What is that?
What's going on?
I'm sincerely sorry.
I'll go see.
Let go!
She must read this letter!
What's going on?
Just pay us our fee! We are here to collect
for the jeweled branch that we made!
What's that?!
The branch they made?
I am Ayabe no Uchimaro,
a craftsman belonging to the Guild of Artisans.
At the order of Prince Kuramochi, we gathered
together precious gems, mounted them...
and put them together, as if it came
from a jeweled tree on Mount Horai.
Really?
However, the Prince has made no
effort to pay us what we are owed!
That's an outrage!
And since Princess Kaguya,
one of his concubines...
sorry, one of his wives, was here,
we decided to take action.
Ill mannered as such a move may be,
in the end we had no choice!
Since the Prince has been avoiding us, it was our
decision to try to collect our payment from her!
That's why we have come to
collect at  your residence!
I understand. I'll talk to him!
So what's going...?
Woh!
Where have you gone?!
Where... where's the branch?
Father, I'm afraid the
Prince has taken his leave.
He has?
We should at least reward the Artisans!
They really did quite a nice job with that branch!
Next to call at the mansion was
Lord Abe, Minister of the Right.
Feast your eyes on this!
It shimmers with an
absolutely wonderous light!
It's extraordinary! In all the world, there's never been
an engagement gift as costly as the one I'm holding here!
However if it should please Princess Kaguya,
the expence is really nothing!
I'm your trifle to win
the heart of this lovely damsel.
In that case then...
Oh, the Princess is close by!
Drop it in the fire.
Huh?
Excuse me?
If it's truly made of fire-rat fur...
it will not burn but merely glisten...
all the brighter.
Of course, Princess!
This fire-rat robe is no fake,
it's genuine! Genuine!
If placed in the fire, it should not burn.
But, I fear that... between the...
Princess and myself,
there remains an issue...
A grain of unwarranted impurity.
A question of my varasity on the subject!
Is that true?
It's very possible.
All the more reason...
to put it in the fire.
To burn all the impurity
of my doubts. Clean away!
Yes, Your Highness!
Look! You see?
Ha-ha
My entire fortune
burning up in my hand!
I've lost everything!
It's a complete disaster!
What a mad sum of money I've stuck into this robe!
Look at it now! Look, look!
It is all beacause you
told me to burn it!
How much do you think the the Minister of
the Right actually spent, to create that fake?
I'm sure that's all I am
to those gentlemen.
What?
I'm a fake jeweled branch
or a fire-rat fur robe that turns to ashes.
Well both of them were
very expensive it would seem.
But have no fear,
your suitors are trying.
I'm told that Grand Counselor
Otomo has gone by ship...
He's traveling to Takoshi in a brave attempt
to secure the stone from the dragon's neck.
What?
He is doing everything he
can to bring you to him...
It's quite a story, they say he
has sent his wife far away
and is in the process of completely
rebuilding his mansion...
A warrior's determination
is a very powerful thing.
All right, Dragon!
Arise and meet your fate!
Watch out!
The Dragon!
Forgive me!
The dragon's everywhere!
Calm down!
The storm will pass.
While the warrior faced his dragons,
Prince Ishitsukuri was paying a call on Princess Kaguya.
What's this?
You found Buddha's begging bowl?
This is extraordinary, Your Highness! I don't know what to say!
Give it to Princess Kaguya.
So you brought something
other than the bowl?
Please, just give it to her.
Well, alright...
Hey Princess, this is a gift
from Prince Ishitsukuri.
Since I first heard her voice three years ago...
Princess Kaguya has not left
my heart for even a moment...
I set out on my quest desperately
searching for Buddha's begging bowl...
Over meadow and mountain I walked,
calling on temples throughout the land.
Been weary to the point of exhaustion,
I sat myself down by a stone on the road.
Suddenly, my eye was taken by a beautiful wildflower
that was growing there at my feet.
Ah! I was overwhelmed by my feelings.
My love for the Princess spread within me...
like the blooms on that exquiste flower.
And I had a moment of inspiration,
It suddenly dawned on me, that what I
really wanted to bring the Princess...
and what she had truly wished for,
was not some distant unobtainable treasure...
but this simple flower,
which itself is a treasure of nature.
This flower has come to represent for me,
the devotion with which I love the Princess
Devotion...
Princess Kaguya!
In truth you are to me...
the only one whom I wish to dedicate my heart.
Could you please perhaps,
accept this lovely flower as a token...
of the depth of my feelings?
Since I was a small boy, I have been
fond of flowers and other plants.
I am also entranced by the nameless flowers
that grow by roadsides or in meadows.
And in my heart...
I always wished that I could live,
as do these flowers that bloom in the fields.
Princess, I want you to
come with me, to that place.
Together we could leave this
loud city and its formalities.
We could go to a rich green land where flowers bloom
in perfusion. Where birds sing and fish leap.
A place brimming with life.
Let us laugh and sleep and sing.
Let us follow our hearts.
Take pleasure in the tasks before us,
with the blessings of the four seasons...
our needs will be supplied.
And we'll spin out a beautiful tale.
Please come with me to some
place far away from here!
Where flowers bloom in perfusion,
where fish leap and birds sing!
Come with me to that place!
Far away from here!
Please!
Excuse me!
What's going on here?
In a place far away from here, husband?
I would love to be taken there!
As I did when you said those very words, to me!
I'm sorry!
I beg for your forgivness!
Would she have been just like all the others?
Plucked from the field like a
flower and then thrown away?
How many more princesses would be forced
to shave their heads, and go into a nunery?
I got it!
Get me down!
All that remained...
was Middle Counselor Isonokami, who was in
search of the mysterious cowry shell amulet.
Counselor!
Is he alright?
The Counselor is dead?
Yes.
A great tragedy. His back was
broken... reaching for the nest.
Goodness, what's the matter?
This garden, it's... it's a fake!
Fake!
It's all fake!
And so am I! So am I!
Stop it.
Everyone's miserable
and it's all my fault.
It's not your fault. It's not!
You mustn't blame yourself.
It is my fault.
All of it, is my fault!
Because I'm a fake!
I never wanted it to happen like this!
My love!
I didn't ask for this!
That may be true.
But it still doesn't
make it your fault.
But in spite of her wishes, there was
even more talk of the Princess...
and in time, His Majesty himself
began to show interest.
She has led five of the highest nobles of the land,
around... by their nose! Interesting!
If she has so stubbornly refused all these men, it must
be the wish of this Princess Kaguya... to come to me.
Let's play her game.
Send word she is to appear before me!
Yes, Your Majesty.
Her father has most certainly raised her well...
so when she becomes mine, give her father the rank of
Court Official!
As your Majesty wishes.
Wonderful!
It's wonderful.
Princess!
Husband! Calm down, please!
Your Highness! I have joyous news!
You've now come to the attention of His Majesty,
who is summoning you to serve in his court!
What?
It's extraordinary!
You'll be one of His Majesty's wives.
Not only that, I will wear
the hat of a court official!
Ah! This is wonderful!
Listen to you! You still don't
comprehend how your daughter feels?
It is you, who doesn't understand!
All that we have done has been
for the sake of this!
For a girl born in this land...
there is no greater happiness than joining His Majesty
in holy wedlock! None!
Now at last, after all this effort,
Her Highness will finally be happy!
Father...
I'm sorry, but please refuse.
What?
I couldn't possibly be a court lady now.
What are you talking about?
You're refusing to serve at court?
Father, my answer is no!
But, you can't...
No one in this land is allowed to disobey an order
from His Majesty! In the slightest degree!
So quit thinking of just yourself, please!
Father... If disobedience to His Majesty
is considered a crime punishable by death...
well then... the only choice is to kill me!
Princess!
Poppa, if your happiness depends on
wearing the cap of a court official...
then I will go to His
Majesty as you wish.
And after you have put on that cap as
part of the court... I will kill myself.
What? She refused?
What is the meaning of this?
She has turned down an offer to live at the palace?
No woman has ever turned me down before!
Very interesting! Now I truly
want to meet her all the more!
Alright! If she is determined to play that game,
I will grace her mansion with a surprise visit.
Yes, Your Majesty.
This way, your Majesty.
She plays the koto beautifully!
Her face is most angelic!
Now, let's waste no
more time with games!
Why are you doing this?
Why, to make you happy of course!
My embrace pleases all women!
Let me go! I will never be yours!
I'm afraid that's not an acceptable answer!
If I wish you to come, they you must obey!
Bring around the carriage quickly!
Where is she?
Where did she go?
I see that I acted in haste. So please,
show yourself, you have nothing to fear.
Please, Princess.
I will simply burn the sight of you into my eyes,
and then withdraw.
How beautiful you are!
Remember your promise.
I will withdraw for today.
However I believe your ultimate
happiness lies in you, becoming mine.
Such beauty I've never seen!
After His Majesty
returned to his palace...
Princess Kaguya, would come out
to the pavillion every night...
to gaze at the moon.
What's the matter, Princess?
Lately you never come in to see me.
You've left your spinning to sit, and you
haven't tended to your plants for days.
You now spend most of your nights
gazing at the moon. I don't understand...
What is it? What's happening with you?
Nothing has happened.
That's not true.
Now c'mon, tell me.
It's obvious from far away
look in your eyes.
Don't worry, there's nothing wrong.
But... but...
Is it something you can't tell even me?
They're coming to take me back!
To the Moon!
The Moon?
Every night I've begged
them to let me stay!
With you!
But it's no use! They're
coming for me on the 15th day!
Who's coming?
What's this about Princess?
I'm very confused.
You have to help me here...
Try to explain this in simple words so
an old man like me will understand, Your Highness...
Oh! You poor thing! There is something
very deep behind this, isn't there?
The truth is... the day you found me,
I was was sent here from the Moon.
From the Moon?
The Moon put you in the bamboo?
Yes.
I understood it, on the day
His Majesty was here.
And now on the 15th day, the people
of the Moon will come for me...
and I must leave you both forever.
What? I don't understand!
You planning to leave us?
Just... what is it we have done
to deserve this?
I mean, from the start all we ever tried to do
was make sure you were always happy!
All this happiness that you wished for me
has been very hard to bear.
Without realizing it...
I prayed for someone to save me.
And when His Majesty grabbed me,
in panic my heart just screamed out...
I don't want to be here anymore!
You mean, you asked them to come here
and take you back to the Moon?
That's just terrible!
What have you done?
I don't want to go back, Poppa.
I wanna stay here!
I won't let it happen!
We'll fight to keep you!
We'll figure something out,
I just won't let them pass!
It's too late!
They are coming!
What have I been doing
here in this land?
Throwing tantrums because I didn't
want to  belong to anyone...
Ignoring what you want from me, and fooling myself
with tiny fake meadows and mountains!
Only now, when I'm forced to go back to the Moon,
do i finally remember...
why I came here, and why it is,
no matter what is happening...
in this strange land, that song
has always been inside my heart.
* Birds, bugs, beasts *
* Grass, flowers and trees *
Yes, that's the song.
I was... I was born to live here!
With the birds, bugs and beasts.
I don't want to leave!
And you won't! I will never let you go!
From the day I found you in the
bamboo and held you so gently in my arms...
I've just loved you as if
you were my very own child!
And when I picked you up and cradled you,
put you on your feet and changed clothes...
I was the happiest man on the face
of the Earth, like I was in Heaven!
It's not too late to save you!
It's not!
You're here! We still have you!
You're still here in my arms!
And these arms of mine, will drive them away!
I will not let them take you! No matter how
many of them come! I'll fight them off!
Is everyone?!
Prepare to defend the princess!
Oh Poppa! I'm sorry.
My Heavens! What a lot
of noise they're making!
How about a song to
make us feel better?
* Go round, go round *
* Waterwheel, go round *
* Go round, and call Mr. Sun *
* Birds, bugs, beasts *
* Grass, flowers and trees *
* Spring, summer, autumn, winter *
* Bring 'em all on *
* Go round, go round *
* Waterwheel go round *
* Go round and call Mr. Sun *
* Spring, summer, autumn, winter *
* Bring 'em all on *
* Go round, come round *
* Distant time *
* Come round, Oh distant time *
* Come round, call back the heart *
* Birds, bugs, beasts *
* Grass, flowers and trees *
* Teach people how to feel *
* If I hear that you pine for me *
* I will want to return to you *
I wasn't aware there was another verse.
I remember...
Long ago in the City of the Moon, a woman who
had just returned from Earth, would sing this song.
When you put on the robe of the Moon,
all memories of the Earth just disappear.
All grief and sadness are gone.
But when she sang that song,
I saw tears fall from her eyes.
It was such a mystery to me. I had to know
what those feelings from Earth were?
That's why I broke the
rules to come to this place.
I wanted to feel all the same
things that she felt, and now...
I know exactly what she was
feeling as she looked back at this land.
Tell me dear...
She wanted...
to come back here. To feel all those wonderful,
mysterious things again! I know it!
If I hear that you pine for me,
I will want to return to you.
If you are waiting for me,
I will return to you...
come round and
call back my heart.
I just... wanna go home!
Prepare a carriage quickly.
Don't bring the word to anyone.
Ginger flowers!
It's been a long time.
What's the matter? Hungry again?
Mama!
Did anybody hear that?
Hear what?
I'll go look.
Sutemaru, it's you!
It's you!
Little Bamboo?
Is it okay if call you that?
We were just coming back
here for the new trees.
And for some reason coming over the pass,
I thought I heard your voice, singing.
I'm so happy to see you!
Yeah.
Tell me? What are you doing here,
dressed like that?
All this time I've wanted to
come back to my real home.
Your real home?
Here?
Uh-hmm.
But weren't you happy in the capital?
Living in a mansion, eating fine
food, wearing nice clothes...
All that time I was wishing I was here
on the mountain, playing with everyone.
Well, everyone's gonna be here soon.
And with you, Sutemaru...
With you, Sutemaru,
I know I would have been truly happy.
Happy, with me?
Now I realize that.
You're joking, right!
I don't think you'd feel that way.
You, living like us!
Sure I would! I did live
like you when we were kids!
In rags like these?
Half-starving, eating roots?
Sometimes stealing dinner
because you hadn't eaten in days?
I saw that!
I also saw when they beat you up.
Oh that? That was nothing.
It's nothing if you answer back!
Answer back by simply being alive!
I just know, I would have been happy.
Little Bamboo!
But it won't happen.
It's too late.
What do you mean?
Ah! You are promised to His Majesty?
No!
I won't belong to anyone!
Let's run away!
It can't happen.
Why not? We can leave right now!
Let's run.
Come with me,
and we'll go!
I'll carry you on my
back and run forever!
We'll go some place where
nobody can ever find us!
I can't run away.
Not any more.
Of course you can, Little Bamboo!
I'll protect you!
I'll protect you from everyone!
But they're coming for me.
Who's coming for you?
I've been found.
So what? Even if you have been found!
So what!
I don't care about that!
I wanna run away with you.
Please!
Sutemaru!
Yes!
I'll run, too! As fast as I can!
Little Bamboo!
Sutemaru!
Oh Heaven, oh Earth!
Take me in!
Huh? No!
Please let me stay, just a little longer!
To feel the joy and happiness of living on
this Earth! Please don't take me away!
It's alright Little Bamboo.
I'll hold you tight!
I won't ever let go!
Hold me tighter!
I don't wanna go!
Little Bamboo!
A dream?
It wasn't real?
Dada!
Hi...
And then at last, the 15th
day of August came round.
Fire!
Princess!
Princess...
* Go round, go round *
* Waterwheel go round *
* Go round, and call Mr. Sun *
* Birds, bugs, beasts *
* Grass, flowers and trees *
* Flower, bear fruit *
* bear fruit, and die *
* Be born, grow up, and die *
* Still the wind blows, and the rain falls *
* The waterwheel goes round *
My little girl! My Princess!
Please! No... no!
* Lifetimes come and go in turn *
Princess! Princess!
* Over and over a life revives *
Princess!
* Over and over a life renews *
Princess! Don't leave us!
Not yet!
Please, not yet.
Once I dawn this robe...
I will forget everything I know
and love about this land.
So please just for a moment.
Princess!
Daughter!
Please!
Take us with you!
Forgive me, Momma and Poppa!
Please forgive me!
Now now, let us go.
This heavy heart will no longer trouble you
in the City of the Moon...
And the memory of this impure Earth,
will lift from your mind forever.
It's not impure!
There is grief and sorrow here...
There is also joy and happiness!
All who live on this earth,
experience them in different shades.
All feel compassion.
Princess!