Time of our lives, wonder of surprise
The open blue skies
Reflecting in our eyes
In a perfect place, see the sunny days
Coming into view
'Cause every day feels
like summer with you
Everything feels right starting anew
Every day feels like summer with you
Oh
Once you were here
my worries disappeared
It all became clear
Nothing left to fear
Beyond any price, pure as paradise
Coming into view
'Cause every day feels
like summer with you
Everything feels right starting anew
Every day feels like summer with you
Oh
Baa!
Meeeh!
You're mine
Oh, baby
Hey!
Meeeh!
Baa?
Hey!
Get your rocks off,
get your rocks off, honey
Shake it now now, get 'em off downtown
Get your rocks off...
Ooh. Hey. Oh!
Hey, hey! Hey, hey, hey.
What?
Yeah.
Yeah?
Nah.
Yeah? Yeah?
No.
Hey!
You've got to search
for the hero inside yourself
Search for the secrets you hide...
Shall we?
You're mine
Oh, baby
Yeah
Mine
In a city this big
it's easy to not exist
But that's a problem
you don't seem to get
When you roll like this
You left home a short time ago
but it seems so long
We've only seen this in magazines
and it looked like fun
Every doubletake, every false start,
every wrong move we make
Start again, never at the end
It's a risk we take
Scary things happen right here
all day and night
But who cares when you look like us
you're gonna be all right
We won't come this far
to get nothing back
You can't stop us getting what we want
We will find what we want in the city
And we're really fitting in around here
We're feeling pretty hot in the city
From the way we walk
the walk is pretty clear
We're making it in the big city
And you know
it's always gonna throw it down
Down, down
So step aside, people, we're coming
'Cause we pretty much own this town
This, this, this town
Yeah
We're looking at you
but it's like you're with someone else
In the heart of the city
we could easily lose ourselves
In between making us sing,
we gotta see this through
We can't stop to make it to the top,
got a job to do
We won't come this far
to get nothing back
You can't stop us getting what we want
Ooh, yeah
We're making it in the big city
And we're really fitting in around here
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
No, no, no!
Hey!
No. No!
Hey.
Hey!
Ruff?
She could tell right away
that I was bad to the bone
Bad to the bone
- Bad to the bone
- Got you.
B-b-b-b-bad
Bad to the bone
I broke a thousand hearts
Before I met you
I'll break a thousand more, baby...
That one?
I'm a wonderful thing, baby
Such a, such a
Wonderful
I'm a wonderful thing, baby
Such a, such a
Baa!
Baa.
Baa?
Shoo! Shoo!
Shoo!
Wish I were with you
But I couldn't stay
Every direction leads me away
All I want
Is to be home
Stand in the mirror
You look the same
Just looking for shelter
From the cold and the pain
And all I want
Is to be home
Yeah.
Every day feels like summer with you
Everything feels right starting anew
Baa
Baa!
Yeah.
Hey!
Baa!
Yeah!
Arf!
Baa!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Heeey!
Arf.
Baa!
'Cause every day
Feels like summer with you
Everything feels right starting anew
Every day feels like summer with you
Oh
Once you were here
My worries disappeared
It all became clear
Nothing left to fear
You have got my back
Keeping me on track
Like you always do
'Cause every day
Feels like summer with you
Everything feels right starting anew
Every day feels like summer with you
Oh
Hey, yo, Shaun,
you ready to kick it with us, man?
Baa!
That's what I thought
Let's take this up another level
Oh, yeah
- You ready?
- Baa!
All right, let's go Rizzle Kicks, yeah
Yo! What you know
about Shaun the Sheep?
Peeps hang on the words he bleats
Like, yo, best thing you heard
Best in the herd
Count on him but don't fall asleep
What you know about living in a barn?
Shaun be the joker spinning that yarn
Got them lyrics
Kicking them bars
If you're with it, Shaun
For Shaun the Sheep
He's Shaun the Sheep
He even mucks about
with those who cannot bleat
Keep it in mind, he's one of a kind
Oh! Life's a treat
with Shaun the Sheep
He's Shaun the Sheep
He doesn't miss a trick
or ever lose a beat
Perhaps one day, you'll find a way
To come and meet with Shaun the Sheep
Oh, yeah!
Oozing with character
His baa is hard to beat
What?
From England to Africa
You can't not love this sheep
What?
Round the world, he travelled far
And gee, he makes me proud
What?
King amongst the herd
Oh, they should give him a crown
Baa!
Who's that?
He's Shaun the Sheep
He's not afraid to make
the intellectual leap
Oxford Uni
For brains and guile
Oh, yeah?
With a wink and a smile
You can't compete with Shaun the Sheep
Oh, no way
La, la, la, la
Sheep
La, la, la, la, la
La, la, la, la
Tell 'em.
Let's go!
Oh, yeah!
Whoo!
We rock, kid
For Shaun the Sheep
La, la, la, la
He even mucks about
with those who cannot bleat
La, la, la, la
Keep it in mind
He's one of a kind
Oh! Life's a treat
with Shaun the Sheep
Yeah!
He's Shaun the Sheep
He doesn't miss a trick
or ever lose a beat
Perhaps one day you'll find a way
To come and meet with Shaun the Sheep
Oh! Come and bleat
with Shaun the Sheep
Baa!
Yo!