Maybe you can hear the train
entering the station,
bringing the choirboys home to Vienna
after their four-month tour of America.
- Hello, Max.
- Oh, good to see you.
- And you, Herr Director?
- How are the boys? Are they well?
They are fine, all of them.
Don't they sound like it?
- Welcome back, Max.
- Freddy. Hi, boys.
- Hello, Peter. Had a good time?
- Yes, thanks, sir.
All ready for school tomorrow, huh?
Harry, Welcome home.
- Skip,
- I brought him for you.
Thanks.
I wish I could go to America.
How do you get in the choir?
You give an audition.
What's an audition?
You sing for the teachers
and Director Eisinger.
A song, you mean?
Mm. I've got to find my parents.
Hey, I can sing.
You can?
Can I join the choir?
Will you be going on another trip soon?
- I guess so.
- Where to?
I don't know.
Japan, maybe, or Australia.
- Dad, Mother,
- Peter, darling.
Hello, son.
Hey, Toni.
Come on.
A fine thing.
So busy you can't even say hello, huh?
Sorry, Dad. Hello.
Dad, have you ever been to Australia?
Of course not.
Now, listen, Toni,
I've got a big surprise for you.
Guess what?
You're going to drive the train
into the shed.
How about that, huh?
Mom, they're going
to Japan and Australia next.
Oh, are they, dear?
You always say I sing well, don't you?
Now, Toni, you'll be driving a train
like this yourself one day.
Maybe even bigger. So now's the time
to learn, come on. First lesson.
Pull that.
Very good. All right, you can sit down.
Uh, Felix Meinl, please.
Now, Felix, I want you to sing
a C-major scale, all right?
- Yes, sir.
- Now.
That's Felix now. Pretty good, eh?
- Your boy sung yet?
- No.
- Only two vacancies, you know.
- Only two?
Listen.
Good.
Do you hear that?
Clear as a bell.
- How old is your boy?
- He'll be 1 2 in January.
They like them young, you know.
Felix isn't ten yet.
I wouldn't worry.
It's the voice that matters.
It's a nice-looking building, isn't it?
I wish they could live at home, though.
They look after them well.
That's Friedel now.
Your boy?
He's an orphan.
Sings in the village choir.
I'm the organist.
- He sings well.
- I taught him everything he knows.
What's he doing?
That's just what
I told him not to sing.
I like it. It's fun.
Maybe.
But it won't get him into the choir.
Your boy?
You have a song there,
haven't you?
- Yes, sir.
- Go ahead, then.
- When did this come?
- Yesterday.
- Huh?
- Well, you were tired last night.
Vienna Boys Choir?
Augarten Palace? What's this?
"In connection with the audition
given by Toni Fiala..."
What audition?
Did he give an audition?
- Yes, he did.
- When?
Last week.
- He sang beautifully.
- Oh, did he?
And may I ask who arranged it?
Well, I did, of course.
I wrote to Herr Eisinger,
the director, and he...
Fixed it all up on your own,
without a word to me.
- Behind my back.
- Well, I had to.
I knew you'd never let him go.
Oh, did you?
Well, you could've asked me.
And what would you have said?
I'd have said no.
What do you think I'd have said?
This all comes of...,
This all comes
of you playing the piano.
I should have stopped it years ago.
What do you mean, stopped it?
You talk as if music
is something to be ashamed of.
Well, I know what's
good for my son, that's all.
You know,
You don't know anything about him.
Toni's my son, too. Don't forget that.
- And it's me he takes after, not you.
- Oh, does he?
Yes, he does.
Toni was born to sing.
He has real talent,
and I want him to develop it.
And I want him to go to a proper school
and learn a proper trade.
And that is what he's going to do,
But this is a proper
school. Don't you understand that?
He'll get a good education,
besides singing in the choir.
Until his voice breaks.
They'll throw him out.
No, they wouldn't.
He could stay.
And how am I supposed
to pay for all this?
You don't pay.
It won't cost you anything.
- Herr Eisinger told me.
- Don't believe it.
Where do they get the money
to run the place?
From their concerts.
All over the world people go
to hear the Vienna Boys Choir.
Toni could travel, see other countries.
Well, he's not going.
Music, singing. Standing up
on a platform in a sailor suit.
I won't have it.
Oh, why can't I make you understand?
Toni loves music.
It means something to him.
He's different from other boys.
- I don't want him to be different.
- Well, I do.
One day, he'll be famous.
Composing maybe,
or playing in a great orchestra, like...
Like your brother
with his trumpet.
A dance band in Prater Park on
Saturdays and Sundays, if he's lucky.
Well, that's not
going to happen to Toni.
Dad, please.
I'm late for work.
But, Dad,
To be a Vienna choirboy...
Dad,
There were eight boys there,
and they only wanted two.
And they chose me.
Well, now they can
choose somebody else.
Dad, please, you've got to let me go.
Toni, come on up.
We'll talk about it some more tonight.
If you think I'll change my mind,
you're wrong.
Come on.
So if you'll get
the parts together, Joseph?
- I can go to the library now.
- All right.
- You are Toni, aren't you?
- Yes, sir.
Here's Director Eisinger.
This is Toni Fiala, sir.
Oh, yes, of course.
Good morning, Frau Fiala.
- Good morning, Herr Eisinger.
- Toni.
- This is my husband.
- How do you do, sir?
- Your first visit, of course.
- Yes, it is.
He's quite happy now,
about Toni's coming here.
Good. I'm sure you won't regret it.
He'll be in the choir
under Herr Heller here.
How about his ordinary lessons?
You don't have to worry
about that, Herr Fiala.
- We have first-class teachers.
- He's had proper schooling up to now.
I'm sure he has.
You understand, of course,
he'll be on probation for a month
before we accept him
as a permanent choirboy.
If he works hard at his music,
shows promise, then he stays.
He'll work hard. Won't you, Toni?
And if he's no good,
you throw him out?
Well, that goes for me, too.
If he doesn't get on with his schooling,
I'll pull him out.
- Now you remember that, Toni.
- Yes, Dad.
Uh, Peter? Peter.
This is Toni Fiala.
He'll be in your choir.
- How do you do?
- Pleased to meet you.
Will you look after him
till he knows his way around?
- Yes, sir.
- Right.
Goodbye, dear.
Work hard.
Bye, Dad.
Bye, son.
I'll show you
where to put your things.
That's all right.
But listen as you play.
Train your ear
as well as your fingers.
Yes, sir.
A good ear will
help you sing well, too.
It was you
in the eighth bar, wasn't it?
Yes, sir. I sang a B natural.
That's right.
Sing the bar again, please.
That's it.
Now, there was something wrong
in bar three.
Let me hear it from the start again.
Well?
Put your hand up.
Put it up.
I thought it was you, Toni.
Know what was wrong?
I think I sang D sharp
instead of E.
I'm sure you did. All right.
But always put your hand up at once
if you know you've made a mistake.
Don't wait for me to spot it.
I want you to know
you're wrong yourself.
- All right?
- Yes, sir.
Good. And now,
come out in front, all of you.
But no, no, no, leave your music.
Let's see how you manage
when you're all together.
Come on, come on. Come, come.
Right?
Now then, group one, on the upbeat.
And hit that first note
good and firm.
Group two,
you come in on bar five, all right?
No, no, no. Those top notes.
Not through the nose.
Take a breath, deep,
down here, like this.
And then sing out through your mouth,
good and full, right?
Take it from the beginning.
You should be outside.
It'll be dark soon.
Yes, sir.
Arithmetic?
- Do you enjoy reading this?
- No, sir.
What are you trying to do?
Get ahead of the others?
Oh, no, sir.
They're all better than me.
And my father says,
if I don't do well in class...
Come along.
Naturally, your father wants you
to do well with your schoolwork.
- He'll take me away if I don't.
- I know.
- Are you working hard?
- Yes, sir.
Peter Schaefer says,
I just don't work fast enough.
But then, he's so smart.
Peter is very fortunate.
He's got a quick, clear mind,
and a wonderful feeling for music.
Do you think
he'll be famous some day?
Well, he's a very gifted boy.
He can even compose music.
Did you know that?
And to be able
to do arithmetic, too...
Cheer up, Toni.
Know who that is?
It's Franz Schubert, isn't it?
- He was a Vienna choirboy.
- Was he?
Has the choir been going on
as long as that?
Much longer. Nearly 500 years.
Schubert was a choirboy in 1 808.
Well, not so very long ago, really.
And do you know something, Toni?
He wasn't any good
at arithmetic, either.
He only wanted to sing and write music.
Know this?
Schubert wrote this
while he was still a choirboy.
- He did?
- And plenty more.
Music seemed to pour out of him.
He just couldn't write it down
fast enough.
And then, one day,
his father came to the school
and looked at his school record.
It was terrible.
He told the director
he was taking his son away.
- And did he?
- No.
The director persuaded him
to give Franz another chance,
and so he stayed.
Do you think the director
could persuade my father?
Maybe your grades will improve.
Do you know this?
Yes, sir.
That's Schubert's The Linden Tree.
Hello, Peter.
This is one of your favorites.
Come and join in. It'll help Toni.
You sing the alto line, Peter.
I've always sung the lead.
It's a little high for you now.
Try the alto this time.
Good. You sing well together.
When you're a famous conductor,
don't leave Schubert out, Peter.
You know what he meant.
There's still some light.
Peter, take Toni out for some
fresh air before bedtime, hm?
Yes, sir.
But why do you blame me?
He asked me to sing.
That's my song. I've always sung it.
Herr Heller said
we sing well together.
Look, I'm the leader in this choir.
I will be for a year yet.
And I'm not singing any duets
with any new kid.
Hey, over here,
Hey, leave that alone.
Is it yours?
Yes. My dad gave it to me
last Christmas.
It's got two wavebands,
seven transistors.
Boy, I never saw one
like this before.
- How do you turn it on?
- No, don't.
A radio?
You're not supposed to have it here.
It's mine, Peter. I'm taking it home
with me this weekend.
Anyway, I wasn't playing it.
Come on, Peter, let's have some music.
- It's against the rules.
- There's nobody around.
No, don't do it.
We'll get into trouble.
You'll get into trouble.
It's your radio.
Give me that,
Try and get it.
Watch it,
Hey, Toni.
You're wanted in the director's office.
What for?
Can't you guess?
Come on, hurry up.
It wasn't only me.
You're the one who got caught.
Go on.
Do you think he'll tell?
How do I know?
Come in.
Well, Toni, you've completed
your period of probation.
Herr Heller came in to see me,
and we had a long talk about you.
I've studied your report card.
Your grades are not too good.
Although, your teachers assure me
that you are determined to improve.
And so...
...we have decided to accept you
as a Vienna choirboy.
Well?
- You mean I can stay?
- We want you to stay.
Hey,
Peter, I can stay,
Herr Eisinger told me I can stay.
What about last night?
Did you talk?
He didn't even ask me.
Herr Heller was there too.
I'm sure he hadn't said anything.
That's 'cause it was you.
Anyway, I'm really in the choir now.
And we're giving a concert in two weeks
at the children's hospital,
and Herr Heller says
I'm going to sing a solo.
- For eight bars?
- No, a whole song.
And we're all going
to dress up for it.
It's called The Postman.
Do you know it?
Yeah. Yeah, I know it.
I've got to find Friedel
and tell him I'm staying.
You know the cue
for you and Peter to come in?
- Yes, sir.
- Good.
I've never sung
to an audience before.
Not a solo.
Come on, get into it.
- lt feels too big.
- lt is too big. It was made for me.
I always sang The Postman song.
I'm sorry, Peter.
It was Herr Heller's idea.
Maybe you won't sing it.
Maybe you'll miss your entrance cue.
Heller wouldn't like that, would he?
Peter,
Peter, let me out,
Unlock the door. Please, Peter.
Ferdy, go and see
what's keeping Toni and Peter.
Yes, sir.
Where's Toni?
- I've locked him in.
- What?
Just to scare him.
Peter, Please open the door,
Don't worry,
I'll let him out in time.
Our mail is on its way
Go on, Peter, let him out now.
It's his first solo.
All right.
OK, Toni...
Look.
His back is bent beneath the load
The letters, we're awaiting
The news, anticipating
My goodness, we all feel the same
It's time the postman came
Again.
It's time the mailman came
Our watches say the same
The letters, we are awaiting
The news, anticipating
My goodness, we all feel the same
It's time the postman came
Here's mail for one and all
Now answer to my call
For you, a letter
And, for thee
a package from across the sea
The parcels, fascinating
And letters here are waiting
So gather round and you shall see
Here's mail for one and all
So gather round and we shall see
There's mail for one and all
- Toni.
- Yes, sir.
I want to talk to you
about your entrance today.
Don't you think it was
a little bit foolish of you?
Peter.
That stunt of young Toni's,
spectacular, but a little dangerous.
Did you know about it?
Yes, sir.
Of course, he swore you didn't.
He said he thought it up
all by himself.
But he might have fallen, you know.
I'm sorry, sir. It was my fault.
Well, maybe.
I don't expect you to be
a flock of angels,
even though you sing like them.
But you are the eldest, Peter.
All right.
Anyway, his solo was good, wasn't it?
Yes, it was.
Take a little interest in him
and help him along, if you can.
Good.
Why are you learning that?
I'm supposed to sing it
at High Mass, Sunday.
But it's so hard.
I'm not really good enough.
Who says so?
Come on.
So, it was all your own idea, was it?
What?
Oh, climbing in through the window.
Yes. 'Course it was.
Come on, sing.
No. No, no, no.
You're taking it too slow.
Sorry.
Again, from here.
Stop fidgeting.
Why don't they
give us cushions to sit on?
Be quiet.
Remember where you are.
I know that all right.
How much longer?
He sings again, doesn't he?
I think so.
- Toni.
- Yes?
- Where's Peter? Have you seen him?
- No, I haven't.
He hasn't eaten his lunch yet.
Go and look for him,
will you, please?
- OK, I will.
- Hey, wait for me.
Might have been Heller himself.
- Best orchestra I ever heard.
- Especially the strings.
No, Give it back,
it's none of your business.
It's a song. Words and all.
Is it yours, Peter?
Let me see.
Come on, boys, let's sing it.
OK.
- You'd only laugh.
- Why should we?
Come on, Peter, you conduct.
Go on, Peter.
Yeah, give us the note.
All right...
...but if you laugh...
...I'll murder the bunch of you.
All right, here's the note.
Now.
Oh, once upon a time
There lived a hen, and every day
As hens will do, an egg she'd lay
And thought she was sublime
And nearby was a stream
And in the stream there lived a trout
Who very calmly swam about
And listened to her scream
The trout said to the hen
Why such a fuss for just one, dear?
I lay a million eggs a year
And never flip a fin
Nor end up in a tin
Never mind, let's do it again.
He's frowning terribly, Mom.
Aw, don't you worry, dear.
I'll deal with him. Come on.
Hello, Dad.
It's not very good, is it?
It's not good at all.
But look, dear,
just because they say his...
What is that you were playing?
That? Oh, it's Mozart.
Do you have a lesson every day?
- Most days.
- Besides your singing?
We sing every day, of course.
Will you take that...
thing on the tour with you?
I suppose so, if I go on the tour.
What do you mean?
You are going, aren't you?
I don't know.
They might not let me, because of that.
You mean because
your arithmetic's not so good,
they'll stop you
from going on the tour?
That's a fine thing, isn't it?
Well, I won't have it.
But you always said
if his schoolwork wasn't good, you...
Never mind what I said.
The boy's a musician,
any fool can see that.
And I'm not having them
spoil his chances
for the sake of a lot of figures.
Dad, you mean it?
You leave it to me, son.
I'll talk to that director of yours.
Come on, now.
Let's hear some more music.
Arithmetic,
No, no, no, not that.
Sing.
But, Herr Fiala,
when Toni first came here,
it was you who insisted
it was his schooling that mattered.
A man can change his mind, can't he?
But in three or four years' time,
when his voice breaks...
Arithmetic, who cares
if he's not so good at it?
He's not going to be a bank clerk
or a lawyer or a bookkeeper, is he?
Possibly not.
Let me tell you, that boy's got talent.
And if you can't see it, I can.
I'm sorry, Herr Eisinger.
I'm afraid my husband
is rather outspoken.
I know my own mind, that's all.
But you understand, don't you, that
the final decision must rest with me?
All the other boys are going,
aren't they?
As it happens, yes.
Their schoolwork was satisfactory.
And Toni's wasn't? All right, then.
But I want him to go on that tour,
and that's final,
Your husband may not be a musician,
but he knows
how to change his tune, doesn't he?
Alas, my love
You do me wrong
To cast me off discourteously
And I have loved you so long
Delighting in
Your company
Greensleeves
Was all my joy
Was my delight
Greensleeves
Was my heart of gold
And who but my Lady
Greensleeves
Very nice, fellows.
But you haven't told us yet
where we're going on tour this year.
- You must tell us now.
- Please, sir.
All right, all right.
We're going to lndia,
Japan and Australia.
I told you it was gonna be Australia,
I'm gonna buy a boomerang.
And now about the Strauss opera.
I've picked the cast
and the director has approved it.
Peter, this time
you'll play Kipfel the baker.
It's within your range and not too high.
Yes, sir.
Uh, Friedel,
you'll be Mitzi,
the baker's daughter, all right?
Yes, sir.
Who's going to be my boyfriend?
Franz...
Let's see, now...
Oh, yes. That'll be you, Toni.
Joseph, you'll play the dandy.
Ferdy, you are the policeman.
And, Gerhard, you'll be
the captain of the guard.
Yes, sir.
Hey,
They should be turned up,
shouldn't they?
Don't take them off, I'll pin them.
Come here, Friedel.
Stand still, will you?
That's right.
Oh, Mitzi, will you marry me?
Isn't she sweet?
May I see you home?
Has it really broken, Peter?
Maybe it's just the top notes.
You could fake them.
No.
It's gone.
What are you going to do?
You know the part.
Here.
Hey, Toni,
What's the matter?
It's... It's Peter.
His voice is gone.
- Gone?
- lt's broken. He can't sing anymore.
- Not at all?
- I heard it. Just now.
But if he can't sing...
He said I'd have to play for him.
I know the part.
Where is Peter?
He ran out. What should we do?
Nothing yet. And don't tell anyone.
How many vacancies
are there this time?
Only two, I think.
Three.
Hey, Joseph. Have you seen Peter?
Peter? No, I haven't.
Peter.
Bet I can beat you to the top.
Bet you can't.
Come on, then.
Go.
What's the matter?
Didn't eat your spinach today?
I'm sorry, Peter.
- What for?
- Ferdy told me.
I don't know what you're talking about.
I heard it, too, just now.
Oh, well.
That happens to all of us
sooner or later.
Are you sure it's gone?
I'm not a choirboy anymore.
That's not everything.
I'll have more time for composing,
learning to conduct.
I'll go to the conservatory.
But, Peter, what about the tour?
You won't be able to go.
Maybe it's just a cold.
Maybe it'll be back tomorrow.
Peter, where are you going?
You can't see Herr Heller,
he's gone downtown.
I'll see him when he comes back, then.
Don't tell him, Peter.
Please don't tell him.
Why not?
I can't sing anymore.
I know, but maybe there's a way.
Anyway, don't tell him yet.
Please, Peter.
I've got to tell him.
We'll think of something.
With the dress rehearsal tomorrow?
Why don't you grow up?
Hello, Peter.
Have you come to lend us a hand?
Sir, I wanted to talk to you.
Right. Won't be a minute.
Hey, catch this cable.
Is it something urgent?
Well...
Now, plug it into the wall, over there.
He'll never get away with it.
They'll notice.
Not if we work it right.
He'll just have to keep his mouth shut
until we leave, that's all.
That'll take some doing.
Not if we all help him.
He won't let us. He'll tell Heller.
That's why we've got to hurry.
It's worth it, isn't it?
To have him on the tour with us.
They'll send him back
as soon as they find out.
All the way from lndia?
What will he do, then? He can't sing.
He can help Herr Heller, look after
the music, that sort of thing.
What about tomorrow, though?
The dress rehearsal?
He has to sing a solo.
That's sure to give him away.
Ferdy's gonna sing for him.
What?
- Shh,
- How?
I've thought it all out.
There's a way.
Sir, I just wanted to...
It won't take a minute,
then I'll be down.
Yes, sir.
So, that'll do it.
Come and have a look at it
from out front.
Can I say something, please, sir? I...
Max?
I'd like to check
all the concert dates with you.
- Right now?
- ln my office. Do you mind?
- Of course not.
- Please, sir...
Stay and help them here, Peter.
I'll be right back.
Yes, sir.
Oh, Peter,
I was looking at the song you wrote.
It's very promising.
Thank you, sir.
Why not put it in as an encore
now and then, Max?
I'd like to. How about it, Peter?
That'd be wonderful, sir.
- Good.
- Come along then, Max.
Hey, hey, what's this?
We just wanted to look
at the stage, sir.
All right, but don't get in the way.
Hey, Peter,
- We've got to talk to you.
- What about?
Up in the attic. Come on.
Hey.
You're doing great, Peter.
I'm sure they'll think it's you singing.
I'll never keep it up.
Yes, you will. You're doing fine.
Is something wrong?
- I'm sorry, Peter.
- Oh, go away.
I was trying to help you.
And I ended up making a fool of myself,
in front of everybody.
But, if you'd only kept it up...
How could I? He knew, Heller knew,
I'll take the blame. I'll tell him.
Oh, go away. Get out, will you?
Hello, Toni.
It was my idea.
Peter had nothing to do with it.
I talked the others into it
so he wouldn't miss the tour.
I know.
Why didn't you tell me
about your voice?
We've both known it was going
for some time, haven't we?
It was just bad luck
it should happen now,
but you should have told me.
I tried to yesterday
when you were fixing the lights.
Then Herr Eisinger came in
and talked about my song.
I see. That did make it tough for you.
It's not my voice that matters.
That happens to all of us.
It was being left behind, just when...
Just when what, Peter?
I'd planned to start writing on
the tour. Really work at composition.
- You could do that here.
- I know, but...
But what?
I wanted you to help me. You...
You understand.
And you know what I'm getting at.
Well, maybe when I come back.
Try to see it straight, Peter.
This isn't the end for you,
it's the beginning.
It's fun being a kid, but...
Well, till now
you've only been rehearsing.
See what I mean?
Anyway, we'll talk about it
some more tomorrow.
Naturally, it's a shame
that this should happen now.
But, for Peter,
there are compensations.
He'll still live here,
he'll work at the music conservatory.
He is talented, no doubt about that.
There's a great promise there,
as Max says.
Which is why I think he deserves
special consideration.
And that's not favoritism.
It's simply doing our job,
to encourage outstanding talent
when we find it.
I agree with that, of course.
He's still only a boy, don't forget.
He's not sure of himself yet.
He's a little scared of growing up.
So, just for a while,
he still needs other boys around him,
the boys he's worked and played with
for the past four years.
And that's why I say
he should come on this tour.
But, Max, we simply can't afford it.
Not as a passenger.
I'm not suggesting that.
- As what, then?
- As my assistant.
Let him be deputy conductor.
Well, that's certainly
a revolutionary idea.
He could do it.
His knowledge and understanding
are remarkable for his age.
And his technique's not bad at all.
The choir conducted
by one of the boys themselves?
That might be quite effective.
But would it be good?
It could be.
He wants to conduct and I'd coach him.
And it'd give him the belief in himself
he needs so badly at this moment.
Well, gentlemen,
what's our decision going to be?