[military drum cadence]
[military march music]
♪ ♪
[playing Anchors Aweigh]
- RIGHT FACE!
[helicopter rumbling]
- TEN...HUT!
- "DEAREST SWEET...
"THOUGHTFUL,
"UNDERSTANDING JANE,
I KNOW YOU WON'T BELIEVE THIS,
SWEETHEART..."
"BUT HERE GOES ANYWAY."
[deep breath]
"YOU MAY RECALL,
"YOU AND I
WERE TO BE MARRIED
"A YEAR AGO LAST JUNE."
"AS I DIDN'T TURN UP
FOR THE WEDDING
"AND SO MUCH TIME
HAS GONE BY,
"I CAN IMAGINE
YOU HAVE BEEN WONDERING--
"HA HA--
"WHAT HAPPENED.
"IT ALL BEGAN ONE DAY
DURING A ROUTINE MISSION
IN THE FAR PACIFIC."
- [over radio]
MANDRAKE 1-7 TO WINGDING.
I HAVE AN ANGEL 1-6.
REQUEST NEW COORDINATES
FOR POSITION FIX,
INDICATING 3-4-0,
HEADING 2-7-2.
FIRE WARNING LIGHT ON.
FIRE WARNING LIGHT ON?
SMOKE AND FIRE
FROM STARBOARD SIDE!
ESTIMATED POSITION, 300 MILES
WEST OF PORT MORESBY.
MAYDAY! MAYDAY!
EJECTING, OUT.
OH!
WHOA!
[plane whistling]
[panting]
SURVIVAL KIT.
AH, BOY.
narrator:    "SURVIVAL
AT SEA AND LIKE IT!"
- OH, BOY.
narrator:
"CHAPTER ONE: DOWN AT SEA.
"ALL RIGHT, MISTER, LET'S TAKE
STOCK OF THE SITUATION.
"FIRST THING WE'VE GOT TO
REMEMBER IS RELAX.
"DON'T PANIC.
"TRY TO ACHIEVE A CHEERFUL,
"CONSTRUCTIVE
FRAME OF MIND AT ALL TIMES.
"NOW LET'S
CHECK OUT THE SUPPLIES
"IN YOUR WATERPROOF
SURVIVAL KIT.
"HERE WE GO.
WATER FLASK."
- YEAH.
RIGHT.
narrator:
"FISH HOOKS."
- OW! MM!
narrator:
"NYLON CORD."
- A-FFIRMATIVE.
narrator:
"COMPASS."
- YEAH.
narrator:
"SHAMMY CLOTH."
- ALL RIGHT.
Narrator:
"DYE MARKER, SIGNALING MIRROR,
WATERPROOF
MERCURY FLASHLIGHT--"
- NO, HOLD IT, HOLD IT, HOLD IT.
narrator: OH.
- OKAY.
narrator: "FLARES,
"WHISTLE,
"SUN VISOR,
BAILING SPONGE."
- ROGER.
narrator: "SOLAR STILL
FOR MAKING DRINKING WATER,
"SUNBURN OINTMENT,
"FABRIC PATCHING KIT,
"AIR PUMP,
KITCHEN MATCHES."
- HOLD IT. HOLD IT.
I DON'T SEE ANY AIR PUMP.
narrator:
"CONCERNING AIR PUMP,
SEE ASTERISK
AT BOTTOM OF PAGE."
"ASTERISK. AIR PUMP,
DISCONTINUATION OF.
"DUE TO INEFFICIENT PERFORMANCE
OF AIR PUMP IN SURVIVAL KIT,
"THEY ARE
NO LONGER IN USE.
USE YOUR LUNGS."
- OKAY, HOW ABOUT SOME FOOD?
narrator:
"EACH KIT HOLDS SIX TINS
"OF CONCENTRATED
FOOD TABLETS,
"EACH UNIT ROUGHLY
THE NUTRITIONAL EQUIVALENT OF...
[chuckles]
A THANKSGIVING TURKEY DINNER."
- HMM!
narrator: "FIRST, HOWEVER,
A WORD OF WARNING.
TAKE NO MORE
THAN ONE TABLET OF EACH..."
- OR THEY'LL HANG IN YOUR CHEST
LIKE A LEAD BALLOON.
[hiccups]
narrator: "OR THEY MAY CAUSE
SOME INTERNAL DISTRESS."
- [hiccups]
"H," "H," "H," "H."
[hiccups]
THAT'S GREAT.
NOTHING LISTED FOR HICCUPS.
[hiccups]
WHAT CAN I TAKE? [hiccups]
PUT A SHOPPING BAG
ON YOUR HEAD.
THAT'S NO GOOD.
NO SHOP--[hiccups]
NO SHOPPING BAG.
WHAT ELSE? [hiccups]
FRIGHTEN YOURSELF.
ALL RIGHT.
UH...LOOK OUT!
THERE'S AN OCTOPUS
IN THE BOAT!
[hiccups]
THERE'S ANOTHER ONE.
WHAT ELSE?
STAND ON YOUR HEAD
AND HOLD YOUR BREATH.
[hiccups]
OKAY, I'LL STAND ON MY HEAD
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE OCEAN.
[hiccups]
I DON'T THINK
THIS IS GONNA [hiccups] WORK.
A SAIL!
HEY, SAIL! AHOY!
OVER HERE, SAIL!
LOOKS LIKE A CHINESE JUNK.
HEY! HERE!
AMERICAN!
HEY! HURRY UP!
CHOP-CHOP!
OH, NICE CHINESE SAILOR
MAKE AMERICAN BOY
VERY HAPPY.
HEY! [hiccups]
HEY, OVER HERE, SAILBOAT!
YOU'RE NOT A SAILBOAT!
YOU'RE A SHARK.
YOU'RE A SHARK!
HEY! NO, GO BACK!
GO BACK! NO!
GET OUT OF HERE!
WHOA!
[shark scrapes raft]
narrator: "SHARKS ARE
ALL COWARDS AT HEART.
"CHANCES ARE,
A WELL-PLACED BLOW
"ON THE SENSITIVE AREA
AROUND HIS NOSE
WILL SEND HIM PACKING."
- A BLOW ON THE NOSE?
YOU GOTTA BE KIDDING.
narrator: "A WELL-PLACED BLOW
ON THE NOSE!"
- OKAY.
COME AND
GET YOUR WELL-PLACED BLOW.
AAH!
OH! OH!
AH, THIS ISN'T IN THE MANUAL,
BUT COME AND GET IT!
HA HA HA!
HA! A WELL-PLACED BLOW
ON THE NOSE, HUH?
PUT THAT
IN YOUR MANUAL NEXT TIME.
[escaping air squealing]
AAH!
[air squealing]
[inflation tube squeaking]
[escaping air squealing]
[hiccups]
[squealing diminishes]
[sputtering]
[hiccups]
[blowing]
[sputtering]
AAH!
[inflation tube squeaks]
"AND THAT, DEAR JANE,
IS HOW I DISCOVERED
A NEW WAY TO GET RID
OF THE HICCUPS."
"THE FINAL LEAK WAS PATCHED,
"AND AFTER A CERTAIN AMOUNT
OF TWISTING AND TURNING,
I MANAGED TO FALL ASLEEP."
[shark scraping]
"EVERYTHING MIGHT
HAVE BEEN ALL RIGHT
IF IT WASN'T
FOR MY OLD PROBLEM--"
"SLEEPWALKING."
AAH!
[grunts]
[helmet crunches]
YOU COME BACK,
YOU GET MORE OF THE SAME!
"NOW I WAS IN REAL TROUBLE.
"EVERYTHING--FOOD, WATER,
EVERYTHING I NEEDED
TO SUSTAIN LIFE, WAS GONE."
"FOUR DAYS LATER.
"NO FOOD,
"NO WATER.
"THE SUN BEAT DOWN
RELENTLESSLY.
"EVEN THE SHARK
HAD RUN OUT ON ME.
NOT A SIGN OF LIFE
ANYWHERE."
narrator: "IF YOU SHOULD RUN
OUT OF PROVISIONS, DON'T PANIC.
"MAN HAS BEEN KNOWN TO LIVE
OVER 70 DAYS WITHOUT FOOD.
"HOWEVER,
AND MARK THIS WELL,
MAN DOES REQUIRE WATER."
"MORE THAN FOUR DAYS
WITHOUT WATER,
"AND THE HUMAN MACHINE
WILL FIND ITSELF
IN EXTREME DIFFICULTY."
[thunder booming]
- WATER.
HEY.
HEY, RAIN.
SOAK IT UP.
HEY! HEY, RAIN!
[laughing]
RAIN!
SAVE THE RAIN!
BEAUTIFUL RAIN!
[laughing]
I'VE GOT RAIN!
I'VE GOT BEAUTIFUL RAIN!
HEY, SAVE
THE BEAUTIFUL RAIN!
I'M SINKING!
GET RID
OF THE BEAUTIFUL RAIN!
GET RID OF THE RAIN!
OH!
[grunts]
[Hawaiian music playing]
[people chattering]
- HEY.
OOH.
[chuckling]
YOU'LL HAVE
TO EXCUSE MY APPEARANCE.
I HAD A ROUGH NIGHT.
I MUST LOOK A SIGHT.
[wind whistling]
[birds calling]
narrator: "CHAPTER 10:
ALONE ON AN ISLAND.
"WELL, WE MADE IT,
DIDN'T WE?
"SO KNOCK OFF LYING THERE,
MISTER, AND MOVE IT.
LOTS OF THINGS TO DO!
UPSA-DAISY! IN THE--"
[narrator's voice muffled
and gurgling]
- SHUT UP!
"ONCE I MADE MY PLIGHT KNOWN
TO THE OUTSIDE WORLD,
I FELT BETTER."
"THE NEXT MOST PRESSING THOUGHT:
WHERE WAS I?
"I MADE
A CRUDE SEXTANT
AND TOOK A NOON SIGHT
ON THE SUN."
ACCORDING TO MY CALCULATIONS,
I AM SOMEWHERE BETWEEN...
ELMIRA, NEW YORK,
AND MUNCIE, INDIANA.
YA--
"NIGHT WAS COMING ON NOW.
"WITH PALM FRONDS
AND STICKS
"AND MY PONCHO
FROM THE DINGHY,
I BUILT
A SNUG LITTLE SHELTER."
OH, BOY, AM I LOOKING FORWARD
TO A GOOD NIGHT'S SLEEP.
WELL, AS CONFUCIUS SAY,
"WHEN IN SOUP,
MIGHT AS WELL ENJOY FLAVOR."
BOY. TOO MUCH!
[wind blowing]
[thunder booming]
[pancho creaking]
OH.
[sputtering]
NO!
OW!
OH OH! AH-OOH!
OOH!
"THE DAYS BEGAN TO PASS.
"STILL NOT A GLIMPSE
OF A PLANE OR SHIP.
"NOT A SIGN OF LIFE ANYWHERE,
"SAVE FOR BIRDS
AND SMALL ANIMALS.
"TRYING TO CONSERVE
MY OLD CLOTHES
"BEFORE THEY
BECAME HOPELESS TATTERS,
"I FASHIONED NEW ONES
OUT OF THE MATERIALS AT HAND.
"NOTHING PRETENTIOUS,
A WARM-WEATHER ENSEMBLE.
"PLEATED HAT OF PALM,
"ANTI-SUNSTROKE ACCESSORY,
"AND A JACKET
CUT ALONG SIMPLE LINES.
A DEEP, PLUNGING 'V'
IN FRONT AND LACED SIDES."
[birds squawking]
LET'S SEE.
MAY, JUNE, JULY.
7, 14, 21...
22ND, 23RD, 24TH.
ANOTHER DAY, ANOTHER NUT.
JULY 25TH.
♪ HAPPY BIRTHDAY TO YOU ♪
♪ HAPPY BIRTHDAY,
LIEUTENANT CRUSOE ♪
♪ HAPPY BIRTHDAY TO YOU ♪ ♪
HMM!
[jungle creature vocalizing]
"DRIVEN
BY LONELINESS AND CURIOSITY,
"I RESOLVED TO
EXPLORE THIS LONELY ISLAND,
IF IT WAS AN ISLAND."
"STILL NO SIGN
OF ANOTHER HUMAN BEING.
IT WAS ALMOST AS IF I WERE
THE FIRST PERSON ON EARTH."
"I GUESS I ALWAYS KNEW
IT WOULD HAPPEN SOMEDAY.
"DEAR, YOU NEVER KNEW
MY FATHER.
"HIS NAME WAS JOE CRUSOE.
"POP WAS
A FRUSTRATED STREETCAR MOTORMAN
"BACK IN KANSAS CITY, KANSAS,
"WHO ALWAYS WANTED
TO RUN AWAY TO SEA.
"HE NEVER MADE IT,
"BUT HE STUCK ME
WITH THE NAME ROBINSON.
WHY COULDN'T DAD HAVE
NAMED ME DWIGHT OR LYNDON?"
[wind whistling]
"IT WAS INDEED AN ISLAND.
"NOW I KNEW FOR CERTAIN.
I WAS ALONE."
"I TOOK
A NEW DIRECTION HOMEWARD,
"COMING UPON
A PART OF THE SHORE
"THAT WAS UNKNOWN TO ME.
"AT FIRST,
I PAID SCANT ATTENTION
"BECAUSE I WAS TOO BUSY
FEELING SORRY FOR MYSELF.
THEN I SAW IT."
[foreboding Japanese
music playing]
♪ ♪
[hatch creaking]
[hatch thuds]
HELLO?
HELLO!
UH, WAR OVER.
ME...ME A FRIEND
OF SESSUE HAYAKAWA.
OKAY?
HELLO?
ANYBODY HERE?
[imitating sonar]
BOOP-BOO-BOO-BOOP.
[chuckles]
I'VE ALWAYS WANTED
TO DO THIS.
BOOP-BOO-BOO-BOOP.
BOOP-BOO-BOOP.
OW.
HELLO!
[metal creaking]
[creaking]
[squeaks]
[metal creaking]
[heart beating]
[clattering]
[metal scraping]
[scrapes]
AAH!
[metal creaking]
[footsteps]
WHAT? OH, I...
HELLO. HA.
OH. [laughs] THAT'S ...
[hands thud]
MMM!
UH, HELLO THERE.
[laughs] UH...
CAPTAIN NEMO,
I PRESUME, HUH?
I MEAN,
YOU PROBABLY NEVER READ
20,000 LEAGUES UNDER THE...
I SURE ADMIRE
THAT GUN YOU GOT THERE.
BET SOMETHING LIKE THAT
COULD BLOW
A HOLE BIG ENOUGH TO...
UH...
MIND IF
I HAVE A LOOK AT IT?
UH, THAT'S--
IT'S NOT AN AMERICAN-MADE--
[bullet ricocheting]
[shatters]
- [blows]
[gunshot]
[shrieking, whimpering]
- WELL, THERE, THERE, BUDDY.
IT'S OKAY NOW.
HEY, LISTEN,
HOW'D YOU GET HERE ANYWAY?
LISTEN, WHO ARE YOU?
HUH?
A FELLOW AMERICAN!
OH, BOY. IF YOU ONLY KNEW
HOW GLAD I AM TO SEE YOU.
WHAT'S THIS?
"ASTRO-CHIMP FLOYD?
"PROJECT MERCURY.
"DISCOVERER OF BEARER
PLEASE NOTIFY NAVY DEPARTMENT,
WASHINGTON, D.C."
AN ASTRO-CHIMP.
WELL, SIR,
LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHING,
WHAT AN HONOR IT IS
FOR ME TO MEET YOU.
IN MY BOOK, YOU'RE ONE OF
THE GREAT HEROES OF OUR TIME.
HEY, YOU MIND
IF I LOOK AROUND IN HERE?
"OF COURSE,
HE COULDN'T ANSWER,
"BUT I COULD ALMOST FIGURE IT
OUT FOR MYSELF.
"IT WAS YEARS
SINCE THE CHIMP PROGRAM
"ON SPACE PROBES
WAS PHASED OUT.
"FLOYD PROBABLY LANDED
OUT OF RECOVERY RANGE,
"FLOATED TO SHORE
IN A SPACE CAPSULE,
"BROKEN OUT,
AND MANAGED SOMEHOW TO SURVIVE.
"AFTER ALL,
WHY SHOULDN'T HE SURVIVE?
"FLOYD WASN'T
JUST ANY ANIMAL.
"THE NAVY SELECTED
THESE CREATURES ORIGINALLY
"FOR THEIR HIGH DEGREE
OF ADAPTABILITY.
"AND AS I RECALL,
"THE I.Q.s OF THOSE ASTRO-CHIMPS
COMPARED FAVORABLY
WITH, SAY, THOSE
OF YOUR AVERAGE NAVAL ENSIGN."
OH, BOY!
A JAPANESE SUPERMARKET!
WAIT A MINUTE.
LET'S NOT LOSE OUR HEADS HERE.
I DON'T NEED COMIC BOOKS.
I DON'T NEED
THE GAS MASK, EITHER.
I DON'T NEED...
WHATEVER THAT IS.
NOW, LET'S DO IT
THE WAY ROBINSON CRUSOE
DID IT
HUNDREDS OF YEARS AGO.
STILL MAKES SENSE.
YOU TAKE THINGS
OFF THE SHIP
IN THE ORDER
OF THEIR IMPORTANCE.
A STORM COULD COME ALONG
AND TAKE THE BOAT
RIGHT OFF THE REEF
AND SINK IT IN DEEP WATER.
TOOLS.
NEED PLENTY OF TOOLS.
CANDLES.
BLANKETS.
OH, CAN I USE BLANKETS.
GOSH, THESE LITTLE JAPANESE
HOUSES ARE SURE CUTE.
THEY'RE SIMPLE, TOO.
HEY, FLOYD, I'LL BET
WE COULD BUILD ONE OF THEM.
LET'S SEE.
"WE STRIPPED THE SUBMARINE
OF TOOLS AND MATERIALS,
"AND BORROWING SOMEWHAT
"FROM THE TINKER TOY SCHOOL
OF ARCHITECTURE,
"WE FINISHED
IN A COUPLE OF WEEKS.
"IT LOOKED A LITTLE LIKE
A DOLLHOUSE WITH A HANGOVER,
BUT WE WERE PROUD OF IT."
"WE NOW HAVE A NEW ADDITION
TO THE HOUSEHOLD.
"A LITTLE MYNAH BIRD
"CAME BY WHILE
WE WERE FINISHING THE HOUSE,
AND IT SEEMS HE HAS
ATTACHED HIMSELF TO US."
- [chirps]
- HELLO, JANE.
- NO, NO.
UH, ME ROB, YOU JANE.
- ME ROB, YOU JANE.
- NO, LET'S
GET THIS STRAIGHT.
JANE.
GET THAT? REMEMBER?
- REMEMBER? JANE.
REMEMBER? JANE.
- NEVER MIND.
WE'LL WORK ON IT LATER.
[Floyd chattering]
- OH, FLOYD,
THAT'S VERY PRETTY.
JUST PUT IT OVER HERE.
ANYPLACE IS ALL RIGHT.
VERY PRETTY!
"I MUST CLOSE NOW,
SWEETHEART,
AS I WANT TO CATCH
THE OUTGOING TIDE."
"I'LL BE WRITING
EVERY DAY NOW.
ALL MY LOVE, ROB."
- REMEMBER? JANE.
REMEMBER? JANE.
- YOU BET YOUR BEADY,
LITTLE BLACK EYES
I'LL REMEMBER JANE.
THAT GIRL
IS ONE IN A MILLION.
BE BACK IN A MINUTE, FLOYD.
I'M GONNA GO DOWN
AND MAIL A LETTER.
- REMEMBER? JANE.
- [whistling]
ONWARD, O MISSIVE OF LOVE,
THROUGH WIND AND RAIN
AND SLEET AND SNOW,
THE MAIL MUST GO THROUGH.
[water flushing]
[whistling]
[shells clacking]
ALL RIGHT.
I'LL CALL YOU.
LET ME SEE YOU BEAT
THREE PRETTY LITTLE GEISHAS.
ALL RIGHT. ALL RIGHT.
THREE SAMURAI
BEAT THREE GEISHAS.
GO ON. TAKE 'EM.
[bird squawks]
OH, BOY!
- AH, SHUT UP!
- SHUT UP. DEAL.
- GOTTA GO PLAY A GAME OF SKILL
WITH A DUMB ANIMAL.
- AWK! SHUT UP AND DEAL.
SHUT UP AND DEAL.
- HAVE I GOT A SURPRISE FOR YOU
COME THANKSGIVING.
- SHUT UP AND DEAL!
- WONDER WHAT THIS STUFF IS
WE GOT OFF THE SUBMARINE?
LOOKS LIKE SOME KIND
OF A JAPANESE SOFT DRINK.
- OH, BOY.
OH, BOY.
OH!
[bottle fizzes]
- IT'S NOT BAD.
KUMQUAT COLA
OR SOMETHING.
- OH, BOY! [squawks]
- A LITTLE FOR YOU
AND A LITTLE FOR ME.
OKAY, BUDDY BOY,
HERE WE GO.
I DEAL AGAIN.
[fizzing]
OKAY.
I OPEN FOR TWO CLAMS.
AND FOR PETE'S SAKE,
FLOYD,
DON'T GO APE
WITH THE BETTING.
IT ALWAYS SPOILS THE GAME.
OKAY, HOW MANY CARDS?
NOW, COME ON, FLOYD!
I'M TRYING
TO TEACH YOU THE GAME.
A FULL HOUSE.
ALL RIGHT. LUCKY.
[drink fizzing]
[imitating Boris Karloff]
WATCH THIS ONE.
[chuckles]
MMM.
COME ON, FLOYD.
BOTTOMS UP.
CHUG-A-LUG.
HOW MANY CARDS?
ALL RIGHT, WISE GUY.
OKAY, WISE GUY.
I'LL PLAY THESE...
AND I'LL BET 'EM ALL.
[shells rattling]
READ THEM AND WEEP.
NOT AGAIN.
ALL RIGHT,
TAKE IT ALL.
GO ON, TAKE IT ALL!
HOPE YOU'RE...
HOPE YOU'RE PROUD OF YOURSELF.
DO YOU--
DO YOU KNOW SOMETHING,
MY FINE, HAIRY YOUNG FRIEND?
[slurring]
YOU KNOW SOMETHING?
YOU PLAY POKER LIKE A WOMAN.
YOU KNOW WHY?
BECAUSE
A WOMAN DOESN'T KNOW
WHAT CARDS SHE'S PLAYING,
EITHER,
AND SHE ALWAYS WINS.
AND I'LL TELL YOU
WHY SHE ALWAYS WINS.
- REMEMBER? JANE.
[squawks]
REMEMBER? JANE.
- FLOYD, DID I EVER SHOW YOU
A PICTURE OF MY FIANCEE?
THIS IS
THE MOST BEAUTIFUL CREATURE
IN THE WHOLE WORLD, FLOYD.
ISN'T SHE LOVELY?
I DON'T SUPPOSE YOU ASTRO--
[hiccups]
ASTRO-CHIMPS EVER HAD
A LADY FRIEND, HUH?
I MEAN,
YOU JUST NEVER HAD ONE.
ALL THAT RIGOROUS
FLIGHT TRAINING AND--AND, UH...
REGULAR...REGULAR HOURS
AND NO DAMES,
STRICT...STRICT RULES.
OH, FLOYD, SHE'S LOVELY.
SHE'S--SHE'S IN SHOW BUSINESS,
I SEE, HUH?
OH, FLOYD,
HOW YOU MUST MISS HER.
FLOYD?
FLOY--FLOYD, A TOAST.
A TOAST WITH THIS DELICIOUS
JAPANESE SOFT DRINK.
TO OUR LADIES FAIR...
WHERE E'ER THEY ARE, MAY BE.
FROM--FROM THEIR LONELY,
LOYAL SAIL--UH, BOYS.
[sniffling]
FLOYD, YOU LOOK TERRIBLE.
I BETTER PUT YOU TWO
TO BED.
YOU KNOW,
YOU SHOULDN'T--
YOU SHOULDN'T BREAK
TRAINING LIKE THAT, FLOYD.
JUST A MINUTE, FLOYD.
[bottle fizzes
and whistles]
MM.
YOU KNOW SOMETHING,
FLOYD?
THEY OUGHT
TO BOTTLE THIS STUFF.
[bird squawks]
- CAW! CAW! CAW!
FLOYD, A TOAST.
TO THE UNITED STATES NAVY
AND TO THE WORLD
IN GENERAL,
WHEREVER THEY MAY BE.
[lullaby playing]
♪ ♪
- COCK-A-DIDDLE-DOO!
AWK! COCK-A-DIDDLE-DOO!
COCK-A-DIDDLE-DOO!
COCK-A-DIDDLE-DIDDLE!
COCK-A-DIDDLE-DIDDLE-
DIDDLE-DIDDLE!
- OOH.
- COCK-A-DIDDLE-DOODLE!
AWK!
IT'S NOT
"COCK-A-DIDDLE-DOODLE."
IT'S "COCK-A-DOODLE-DO."
"COCK-A-DOODLE-DO."
HOW MANY TIMES
DO I HAVE TO TELL YOU?
- COCK-A-DOODLE-DO!
COCK-A-DOODLE-DO!
[squawks, laughs]
[squawking and laughing]
- OH, THAT WAS A GREAT IDEA...
- COCK-A-DOODLE-DO!
TRAINING THE BIRD
TO BE AN ALARM CLOCK.
OH!
[whistles]
- [chattering]
- MMM.
KUMQUAT COLA.
[thuds]
AH!
[gasps]
WHY DON'T YOU LEAD OFF?
YOU GO OFF FIRST.
HERE.
NOW, REMEMBER,
KEEP YOUR HEAD...
WATCH YOUR GRIP.
THAT--NO, THAT'S ALL WRONG.
YOU LIFTED YOUR HEAD...
NICE SHOT.
LOUSY FORM
AND A NICE SHOT.
SOMETIMES IT'S JUST LUCK.
OOH!
- [chattering]
[laughing]
- OH, DON'T GET FUNNY.
JAPANESE CLUBS ARE
A LITTLE SHORT FOR ME, FLOYD.
- [loudly groans]
- OHH.
OH, THAT'S A GREAT LIE,
THAT IS.
RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE
OF A FOOTPRINT.
FLOYD, YOUR FOOTPRINTS
ARE ALL OVER THE PLACE.
HOW MANY TIMES
HAVE I TOLD YOU
TO RAKE OVER
YOUR FOOTPRINTS
WHEN YOU WALK
THROUGH A SAND TRAP?
IT'S ONE OF THE CARDINAL RULES
OF PLAYIN' GOLF.
YOU REPLACE YOUR DIVOTS
AND YOU...
YOU KNOW SOMETHING?
THAT DOESN'T LOOK
LIKE YOUR FOOTPRINT.
[chuckles]
FLOYD, I'M SORRY.
IT'S ONE OF MINE.
LOOK AT THIS.
[chuckles]
ACTUALLY,
IT'S A LITTLE, UH...
LITTLE SMALL FOR MINE,
ISN'T IT?
FLOYD...
WE'RE NOT ALONE.
[whispering]
COME ON!
STAY CLOSE TO ME, FLOYD.
WHY'D IT GET SO QUIET
ALL OF A SUDDEN?
- [screeches]
- COME ON, LET'S GO.
THAT MEANS EVERYBODY,
SAILOR.
- [hooting]
- COME ON!
- [whimpering]
- SEE, FLOYD?
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
JUST AN ORDINARY DARK,
TERRIFYING CAVE.
- [screams]
- AAH! OWW!
[thud]
- AAH!
- HEY! BE CAREFUL!
YOU'RE GONNA HURT SOMEBODY!
- [chattering]
[screeching]
- OW! OW! OW!
OW! OW!
OW!
[Rob groans]
NOW, LISTEN.
JUST CALM DOWN.
I'M NOT--
I'M NOT GONNA HURT YOU.
SEE? I'M NOT
GONNA HURT YOU. JUST--
THAT'S IT.
I'M NOT GONNA HURT YOU.
NOW, WAIT. DON'T, DON'T.
HEY!
DON'T STAND THERE,
YOU DUMB APE!
WE'RE NOT PLAYIN'!
- [grunting]
- WHAT IS THE MATTER
WITH YOU?
OW!
[girl straining]
- ALL RIGHT...
[panting]
NOW, I TURN YOU LOOSE,
YOU GONNA BE GOOD?
ALL RIGHT.
NOW, JUST--JUST STAY CALM.
SEE?
NOTHING TO BE UPSET ABOUT.
JUST BE CALM.
THAT'S IT.
ALL NICE. NICE NOW.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
ME TOURIST.
ALL SMILES.
SEE TEETH?
BOY, YOU KNOW SOMETHING?
YOU'RE AS STRONG AS A MAN.
- [growls]
- OH, BOY!
DOGGONE IT! WATCH IT!
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH YOU?
[girl growls]
- OW!
QUIT! OW!
"SO HERE, MY DEAR,
WAS THE DILEMMA.
"I COULDN'T
TURN HER LOOSE.
"POOR, WILD THING
"ONLY SEEMED TO HAVE THIS
ONE FIXED IDEA IN HER MIND.
"SHE SIMPLY
WANTED TO KILL ME,
"SO I HAD TO KEEP HER.
"I'M SURE YOU UNDERSTAND.
I HAD TO KEEP AN EYE ON HER
FOR MY OWN PROTECTION."
[laughs] I SURE TIED MYSELF
A KNOT THERE.
THERE IT IS.
OKAY, NOW...
NO MORE FUNNY STUFF, HUH?
THERE.
SEE?
YOUR FRIEND ROB NO HURT.
UH...YOU HUNGRY?
WANT, UH, FOOD?
KAU KAU?
YOU THIRSTY?
WANT WATER?
DRINK?
YEAH.
"LIKE ALL WILD THINGS,
"I KNEW,
SOONER OR LATER,
SHE'D RESPOND
TO A LITTLE HUMAN KINDNESS."
HEY! TAKE IT EASY!
HEY! THAT'S DANGEROUS!
[Floyd screeching]
HEY! HERE WE GO!
LADY, WATCH IT!
OKAY.
WE KNOW HOW TO DIE
IN KANSAS CITY.
JUST MAKE IT QUICK.
- [crying]
- LISTEN, IF YOU DON'T MIND
MY SAYING SO,
YOU SEEM
A LITTLE ERRATIC.
- [sobbing]
- HEY, WHAT'S
THE MATTNOW?
[girl sobbing]
- HEY, WHAT'S WRONG
WITH YOU?
WHAT DID I DO?
LOOK...
YOU--YOU LIVE THIS ISLAND?
YOU GROW UP HERE?
WHERE...WHERE HOUSE?
WHERE YOU SLEEP, HUH?
- [sobbing]
- YOU--YOU COME, UH...
YOU COME ACROSS WATER?
YOU PADDLE ON BOAT HERE?
YOU--YOU LIVE OTHER ISLAND?
YOU--YOU ALL ALONE?
NOW WE'RE GETTIN' SOMEWHERE.
YOU GOT, UH...
YOU GOT A FATHER?
[Floyd hooting]
- PLEASE STAY
OUT OF THIS, FLOYD.
I'M TRYING
TO FIND OUT SOMETHING.
HOO-HOO-HOO--OH.
I'VE BEEN AROUND
THAT CHIMP TOO LONG.
WHO IS YOUR FATHER?
YOUR FATHER, UH, FISHERMAN?
FATHER FISH?
UH, FATHER RAISE COCONUT?
UM...
FATHER HAVE TRADING POST?
MAKE BOATS.
FATHER MAKE BOATS?
YOUR FATHER'S A MONKEY?
FATHER'S A...HE, UH...
A CHIEF, HUH?
FATHER, CHIEF!
OH, YEAH. BIG CHIEF.
YEAH.
UH, IS HE A NICE FELLA?
HE NOT NICE FELLA.
HIM, UH...
UH, MAYBE CANNIBAL?
YOU KNOW, UH...
CANNIBAL.
- [laughs]
WELL, THAT'S GOOD.
UH, SHE SAYS
HER FATHER'S A HEADHUNTER.
[laughing]
WHY YOU COME THIS ISLAND?
YOU...
YEAH, YOU--YOU FATHER.
YEAH.
HE SAY YOU...
YOU...
UH, S--UM...
YOU, UM...
OH! MARRY!
YOU MARRY! YEAH.
YOU MARRY...
UH, A GUY OTHER ISLAND?
AND HE'S UGLY, YEAH.
UGLY GUY
FROM OTHER ISLAND.
YOU FATHER...
HE GET, UH, BRACELETS,
YEAH, NECKLACES, AND...
OH-HO,
HE GETS PAID FOR THIS.
HE GETS MONEY.
UH-HUH.
YOU...YOU SAY NO.
YOU SAY BIG NO.
YOU SAY NO,
YOU WANT TO MARRY, UH...
YOU WANT TO MARRY...
THE CHIMP?
YOU WANT TO MARRY, UH,
TALL. TALL.
BIG, YEAH.
BIG FELLA WITH A--
THAT SMILES A LOT.
YEAH, A LOT OF TEETH.
UH-HUH.
BUT...WAIT.
YOU FATHER, HE...
HE SEND YOU
TO THE...TO SEAGULLS.
NO, THE--
SEND YOU TO THE...
THE SHARKS.
I GOT THAT, YEAH.
BUT WAIT.
FATHER...
CHANGED HIS HEAD.
CHANGED--
CHANGED HIS MIND!
FATHER CHANGED HIS MIND.
YEAH?
HE PADDLED YOU...
TO THIS ISLAND.
WELL, WHY?
HE BRING YOU TO SEE...
A BIG...
FRANKENSTEIN.
NO, YOU SEE
THE BIG, GREEN GIANT. NO.
- OOH!
TURN YOU INTO STONE.
- NO. KABUNA.
KABUNA!
- WHO'S KABUNA?
- KABUNA EVIL GOD
OF ISLAND.
KILL, KILL!
BIG HOO!
ALL FINISH UP.
- THE BIG STONE FACE
WHERE I FOUND YOU, HUH?
WELL, WHY DIDN'T YOU SAY...
YOU SPEAK ENGLISH.
- OH, YES.
SPEAK ENGLISH PLENTY GREAT.
FLUENTLY.
- WHY DID YOU KEEP IT
SUCH A BIG SECRET?
WE WOULDN'T HAVE HAD TO GO
THROUGH THAT OTHER STUFF.
- I LIKE OTHER STUFF.
GOOD GAME.
A JOY FOR ME.
MOST TIME,
I CATCH SAD LIFE.
MUST MAKE UP GOOD THINGS.
- OH, YOU
MAKE UP THINGS, HUH?
LIKE ABOUT YOUR FATHER
A BAD CHIEF
AND SENDING
YOU HERE TO DIE.
- OH, NO. ALL TRUE.
FATHER ALL BAD.
THROW ALL WIVES, NOISY DAUGHTERS
KAU KAU TO SHARK.
LAUGH.
HA HA HA HA!
- WAIT. HIS OWN WIVES
AND DAUGHTERS?
- WHY NOT?
GOT PLENTY LEFT.
- AND HE BROUGHT YOU
HERE TO DIE?
- YES. KABUNA GET ME.
KILL, KILL. MASH, MASH.
I DIE OR FINISH UP.
- OH, FOR...
JUST BECAUSE YOU WON'T MARRY
SOME DUMB CLUCK!
A WOMAN SHOULD HAVE THE RIGHT
TO MARRY WHOM SHE WANTS.
- WOMAN GOT WHAT?
- RIGHTS.
- WHAT'S A MATTER WORD,
"RIGHTS"?
- WELL, IT'S SOMETHING
WOMEN HAVE WHERE I COME FROM.
THEY, UH...
THEY DO WHAT THEY WANT.
- [chuckles]
FATHER BELONG ME
BE CROSSIN' COCONUT,
HE HEAR YOU SING OUT
THIS "RIGHTS."
- WELL...[chuckles]
I'M NOT LOOKING FORWARD
TO MEETING YOUR FATHER.
HE NOT COME ALONG
THIS SIDE BY AND BY, HUH?
- NO.
- OH, GOOD.
HEART BELONG ME
TICK-TOCK MUCH BETTER.
LOOK, I DON'T LIKE TO KNOCK
SOMEBODY ELSE'S FAMILY,
BUT THIS FATHER OF YOURS
SOUNDS LIKE A...
- HE NOT FRIGHT ME.
- WELL, I'LL TELL
YOU SOMETHING.
HE FRIGHT ME.
MM-HMM.
BOY, WHAT AM I
GONNA DO WITH YOU?
- NOTHING CAN DO.
FATHER AND KABUNA
WORK TOGETHER.
PLENTY SMART.
- ANYWAY,
YOU STAY HERE TONIGHT.
OH, EVERYTHING'S OKAY.
I'LL SLEEP OUTSIDE.
YOU SEE,
EVERYTHING'S OKAY.
I'M PRACTICALLY MARRIED
ANYWAY.
WAIT A MINUTE.
HERE, I'LL SHOW YOU
A PICTURE OF, UH, MY GIRL.
[laughs]
THERE. LOOK AT THAT.
BEAUTIFUL, ISN'T SHE?
- EWW. LOOKS SICK.
WHERE GIRL COLOR GO?
- OH, WELL, SHE'S
WHAT WE CALL A BLOND.
THEY HAVE MORE FUN,
YOU KNOW. [laughs]
FLOYD.
NOW, DON'T WORRY.
I'LL LEAVE FLOYD HERE
TO GUARD YOU.
YOU GOT THE PICTURE,
FLOYD?
I AM APPOINTING YOU
OFFICIAL PROTECTOR.
NOBODY,
AND I REPEAT, NOBODY
GETS IN HERE TO BOTHER
THAT YOUNG LADY TONIGHT...
AND THAT INCLUDES ME.
NIGHT.
JANE WOULD
BE PROUD OF ME.
TAKES A LOT OF CHARACTER
TO WALK AWAY
FROM A BEAUTIFUL NATIVE GIRL
LIKE THAT.
I GUESS AT HEART,
I'M JUST A GOOD, WHOLESOME KID.
GOOD, WHOLESOME,
STUPID KID.
[wind whistling]
HAMMOCK DOESN'T LOOK
TOO BIG TO ME.
[thunder rumbling]
[thunder booming]
[rain falling]
AW, DON'T TELL ME
IT'S GONNA...
AW!
[wind howling]
AW, NUTS! AW!
[thunder booming]
OH, HI, BOY.
THAT-A-BOY. THAT'S
THE WAY TO STAND A WATCH.
WHAT...
CUT THE CLOWNING, FLOYD!
IT'S JUST ME! COME...
LOOK, STUPID,
I JUST WANNA
GET A BLANKET OR SOMETHING
'CAUSE IT'S RAINING!
I'M NOT GOING IN THERE
TO STAY. NOW, COME ON!
FLOYD, HAVE A HEART.
I'M FREEZIN OUT HERE.
ALL I WANNA DO IS GET
THAT BLANKET THERE.
GO ON, FLOYD! PLEASE!
BOY, IF THAT
ISN'T TYPICAL.
YOU GIVE A CHIMP
A LITTLE AUTHORITY,
AND THEY WANT TO
TAKE OVER.
THANKS A LOT!
I'D LIKE TO PUT YOU
BACK IN ORBIT.
DUMB MONKEY.
[fabric tearing]
"BUT, UH,
AFTER THE FIGHT WAS OVER,
"WE CAME TO TERMS.
"AND SO, MY DEAR,
"THAT'S HOW
YOUR VERY OWN
"LIEUTENANT ROBIN CRUSOE MET
HIS MAN FRIDAY,
"EXCEPT SHE WAS A GIRL.
"I NAMED HER
'WEDNESDAY.'"
- WEDNESDAY. AWK!
- "DON'T GET THE IDEA
"SHE'S ONE OF THOSE...
GORGEOUS ISLAND GIRLS."
- ISLAND.
- "SHE'S JUST A PLAIN
LITTLE THING, ACTUALLY."
- YOU WRITE SCRITCH-SCRATCH
ALONG HER?
- OH, YES, UH, TWICE A DAY.
- WHAT HER NAME?
- WHO?
- REMEMBER? JANE.
- UH, REMEMBER JANE.
JANE!
THAT'S HER NAME. JANE.
SHE'S A REAL
LOVELY LITTLE LADY.
- HMM!
[bird cackles]
DEAREST JANE.
DEAREST JANE. AWK.
- "ANYWAY, THE REAL PROBLEM
ISN'T WEDNESDAY.
"IT'S TANAMASHU,
"THAT OLD
HEADHUNTER FATHER OF HERS.
"MEANTIME, ALL MY LOVE.
HURRIEDLY, ROB."
- DEAR JANE.
REMEMBER JANE. AWK.
- ♪ GO TELL AUNT RHODY ♪
♪ GO TELL AUNT RHODY ♪
♪ SHE'S REALLY UNCLE FRED ♪ ♪
[tank flushes]
IT'S HIM! TANAMASHU!
WEDNESDAY!
TANAMASHU'S COMING!
THAT NUTTY FATHER OF YOURS,
HE'S COME!
WE'VE GOTTA BLOW
OUT OF HERE!
FLOYD, WILL YOU PUT DOWN
THAT SILLY COMIC BOOK?
WE'LL HIDE IN THE JUNGLE!
WEDNESDAY,
WHERE YOU GOIN'?
GIVE ME YOUR HAND.
- [chattering]
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE!
- FLOYD, COME ON!
- [chattering]
[women conversing
indistinctly]
- I DON'T
LIKE THE LOOKS OF THIS.
- [hooting]
- WELL, I MEAN,
I LIKE THE LOOKS OF IT,
BUT I DON'T
LIKE THE LOOKS OF IT.
[women conversing
excitedly]
- SO?
SO LET'S GET OUTTA HERE!
[lighthearted
orchestral music]
COME ON, FLOYD!
♪ ♪
HEE-YA!
- [laughing]
[lighthearted
orchestral music]
♪ ♪
[giggling]
- OH, BOY.
[deep breath]
- [laughing]
- [coughing]
[Rob gasps]
WHO ARE YOU?
- SORRY.
THESE ALL SISTERS-COUSINS
BELONG ME.
- OKAY,
YOU CAN TELL FUN TIME
SISTERS AND COUSINS
TO GET OUT OF THE WAY
IF THEY DON'T WANT TO SEE
AN INNOCENT MAN DROWN.
- ONE MOMENT.
SISTERS-COUSINS
ALL MUST RUN FOR LIVES!
WAS ALL MY FAULT.
I NOT GO MARRIAGE
WITH UGLY,
BAD SNAKE ISLAND CHIEF.
FATHER BELONG ME
CATCH CRAZY!
FATHER PLENTY CROSS.
KILL, KILL!
BIG HOO!
BEGIN TO THROW
ALL DAUGHTERS-COUSINS
KAU KAU TO SHARK.
- I'M DROWNING!
YOU GOTTA BELIEVE ME.
I'M VE--VERY SINCERE.
- ONE MOMENT!
I TELL SISTERS-COUSINS,
WOMAN GOT RIGHTS!
- GAH! MY WHOLE--
MY WHOLE LIFE PASSING
IN FRONT OF MY EYES!
[gasps]
- WOMAN GOT RIGHTS,
YOU SAY!
- OKAY, OKAY,
WOMEN GOT--.
WOMEN GOT RIGHTS.
[gasps]
- SO WE NOT GO NOW.
- YOU JUST
SAID YOUR FATHER'S GONNA
KAU KAU EVERYBODY
TO THE SHARKS.
- BUT FATHER
GOT TO CATCH FIRST.
FIRST WE FIGHT!
- [gasps]
FIGHT? FIGHT?
WEDNESDAY, YOU'RE OUT
OF YOUR MELANESIAN MIND!
YOU CAN'T FIGHT!
- WE TRY.
SISTERS-COUSINS
FIGHT GOOD, PROBABLY.
- [gasps and coughs]
- YOU BE OUR CHIEF.
- ME?
- WELL, CHIEF, ADMIRAL, GENERAL.
WHAT IS WORD?
- THE WORD'S--[blows]
THE WORD'S NO!
- [gurgling and spitting]
- [hooting]
[women singiAnchors Aweigh]
- "FOLLOWING A BRIEF PERIOD
"OF BRAINWASHING,
"I DECIDED TO ACCEPT
THEIR OFFER
AND MAKE THE BEST OF IT."
all: ♪ UNTIL
WE MEET ONCE MORE ♪
♪ WE WISHING YOU A HAPPY ♪
♪ VOYAGE HOME ♪
[whistle blows]
- COMPANY, HALT!
NOW HEAR THIS!
IN MY BOOK, LADIES,
THERE'S JUST ONE WAY
TO DO THINGS,
AND THAT IS
THE NAVY WAY.
all: [giggling]
- THE ENTIRE EFFICIENCY
OF A FIGHTING MACHINE
IS BASED
ON JUST ONE THING.
DISCIPLINE.
- [giggling]
- DISCIPLINE, DISCIPLINE,
[stick snaps]
DISCIPLINE!
all: [giggling]
- WE SHAPE UP
OR SHIP OUT!
ALL RIGHT, LET'S SEE IF WE CAN
FORM A LINE ALONG HERE.
ON THE DOUBLE!
ALL RIGHT, LADIES.
SHAPE UP!
OH, THAT'S
ENOUGH SHAPING UP.
I SAID, THAT'S--
AT EASE!
ADMIRAL HONEY,
THEY ALREADY AT EASE,
THANK YOU.
FEEL FINE.
LIKE YOU PLENTY.
- THAT'S NOT WHAT I MEANT.
NEVER MIND.
- [giggling]
- ALL RIGHT, SAILOR,
WIPE THAT SMILE OFF YOUR FACE.
I SAID WIPE IT OFF!
- OKAY, HONEY.
[laughing]
- YOU MEAN "SIR."
- OKAY, HONEY, SIR.
[women giggling]
SMARTEN UP, SAILOR.
SMARTEN UP.
all: [giggling]
- ALL RIGHT,
BELAY THAT GIGGLING!
SAILORS DO NOT GIGGLE!
WHAT--
WELL, THANK YOU.
WAIT A MINUTE. NO.
WAIT A MINUTE. LET'S
NOT CONFUSE THE RELATIONSHIP
BETWEEN AN OFFICER
AND ENLISTED PERSONNEL.
LADIES, DISCIPLINE
IS VERY IMPORTANT HERE!
COME ON!
WILL YOU KNOCK IT OFF?
KNOCK IT...
COMPANY, DISMISSED!
- [laughing]
- IT'S GONNA BE
A VERY TOUGH WAR.
- HMM, NOT MUCH
GOOD-LOOKING HOUSE.
- THAT DOESN'T MATTER.
WHAT'S REALLY IMPORTANT IS THAT
WE GET OUR BATTLE STRATEGY
VERY CLEARLY
IN OUR MINDS.
- OKAY, ADMIRAL HONEY.
YOU BOSS.
- YEAH. ALL RIGHT.
WHERE DOES FATHER
USUALLY LAND HIS CANOES?
- ALWAYS HERE.
ALWAYS TAKE THIS PATH
TO KABUNA HERE.
- WHAT DOES FATHER DO
AT KABUNA?
- THEY DO GOOD BUSINESS.
FATHER STAND TO KABUNA.
FATHER SAY...
[deep voice]
"I, TANAMASHU, HERE.
WHAT GREAT GOD KABUNA
GOT TO SAY?"
AND KABUNA SAY,
"YOU GOOD CHIEF,
TANAMASHU.
"KABUNA LIKE YOU PLENTY.
"TELL PEOPLE
TO BRING YOU BEST FISH,
"BRING YOU PRETTY NEW GIRLS,
"THROW OLD WIVES
KAU KAU TO SHARK.
THIS MAKE KABUNA
PLENTY HAPPY."
- SOUNDS A LITTLE FISHY
TO ME.
YOU MEAN,
PEOPLE HEAR KABUNA SAY THIS?
- OH, NOT PEOPLE.
PEOPLE NOT HEAR.
KABUNA SPEAK ONLY TO FATHER.
ONLY FATHER HEAR.
- OH!
ONLY FATHER HEAR, HUH?
[chuckling]
I THINK I KNOW THAT BIT.
- WHAT'S
THE MATTER, "BIT"?
- I MAY JUST VISIT KABUNA
MYSELF.
I MAY OUTSMART FATHER.
- [laughs]
YOU OUTSMART FATHER?
- WEDNESDAY, ALL DUE RESPECT
TO YOUR FATHER,
BUT HE IS, AFTER ALL,
JUST A SAVAGE.
ON THE OTHER HAND,
I AM GRADUATED WITH HONORS
FROM ONE OF
THE FINEST TECHNICAL SCHOOLS
IN THE UNITED STATES.
NOW, IN ALL HONESTY,
WHO DO YOU THINK
IS GOING TO OUTSMART WHO? WHOM?
- FATHER.
YOU GOT SOME OTHER PLAN,
ADMIRAL HONEY?
- [sighs]
WELL, AS A LAST RESORT,
I MEAN ONLY
AS A LAST RESORT,
WE MAY HAVE TO FIGHT,
MAKE A BIG HOO-HOO.
- THIS GOOD TYPE PLAN.
ALL SISTERS-COUSIN
LIKE TO MAKE BIG HOO-HOO!
- OKAY, BUT, REMEMBER,
WE HOO-HOO
ONLY IN THE CASE
OF EMERGENCY.
SOMEONE MAY GET HURT
IF WE HOO-HOO,
AND I'M AFRAID
I KNOW WHO.
AHEM.
ALL RIGHT, YOU YOUNG PEOPLE,
LET'S GET TO WORK.
SNAP IT UP!
[snap]
MM-HMM.
- COUSIN, TAKE TOPSIDE.
PLENTY HURRY.
- WHAT'S THE MATTER
THIS THING?
- DON'T KNOW.
ADMIRAL HONEY SAY MOVE IT,
WE MOVE.
NOW COME ALONG,
SISTERS-COUSINS,
ON YOUR TOES!
GUNG-HO!
NOW, MOVE OUT, MOVE OUT.
COME ON.
- WHAT'S THE MATTER THIS?
MAYBE CANDY STICK.
YOU THINK?
- MAYBE CANDY,
MAYBE NOT.
- HEY, WATCH IT!
HEY, THOSE ARE FLARES!
EXPLOSIVE.
[whistles,
imitates explosion]
THEY'RE--
JUST TAKE THEM UP TOPSIDE.
DON'T FOOL AROUND.
- COME ALONG, SISTERS-COUSINS,
NOW ON YOUR TOES!
GUNG-HO!
NOW, MOVE OUT!
COME ON, MOVE OUT.
[equipment humming]
- WELL, HERE GOES.
[generator rumbling]
HEY!
HEY, I DID IT!
I GOT THE GENERATOR WORK--
[thud]
OW! OH, BOY.
[women giggling]
- STOP HORSIN' AROUND!
THIS THING IS DANGEROUS!
STOP IT!
AH!
HEY, AWAY FROM THE WATER!
THAT WIRE'S HOT!
SWEETIE, THAT LINE RUNS
BACK TO THE GENERATOR.
YOU STEP IN THE WATER
WITH THE JUICE TURNED ON,
[laughs] YOU'LL LIGHT
UP LIKE A ROMAN CANDLE.
I MEAN,
YOU SHOOT OFF, UH, SPARKS.
YOU KNOW,
I MEAN, BIG SMOKE.
- THANK YOU.
YOU ARE
PRETTY NICE YOURSELF.
- YEAH.
[pump humming]
HEY!
- [laughs]
- SO FAR, SO GOOD.
- LIKE YOU SAY,
SO FAR, SO GOOD.
- YEAH...
YEAH.
WEDNESDAY,
I DO NOT LIKE THIS.
- SISTERS-COUSINS TAKE GOOD CARE
OF ADMIRAL HONEY.
- FOR YOUR INFORMATION,
ADMIRALS DON'T GET CARRIED
AROUND ON LITTERS
BY GIRLS,
AT LEAST NOT IN WARTIME.
- WELL,
LADIES GOT TO RESPECT,
GOT TO LOOK UP
TO ADMIRAL HONEY.
RIDE IN LITTER,
SAVE FACE,
ALSO FEET.
- IT'S NOT MY FACE
I'M WORRIED ABOUT.
- [chattering]
- FLOYD, NO, NO.
GET DOWN FROM THERE.
YOU DO IT LIKE THIS.
I ALWAYS THOUGHT
YOU WERE THE BIG BRAIN.
NO, YOU IDIOT!
STAY BACK!
- [shrieking]
- [laughing]
DON'T GET SORE AT ME.
WHY DIDN'T YOU WATCH
WHAT YOU WERE DOIN'?
WELL, MAYBE WE'VE LEARNED
A LITTLE LESSON NOW.
YO-OH!
MOVE IT OUT.
PERISCOPE SECURE
AND WORKIN'.
NOW, LET'S SEE--
FLARES.
TWELVE CASES.
SMOKE BOMBS, SIX.
OXYGEN TANK, ONE.
SMOKE MASKS.
TWO.
FIRST-AID KIT.
FIRST-AID KIT, ONE.
FLAMETHROWER, ONE.
O-KAY.
- [chatters]
- AND...
FIRE EXTINGUISHER,
CARBON-DIOXIDE SPRAY TYPE.
NICE EFFECT.
OKAY, BATTERY PACKS,
SIX.
EXTRA SPOOL OF WIRE,
DOUBLE 14-GAUGE, TWO.
WATER VALVE INSTALLED
AND WORKIN'.
AND THAT'S ABOUT IT.
MM-MM.
[amplifier humming]
[blows]
HELLO, HELLO.
TESTING, ONE, TWO, THREE.
TESTING.
[blows]
HELLO.
HOW NOW BROWN COW.
[humming louder]
HELLO, BROWN COW.
ONE, TWO, THREE. TESTING.
[over loudspeaker]
TESTING.
WOOF-WOOF.
HELLO, MAX.
HELLO. HELLO.
HELLO. HMM!
HELLO!
HOW NOW BROWN COW.
'ROUND THE RUGGED ROCK
THE RAGGED RASCAL RAN.
SISTER SUSIE SELLS SEASHELLS
BY THE SEASHORE.
[whispering]
SOFT.
WHAT LIGHT
IN YON' WINDOW BREAKS?
[over loudspeaker]
IT IS THE EAST,
AND JULIET IS THE SUN.
SEE HOW SHE LEANS
HER CHEEK UPON HER HAND.
WOULD THAT I WERE A GLOVE.
YOU READ...
[chuckles]
SORRY, FOLKS.
KABUNA
A LITTLE HAMMY THERE.
[laughs]
OKAY.
KABUNA SAY DAUGHTER
OF TANAMASHU SPEAK!
GO AHEAD, WEDNESDAY.
THAT'S YOUR CUE. SPEAK.
- OKAY.
I, DAUGHTER
OF TANAMASHU, SPEAK.
- PROCEED!
KABUNA LISTEN!
- I SAY WOMAN GOT RIGHTS.
- OKAY!
- I SAY WOMAN
GOT RIGHT TO TALK.
- THAT'S RIGHT!
- I SAY WOMAN GOT RIGHT
TO CHOOSE FIRST-CHOP FELLA!
[cheering]
I SAY TANAMASHU NO GOOD.
I LOVE TANAMASHU.
HE MY FATHER,
BUT HE NO GOOD.
WE GIVE HIM BIG SQUEEZE!
[cheering]
- KABUNA GOT TO GO ALONG
WITH DAUGHTER OF TANAMASHU.
DAUGHTER PLENTY OKAY.
KABUNA SAY
WOMAN GOT RIGHTS.
- HEY!
- WOMAN GOT
RIGHTS TO TALK.
- HEY!
- GOT RIGHTS TO CHOOSE
FIRST-CHOP FELLA.
- HEY!
- TANAMASHU PLENTY TOUGH?
OKAY.
THE BIGGER THEY ARE,
THE HARDER THEY FALL.
AND THE TEAM
THAT WON'T BE BEATEN,
CAN'T BE BEATEN.
[cheering]
ALL RIGHT,
NOW GO OUT THERE
AND WIN ONE
FOR OLD KABUNA!
[cheering]
all:
♪ ANCHOR AWEIGH, ME BOY ♪
♪ ANCHOR AWEIGH... ♪ ♪
[women giggling]
[giggling]
- ALL RIGHT.
WHAT'S GOING ON IN HERE?
THERE'S NOBODY IN THOSE
LOOKOUT STATIONS OUT THERE!
THERE'S A WAR
GOING ON, YOU KNOW?
COME ON! EVERYBODY
MOVE IT BACK TO THEIR WORK!
ON THE DOUBLE!
- SORRY. MY FAULT.
- WELL, A FINE COMBAT FORCE
THIS IS.
THERE'S NOBODY
ON THOSE LOOKOUT POSTS.
EVERYBODY'S IN THERE
PLAYING LAUGH AND GIGGLE
WHILE TANAMASHU
QUIETLY SNEAKS IN HERE
AND CUTS OUR THROATS.
- WEDNESDAY SORRY.
- WELL, WE GOTTA RUN
A TIGHT SHIP AROUND HERE.
LOOK, I AM TRYING
AWFULLY HARD
TO KEEP A GRASP ON THE...
REALITIES.
HOW ABOUT WEDNESDAY FIX YOU
BREAKFAST, ADMIRAL HONEY?
- WELL, OKAY.
I'LL WRITE MY LETTER.
- OKAY.
YOU WRITE, I FIX.
"DEAR..."
UH...
"DEAR...
DEAR..."
"MY UNDYING LOVE,
YOUR JANE."
JANE, JANE.
THAT'S IT.
JANE.
WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH ME?
OH, HONEY,
I DON'T KNOW WHAT'S COME...
OOH.
JANE?
I GOTTA GET OFF THIS ISLAND
PRETTY SOON.
[groans]
"DEAR OLD JANE."
UH, "DEAREST JANE..."
- TANAMASHU.
TANAMASHU COME!
TANAMASHU!
[straining to blow shell]
- "AS THE DAYS WEAR ON,
I CAN'T HELP FEELING
MORE AND MORE..."
- TANAMASHU!
TANAMASHU COME!
TANAMASHU!
[screaming]
- TANAMASHU COME!
SOUND THE ALARM!
- SOUND THE ALARM!
[sheet metal clanging]
- "THIS IS IT.
"9:22 A.M.
"TANAMASHU SIGHTED.
"IF YOU DON'T HEAR
FROM ME AGAIN,
"YOU'LL KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
LOVE, ROB."
TANAMASHU COME!
SOUND THE ALARM!
- TANAMASHU COME!
[tray crashes]
WHOOP WHOOP WHOOP WHOOP!
[bird whistling
and whooping]
[Floyd hooting]
BAD ENOUGH
I GOTTA BE STRANDED
IN THE MIDDLE
OF THE SOUTH PACIFIC
WITHOUT A BUNCH
OF HYSTERICAL WOMEN.
ADMIRAL I HAD TO BE
WITH MY BIG MOUTH.
CAN'T WAIT FOR THE NAVY
TO COME AND GET ME.
[banging, screaming]
- TANAMASHU COME!
[bird whistling]
- [blows]
[whistle blows]
ALL RIGHT, EVERYBODY!!
EVERYBODY REMEMBER
YOUR BATTLE TRAINING NOW!
REMEMBER YOUR TRAINING!
LET'S NOT LOSE OUR HEADS!
HEY, UH,
ADMIRAL HONEY'S
NOT GONNA LET ANYTHING
HAPPEN TO ANYBODY!
I GOTTA GET
A HOLD OF MYSELF.
ALL RIGHT, NOW!
BATTLE ALERT!
BATTLE PLAN "A."
[stammers]
[whistle blows]
ALL RIGHT, NOW,
PLAN "A" FOR ABLE
IS UNDER OPERATION
RIGHT NOW.
UNIT COMMANDERS, YOU GET
YOUR MEN IN THEIR POSITIONS.
YOUR WOMEN!
UH, WEDNESDAY,
GET MY--MY BINOCULARS.
OKAY? NOW GET YOUR WEAPONS,
EVERYBODY.
[groans]
I WANNA WISH EVERYBODY
A LOT OF GOOD LUCK,
AND KEEP YOUR SPIRITS UP.
KEEP YOUR
COMMUNICATIONS OPEN.
ALL RIGHT.
UH, MOVE OUT!
MOVE OUT!
[women shouting]
UH, WEDNESDAY!
WEDNESDAY, YOU GO--
YOU, UH--
YOU GO WITH ME.
NOW, REMEMBER,
WE HOLD TO PLAN "A,"
UNLESS I SIGNAL.
NO VIOLENCE.
WE'RE GONNA NEGOTIATE.
UH, TALK-TALK.
- OKAY, OKAY,
BUT TALK-TALK
STILL LOUSY IDEA.
YOU DON'T KNOW FATHER.
- WHICH ONE    IS DAD?
YOU KNOW,
I CAN'T HELP WONDERING
IF YOU'RE BEING FAIR
TO YOUR FATHER.
- FATHER UNDER UMBRELLA.
- HE CAN'T BE AS BAD
AS YOU'RE PAINTING HIM.
[thud]
- WHAT FATHER DOING NOW?
- [speaking
native language]
- CHANGING A TIRE.
ALL RIGHT, GET READY.
GO ON.
- [speaks native language]
women:
♪ ANCHOR AWEIGH, ME BOY ♪
♪ ANCHOR AWEIGH ♪
- [speaking native language]
all: ♪ FAREWELL
TO COLLEGE, BOY ♪
♪ WE SAIL ON BREAK OF DAY,
DAY, DAY, DAY ♪
♪ THROUGH OUR LAST NIGHT ♪
- HUH?
♪ ASHORE ♪
♪ DRINK TO THE FOAM ♪
♪ UNTIL
WE MEET ONCE MORE ♪
♪ WE WISHING YOU
A HAPPY VOYAGE HOME ♪ ♪
- [speaking
native language]
[speaking
[speaking native
language]
BAD DAUGHTER!
YOU!
[speaks native language]
both:
[speaking native language]
- GRAB BAD DAUGHTER!
- ONE MOMENT, PLEASE.
BAD DAUGHTER
GOT RIGHT TO TALK.
ALL WOMEN GOT RIGHTS.
- WHY?
WHY BAD DAUGHTER
WANT RIGHT TO TALK?
WHAT'S THE MATTER, HUH?
GET EVERYONE MIX UP!
[laughs]
WELL, EVERYTHING
IS OKAY.
NO, WOMAN DON'T GOT TO NEED
RIGHT TO TALK.
GREAT KABUNA SAY THIS.
- GREAT KABUNA
NOT SAY THIS.
GREAT KABUNA SAY, "NO, NO, NO!
WOMAN GOT RIGHTS!"
- KABUNA SAY,
"NO, NO, NO, NO"?
HOW YOU KNOW?
- KABUNA TELL ME THIS.
- [laughing]
GREAT KABUNA
TELL HER THIS!
EVERYONE KNOW KABUNA SPEAK
ONLY TO TANAMASHU!
- KABUNA SPEAK TO ME.
- MAYBE. [chuckling]
MAYBE SO.
HOW ABOUT
WE ALL GO KABUNA, HMM?
EVERYONE SEE KABUNA
SPEAK ONLY TANAMASHU!
MAYBE GREAT KABUNA
SPEAK BAD DAUGHTER, TOO.
OKAY, WE GO?
- OKAY.
- OKAY, WE GO.
WE HAVE FEAST, GOOD TIME,
DANCING!
TALK ABOUT WOMAN RIGHTS
TO GREAT KABUNA.
MAYBE THROW BAD DAUGHTER
KAU KAU TO SHARK.
SHARKS GOT RIGHTS,
TOO, EH?
[laughing]
[speaking
native language]
- BOY, HE'S WALKIN'
RIGHT INTO IT.
[Tanamashu
speaking native language]
- COME ON, FLOYD!
WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH YOU?
WILL YOU LET GO?
I CAN TALK TO YOU LATER.
COME ON, FLOYD.
GOTTA GO.
IT'S VERY IMPORTANT, FLOYD!
I GOTTA GET
OVER TO KABUNA-AAH!
FLOYD, GET ME DOWN FROM HERE!
- [laughing]
- [speaking native
language]
- KABUNA SPEAK TANAMASHU,
THEN WE DIE,
ALL FINISHED UP.
- EVERYTHING OKAY.
KABUNA OKAY.
HE WITH US, REMEMBER?
- FLOYD!
THIS IS NO TIME FOR GAMES!
LET GO!
AW, COME ON, FLOYD!
- [chattering]
- O MIGHTY KABUNA,
TANAMASHU GIVE YOU GREETINGS.
GREETINGS...
KABUNA.
HUH?
MIGHTY KABUNA,
BAD DAUGHTER WISH
YOU SPEAK.
YOU LIKE THIS?
UH-HUH.
BAD DAUGHTER,
GREAT KABUNA
SAY SPEAK OKAY.
- GREAT KABUNA,
SPEAK TO ME.
SPEAK
SO NOT ONLY I HEAR,
NOT
ONLY FATHER HEAR,
BUT EVERYONE HEAR.
- OKAY, FLOYD, I'M LOOSE.
YOU CAN LET GO NOW.
OHH!
- [hooting]
- SPEAK OF TANAMASHU.
SPEAK OF WOMAN
GOT RIGHTS.
SPEAK OF ALL THINGS.
WE WAIT PATIENTLY,
GREAT KABUNA.
THIS IS WHAT ROB HONEY
CALL "CUE."
WOOF-WOOF.
- WOOF-WOOF?
- GREAT KABUNA,
MAYBE ONE WORD?
MAYBE SMALL WHISPER?
- AH!
KABUNA PRETTY SMART, EH?
both: [laughing]
- GRAB WOMAN!
[screaming]
- [laughing]
- [over loudspeaker]
JUST A MINUTE, CHARLIE!
HOLD IT!
- HUH?
- DROP THOSE GIRLS!
TANAMASHU, LISTEN!
KABUNA NOW SPEAK
TO ALL PEOPLE.
[whispering]
KEEP IT UP, FLOYD.
KABUNA SAY
WOMAN GOT RIGHTS!
- WHAT'S THE MATTER HERE?
THIS NOT KABUNA VOICE!
NO!
ONLY TANAMASHU
CAN HEAR KABUNA VOICE!
- NOT TRUE!
KABUNA PLENTY TIRED
TANAMASHU PUT WORDS IN MOUTH.
- TANAMASHU THINK MAYBE
THIS SOME KIND OF TRICK.
WHY GREAT KABUNA SPEAK
WHITE MEN FASHION, EH?
- KABUNA
SPEAK MANY TONGUES.
SPEAK WITH
FLAMING TONGUE OF ANGER!
- [gasps]
[shouting
in native language]
[overlapping shouts]
- KABUNA SPEAK WITH
ICY BREATH OF CONTEMPT!
- [grunting]
[women giggling,
Tanamashu shivering]
- WHAT YOU SAY NOW,
BAD CHIEF TANAMASHU?
- I SAY YOU FAKE!
- WHAT YOU CALL KABUNA,
KABUNA CALL YOU DOUBLE!
- I SAY YOU
ONE BIG FINISH-UP LIAR!
- GET
ON THE WATER, FLOYD.
NOW YOU MAKE KABUNA
PLENTY MAD.
GET THE WATER.
COME ON, FLOYD.
TURN IT ON!
[water whooshing]
[Tanamashu groans]
[shouting
in native language]
- [laughing]
RIGHT ON TARGET!
POUR IT ON!
KEEP IT COMIN'!
MORE PRESSURE, FLOYD!
DON'T BE AFRAID OF IT!
[hose creaking]
- OOH!
[creaking]
- HEY! NO! WHOA!
AAH AAH AAH!
- AHH!
- OH, ROB!
- FLOYD!
FLOYD!
- AH-HA-AHH!
- FLOYD, TURN IT DOWN!
- [shouting indistinctly]
- FLOYD!
HEY, FLOYD!
TURN IT DOWN!
- [screams]
- AAH! AAH!
- [groans]
OOH!
- HEY!
NO!
AAH!
DOWN, YOU IDIOT!
DOWN!
- [screeching]
- WHOA!
TURN IT DOWN!
[whistle blows]
GO ON!
GET OUT OF HERE!
PLAN "B"!
ALL RIGHT, YOU GUYS.
YOU WANT
KABUNA GET TOUGH? HUH?
BACK!
[laughs]
- [growling]
- HOLD IT! HOLD IT.
KABUNA WATCH EVERY MOVE.
- GRAB HIM! GET HIM!
- FLOYD.
FLOYD, TURN ON THE WATER.
- [muttering native language]
- [laughing]
- HOLD IT! HOLD IT.
FLOYD! TELL KABUNA
HIT THE WATER!
- [hooting]
[hoots]
[hooting]
[chattering]
- [mutters]
- YOU DARE DEFY
GREAT GOD KABUNA?
[grunts] BACK!
GREAT KABUNA,
TURN ON THE WATER!
ANYBODY, HIT THE WATER!
DON'T BOTHER ME, FLOYD.
I'M BUSY.
[coughs]
- [growls]
[warriors muttering]
- [muttering]
- [explosions]
- [screeching]
[flares whistling]
- HEY!
LOOK OUT! BACK!
[ricochets and explosions]
OW!
CUT IT OUT, WILL YA?
KABUNA SAY
HE READY TO BLOW!
- [grunting]
- AAH!
- [screaming]
RUN! GO!
- I TOUGH CHIEF TANAMASHU!
TANAMASHU NEVER RUN!
[ricochets]
- [groans]
- [straining]
LET GO!
- [speaking
native language]
- AAH!
[whistling and explosions]
- AAH! WAIT!
WAIT FOR ME!
TANAMASHU...ALWAYS RUNS!
WAIT! WAIT!
[traps springing]
WHERE?
WHERE EVERYBODY GO?
WHAT'S THE MAT--
[gasps]
- [laughing]
- [shouting
in native language]
[shouting
HUH?
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
[shouting
in native language]
[water gurgling]
[shouting
in native language]
- HE MY FATHER.
I PULL.
- OKAY.
- [screaming and muttering
in native language]
[shouting
[groans]
in native language]
[muttering
- OOH!
- [sighs]
[speaking
native language]
HEY!
[shouting
in native language]
[screaming]
[shouting
in native language]
[gasps]
[whistle blows]
[Tanamashu crying]
- YOU, UH, HAVE ENOUGH?
YOU SAY UNCLE?
- [crying, speaking
native language]
- FATHER SAY UNCLE.
[rumbling]
[explosion]
LOOK!
KABUNA SMILE!
[native drums playing,
women shouting]
♪ ♪
- HEY.
VERY GOOD, OKAY.
- OH, THANK YOU.
SAY, UH, TANAMASHU, UH,
I'M SORRY
ABOUT THOSE BOATS.
- OH.
- WELL, IT
MUST TAKE A LONG TIME
TO HOLLOW OUT
ONE OF THOSE THINGS.
- [speaking
native language]
- YEAH.
- KUAGA,
-    KA-WA-WA?
-    KWAGIKA.
- OH, KWALIGI.
[laughing]
[women shouting]
- YOU KNOW,
SHE IS A WONDERFUL GIRL.
- [grunts]
- SHE'S GONNA MAKE
SOME HEADHUNTER
A GREAT
LITTLE WIFE SOMEDAY.
- [laughs]
SURE! SURE, GO!
GO DANCE
WITH BAD DAUGHTER!
GO! [laughs]
- [laughs] HEY!
[Tanamashu laughing]
HEY!
WISE GUY DANCE OKAY!
[laughing]
WISE GUY DANCE
PRETTY GOOD MARRIAGE DANCE!
[laughing]
- MARRIAGE DANCE?
UH, NO, NO.
WAIT A MINUTE.
PLEASE, PLEASE.
- TANAMASHU
DON'T LOSE DAUGHTER, NO!
TANAMASHU
GOT WISE-GUY SON!
[laughing]
- AAH!
[Tanamashu laughing,
drums stop]
- OH, I'M--
I'M TERRIBLY SORRY.
I--I...
UM, LOOK,
I DIDN'T MEAN...
UM, WEDNESDAY,
I'M NOT GOOD ENOUGH FOR YOU.
I MEAN, SHE--
SHE'S A CHIEF'S DAUGHTER.
WELL, I MEAN,
YOU KNOW THAT.
♪ UM-DIDDLE-DIDDLE,
UM-DIDDLE-AY ♪
UM-DIDDLE-EE ♪ ♪
- IF YOU DAUGHTER TANAMASHU,
GO GET HIM!
[laughing]
- OKAY, I DO.
- [laughing]
- MMM!
[helicopter hovering]
CHOPPER!
HEY!
HELP! HELP!
HEY! HELP!
HELP! HEY!
HELP! COME ON!
YOU DUMB...COME ON!
CAN'T YOU READ?
AAH!
HELP! YA--
COME ON!
HEY!
COME ON! COME ON!
THE NATIVES ARE AFTER ME!
- HEY,
THERE'S A GUY DOWN THERE
PUTTING OUT
A DISTRESS SIGNAL.
- YEAH? WELL, TAKE IT EASY.
YOU KNOW THE RULES.
DON'T MEDDLE WITH THE AFFAIRS
OF THE NATIVES.
- I DON'T THINK
THIS GUY IS A NATIVE.
AND THOSE GIRLS LOOK LIKE
THEY'RE GONNA CREAM HIM!
- GIRLS?
- WHY DIDN'T YOU SAY SO?
- LET'S CHECK IT OUT.
- HEY! HEY!
AAH! THEY'RE COMING!
LOOK! LOOK!
THEY'RE GONNA KILL ME!
YOU GUYS, LOOK OVER THERE!
HELP! I'M NAVY!
LOOK, I'M NAVY!
OH, PLEASE HURRY!
THEY'RE COMIN'!
[makes slashing sounds]
HELP!
- OKAY, I'M HOOKED UP.
- HURRY! HURRY!
AAH! HURRY UP!
OHH!
HEY!
OOH!
- HAUL HIM UP!
- TAKE IT UP!
- WATCH IT!
- I DON'T KNOW WHO YOU ARE,
BUT I SURE DO
ADMIRE YOUR STYLE.
THOSE CHICKS WEREN'T ABOUT
TO LET YOU GO.
- HEY, DON'T I KNOW YOU?
CRUSOE. LIEUTENANT CRUSOE.
- YEAH.
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
THOSE GIRLS--
OH, WAIT!
WE GOTTA GO BACK.
BACK?
YOU'VE GOTTA BE
OUT OF YOUR SKULL.
THOSE PEOPLE ARE DANGEROUS.
- I'M SORRY. WE'VE GOT TO.
THERE'S ANOTHER GUY
BACK THERE
MORE IMPORTANT THAN I AM.
- LOWER AWAY!
- BE RIGHT BACK!
FLOYD!
FLOYD, WHERE ARE YA?
FLOYD?
GET OUT OF THERE,
YOU COWARD.
BOY, A BIG HERO
YOU TURNED OUT TO BE.
WE GOTTA MOVE.
THAT GIRLS' OLYMPIC TEAM
IS COMING--THEY GOT SPEARS!
COME ON. THEY WANNA KILL US,
BOY. MOVE!
YOU WANNA BE
AN APE-SKIN RUG?
- [hooting]
- COME ON! COME ON!
FLOYD, GET UP THERE!
GO ON! GET UP.
GET UP, FLOYD!
TAKE IT UP!
[helicopter straining]
WEDNESDAY,
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND!
TAKE IT UP!
WEDNESDAY!
WEDNESDAY,
I DON'T DESERVE YA!
GOOD-BYE, WEDNESDAY!
[spear whooshes]
GOOD-BYE, WEDNESDAY.
[whoosh]
"AND THAT'S JUST ABOUT
THE WAY IT WAS, DEAR."
"WE HAD A GREAT RECEPTION
ON THE CARRIER.
"OF COURSE,
IT WASN'T FOR ME.
"IT WAS ALL FOR FLOYD,
"OUR NATION'S FIRST HERO
OF OUTER SPACE.
THEY'D BEEN SEARCHING
FOR HIM FOR YEARS."
- WELCOME ABOARD,
LIEUTENANT.
WELL, FLOYD, I'M DELIGHTED
TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
YOU MUST HAVE
HAD SOME EXPERIENCE.
- SIR, I KNOW
YOU'RE VERY ANXIOUS
TO HEAR ABOUT
THE WHOLE STORY.
THE WHOLE THING STARTED--
- UH, LATER, LIEUTENANT,
IF YOU DON'T MIND.
EXCUSE ME.
FLOYD, I'VE GOT SOME PEOPLE
I WANT YOU TO MEET,
AND THEN WE'VE GOT
A LOT OF THINGS TO DO.
- THE PRESIDENT'S
ON THE PHONE, SIR.
HE WANTS TO TALK TO HIM.
- CAPTAIN? SIR?
I'D LIKE TO GIVE YOU
A FULL REPORT.
IT'S REALLY
AN INTERESTING STORY.
I WAS FLYING ABOUT 16--
- HEY, MISTER.
HEY, MISTER, THAT'S A PRETTY
GOOD OUTFIT YOU GOT ON THERE.
MIND IF I TAKE A PICTURE
TO SEND MY GIRL?
- NO, FINE. GO AHEAD.
- SAY, WHAT ARE YOU,
SOME KIND OF A HERMIT
OR SOMETHING?
- I'M GLAD
YOU ASKED THAT.
YOU KNOW, THIS WHOLE THING
STARTED
OH, SOME MONTHS AGO.
I WAS FLYING ALONG
ABOUT 16,000 FEET, I'D SAY.
- SAY, EXCUSE ME, WILL YA, MACK?
THEY'RE TAKING THE CHIMP AWAY,
AND I WANT TO GRAB
A PICTURE OF HIM.
OH, GO AHEAD.
[military march music]
♪ ♪
"ANYWAY, DEAR,
THAT'S JUST THE WAY IT HAPPENED.
"I'LL BE HOME SOON.
ALL MY LOVE, ROB."