While the city sleeps
Every night he creeps
Just surveyin' his domain
He roams around
like he owns the town
He's the king
He makes that plain
He knows every trick
Doesn't miss a lick
When it comes to keepin' fat
Some city slicker
No one is quicker
Than
That darn cat
Every nook and cranny
And garbage can he inspects
So thoroughly
When he's on his rounds
Nothin's out of bounds
To his curiosity
He can smile and purr
At a pretty her
Till she don't know
where she's at
Nose like a Geiger
Oh, what a tiger is
That darn cat
He's a sly old codger
An artful dodger
A scrounger unsurpassed
A ball of fire
A nine-live wire
Who just can't be outclassed
Yeah, this midnight rover
He lives in clover
It's an art he's got down pat
Never was a greater
Smooth operator than that
Darn
That darn cat
Hey, what do you say, fella?
Hey, you're taking my food, huh?
Iggy.
- What kept you?
- The lousy buses.
- Where'd you leave the car?
- Outside of Fresno, Route 99.
All right. Okay. They found it.
- The scan came in on the radio.
- What'd I tell you?
The fuzz'll fall for the whole deal,
hook, line and sinker.
Maybe. We've got
the federal fuzz on us this time.
So what? Who cares?
Wait till they pick up them hot 20s
I've been dropping off
all the way up the valley.
They're gonna lose their minds.
Look at us,
livin' in this solid pad,
a block and a half away
from where we pulled the job.
What about them headlines?
We're big news.
Front page,
every one of them...
- Shut up, will you?
- Shut up? Sure.
"Two bank robbers
stage daring, daylight holdup."
Hey, how about that, huh?
"Daring... daring."
"Two armed men
wearing Halloween masks
robbed the North Valley bank
early today...
- I gotta look.
...seizing a teller,
Miss Margaret Miller,
to shield their getaway."
Wow. Does this turn you on, huh?
Two hundred and fifty
thousand dollars.
- Iggy.
- Wow.
Iggy, we don't get 250,000
like the papers say.
We get 160 grand.
A hundred and six...
- Are you tryin' to snow me?
- Get your hands off me, meatball.
Get 'em off.
Don't you do that again.
A hundred and sixty.
How come the papers
don't say that?
- Do you believe the papers or me?
- What do I know?
I've been out risking my neck,
laying phony leads.
You've been in here,
sitting on the glue.
Well, why don't you ask
Miss America there?
She's the money lady.
Hey, it was a quarter million,
wasn't it?
Two hundred grand?
One lousy hundred sixty...
Don't do it, Iggy.
What I want to know is,
how come it don't bother you, huh?
Two of you wouldn't
have cooked this up?
Oh, come on, Iggy.
You're more of a drag than she is.
All right,
what are we gonna do about her?
To tell you the truth,
she's been a pretty good girl.
No hysteriaville, no gas.
No struggling.
She's got consideration
for other people.
I say we ought to
turn her off right now.
Is that another one
of your big ideas?
You see this?
Everyone in town is gonna be lookin'
at our girl's picture.
They dig her now,
all those helpful little citizens.
And that one little old man,
Eyewitness Charlie, with 20l20 vision.
Who always happens
to be looking out a window
when you're dragging out a body.
- What's the action then?
- We cool it, cool it, all of us.
- Cool it.
- Mother, I'm gonna take this gag off.
You got any ideas about noise?
All right. That's good...
...because I've got sensitive ears,
and when someone yells,
I do things.
Things like make me hate myself
in the morning.
Now, Mother, here's the picture.
We hole up here a few days.
We're stuck with you.
Now, we don't want you getting sick
or scared or finking out.
That's no good.
Not for us. Not for you.
What are you
gonna do with me?
Well, first you've got
to believe one thing.
One killing, more or less,
won't make any difference.
We've got nothin' to lose.
Anybody we knock off from here on in,
is just a little more gravy, see?
- I understand.
- That's solid, Moms.
Come on.
Let's make with the cookin'.
Iggy brought groceries. Come on.
We got steaks, we got salmon.
What's it gonna be?
Steak. I'll have mine rare.
Make mine well.
I can't stand the sight of blood.
Some desperate character
I got for a partner, huh?
All right, fleabag,
get out of here.
- Let him stay a while, Dan.
- What for?
- I like cats.
- You like cats?
Yeah. I ever tell you about
Acey-Deucy, my old cat?
- No, and you ain't going to.
- As long as he was alive, I was lucky.
- He was a real friend.
- You're breaking my heart.
Come on, I want to talk to you.
Don't stand there flapping your ears.
Make with the cooking.
I like the cat.
Don't forget, I'm watching you.
I don't trust that dame.
I don't trust her.
I don't want you to trust her.
The thing is,
she might play along
if we con her into thinking
we might turn her loose.
- You wouldn't, would you?
- Are you out of your mind?
Nah, you're kidding.
What's holding you up?
Move it, will you?
I think my watch stopped.
What do I care?
What's with the watch?
- I wanted to time the steaks.
- That's a clock, ain't it?
Move it, will you?
What do you think you're doing?
Not that way, Dan,
somebody will hear.
He wanted to go out.
I... I didn't make a break.
I... I wouldn't do it. I wouldn't.
Okay.
Because I got friends.
Ten little lead-nosed friends in here.
And they all run faster
than you do, Moms.
I know.
Now, let's get one thing straight.
Don't touch that door again.
Not that door,
or any window in there.
- You got that straight?
- Got it?
- Yes.
- You just used up all your luck, lady.
Now, don't try me again.
How about Thursday night
at the drive-in?
- What's playing?
- Night of the Surfer.
- What was that we saw tonight?
- Surfer Beach Party.
- And the night before last?
- Son of Surf and Sinbad the Surfer.
- Double feature.
- Canoe...
Do you ever get a spooky feeling
that we keep seeing
the same movie over and over?
And all they do
is change the titles a little?
Yeah, it's terrific stuff, isn't it?
Couldn't we, just once,
see a nice quiet movie,
where boy meets girl,
they have problems
which aren't weird, they fall in love,
and live happily ever after?
Why would you want
to see unhealthy stuff like that?
Oh, I don't know. Maybe once
I'd like to go to a movie
where I don't get seasick.
I'll make you a deal.
You go with me Thursday night,
next time I'll take you to one of those
happily ever after clambakes. Deal?
- I guess.
- Where's the thing playing?
Oh, who knows? Maybe they don't
make movies like that anymore.
Well, sure.
You wanna know why?
Because people don't want to
be depressed by all that slop.
Ha! That Henderson boy went
right into the house with her.
Right into the house.
She and the Henderson boy,
the two of them.
Why shouldn't he go
in the house?
He's been hanging around
since he was old enough to wave bye-bye.
Nevertheless,
they happen to represent
two separate and distinct
members of the opposite sex.
- Alone, in that house.
- You tell them, kid.
With their parents all over Europe,
someone's got to keep an eye
on those girls.
Meantime,
by authority of
the Federal Communications Commission,
and the grace of
a kindly Providence,
which gave me the power of
not having to listen to people,
I am now going off the air.
Don't you dare take that thing off!
I haven't finished talking.
Good night, old woman.
I can't hear what you're sayin',
but whatever it is,
I disagree with you 100 percent.
You're out of peanut butter.
How come there aren't any olives?
- Put them on the shopping list.
- Okay.
Hi, DC.
You know, Patti,
sometimes you worry me.
You don't eat enough
to keep a bird alive.
Canoe. This is just a wild idea,
but has it ever occurred to you
there's more to life
than surfing and eating?
- Like what?
- Forget it.
I just realized
I was talking to myself.
- Hey, your folks are in Venice.
- I know.
Your father got indigestion
from a clam sauce, but feels better now.
Huh.
Bills, bills, bills.
Look at this, nothing but bills.
Surf news should be
comin' up about now.
You listen. I'm gonna straighten up
and go off to bed.
- Okay.
- Hi, DC.
Watch the crumbs, will you, fellas?
Pass the word. Watch the crumbs.
According to authorities,
the desperados and their victim
may have traveled north
in an effort to escape this area.
- Their car was discovered on...
- That's Miss Miller.
...outside of Fresno.
- Who?
Miss Miller, the Christmas Club window
at the bank.
- I've known her for years.
- Oh, yeah, so have I.
She goes to our Laundromat.
Kind of creepy, isn't it?
All this happening in your
own neighborhood, to people you know.
Want me to stick around
until your sister comes home?
- You know, the protecting bit.
- No, thanks.
All right.
And now, surfers,
here's the word for tomorrow.
This is your Weather Gremmie with
the beach news for the a.m.
Goleta to Zuma,
sea conditions light to moderate.
Malibu, moderate in the early morning,
with some real heavies expected.
Hey, Pat, surf's up tomorrow at Malibu.
You want to go?
Yeah, sure.
Good night.
That's all for tonight, surfers.
The word is "go."
See you at the beach.
Mmm. Come on, here. Come on.
That's a good boy.
Good one.
Wow. 11:15?
Man, I gotta get some sleep.
- I thought we'd almost had it there.
- Sorry, one of Patti's friends.
Oh.
- Is it a date, then?
- Mm-hm.
You won't regret it, I'm sure.
Mother is an extremely fine cook.
- I'm sure she is, Gregory.
- Mother cooks the best duck.
And as for the duck,
did I tell you it was a Gadwall?
No, I don't believe you did.
I, uh, stood all day
in a duck blind to get it.
In the pouring rain.
I almost got pneumonia.
- Oh, I'm so sorry.
- No. It's all right. It was worth it.
Well worth it.
It's a beautiful creature.
Perfectly beautiful. Superb eating.
Mother... Mother prepares duck
in the classic, old-fashioned way.
She hangs it out
on the screen porch
for 48 hours before cooking.
It makes all the difference
in the world.
- All the difference in the world.
- I, um...
I'm looking forward
to meeting your mother.
I've heard so much about her.
I know you two are gonna be
the very best of friends.
And now, uh...
- Good night.
- I'll see you in the morning.
- Mm-hm.
- Same time as usual?
- Hmm.
Quiet, Blitzy.
Good night,
my little beauties.
Oh!
Okay, where's the duck?
- I beg your pardon.
- I want my duck!
Your duck?
If you please.
I'm sorry,
I really don't know...
Where is that sneaky,
miserable guttersnipe?
- He's got my duck.
- What duck?
Don't you dare pretend with me.
- I saw him come in here with it.
- You saw who come in?
Patricia Randall,
I have had all I can take.
That rotten cat of yours,
he molests my prize albino fantails,
crawls all over my car every time
I wash it with his muddy paws.
He digs up Mother's bulbs.
He's driven my dog to the brink
of a nervous breakdown.
You mean DC?
Well, I'm sorry,
but actually, he isn't my cat.
He isn't anybody's cat.
What are you talking about?
He lives here, doesn't he?
Of course, but don't you see?
You don't own someone like DC.
He's family.
Oh,
but what am I gonna do?
Shoot. I spent all day
in a duck blind.
Humph! Pouring rain.
And I get one duck.
One single Gadwall.
And that flea-raddled fiend
had to go and steal it.
I know you're upset,
but be honest. It was dark, wasn't it?
It could have been that nasty cat
from across the street.
The one who does everything
that DC gets blamed for.
Now, do you think...
Oh, DC, how could you?
Hold this.
DC, give that to me this instant.
I want you to know
I'm very, very disappointed in you.
Oh.
Oh, Gregory, I am sorry.
I can't think what
could have come over him.
Bad, bad cat. Ah!
"Bad, bad cat"?
You're a menace
to the whole neighborhood.
Mark you, if I had my way,
the authorities would
do away with you.
Now, wait a minute, Gregory.
DC's a cat.
He can't help his instincts.
He's a hunter, just like you are,
only he's not stupid enough
to sit out in the pouring rain all day.
Well!
Just let me make myself quite clear.
You better keep him locked up at night.
The next time I find him at our place,
I'll give him a pantsful of buckshot.
Nine times, if necessary.
I know.
I don't care for him much, either.
But he does have a point,
don't you think?
Was that Gregory
I heard down there?
- Correct.
- He sounded angry.
Yeah, I believe he was.
- What goes on around here, anyway?
- Nothing, nothing at all.
DC just happened to take a duck
off Gregory's back porch.
- "Happened" to take a duck?
- Yes.
Gregory came stamping and banging
over here to find it.
Furious. Made a perfect fool of himself.
I don't think he's a stable person.
- There goes my duck dinner.
- Your what?
He invited me to his house for dinner.
His mother was gonna fix the duck.
Fix the...
Ingrid, don't you see?
You're walking into a trap.
For goodness sakes, Gregory drives me
to work in the morning.
At night he picks me up
and he takes me home.
If he wants to go
to all that trouble,
the least I can do
is be courteous if he asks me to dinner.
How can you be so blind?
It began with
the old car pool routine, right?
Why shouldn't it? His law office
happens to be next door to where I work.
But the point is, there used to be
five people in that car,
then Gregory traded in his sedan
for a two-seater sports car.
And Mr. Burke,
Miss Patters and Miss Mosely
were ruthlessly squeezed out
to find other transportation, correct?
- Now, listen...
- Creeping matrimony, that's what it is.
The car pool, the duck dinner,
a movie here and there.
Inky, you're taking the gas
and you don't even know it.
Thank you, dear,
I'm sure you mean well,
but I think I can handle
the Gregory situation
in my own bumbling way.
I'm sorry, but I suppose at your age,
when that important person
hasn't come into your life,
- well...
- Well, what?
Well, I suppose a tinge,
just the faintest tinge, of desperation,
begins to blow your judgment.
Good night.
I can assure you, there is no tinge
of desperation in my outlook.
- And my vision is exceptionally clear.
- Good.
Which, I might add,
brings us to your friends.
- My friends?
- Yes, dear.
The one we've been tripping over
all these years.
Canoe? That's very unfair.
Canoe is...
well, he's just defenseless.
He's very sweet and young, and...
...needs help.
- I certainly agree he needs something.
Doesn't he do anything
but mope around in shorts
- and eat us out of house and home?
- Just shows how little you know him.
- Canoe has plenty of ambition.
- What?
To be the first 50-year-old surfer
at Santa Monica?
If you ask me, he's...
What's the matter?
DC's wearing a wristwatch.
Well, what will that dear, sweet,
innocent cat be bringing home next?
The Hope Diamond, I imagine.
- Where do you suppose he got it?
- I don't know.
Probably some child slipped it on,
or some teenager put it on for a joke.
Good night. Check with lost and found
in the morning.
Ingrid?
Look. Someone started to scratch
something on the casing.
See? "H-E,"
and that looks like part of an L.
H-E-L...
I'll bet somebody was trying to write
"help" and they were interrupted.
Somebody's in trouble.
What cooks in that wild
little head of yours now?
Somebody's in trouble.
I feel it in my bones.
You bet. Now get out and let me
go to sleep. I'm a working girl.
Don't you think
we ought to do something?
Good night.
Come on, DC, give.
Someone does need help, don't they?
I know you could find a way to tell me
if you really wanted to.
A smart cat like you.
You can be such a rat sometimes.
Don't say anything,
just point me towards the coffee.
What's wrong with you?
I didn't close my eyes once last night.
Oh, I've got huge dark circles
under my eyes.
- And me so young.
- What's bothering you?
I just couldn't stop thinking
about this watch.
Especially that pitiful
cry for help on the back.
Oh, you're not going to start that,
so help me...
You know, I thought
and thought and thought,
and I think I finally know the answer.
The watch belongs to her.
- The kidnapped woman?
- Yeah.
Come off it. How far out can you get?
Does it have a name?
No, but it's exactly the sort of watch
a woman like that would wear:
Feminine, yet...
bank tellerish, if you see what I mean.
Patti, you are absolutely impossible.
Have a nice day at the office, Inky.
You've got that terrible
butter-won't-melt-in-your-mouth
expression.
I know what's going on
in your little mind,
- and I forbid it.
- What do you mean?
You're not going to over dramatize this,
like you do everything else.
I absolutely forbid you to get
the police stirred up
with another of your hallucinations
about people in trouble.
You're not to go near
the police with that watch.
- Certainly.
- Bye.
- Good morning, Ingrid.
- Good morning.
Naturally, I wouldn't go to the police.
This is a job for the FBI.
May I help you?
- Yes, I'd like to see a, uh...
- We call them agents here.
- Yes, I'd like to see an agent.
- May I ask what about?
I have information
about one of your crimes.
- Thank you. Would you wait over there?
- Yes.
- These are for you, Mr. Hart.
- Thank you.
- I'm back at 11:00.
- Yes, sir.
- Morning, Hart.
- Good morning, Mr. Kelso.
- Hi, Vicky, anything for me?
- No, sir.
If Mr. Paul calls about
the bank records, put him through.
See you around.
- Is he an agent?
- Yes, he is.
- Nice face, hasn't he?
- Why, yes.
Yes, Mr. Ellender?
The messenger hasn't arrived yet.
I can put a tracer on it.
We haven't heard
from Denver all morning.
I'll connect you with Agent Morrow.
He's got the reports on that case.
Well, we've got 22 Howards
in Los Angeles County.
Better start right at the top.
Mr. Kelso, I have something to report
on one of your cases.
It's a family cat.
He's called DC.
That means "Darn Cat."
Daddy named him,
he called him something worse,
Mother won't let us use that.
Excuse me.
First, what is your name?
Patricia Randall,
808 Pendleton Avenue.
Uh-huh, and what is
this information you have, Miss Randall?
It's DC, our cat.
He likes to prowl around at night,
as cats do. Nothing wrong with that.
And he likes people, as a general rule,
if they're nice and give him food.
He goes back.
I think he has a regular route
to pick out food,
sort of like a milkman in reverse.
- And this relates to one of our cases?
- Yes. Yes, it does.
Last night
DC was out roaming around,
and stole a duck from Mr. Benson
down the street.
Ah, Miss, um, Randall...
I'm afraid that
that's a police matter.
You see, our jurisdiction is limited
to certain fields of investigation.
At the present time,
duck stealing is not one of them.
How about bank robbery
and kidnapping?
Maybe I'd better hear
the rest of your story.
Thank you.
Well, last night DC came home
wearing a wristwatch.
- Wearing a wristwatch?
- Yes.
- Instead of his collar.
- Oh.
And I couldn't help thinking what
I would do if I were poor Miss Miller,
held prisoner by two hoodlums,
- and a stray cat came wandering in.
- Mm-hm.
Don't you see? I'd try to put
something of mine on the cat as a clue.
Like a wristwatch, maybe even
try to scratch something on it.
Do you have this wristwatch?
Mr. Kelso, I knew you'd understand.
That's why I selected you personally.
Here.
You see, of course, on the back,
where she started to scratch
the word "help,"
- and was interrupted.
- Uh-huh.
"H-E..."
And that squiggle could be an "L."
Well, that doesn't quite
spell "help," does it?
She was wearing a wristwatch
at the time of her abduction.
We have only a superficial description.
- This may or may not be the watch.
- But wouldn't it be enough to start on?
I wonder if you could wait here
for just a few moments?
Of course. My entire day
is at your disposal.
Thank you, Miss Randall.
- It's a goofy idea.
- That's what I thought too, sir.
- The only thing is, I like it.
- You do, sir?
I don't like this paper chase
someone's leading us on.
Those 20-dollar bills from the bank
we've been picking up
- at convenient towns up the valley.
- They went in another direction?
Or stayed here in the city.
This watch lead ties in with that.
- How's your workload, Kelso?
- Me, sir?
Uh, well, I'm going over
old bank records on Johnny the Cooch.
- We're ready to trip him up.
- The Cooch can wait.
Kidnapping takes priority.
I want you to set up surveillance
and tail this cat.
- Tail the cat?
- He may take us to the criminals.
That's all.
Actually, I don't have
any experience in tailing cats.
For that matter, who does?
Sorry, sir. You wish me to set up
a surveillance on this informant,
exactly as if we thought of him
as a person?
Unless, of course, it works out better
to think of him as a cat.
Sir, I think it's only fair to tell you,
I don't get on well with cats.
There's a kind of an antagonism
between us.
- Is that so?
- Yes, and I have a slight allergy.
Allergy? I know the medical records
of every man in this office.
Have you been keeping
something from me?
It's a very small allergy, sir.
- Hardly worth mentioning.
- Don't.
Stay in touch. I'm available
on this case 24 hours a day.
Yes, sir.
Sir, it's just that every time
I'm around c...
C...
Gesundheit, and good luck.
Thank you, sir.
Yes, a lot of people
are gonna be sorry
for the things they said about DC.
Wait till they find out
he's working with the FBI.
I don't think we should expose
your cat's relationship with us
at this time.
I'd like to remain
as inconspicuous as possible.
You don't want everyone in the
neighborhood to know who you are?
Exactly. People tend
to become over stimulated
when they discover an FBI man
in the neighborhood.
It interferes with the quiet,
orderly process of investigation.
- Hmm.
- Especially kidnap cases.
See, this places the life
of the kidnap victim
into additional jeopardy.
We've gotta not
generate too much heat?
The kidnappers'll chicken out,
kill Miss Miller,
dispose of the remains
and take off?
Uh, that's one way to put it, yes.
Oh.
You go first.
Remember, everything
quiet, calm, inconspicuous.
Quiet, calm, inconspicuous.
That brazen creature.
Right in broad daylight!
What are you cackling about now?
A strange man just went
into the house with Patti.
- So what?
- He was carrying a bag.
Don't get yourself up
in a sweat, old woman.
- It's probably the plumber.
- It was not the plumber!
- This man was nicely dressed.
- That's the way plumbers dress now.
The prices they charge these days,
I'm surprised he wasn't
wearing a tuxedo.
Do you have any friends?
People who are in and out all the time?
I'm afraid so.
Father always complained
we were running a rehabilitation center
for punch-drunk juveniles.
Uh-huh. I'd prefer a room
on the second floor, actually.
To reduce the chance of somebody
coming in and finding me at work.
- This your room?
- Ingrid's. My sister.
- Oh. Would she mind?
- No, not at all.
- She'd be only too happy to help.
- Good.
That's the side door
from the kitchen?
Yes, that's the exit DC uses when
he goes out for an evening on the town.
Uh-huh. Tonight, we'll set up
our communications unit in here.
Whatever you like.
All right. And now, I suppose
I'd better meet the c... c...
Bless you. What did you say?
I said I...
...suppose I...
...better meet the...
- Oh.
Ah, DC. He's probably goofing around
under the bed or something.
That's his favorite spot.
Ah, your sins have caught up with you.
This is your FBI.
Well. This is the...
...informant, as we say
down at the office.
Hear that, DC?
You're the informant now.
Nice little kitty cat.
Good, good kitty cat.
- Is he friendly?
- Mm-hm.
He almost got me that time.
He's all right.
Don't make any sudden moves
because it tends
to set off his reflexes or something.
Uh-huh. Oh, yeah.
Doesn't seem to like me, does he?
I guess that's a bad sign,
the kind of people
- that animals don't like?
- It doesn't mean a thing.
DC and Daddy loathe one another,
and Daddy's
the Lamb of the Year.
Say, I wonder if you would excuse me
for just one minute. I think we better
get this show on the road.
- What are you going to do?
- I have some work to do with DC
before we start our surveillance.
Photos and so on.
- Oh, for the papers, you mean?
- No, for our own people to study.
See, there's finger... paw prints,
plaster impressions...
...samples of his fur...
Bless you.
You're catching a terrible cold.
DC, pull yourself together.
You want me to get you something?
No, no. I'm fine. It's just
a slight allergy I have around c... c...
- Around, uh...
- Oh.
Wonder if you'd put him on the bed
and let me get a picture of him?
- There you go.
- Could you get him to stand up?
- I'll get a full-figure shot.
- Oh, yes.
Uh...
There we go.
Come on, DC, cooperate.
Come on, DC, you're working
for the FBI now. There.
There.
Uh, that's not any good.
We can't see him properly.
Wait a minute.
Here's what he likes.
Here.
Where'd he go?
Back under the bed.
I should've taken the paw prints first.
You're right.
He's not about to come out.
Can't we just get a hold of him there
and drag him out?
Sure, if you want to lose a hand.
The Bureau has spent $19,800
of the taxpayers' money
training me for emergencies.
They expect something for their cash.
I have no intention of being
intimidated by this c... c...
...animal.
- Well, you are a very brave man.
- Thank you.
All right, when I count three,
we'll both grab him at the same time.
- But move fast.
- Let's go.
- You ready?
- Let's go. Yeah.
One, two, three.
Oh, DC. You're bleeding.
No, it's nothing.
Probably just an artery.
Say, would you get him
down for me, please?
You're not going ahead with this?
I'm afraid you underestimate me.
We shall proceed
with the paw printing.
All right.
Come on now, DC,
don't be difficult.
- What's that?
- It's ink.
Ink? Can't we do that
in the bathroom?
Ingrid will murder me
if we get ink on the rug.
Oh, sure. Let's go.
Don't make such a fuss, DC.
You should be ashamed of yourself.
Sorry about the washing.
Girl's bathroom, you know.
- It's okay.
- DC!
- Come on.
- Good old kitty cat.
Nice, nice kitty cat.
Spread this out over there.
Let's see. I guess I'll put the paw print
in the space for the thumb.
Oh, hurry.
I can't hold him any longer.
Oh, all right.
Here we go, now.
Just relax there.
Take it easy, there, now.
It won't hurt a bit.
Oh, Canoe.
- Can I what?
- No, he's a friend of mine.
- I promised to go to the beach.
- That's not so good.
Is he one of the kids
that hangs around?
Yes, and he has kitchen privileges,
and he's as easy to get rid of...
Try to get rid of him.
It's important.
- What do I say?
- Anything. Just keep him away.
All right.
Hurry back,
for the love of heaven.
Okay, tiger,
it's either you or me.
- Patti?
- Yes?
What kind of a get-up is that
to go surfing in?
Want the crowd
to think you're an eccentric?
Please go on without me.
I don't think I can make it today.
Well, Patti, are you all right?
I've never seen you like this before.
- Can I help?
- It's all right.
I just feel terribly, terribly weak.
If you're so weak,
how come I can't get through the door?
Please go, Canoe.
I can't bear you
to see me looking like this.
What was that?
- What was what?
- That bloodcurdling scream.
Canoe, will you please go?
I'm sorry. I didn't realize
I was butting in on a murder.
Oh, don't be silly.
You know how DC hates water.
He's having a bath.
By himself?
All right. If you won't go to the beach,
I'll make myself a sandwich.
Kitchen privileges
are temporarily withdrawn.
He's gone.
Paw prints everywhere!
Yeah, except on the card.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Aha. The best paw print I ever made.
The first point I wish to make
is that time is not on our side.
The word is move,
and move swiftly.
We're gonna follow an informant whose
information may or may not be reliable.
However, he could lead us
to the Miller kidnappers.
Okay, here's the physical.
- DC Randall.
- Siamese.
- Male.
- Blue.
- 17 pounds.
- Seventeen pounds?
- Exactly.
Hair, or in this case, fur:
Black streaked with tan and white.
- You did say "fur"?
- Correct.
- You want us to follow a cat?
- That's the assignment.
How do you follow a cat?
They go through fences and culverts.
They climb trees and phone poles.
Wither he goest, you will go.
- You have a question, Graham?
- I've got an old dog
who's a lot better
at tracking cats than I am.
We don't have time for comments.
I'd like to remind you,
a woman's life is involved here.
- Sorry.
- Okay.
Now, tonight you'll take up
your initial positions
in the area surrounding
the Randall house, here.
When the informant leaves,
it'll be our job to contain him loosely,
within a moving, fluid perimeter.
It's important he doesn't
become aware of us
as this might alter
his regular nocturnal behavior.
Hold it.
Who do you think you're kidding?
- What do you mean?
- You think I don't know
- what's going on upstairs?
- You do?
I didn't come in from Stupidsville
on last night's bus.
- You've got a woman in that apartment.
- Hold it. What does that mean?
Don't double-talk me.
I've got ears, haven't I?
Uh, it's Dan's mother.
She come in unexpected, sudden-like.
We didn't know. That's all.
I don't care if it's Pocahontas.
You got three people living there,
and that'll cost you another 20 dollars.
- I'll bring it right down.
- Don't bother.
I'll come up and get it.
I like to know my tenants.
- Can't. She's sick.
- What's wrong with her?
- Nothing catching, is it?
- It's her nervous system.
It's all fouled up.
She can't stand visitors.
Iggy.
- We gotta leave, gotta get out of here.
- What for?
The old battle-ax knows
we got a dame up here.
She heard her talking.
I told her it was your mother.
Why didn't you tell her
it was the TV?
I told you a million times, the TV.
- I gotta talk to you. Private.
- Why private?
- We got no secrets from Moms.
- Come on, will you? Please.
All right, all right.
Go in the kitchen
and get a glass of water.
And stand by the sink,
where I can see you.
Okay, fill me in.
Well, I found a place.
Where?
I got a big bin I spotted
in an alley two blocks away.
Back of a store,
where they dump trash.
Not so good. It's too close.
Anyway, I don't like bodies.
They always turn up at the wrong times.
We gotta unload her. The lady downstairs
is gonna start nosing around.
I say we got it made,
just as long as we sit tight.
- I say we make a move.
- We sweat it out right here.
Listen, Dan...
...anything else I play it your way,
right?
- Just one condition.
- Who says you make conditions?
- Just one.
- Such as?
She goes.
All right. But not until later.
And not in the trash bin.
See if you can't lose the car somewhere,
get her out of the city.
You sure your sister
won't mind us using her room?
No, not a bit. I told you,
she'd be happy to help.
Good.
Spires, this is Control.
Do you read me?
Sweet and clear. You reading me?
Affirmative. Excuse me.
What's your exact position?
In the alley, about 30 feet
from the Randall back gate.
You're the only one who can see
the informant when he hits the alley.
Let me know which way he turns.
Cahill, what's your field of vision?
West of Whittier,
east of the bend in Wetherby Drive.
- Stand by. About three minutes to go.
- You're young to be doing this work.
- I mean, it's terribly responsible.
- I'm really not that...
...not that young.
Kelly, are you settled in?
Affirmative. South side of Maple,
50 feet from the junction with Wetherby.
Got it.
You're very athletic looking.
Do you surf?
Uh, no, not anymore.
My legs always looked ridiculous
in those shorts.
Besides, I was scared to death
half the time.
I don't believe that.
Look at the brave, wonderful things
you FBI people do in your job.
Maybe we could
chat some other time, huh?
As you very properly pointed out today,
a woman's life may depend on what we do.
I'm sorry.
Do you want me to leave?
Maybe that would be best, yes.
Oh, all right.
I only thought if DC happened to wake up
and find a strange man in the bedroom...
I just don't know
how he's gonna take it.
Uh, you've got a point there.
- Graham, are you settled in?
- Opposite the west end of the alley.
If the informant goes west,
you've got him.
If he goes the other way, stand by.
I'll give you a new position.
- Who's the square red one?
- The informant.
- The informant?
- Yeah.
Oh, DC. Oh.
Say, are you sure he
always goes out at 9:00?
Oh, yes.
Unless, of course,
it's one of his contrary nights.
All agents now stand by.
- For goodness sake, act casual.
- What?
Don't let him suspect
anything's going on.
Oh, oh.
Nice kitty cat.
Good old kitty cat.
You can save the hypocrisy.
- He knows you don't like him.
- Oh.
You're all tensed up.
He's getting the idea something's wrong.
Can't you act casual?
Well, certainly nice weather
we're having, isn't it?
And there's a bit of a wind
coming up from the east.
That's terrible.
Can't you do any better?
- Well...
- And be careful what you say.
He can't understand
what I'm saying, can he?
Not everything, of course.
He's just a cat.
But mostly everything.
I told you before,
let my stuff alone.
And come on
in the house, snoopy.
- I thought he's supposed to go out.
- Shh.
Spires, he's on his way.
I have the informant in sight.
He's turning west on the alley,
toward Whittier Drive.
Graham, he's coming your way.
Can you pick him up?
I've got him.
He's in the backyard of the
next-to-last house on Maple.
I'm going to investigate.
Spires and Cahill,
the informant is moving north.
Stand by for new positions.
He's looking up
at the side windows of the house.
- Who lives here?
- The Hendersons.
- They moved in last winter.
- Forget it. He's moving to the street.
Kelly, next-to-last house on Maple,
informant coming through.
I make him, Control.
He's on Maple Street,
bearing toward the business area.
All right, Kelly,
leave the car and follow on foot.
Spires, move to the junction
of Whittier and College.
The informant is approaching
the junction of Whittier and State.
Okay, Graham,
move to Seventh and State.
Junction Seventh and State.
The informant has now
turned west onto State Street.
Cahill, move to Eighth Street,
about a half block south of Main.
The informant is moving down the alley
leading from State Street to Main.
The informant is stopped on Main Street
in front of a delicatessen.
That's Mr. Bartel's delicatessen.
DC always hangs around there and
it drives Mr. Bartel out of his mind.
Get out of here.
Informant's moving, crossing
to the south side of the street.
Stay put for a minute, Kelly.
Graham, move to Seventh and Main.
Cahill, had a visual
on the informant yet?
Have him, Control.
He's approaching my position.
Informant passed my position, proceeding
toward the middle of the block.
Informant has gone into the side yard
of an apartment building.
Stick with him.
- Does DC know anybody on Eighth?
- Who knows?
He's still in the yard. He's interested
in something on the second floor.
Let's start
pulling in our perimeter.
Kelly, move down Eighth to the building.
Cahill, stay with the informant.
Graham, cut through the backyards
and come behind the apartment.
- DC won't be hurt?
- I have to ask you to be quiet.
Spires, start your car and move towards
the location with your lights off.
Back away from that window.
Why don't you let her stick her head out
the window and yell for help, meathead!
What'd I do?
Hold everything.
Informant's on the move again.
He's proceeding north on Eighth Street
the way he came in.
Oh, no.
Cahill, stay with the informant.
Others return to positions.
I thought we had something there.