All my life, I've lived and worked
in the big city,
which...
never I think of it,
is kind of a problems,
since I always feel
uncomfortable around crowds.
I mean it. I.. I have this fear
of enclosed spaces.
I.. I.. I.. I everything makes me
feel trapped all the time.
I mean, I.. I always tell myself,
there is gotta be something
better out there but...
maybe, maybe,
maybe I think too much, yeah.
I.. I.. I think everything
must go back to the fact,
that I had a very anxious childhood.
You know, my mother
never had time for me.
You know, when you're the middle child
in a family of 5 million,
you don't get any attention.
I mean, how is it possible?
And I've always had these...
these abandonment issues
which plague me.
My father was, was basically a drone,
like I've said.
And you know the guy flew away
when I was just a larva.
And...
my job...
don't get me started on because I...
it really annoys me.
I.. I was not cut out to be a worker,
I'll tell you right now.
I.. I.. I feel physically inadequate.
I.. I.. My whole life, I've never,
I've never been able to lift more than
10 times my own body weight.
And, and when you get down to it,
handling dirt is, you know...
is not my idea of a rewarding career.
It's this whole...
gung ho, super organism thing that, that...
that you know, I can't get.
I try, but I don't, I don't get it.
I mean, you know...
What is it? I'm supposed to
do everything for the colony.
And.. And what about my needs?
What about me?
I mean, I've gotta believe there is someplace
out there that's better than this.
Otherwise, I would just curl up
in a larval position and weep.
The whole system makes me feel...
insignificant.
Excellent.
You've made a real breakthrough.
I have?
Yes, Z.
You are insignificant.
I am?
Ground floor.
Worker.
Soldier.
Let's try it again.
Firm grip.
Swing hard.
Back straight.
Concentrate.
Follow through.
Ok. I've got to keep a positive attitude.
A good attitude, even no one,
I'm utterly insignificant.
I'm.. I'm insignificant, but with attitude.
Sorry, Z.
I didn't see ya.
Great, Azteca.
It's working already.
I'm.. I'm so meaningless, I'm invisible.
Now, you're getting it.
After all,
it's not about you.
It's about us,
the team.
It's about...
this.
A giant hole in the ground?
Ok, people. Are we feeling good?
Yeah.
Great.
Now, R-1734 through Z-7829,
you guys are on wrecking ball.
You got it.
Swell.
You got it. Alright.
Swing time.
Let's get physical.
I love this job.
Now, remember Azteca, be the ball.
That's the main thing.
Remember that.
You know, gotta be one with the ball.
Would you cut it out already?
Jeez. I love my work.
And you well...
You think too much.
Come on, Z.
Help us build a bigger, better colony.
And for crying out loud,
try to be happy about it.
Sure, you know.
I mean, why...
How could I possibly be unhappy being
a piece of construction equipment?
Ok workers, remember.
Here it comes.
Be the ball.
Let the energy flow through you.
Grin and bear it.
This is.. This is for the colony.
This is...
This is just a lawsuit waiting to happen.
Hang on. Here we go.
Faster. Harder.
Did I happen to mention,
that heights make me nauseous?
No.
This is a ball.
Oh, Z.
Yes. Yes. Yes. I understand.
I dropped the ball.
Workers.
They're weak.
They lack discipline.
They lack commitment.
General, I know there is been a glitch
or two.
But...
everybody is working full tilt as it is and...
You can't help it,
it's your nature.
But in spite of your limitations,
you are going to finish
this tunnel, on schedule.
Come hell or high water.
From now anyone who falls behind is going to have
personally to explain themselves to Colonel Cutter.
And let me assure you,
the colonel is not as understanding
as I am.
Dismissed.
Four more days, Cutter.
Four more days.
Then we can bid final farewell
to their kind of incompetence.
Yes, sir.
A fresh start.
Imagine it!
A strong colony, sir.
A colony, we can be proud of.
Yes, but we're not there yet.
Cutter,
we just got word that a termite
army has mobilized against us.
Against us?
We'll have to send troops
deep into hostile territory,
to attack their colony.
Attack a termite colony, sir?
That is suicide.
Exactly.
Do you have the list I asked for?
Yes, General.
These are the units loyal to the queen.
Then they're the ones we'll be sending.
It's a shame.
There is some fine officers here.
Don't we need the queen's approval,
to declare war?
Our very next stop, Cutter.
General, we've been at peace
with that colony for years.
Why would they attack us?
They want our land.
They're desperate
for more foraging territory.
Perhaps they think we've
grown soft or weak.
Why don't we dispatch an ambassador,
negotiate a new treaty?
Certainly we don't need to send soldiers.
Believe me.
Every ant in this colony
is so precious to me.
That's why we must strike now.
We have the element of surprise.
If the termite shock
troops enter our colony,
well...
Yes General,
I know what they can do to us.
Very well.
You've made a wise decision.
In fact, you've insured
the future of this colony.
Hello General.
Princess Bala.
Oh what a nice surprise.
You look lovelier each time I see you.
Thanks.
I hope you're not just here on business.
Oh, of course...
of course not.
Because...
it might be nice if we had...
a conversation,
once before we get married.
You're absolutely right.
Cutter, schedule some private
time for me and Princess Bala.
In fact sir, there is time right now,
for a personal moment.
We're, a few seconds ahead of schedule.
Excellent.
Princess.
Well,
a few seconds isn't much but...
I guess if it's quality time.
So...
how was your day?
Anything interesting happen?
We declared war.
Declared war?
Boy...
talk about a rough day.
Sir, I hate to interrupt but,
time stands still for no ant.
Princess.
Mom,
could you remind me,
why am I marrying this guy?
Bala, do we have to argue
about this again?
We don't seem to have anything in common.
The guy is a stiff.
Yes darling, I know the general
may be a little gruff and...
somewhat overbearing at times but...
I know that he cares about you.
He is just not particularly good
at showing it.
But you should've seen how persistently
he asked for your hand in marriage.
But why me?
Because you're the one
who has to continue my work.
It's your place, dear.
What if I don't like my place?
Everyone has their place, Bala.
You,
the soldiers, the workers.
Now, it's not all that bad
being princess, is it?
Would you prefer to be
carting around dirt all day?
Oh mother, don't be so dramatic.
At least they seem to have
some fun every now and then.
Two aphid beers.
Why'd I have to be born a worker?
You soldiers get all the glory,
plus you get to go out in the world.
You know you meet interesting insects,
you get to kill them.
Yeah. But you get to spend
all day with those...
beautiful worker girls.
Weaver, they're career girls.
They're obsessed with digging.
I really don't think I'm ever
gonna meet the right girl for me.
Who said a girl for you?
I was talking about a girl for me.
Don't you want your aphid beer?
Call me crazy but...
I have a thing about drinking from
the anus of another creature. Ok?
Suit yourself.
Me, I'm cutting loose.
We got royal inspection coming up.
Inspection?
Meaning you're gonna stand around like an idiot
while a bunch of blue bloods smirk at you.
I don't know how
you put up with it, Weaver.
Z,
I've known you for a long time. Right?
Definitely.
You were born two seconds after me.
Yeah. And ever since we were little,
I've been listening to you complain.
What are you bitching about?
In case you haven't noticed,
we ants are running the show.
We're the lords of the Earth.
Hey. Don't talk to me about earth, ok?
Because I just spent all day
hauling it around.
There is just gotta be a better place.
There is.
I've been there.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Were you talking to me?
There is a better place...
Insectopia.
Really.
Lunatic at 3:00.
You can't understand
till you go there and see it yourself.
You can be your own ant there.
The streets are paved with food.
Nobody telling you what to do.
No wars.
No colony.
I shoulda never left.
Yeah. Fascinating.
We were on a long range recon.
I got cut off from my unit.
Nothing like post-traumatic stress
disorder to make your day complete.
Then I saw it...
Insectopia!
You head towards the monolith.
Ten clicks past the great canyons
to the land of red and white.
Hey, gramps.
You've had enough for one night.
Come on.
Before you get in trouble.
Head for the monolith.
Listen to me!
The monolith!
That guy is got a screw loose.
Cross the lake!
Insectopia.
Wouldn't it be great if it were that easy?
Yeah.
Dream on, Z.
Cross the lake.
Look for the land of red and white.
This is so...
gritty.
Ten minutes and we're out of here.
Right? I mean this place is off limits.
Just blame it on me.
Say it was all my idea.
It is all your idea.
Besides, no one is gonna recognize us.
Come on, girls.
What do you say?
Let's take a walk on the wild side.
Ok, everybody. 6:15. Time to dance.
Time to cut a rug, Z.
Oh, no. That's ok.
I'm gonna...
I'm gonna leave the rug
just the way it is, Weaver.
Step back, ladies.
I'm gonna ask one of these
workers to dance with me.
What a bunch of losers.
Mindless zombies capitulating
to an oppressive system.
Hi. Want to dance?
Absolutely.
Follow me.
So, how come I haven't seen you
around here before?
I don't get out much.
I... I work over at the palace.
The palace?
I bet those royals really live it up.
Of course they're all a little...
you know from inbreeding.
What?
What on earth are you doing?
Well, actually, to tell you the truth,
I'm.. I'm sort of making it up.
Really?
You know, why does everybody
have to dance the same way?
You know, that's completely boring.
You know, it's monotonous.
It's no fun.
Watch your step, worker.
You watch yours, buddy,
or you'll be in big trouble.
That's. That's ok. I'll...
I'm gonna let him off this time.
Are you crazy?
This guy is built like a pebble.
Aren't you even gonna defend yourself?
Hey, buddy. Get back in place.
Me?
What if he doesn't want to?
Yeah. Wha.. What if I don't like my place?
What's he talking about?
We got us a troublemaker.
Buckle up, Spanky.
This one goes out
to all the lazy workers.
You ought to watch that
aggressive behavior, buddy.
He is just a worker.
Princess Bala! Princess Bala!
The guards are coming.
Let's get outta here.
Wait!
Princess?
You're a princess?
I gotta go.
When can I see you again?
Let me think.
Never.
Bye.
No. Wait.
♪ What a day it has been ♪
♪ What a rare mood I'm in ♪
♪ Why it's almost like being in love ♪
♪ There is a smile on my face ♪
♪ For the whole insect race ♪
♪ Why it's almost like being in love ♪
Can I get you another one, pal?
No.
Thanks I...
I think I'm gonna go.
Yeah, I don't blame you.
It's always slow in here the night
before one of those royal reviews.
I guess the soldiers need their
shut-eye before they meet the queen.
I don't blame ya.
That's it!
You know I was once...
See ya.
Weaver.
I figured it out.
Weaver. Weaver.
What? What?
I got a great idea.
You gotta switch places with me.
Let me go to the
inspection instead of you.
What time is it?
Weaver.
The royal family will be there.
This is the only way I can see her.
See who?
Princess Bala.
Are you nuts?
You want me to switch places with you?
Do you know how much trouble
you can get into
for even talking about
impersonating a soldier?
You can get in trouble just for listening
to someone talking about
impersonating a soldier.
You have to help me.
If I can't see her again,
my life is not worth living.
Plea.. Plea.. Please Weaver. Please.
Switch jobs with me.
Just for a day.
Th.. Think. Think of all the things
that I've done for you.
I can't think of any.
Ok. So, think of all the things
that I'm gonna do for you.
Would I meet some worker girls?
Are you kidding?
They always go after the new guy.
It's like a sport for them.
And.. And believe me, they will definitely go
for an adorable little insect like you.
Weaver, I...
I have to see her again.
Z, what kind of chance
do you have with a princess?
I mean, she probably
won't even remember you.
I.. I know it sounds nuts,
but I have to try.
Oh, boy.
Princess, fancy meeting you here.
What do you say we lose this crowd?
Oh, me? You know, I...
I wear many hats.
I guess you'd have to call me
a Renaissance ant.
Eyes right!
Beautiful! Just beautiful!
The precision. The order.
Princess Bala! Princess Bala!
Hey. Hey it's me.
Remember Z from the bar?
Princess Bala!
Princess Bala! Princess...
Bala, you must encourage the troops.
Wave.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Guys. I..I..I.. Sorry.
I just got a better offer.
Could you excu...
Company halt!
Excu...
Princess Bala!
Princess Bala.
Quiet there!
Get back in rank.
You new, kid?
Yeah, yes, yes, but...
You know, I'm getting out soon I...
I got a trial membership.
Trial membership.
That's a good one!
Name is Barbatus.
Z.
Right face!
Sacrifice.
To some, it is just a word.
To others, it is a code.
Jeez. I'm really bad at word games.
A soldier knows that the life
of an individual ant doesn't matter.
What matters is the colony.
He is willing to live for the colony,
to fight for the colony,
to die for the colony.
This guy is crazy.
I hear ya.
At 0800 hours,
we received word that the
termite enemy has mobilized.
We have no choice,
but to launch a preemptive strike.
You are the queen's finest.
I know you will all do you duty.
I am proud, to send you into battle.
Into...
I'm sor... I'm sorry. Into battle?
Dismissed.
Left face.
Forward march.
You know, I think
there is been a terrible mistake.
You know, the truth is I just...
I just came for the speech.
Don't worry, kid.
I'll watch out for ya.
Sound off.
One! Two!
Three!
Sound off.
Five!
Six!
Seven!
Eight!
Nine!
Ten!
Eleven!
Twelve!
Thirteen!
♪ We ants go marching one by one.
Hurrah, hurrah. ♪
♪ We slaughter termites just for fun.
So, these.. These termites,
they're.. they're...
These guys aren't gonna put up much
of a fight, right? I mean...
We're talking pushovers, right?
Not really, kid.
They're five times our size.
And they shoot acid from their foreheads.
Hey. Keep it moving, shorty.
♪ We ants go marching two by two.
Hurrah, hurrah. ♪
♪ We'll all be dead before we're through.
He say, what exactly,
what does our platoon do?
I mean, you know, will we be
serving beverages or...
or processing paperwork?
Our platoon has the best assignment of all.
We're the first into battle!
♪ We ants go marching three by three. ♪
♪ Hurrah, hurrah. ♪
♪ Hurrah! Hurrah! ♪
♪ We're off to face our destiny. ♪
♪ Hurrah, hurrah. ♪
Hey. Wait a minute. Let's not get
we're being too hasty here.
These. These guys, sound like bruisers.
What... Just... Just how were you
figuring on beating them?
Superior numbers, kid.
Overwhelm their defenses
and kill their queen.
Hey, fellas. That's.
You're being a little extreme, I feel.
Why.. Why don't.. Why don't we try
and influence their political process,
with campaign contributions?
I like you, kid.
You got a sense of humor.
Forward!
Come on.
Let's kick some termite butt.
Where is everyone?
Something is not right.
Don't be scared, kid.
Attack!
Come on.
Barbatus, you saved my life.
Don't get all sappy about it.
Hey, guys. Look out behind you!
Hey. Hey, guys.
Can somebody help me here?
Can anybody. Hey.
Yeah.
Ok, mama.
Oh, yeah.
Big guy coming through.
I love it.
Hey. Hey. Hey.
Take it easy, muscles.
You're making the rest of us look bad.
What happened to Z?
He is taking a personal day,
so I'm filling in.
You fill in any more and you'll explode.
You got a problem?
No...
Nobody told me digging was
so much fun you know you...
pick the dirt up.
You move it.
You pick it up again.
You move it again.
Lots of reps.
You exercise the arms and the thorax.
Yes, I... I see what you mean.
Yeah. That is fascinating.
Sorry, sir.
I was just having
a little chat with my friend, sir.
You know, I just had a little chat
with General Mandible.
Anybody who doesn't meet his quota
is going to be downsized.
Come on. Cut him a break.
He is new.
Hey.
What do you say we help,
your attitude a little bit by...
taking away your rations for the day.
Thanks for your time.
I don't know what came over me.
Talking back like that.
I must be losing it.
Sorry I got you in trouble
but listen you can...
share my rations.
If you want.
Are you asking me out to dinner?
No. I...
Well...
if you don't have anything else planned.
I'll check my calendar.
You know,
I'm kinda glad Z is taking a breather.
Kid!
Kid, over here.
Barbatus.
Be honest, kid.
Am I hurt bad?
N.. No. Not. Not at all.
You. You're...
Actually, you're looking terrific.
You got, you know,
swell color in your cheeks.
No. I can see it in your eyes.
I'm a goner.
Help me up Z.
I can't feel my legs.
You gotta hang in there, buddy.
You.. You, you know.
I.. I know you're gonna make it.
Just, take, take, take deep breaths.
Because I'm, I'm.. I'm.. I'm gonna try
and find your body, its...
It's bound to be out there somewhere.
Barbatus, han.. hang.. hang on.
Barbatus.
Don't make my mistake, kid.
Don't follow orders your whole life.
Think for yourself.
Barbatus.
We're on schedule.
Work is completed on A section, sir.
We're clearing a path
through D section now.
We need to push harder, Cutter.
I want double shifts around the clock.
We can't afford to let up.
Is that clear?
Crystal, sir.
Good.
What about section...
Excuse me, sir.
This had better be important.
Well, it's about the termite battle, sir.
The enemy was destroyed,
but I am afraid it was a disaster
for our troops, as well.
Well, that's terrible.
Terrible.
There is good news, sir.
One soldier did make it back.
No kidding.
What did you say?
Word is spreading through the colony sir.
And the queen requested a meeting
with the war hero.
Damn!
Good. Damn good.
I'll handle this.
Congratulations, soldier.
Well, you're a little short
for a war hero, aren't you?
A war hero?
Sir, I... I don't actually
think that I'm a hero.
Good.
I don't like heroes.
But, sir. You don't understand. I...
I... I didn't do anything.
I mean, it was all horrible.
It was just, just a massacre.
A massacre upon a massacre.
That's good, soldier.
Now, wave.
There was nothing you could do, Weaver.
You didn't know they were going to war.
I just feel horrible.
Poor Z.
I should have never let him go.
Wait a minute.
That's no soldier. That's Z!
Z?
The little guy made it!
Let's go, soldier.
As I was saying son,
you are an ant after my own heart.
An ant that looks death
in the face and laughs.
Actually, the truth is, I... I...
generally just make belittling
comments and...
snicker behind death is back.
General Mandible.
Keep your comments to yourself.
Let me do the talking.
May I present.
Her Majesty the Queen.
Charmed. Charmed.
And the Royal Princess, Bala.
Welcome home, soldier.
We cannot begin to express
our gratitude for your heroic efforts.
The private has asked me
to convey his most humble appreciation.
Please. Please.
It was nothing really just...
your average run of the mill valor...
and extraordinary courageousness,
you know.
In the heat of battle, there is very
little time to think you know.
One must attack! Attack! Attack!
Well, indeed.
As you can see, Your Highness,
the battlefield is still
fresh in his mind, so...
begging your pardon, but this is
the perfect time to debrief the private.
Please, General.
Not on our first date.
Haven't I seen you somewhere before?
Well, maybe.
Then again, maybe not.
And then, then again.
That's it!
You're the guy from the bar.
Don't...
Bar? What bar?
I danced with this guy at the bar
the other night.
He was just a worker then.
What were you doing at a bar?
Precisely what I want to know.
No. This isn't about me.
I mean, look at this worker.
Look what He is done.
I think you're thinking of someone else.
After all, I am a soldier.
Exactly.
You were a worker.
But now, you're a war hero.
He is a worker?
A worker danced with my fiancee?
Fi... Fiancee?
Wait. Wait... Wait a minute.
This is not.. This is not how it looks.
I can explain this.
This. Hey.
She was the one making all the moves.
Arrest him.
Hey. Hey. Hey wait a minute.
Take it easy.
Can't we discuss this?
What are you doing?
Let go of my daughter.
He is taking her hostage!
No. No. I'm not. I m.. I mean, yes.
Yes I am.
One more step and then
the princess gets it.
Let go of me!
Don't make me hurt her.
What are you doing, you creep?
Are you out of your puny little mind?
There they are down there! Let's go.
Move. Move. Move. Move. Move.
Good.
Here they come to rescue me,
and kill you.
Kill?
Hey, you guys.
Stop it. Stop it.
What are you trying to do?
Get off me, you little twerp!
Wait a minute.
What?
What do you want to do?
Throw away everything we've got?
What're you waiting for?
Hello. Guys.
What is it?
It's beautiful.
Ridgeway, get out of there!
Don't worry. I'm ok.
You?
You're ok?
Hey. Who cares about you?
I almost died here.
Will you please calm down?
You're not gonna let a little near-death
experience ruin your mood, are you?
Hey. This is not a mood. Ok!
You're not listening to me.
Where am I?
Look, what's your name. Just...
climb up that tree,
and find out where I am.
Look, the trick is not to panic.
You know...
you, who panics is lost.
What am I saying?
We are lost.
I've been kidnapped by the village idiot.
Who is the bigger idiot,
the idiot or the idiot
who gets kidnapped by the idiot?
What'd you do,
talk those termites to death?
I can't believe you tried
to pass yourself off as a soldier.
Why are you stalking me?
Don't you realize
that I'm out of your league?
You're the one who was cruising the
worker bar looking for a little action.
And you just happened to find it...
the swarthy, earthy,
sensual worker.
Please.
I was slumming it.
Don't you get it?
I chose you because you were the most
pathetic little bug in the joint.
You know, I was gonna let you become
part of my most erotic fantasies.
But now, you can just forget that.
Write it off, you know.
I.. I guess what you prefer
is Old Blood and Guts.
This guy is idea of a romantic night out
is two seats at a public execution.
Boy. You really chose the right husband.
For your information,
the general and I, are deeply,
deeply, in...
engaged.
You come right back down here
this instant.
We are marching straight back
to the colony so that I...
The monolith.
Absolutely. Wonderful. That's an appealing offer.
But...
considering the options,
you go back. Ok?
Because I'm going to Insectopia.
Come on. Insectopia?
You're crazier than I thought.
Yeah. Well, I happen to have it
on a very reliable source.
Or. Or should I say...
a drunk-raving source, but...
the point is, I'm convinced
the place definitely exists.
Stop!
I order you to stop, worker!
Hey. I got a name. Ok?
It's Z.
And out here, you can't order me around.
Alright. Fine. No problem.
Worker! Worker!
Where are you?
Z?
Wait for me.
No more excuses, General.
I want my daughter back.
Frankly, I'm beginning to doubt
your ability to handle this.
Believe me, Your Highness,
we will spare no effort to bring her back.
Princess Bala is essential
to all our plans for the future.
So he kills himself a hundred termites,
gets a few medals,
then bada-bing, bada-bip,
bags himself the princess.
He looks him dead in the eye...
And says, Bite me.
He said that to General Mandible?
Buddy.
Hey, hey, buddy.
You heard about the war hero,
named Z?
Runs off with the princess, right?
When they sent the guards after him,
he just looks at them and boom!
They burst into flames.
Z?
You talking about Z?
Hey, I know the guy.
He is a friend of mine.
I think your information...
You know Z?
Yeah.
He is a worker.
He used to dig around here.
A worker?
That's impossible.
A worker can't do anything, except work.
Yeah. It's not like we got a choice.
We do have a choice.
I mean, look at Z.
He decided he wanted something,
and he went for it.
He is not alone.
I used to be a soldier,
and I switched places with him.
Wait a second.
You're telling me.
I don't have to be here?
We've got a choice?
The authorities don't want you
to know pal,
but we don't have to work
on the tunnel anymore.
It's the workers who control
the means of production.
If Z don't dig, I don't dig.
People, what is this?
An encounter group?
Let's get back to work.
Why?
On the tunnel anymore!
This guy Z.
He is leading the revolution!
I'll get back to you.
Think about it Z.
Two ants.
Who ever heard of two ants?
Two million ants, maybe.
But two?
Look.
I'm hungry.
I'm thirsty.
And this whole desert thing.
It just doesn't work for me.
I think it's about time
for you to take me back.
Take yourself back.
Excuse me.
You kidnapped me, remember?
That means you have
certain responsibilities.
You can't just abandon me
here in the wilderness.
Yeah, well, it's better than
being back at the colony.
You're not serious, are you?
Maybe you were living the high life,
but personally this beats digging.
If you'd ever done a day is labor
you'd know what I was talking about.
Labor?
What do you know about labor?
How would you feel if you
were expected to give birth,
every ten seconds
for the rest of your life?
Gee.
Water!
All you think about is yourself.
Yeah. Well, nobody else
ever thought about me.
So as far as I'm concerned,
I don't need anybody else.
Help! Help me, Bala!
Help!
B-B-Ba-B-Bala!
Ba-B-Ba-Bal!
Bala!
Hold on. I'll get you out.
Hold on.
Help, Ba-Bal-Ba.
Thanks.
Don't mention it.
Now, maybe we can put
this fantasy behind us...
and head back to the colon...
Oh, Z!
What are you doing?
We've gotta cross the lake.
Am I missing something here?
Didn't we just get out of the water?
Bala, look, what have you got to lose?
I mean, think about it.
Do you really want to be Mrs.
Raving Lunatic?
There is a better place.
Z, please.
Just...
Give me one chance.
If we don't find Insectopia soon,
I promise I'll take you back
to the colony.
I hope you know what you're doing.
Yeah, me too.
We want Z! We want Z!
People, come on.
I know some ants who aren't
gonna make their quota.
Buzz off, pawn of the oppressor.
We want Z! We want Z!
Sorry, sir.
I came as soon as I heard.
I was debriefing the trackers.
And what's the report?
Well, this Z, sir...
He is one slippery character.
They lost Bala's trail,
at the edge of the lake.
The lake?
♪ All we are saying ♪
♪ Is give Z a chance ♪
What's that soldier doing there?
It appears He is holding hands, sir...
with a worker.
I don't like the way
things are going, Cutter.
I'm counting on you for results.
Now, can I depend on you or not?
Yes, sir.
Alright, then.
Let's wrap this up.
We want Z! We want Z! We want Z!
I've heard a lot about this Z.
I even had the pleasure,
of meeting him once.
But where is he now?
Can anyone point him out?
I mean, if this Z
cares so much about us,
then why isn't he here?
I'll tell you why.
Because Z doesn't give
a damn about us.
That's why he kidnapped our princess.
That's why he ran away.
Z is no hero.
We are the heroes.
We are the ones ensuring
the future of our great colony.
And when we've completed
this magnificent structure,
we will reap the benefits.
More food and less work for everyone.
And as further reward
for your heroic efforts,
each and every one of you
will get the day off,
so you can be the guests of honor,
at the Mega Tunnel
dedication ceremonies!
Mandible! Mandible!
Mandible! Mandible! Mandible! Mandible!
Now bring me that soldier.
Oh, my God!
Z! Come here!
It's Insectopia!
You were right.
It really is here.
Alright. Alright!
You're a genius.
Let's eat.
Well.
What's the problem?
There is some kind of force field.
Ex.. Exc.. Excuse me.
Excuse me.
Ho.. How.. How do you get in?
Yeah, well, I'm, I'm afraid
this is a private function.
Who are your friends, dear?
Crawling insects, poopsie.
The poor dears.
Good morning.
Darling, really.
Greeting every insect
that emerges out of the grass?
Pardon me.
I guess you don't recognize me.
I've been traveling and I'm all...
schlumpy.
I'm Princess Bala.
It's even worse.
They're Eurotrash.
Darling, they're poor.
They're dirty. They're smelly.
We have to help them.
If you'll just wait right here,
we'll fetch you a little something.
Please, Muffy.
Not another crusade.
Chippie, we have a social obligation
to the less fortunate.
I know you laugh at my hobbies,
but this is important to me!
You have such a big heart.
That's why you're
my little cuddly-widdles.
My big strong pheromone factory.
Oh, brother.
Suddenly I've lost my appetite.
You know...
I guess I had imagined Insectopia...
I don't know, a little differently.
Muffy!
No!
No.
Look out!
Z, help me!
Z!
Don't let me...
Don't let me go, Z.
Get me out of here!
Bala!
This is not good.
Hi.
Z?
Yes?
It looks like this is it,
just when...
I was starting to like you.
Who the hell is that?
That's enough.
I ain't telling you nothing.
Soldier,
the princess is vital,
to the future of this colony.
She must be returned
to take her proper place as queen.
We already have a queen.
As for your friend Z,
why should I hurt him?
He is not important.
Now soldier,
we all know that one individual ant
doesn't matter.
You...
not Cutter...
Not even her.
Azteca!
Don't tell that tight-ass
anything, Weaver!
Where is Z?
I don't know where he is!
That's too bad.
Wait!
Insectopia.
I know it sounds crazy,
but that's where he'd be going.
Soldier, you think this is a game?
Insectopia does not exist.
As a matter of fact...
it does.
Sir?
I'll brief you on the coordinates.
You're gonna bring the princess back.
And as for Z...
kill him.
But you said he didn't matter.
It's for the good of the colony.
You made the right decision.
Gentlemen,
now you can see how dangerous
individualism can be.
It makes us...
vulnerable.
Let's go.
Take him back to the Mega Tunnel.
Put him on the front line.
Dismissed.
Jeez, what was I thinking?
I almost got you killed.
Z, you know,
you really shouldn't be so hard on...
That's it.
I'm taking you back to the colony.
Insectopia. You know, I..
I must've been crazy.
Z.
But you know what?
I can admit it when I'm wrong.
Z.
And this time, I gotta tell ya,
I was.. I was absolutely, 100 %...
correct.
Have...
Have you ever seen anything...
more beautiful in your life?
It's... Insect...
Don't jinx it.
Come on!
Pardon us.
Alright, everybody.
I want all teams in place,
fully prepared, ready to seal the doors,
here and here.
Make certain the digging crew stays
on schedule for breakthrough,
midway in the dedication ceremony.
Now all we need is the princess.
This stuff tastes like crap.
Really? Let me try some.
Hey, it is crap.
Not bad.
Somebody needs to feed that fire.
Dude, I did it last time.
I'm not gonna get it.
It's not my job.
What about the new guy?
He hasn't contributed yet.
And...
you know he just died
in my arms like that, I...
I.. You know, I.. I...
I don't think he ever, once in his life...
made his own choice.
I never knew it was like that.
I mean up in the palace.
Well,
I guess we just let the general
make all the decisions.
Let me ask you something.
What made you come
to the bar that night?
I guess I was looking for a little trouble.
Well...
trouble is my middle name.
Actually, my middle name is Marion but...
I don't want you to spread that around.
You're pretty strange.
You do know that, don't you?
Well...
strange is not exactly the word
I would use, you know.
I like it.
You're not like anyone else.
Actually, now that you mention it, I...
There is a certain strangeness to me.
I mean it's...
it's... you know, kind of a bizarre quality.
Some have said... freak.
But, but it's...
you know complimentary.
Hey new guy.
We need more wood.
I'll be right back.
Just hold that thought,
Whatever, whatever it is you were thinking.
Hey, you ever wonder why
they call you guys, pests?
What if, like, we're just these
tiny little things...
and we're just, like part of
this whole other huge universe...
that's, like so big,
we don't even know it exists?
Man, that is so deep.
Perfect. Nothing like a little manual labor...
on the most romantic night of my life.
Hi.
I was in the neighborhood
and I thought I'd drop in.
This is...
very bohemian.
Aloha, dude. Welcome to Insec...
Sorry, for interrupting.
You see, our princess has...
gone missing and,
we're just sick about it.
SHe is about yea tall,
fairly easy on the eyes.
Anybody seen her?
That's her.
Don't worry, Princess,
you'll be back home soon.
Listen Cutter, I'm...
I'm not going back.
The thing is, Princess,
I got orders.
Orders?
Can't you just once think for yourself?
Well, that was very impressive.
Wher.. Where is Z?
Z? He is... He is...
Dead.
Z is dead.
You don't need to worry about him.
Z is dead?
He was an ant with ideas.
Too bad for him.
Princess, your colony needs you.
Cutter!
Stop right now! Let go of me!
Bala!
Stop, you...
Oh, no.
What am I gonna do?
Alright, look. look.
Let's.. Let's be rational about this.
You know, Bala and I,
you know, sHe is a princess and I'm...
I'm a soil-relocation engineer.
So wha... You're no...
In the other hand...
I've gotta go back for her.
I'll... I'll give you a lift.
It's the least I can do.
Besides,
it's what my waddly-kiddles would want.
Look...
How.. how about a cup of joe first?
Well old boy.
Ok. You know. I...
I think I saw a puddle of coffee over there.
Saddle up.
Look out!
Princess.
You're just in time.
Take your hands off me.
General, what exactly is going on here?
I demand an explanation.
I'll explain everything, afterwards.
Is the southeast entrance secure?
Yes, sir.
Not afterwards. Now.
I don't like the way you think,
and I don't like the way you run
this colony.
And I don't like you.
The wedding is off.
Things are going to change around here.
You're right, Princess.
Things are going to change.
Why don't we make her
more comfortable?
She'll be here for a while.
What do you think you're doing?
My mother will have your head.
I doubt that.
You've got a fighter spirit, Bala.
And that's just what we need
to start our new colony.
We will rinse away
all the filth from our gutters.
We'll start a new,
with you by my side as my queen.
You're crazy.
I believe history will see things differently.
Alright, gentlemen.
Time to take your positions.
Someday.
Someday you'll thank me.
Pull up!
There it is!
Well then,
go get the woman you love, Z.
So long, Chip.
And thanks.
You there?
Where do you think you're going?
Me? Oh, no, I was just...
You know, I...
You're not supposed to be out here.
All workers are to report to
the tunnel-opening ceremonies.
Yes, yes, of course.
The tunnel-opening ceremonies.
I... Well, I.. I should get going then.
I... You know, the, the...
Hey!
Tunnel... I'm going to the tunnel
opening ceremonies.
Get moving.
I'd better get going.
I'm going to the...
The tunnel-opening ceremonies. I...
Excuse me, please.
Tunnel-opening ceremonies.
Hey, worker!
Opening the tunnel.
They need me.
I'm the key man.
Where do you think you're going?
Tunnel-opening ceremonies.
Hey, come on!
Let me outta here!
Hey!
Gosh, this-this day just keeps
getting better and better.
I mean big trouble!
Are you listening to me out there?
I'm the princess!
Damn it!
Your manners haven't improved much.
Z.
It's you.
You came back for me.
Well, yeah, I came back for you.
You know I...
Have strong feelings for you.
Let's face it, you're, you're...
you're beautiful. I...
A little...
combative at times, but...
I think we can work on that.
You talk too much.
Gee, I think I'm about to become
the strong, silent type.
Come on.
The city is deserted.
We'd better get outta here.
Z.
We can't go.
Mandible is insane. He...
He keeps talking about...
washing away the filth and,
and changing history and...
And I think He is going to try
to kill my mother.
Not just your mother,
everyone.
What's going on?
Look.
Here we are, safe in the city.
But they're gonna seal everybody
off in the Mega Tunnel.
And...
here is the lake.
You're right.
We can't leave now.
Come on.
We gotta get down there.
Today is the realization, of a dream.
A dream of a proud colony.
A pure colony.
A colony, reborn.
Moments from now,
this tunnel will open.
The past will be washed away,
and a new day will dawn.
A stirring speech, General.
I only wish my daughter
were here to appreciate it.
Your Majesty, I know
how concerned you are about Bala.
But my scouts are on her trail
and it's only a matter of time before...
General, I don't want to discuss it.
Just find her.
I will, Your Highness.
Good-bye.
Seal up the doors.
Cutter, did you hear me?
Sir, I've been thinking.
Do we need to go through with this?
Look at what these workers have done.
They got the right stuff.
Isn't there any other way?
Cutter, you're a fine officer.
You have discipline, courage, ability.
But you seem to have a weakness for
the lower orders that I find disturbing.
Now, are you with me?
Sir.
I apologize.
Alright, then.
Seal it up.
Yes, sir.
As I look out
on this magnificent tunnel,
I am filled with pride.
Jump!
In these difficult times,
it is a great solace to know
that you, our workers...
Mom! Wait!
Every worker in the colony is here.
Hey, wait a minute.
That guy owes me money.
This tremendous accomplishment
is a testimony to the strength...
Put your backs into it!
Go warn your mother.
I gotta get to those diggers
before they break through.
There is not enough time.
Hey, leave the pessimism to me, ok?
Excuse me!
Sorry about that. Excuse me.
In a few moments when our expert diggers
break through to the surface,
Mom!
The sun will pour into this...
Mom, stop.
Bala! Where've you been?
Are you alright?
I'm fine.
What happened?
Mother, we're in terrible danger.
Put your backs into it, people.
Wait! Hold...
Hey, stop digging!
Z? Is that you?
We must stop!
Z! You're back!
Oh, Z!
Weaver!
Z!
What's the matter?
Ho.. Hol.. Hold up, everyone.
Stop. Stop digging.
On whose authority?
On your own authority.
If you break through that wall,
we're all gonna...
Drown.
This tunnel is going to flood.
So we've got to get
everyone out of here.
Look, I got orders,
and those orders say dig.
What if someone ordered you
to jump off a bridge?
Oh, brother, I'm asking
the wrong guy here.
Look, think for yourselves!
Give me that!
I've had enough out of you.
Get back to work.
What's that noise?
Let's get outta here!
Run!
Run! Keep going!
Everyone, listen to me.
We've all been deceived.
We need to calmly head toward the exits.
Run for your lives! It's gonna flood!
No. Don't panic.
Don't panic!
Every ant for himself!
All the exits are blocked!
We're trapped!
What are we going to do?
There is nothing we can do!
Yes, there is.
Weaver, give me a leg up.
Everyone, listen to me!
Who the heck are you?
He is Z!
He is Z. He is Z. He is Z.
Listen, we gotta help each other
get outta here, before we all drown.
How?
By making a ladder.
A ladder!
Hey.
If we built this, we can do anything.
Ok, let's move it!
I'm on it.
All of you, gather round.
You, start climbing.
Grab my arm.
Alright. Here I go.
Come on.
Go, go, go!
Right!
Excuse me, Your Majesty.
Z, I've gotta help my Mom.
Don't worry. I know almost
exactly what I'm doing.
I'll see you at the top.
Gentlemen, there comes a time,
in the evolution of a perfect colony,
when the strong are meant
to rise above the weak.
Now is that time.
Below us right now,
the weak elements of the colony,
are being washed away.
Oh, my God, we're not gonna make it!
We need more ants.
You two better get up there.
Weaver, you can't hold it alone.
Get going.
Hang in there, buddy.
Got it!
Hurry up! Go, go, go, go!
Our princess is secured,
and our glorious future is at hand.
We can all stand proud.
It is time for a new beginning.
What the hell is that?
I think that's the weak element, sir.
Give me. Give me a hand!
Z.
You!
Let go!
Don't you understand?
It's for the good of the colony.
What.. What are you saying?
We are the colony!
Cutter!
What are you doing?
Something I should've done,
a long time ago.
This is for the good of the colony, sir.
You useless, ungrateful maggot!
I am the colony!
Look out!
Z!
Men, let's move it!
Get these ants up here.
Keep it moving.
Thank goodness we made it.
Wait here.
Ok.
Thank you.
Weaver.
Where is Z?
Oh, no.
Back up, everybody, back up!
Give him some air. Back up.
Z.
Back up everybody.
Please wake up.
No!
You know Weaver,
you still owe me that dinner.
Babylove.
We made it, Z!
You da ant!
You did it.
We did it.
Fellas! Fellas, please!
This is very embarrassing for me, I...
On.. On the other hand I...
probably could, could get used to this.
There you have it.
Your average boy meets girl,
boy likes girl, boy changes
underlying social order story.
So, what else can I tell you?
We rebuilt the colony.
It's even better than before.
You know, because now it has
a very large indoor swimming pool.
Bala and I, incidentally,
are thinking of starting a family,
you know, just a few kids...
Maybe a million or two to begin with.
And I'm wor..
I'm working with a new therapist,
you know, terrific,
absolutely terrific he is.
He is been putting me in touch
with my inner maggot,
which is helping me a great deal.
And you know I finally feel
like I've found my place.
And you know what?
It's right back where I started.
But the difference is,
this time I chose it.