Mr. Jonathan lyte.
- Good day to you, Mr. Lyte.
- Good day, lapham.
I have a commission for you,
lapham.
Yes, sir.
Your servant, sir.
The teapot to this set
was ruined by a careless maid.
I value the piece
and wish to replace it,
but I must have it
by Monday next.
Monday, sir ?
It's a mighty short time
for such a fine piece.
It looks like one
of revere's best. Why
not take it to him, sir ?
Revere ? Look at the Mark.
You made that set yourself
more than 30 years ago.
So I did.
Oh, but Monday, sir.
I don't know.
It's a long time
since I've done
anything like this.
Very well then, I shall have
to take it to revere.
We can do it, Mr. Lyte.
My master's too modest.
You do not seem overburdened
in that direction.
Who are you ?
- Johnny tremain, sir.
- My apprentice.
Well, since you
allow him to speak for you,
on Monday morning then, early.
Yes, sir.
A fine commission, and you'd
have let it go out the door.
Beautiful, isn't it ?
And I made it.
I think I can do most
of it, sir.
A fine piece like this ?
And you not half through
your term.
Takes a tall man
to cast a great shadow, boy.
Put it away.
But I'm sure I can do it.
Heed holy writ,
proverbs 16:
"Pride goeth before
destruction, and a haughty
spirit before a fall."
I think I can
do anything, cilla.
Just about anything,
if I get the chance.
Well, grandpa's right
when the meek inherit the earth,
I doubt you'll get so much
as one square foot of sod,
Johnny tremain.
Oh, it's no use.
It looked all right
when it was cast, but now--
you think I don't know
what's wrong ?
God's will is playing.
Mr. Lyte will have
to find another Smith.
I'll go to Mr. Revere
in the morning.
He's helped me before,
and he'll know what's wrong.
You've let commissions
go by before when grandpa
didn't feel up to them.
Why are you so anxious
about this one, Johnny ?
Mr. Lyte's our landlord.
Isn't that reason enough ?
What's this ?
Oh, just a Mark
to sign my silver with
when I'm my own master.
Using Mr. Lyte's family crest ?
"J" for Johnny,
"t" for tremain.
What's the "l" for ?
It's a secret
I've never told anyone.
...and all's well !
You can tell me.
Promise on your hope of heaven,
you would never
tell anyone else ?
On my hope of heaven.
Well, my mother told me
my real name is
Jonathan lyte tremain.
"Jonathan lyte tremain" ?
You, a relative
of Mr. Lyte ?
What are you
to him ?
I don't know.
Mother wouldn't tell me.
Why ? Was she afraid
or ashamed ?
Proud, I think.
She was the proudest woman
in the world.
But apprenticing you
to grandpa,
and the lytes almost as rich
as John hancock himself.
She wanted me to learn my trade,
make my own way.
Are you crazy ?
A chance at a big house,
servants, coaches and your own
ship sailing the seven seas ?
I'd rather be my own master
and stand on my own feet.
Johnny, this isn't another one
of your tricks,
is it ?
Maybe you'll believe this.
This was my mother's
christening cup.
If I ever have
to go to Mr. Lyte,
I'm to show him this.
But she made me promise
I wouldn't go to him unless
god himself had forsaken me.
And I never will.
Fresh COD, mackerel.
Come in this morning, at the head of the ferry way.
I'm looking for Mr. Revere.
His shop's
down the street.
Yes, I know. His wife
told me I'd find him here.
He's busy.
I'll wait.
If you want to.
"Countrymen ! Ships laden
with English tea are now
bound for this port.
Shun the detested beverage
and let none be landed
on these shores" ?
What's this ?
The most important
piece of news in Boston.
Tea ?
But I like tea.
Almost everyone does.
The English ministry has already
collected a tax on this tea
and added it to the price.
Now if we let that stuff in,
every time we buy a pound of it,
we'll be paying a tax
we haven't voted.
That's why
to warn everyone of the truth.
- Who is "we" ?
- The sons of Liberty.
- But who are you ?
- Everyone in Boston
who believes...
Their liberties
are worth fighting for.
You can keep your politics.
I'll stick to my trade
and mind my own business.
- Rab, you finished yet ?
- Yes, uncle nat.
If they suit
Mr. Adams.
I'll look at them.
Johnny,
what are you doing here ?
I want to see you.
Oh, in a moment.
Yes, sir.
Excellent, rab.
Thank you, Mr. Adams.
Get them out
to your Liberty boys.
The sooner they're spread
through the town, the better.
I'll nail one
to the governor's door
myself.
Sometimes I wonder why
we trouble ourselves.
Liberty is for the young.
They have the spirit for it.
That's certain.
This lad seems to have
business with you, Paul.
We'll go on.
Good day, gentlemen.
Dr. Warren, Mr. Adams.
Seems everybody in Boston
is interested in tea.
Not tea, Johnny.
The principle behind it.
What is it this time ?
We've been commissioned
to replace the teapot
on a silver set.
I copied this handle
from the creamer
and enlarged it,
but it always
comes out wrong.
This is the work for a master,
not an apprentice.
Mr. Lapham feels
he's too old for such work.
We need the trade badly, sir.
The fault here
is not craftsmanship.
I've seldom seen better.
No, it's in your design.
Enlargement isn't enough.
Proportion has to be
taken into account too.
Now...
We make our curves deeper,
like this.
You see ?
Enough of work, lad.
Don't you hear
the bell ringing
for vespers ?
But I've almost
finished this pattern.
In another hour--
there are things
more important than
a rich man's silver.
The boy is only trying to do
what you can't do yourself.
God granted him a great gift,
but he must learn gratitude
and humbleness.
But grandpa, only an hour ?
It's time that god and his word
came first in this house.
We will begin
our sabbath tonight
as becomes humble people.
Begin with the 19th verse.
"And I will break the pride
of your power.
"And I will make
your heaven as iron
and your earth as brass.
"And your strength
shall be spent in vain...
"For your land shall not
yield or increase.
Neither shall the trees
of the land yield their fruits."
Pray god the Deacon's meeting
lasts extra long, so he won't
miss us from our pews.
We could get put in jail
for breaking the sabbath.
If we get caught.
Fetch a pail of water
so we can douse the fire
if anyone comes.
Then keep watch
down the street.
Hurry up, Johnny !
Yes, Mrs. Lapham.
- The constable's coming !
- Put it away, quickly !
We'll douse the fire.
Johnny !
Oh, Johnny !
Hey, it's you again.
Where you been ?
Around.
What happened
to your hand ?
I burned it.
What's the gun for ?
The tea I told you about,
it's in that ship.
And we're here to stop 'em
from landing it.
Oh, the tea again.
Good morning, sir.
A fine, large day, isn't it ?
That it is, lad.
Hmm, if you're
gonna carry one
of these things,
learn to carry it
right.
Yes, sir.
Who was that ?
Admiral montagu
of his majesty's Navy.
He's taken quarters
for himself over there,
but he can't land
the two companies of marines...
He's got in his flagship.
What do you mean
he can't land them ?
You wouldn't be hanging
around this tea ship
very long if he did.
That's just it.
Governor hutchinson
won't let him.
Half of Boston would turn out
in a minute if those marines
were landed against us.
Why don't you get your master
to give you some time off,
so you can take a turn with us.
My master's a silversmith,
not a troublemaker.
You could have rode
to Charleston for that
charcoal time you been gone.
There were others
ahead of me, and I had
to wait my turn.
Since when has Johnny tremain
taken to waitin' when there's
work to be done in this shop ?
- What's got into you, Johnny ?
- Let the boy be.
Everything in good time.
Oh, time. He's been
mopin' about for weeks.
- But, ma, his hand.
- Time we looked at that too.
Now, unwrap it, Johnny.
Did you hear me, boy ?
Move your fingers.
I can't.
It's no wonder.
They've all growed together.
I know.
Well, so, so that's it.
There'll be no more
following the trade for you.
Why, we're not bound
to his contract after this,
are we ?
Johnny's contract is with me.
Come here, boy.
I've said nothing about
the broken sabbath, Johnny.
God has sent you
enough punishment for that.
If you can't serve me,
you'll have to find other work.
But I want you to know that,
as long as I live,
there will be a place
in this house for you.
Not if I can't earn it.
Johnny ! Johnny.
Johnny, I don't want you
to go off like this.
- Good-bye, cilla.
- But at least stay
until you can find something.
You're a stubborn fool,
Johnny tremain !
"Sixteen hundredweight
of west indies molasses...
"To the order of
hitchbourne and company...
At Boston in the bay
of Massachusetts."
Good, boy. Very good.
Lads who can read
are hard to come by these days.
Now let me see a sample
of your pen.
Well, well, come on, boy.
I'm sorry, boy.
We could have used you.
You've sinew
on your bones, lad.
Enough to weather a voyage
in fine style.
We sail
on the Tuesday tide.
You'll give me a berth ?
Here's my hand on it.
I'm sorry, but who's going
to hire a boy with one hand...
When there are dozens
to be had with two ?
Wait here.
You can bill me for these
at the end of the month.
Yes, sir. Good day, sir.
By your leave, sir.
What is it ?
I wanted to talk to you, sir.
Oh, aren't you
old man lapham's apprentice ?
The young rascal
who ruined the silver
he was making for me ?
Yes, sir, I was.
But my name is
Jonathan lyte tremain.
So, Jonathan lyte tremain.
Well, get on with it.
There's more to it,
isn't there ?
Or shall I tell you
how it goes ?
Your dying mother told you
to come to me in adversity,
that you are my relative.
Isn't that it ?
Why, yes, but I didn't
realize you'd know.
What rich man
doesn't know that trick ?
It's one
of the oldest in the world
and one of the scariest.
But I have this to prove
what I say is true.
- Where'd you get that ?
- My mother gave it to me.
Gave it to you, eh ?
A long time ago, I suppose.
Yes, when she told me
about my name.
Quite so.
Bring that to my house
after supper tonight.
We'll discuss our relationship
in proper surroundings.
Drive on.
Thank you, sir.
What do you want, boy ?
I have an appointment
with Mr. Lyte.
Oh, master tremain !
Can I take your bag, sir ?
Right this way.
Master Jonathan lyte tremain.
Ah, come in, my boy. Come in.
My friend, Mr. Hooper.
Your servant.
That cup, boy.
You know, I think you've solved
the family mystery...
Of long standing,
master tremain.
I think we can agree that these
four cups are identical...
And of one set,
bearing the lyte family crest.
Mmm, it is obvious that
this fourth cup now stands
where it belongs.
There remains
only the question...
Of how it came
into master tremain's hands.
But I've already
told you that, sir.
My mother gave it to me.
Ah, yes, your mother.
Constable,
didn't I report
on August 10 last,
that a window was broken
in this room, and one of these
cups, carelessly left out,
was stolen
along with some other
trifles of silver ?
That you did, sir.
Well, we found our burglar,
constable. Take him away.
Come, boy.
Mr. Revere, rab,
how'd you know I was here ?
He's with us, Johnny.
Lets us know every time
he gets a new tenant.
Looks as though
Mr. Lyte intends
to make an example of you.
But don't worry, lad.
This is Mr. Josiah Quincy.
He's taking your case.
But I can't afford a lawyer,
let alone the best one
in Boston.
-Any innocent man can afford me.
-But I'm a nobody.
We're all nobodies
when we're standing alone.
It's what I tried
to tell you, Johnny.
It's when
we fight together
that counts.
And we happen to believe
that we must fight
just as fiercely...
Against small tyrannies
as against big ones.
So, Mr. Quincy is your lawyer.
And now then, Mr. Lyte,
having heard your testimony
and that of the defendant,
a few questions,
if you please.
Certainly, sir.
You state that
these cups were presents
from your father...
To each of his children
to commemorate their
christening.
Yes. As the sole survivor
of those children,
these cups have all come
into my hands in due course.
Quite so.
And each of your three
brothers has passed onto his
reward through the years,
leaving his goods
and chattels, including
these cups, to you.
But, sir, yours
is a very well-known family,
both here and in england,
and I'm under the impression
that your father...
Had five children,
rather than the four
you mentioned.
True. There was a sister,
lost under tragic circumstances
many years ago,
before any of us
came to America.
Is it not possible that this
boy's story could be true ?
Could he not be related to you ?
You say my name and family
are well-known !
Look at this beggar
from the streets,
and look at me, sir,
and let that be your answer.
Your eloquence is respected
by all, Mr. Quincy,
but I fear, sir,
that not even you
can alter fact.
That heirloom,
of little value in itself,
was plainly stolen...
For no other purpose than
to establish just such
a preposterous claim...
As that young ruffian
has proposed.
Your honor, the apprentices
and scavengers of Boston
get out of hand these days.
They roam the streets
in lawless bands,
roaring out treasonous songs
in the public squares...
And prating of Liberty
like drunken parliamentarians.
Loyal and lawful citizens
are at their mercy.
I suggest, sir, that these
sentiments have prejudiced you
against this unfortunate lad.
Most certainly not !
My reputation for fairness...
Is known throughout
this colony, sir.
I bear no ill will
towards my fellow man,
whatever his age or station.
But I have been robbed,
and the gallows...
Of this city have been
too long empty.
In the interest of justice,
I demand the death penalty !
That, fortunately,
is for the court to determine.
I thank you, sir.
Does that conclude your case,
Mr. Quincy ?
No. No, your honor.
May I remind you, sir, that
we have a full docket today.
I had hoped
to summon a witness...
On behalf of my client.
Out of the way.
Out of the way, sir.
There she is now.
- I call Priscilla lapham.
- Go on.
Do you swear by the living
god that the evidence you
shall tell this court...
Shall be the truth,
the whole truth
and nothing but the truth,
so help you
god ?
I do.
Miss lapham, have you ever
seen this cup before ?
Yes, sir.
Will you tell
the court where ?
In grandfather's shop.
And you know to whom
this cup belongs ?
Him. He showed it to me
the night he told me his true
name was Jonathan lyte tremain.
- When was that ?
- The fifth of July.
- Are you sure of the date ?
- I'll never forget it.
It was just two days
before he burned his hand.
And I submit, your honor,
more than a month...
Before Mr. Lyte says
his missing cup was stolen.
Thank you,
miss lapham.
Oh, just a moment, girl.
Do you know who I am ?
Yes, sir.
Good.
Now, isn't it a fact
that the accident
to which you refer...
Occurred while this young
felon was deliberately
breaking the law ?
He was breaking the sabbath,
if that's what you mean.
Precisely.
We all were,
except grandpa.
Because this unprincipled
boy urged you to it ?
No, sir. Because you'd
brought us an order...
That could have paid all
the back rent grandpa owes you.
Your honor, it is not I who
am prejudiced in this case.
This girl
is obviously in love
with the prisoner...
And is determined
to protect him.
I'm not
in love with Johnny tremain.
He's the most stiff-backed,
thickheaded, stubborn boy
in Boston.
And a lying thief !
That isn't so !
Don't argue with me !
Johnny may be everything
I said, your honor,
but he never told a lie
or did a dishonest thing
in his life.
I am not interested in
your opinions, young woman !
What I want to know is--
one moment, Mr. Lyte.
A tenant who dares
to testify against
her landlord has courage, sir,
and, in the opinion
of this court, no possible
motive but the truth.
This court finds no evidence
to support the charges
against this defendant.
Good day, Mr. Lyte.
Next case.
Thank you, cilla.
It was my duty,
Johnny tremain,
and don't get an idea
it was anything else.
Things look a little brighter ?
Thanks to you and Mr. Revere
and your other friends.
You've all helped me
so much, I'd like
to help you somehow.
That doesn't sound
like Johnny tremain.
- What do you mean ?
- What's happened
to the master Smith...
Who was gonna stand
on his own two feet and let
others stand on their own ?
The one who thought
freemen's rights
and people working together...
Was just a lot of things
that got argued about
by politicians ?
Guess I have learned a bit
about that, haven't I ?
But just the same, I wish
there was something I could do.
Matter of fact,
there is.
Come on. You can help me
with a chore across the street.
Who's goblin ?
Pump some water
in the trough.
I'll bring him out
to meet you.
- Like him, don't you ?
- Who wouldn't ?
He belong to you ?
To uncle nat.
Goblin.
That's a funny name.
He's a funny horse.
His imagination gets
the best of him now and then.
A rag, a paper, a bush.
He thinks they're all terrible
goblins. They eat horses.
I bet I can
make friends
with him.
You know, Johnny,
there is something
you could do...
If you could
only ride.
Why can't I ?
It only takes one hand
to hold the reins.
On goblin, even two hands
aren't enough.
I can do it,
can't I, boy ?
All right.
I'll get a saddle.
We'll see.
- Haven't you had enough ?
- Just a little bit longer.
I think he's beginning
to trust me.
All right, once more.
But that's all.
We've got to show him
this time, goblin.
Do this for me, and I won't
ever let anything happen to you.
No goblin's gonna get you
when you're with me.
Will he do ?
Yes, uncle nat.
We finally got
the horse boy we need.
Good.
I've run tomorrow's paper.
You better start folding it.
Yes, uncle nat.
Can I help ?
If you want to.
They still upstairs ?
They've adjourned.
Five hundred
and thirty-two
subscribers.
Biggest newspaper
in the whole Providence.
Rab, what's it all about ?
The latch on the door
and the people upstairs ?
I was waiting
for you to ask.
You know
what this is ?
It looks like
the Liberty tree.
It is.
It's our badge.
You see, the observer
is really the voice
of the sons of Liberty.
The committee meets
secretly here upstairs,
like tonight.
And sometimes part
of your job will be
to carry messages for them.
Who's the committee ?
The men who organized us.
The greatest patriots
in Boston.
Now, there isn't
any list.
Don't dare write it down
for fear it will fall
in the wrong hands.
So you'll have
to memorize the names.
You trust me ?
Any reason
why we shouldn't ?
Here they come.
Good night.
Good night,
Mr. Lorne.
Good night, doctor.
I'll let you gentlemen out.
Sam Adams, Dr. Warren,
Paul revere, Mr. Quincy;
You know them.
That's the reverend
Samuel Cooper and
his brother, William.
Martin brimmer,
Mr. Mollineaux,
Moses Gill,
Newman greenough,
Tom boyleston,
Oliver Wendell,
Joseph eayers,
Josiah flagg--
oh, Mr. Quincy, sir.
Yes, Johnny,
what is it ?
Mr. Lorne's compliments.
And you owe the Boston
observer six shillings.
Thank you.
Now, remember,
no work for a few days
until the swelling goes down.
Hello, Johnny.
Mr. Lorne's
compliments, sir.
And you owe the observer
six shillings.
Oh ?
Tell Mr. Lorne I'll attend
to it straight away.
Yes, sir.
Mr. Lorne's compliments.
And I owe the observer
six shillings.
Thank you, Johnny.
Mr. Adams just told me.
Yes, sir.
"You owe the observer
six shillings."
That means the committee
is meeting at 6:00, doesn't it ?
Maybe.
What do you suppose
the meeting's all about ?
Well, it could be to draft
a letter of apology
to the governor...
For interfering
in his affairs.
On the other hand,
there's a tea ship
at Griffin's wharf.
It will have been in harbor
20 days tomorrow.
And the law says,
after 20 days, any cargo
that hasn't been unloaded...
Must be seized
by the governor
and sold at auction.
They might want
to talk about that.
They've been talking
over an hour.
Probably dry enough
for some punch by now.
Very well.
May I take this
up for you, sir ?
Oh, I can manage.
Oh, I see. You've never
been up there, have you ?
No, sir.
Very well, Johnny.
Thank you, sir.
Gentlemen !
Gentlemen,
then we're all agreed.
The last detail...
As far as I'm concerned, doctor.
The one move they'll not
expect us to make.
Help yourselves,
gentlemen.
Take my word.
There's not a drop
of tea in it.
Oh, rab !
Have you warned your lads
we may need them ?
Yes, sir.
They're ready.
Good.
We're going from here
to a mass meeting at old south.
Thank you.
A last plea to ship the tea
back to england has been sent
to the governor.
His answer will come back
to me at the meeting.
If he refuses us again,
I'll give you the signal.
You'll know what to do then.
Yes, sir. But we'll be
outside the church.
If there's much of a crowd,
we won't be able to hear you.
There'll be a crowd,
all right. Johnny,
do you have
a whistle ?
I can get one, sir.
Good boy. You get over to old
south and get inside where you
can see me and hear me.
When the governor's
message comes,
if you hear me say,
"this meeting can do nothing
more to save the country,"
you get outside
and blow on that whistle
for all you're worth.
Understand ?
Yes, sir.
Gentlemen, a toast.
A toast to the hope that
is foremost in all our hearts:
A reasonable answer
from governor hutchinson.
We stand
upon moral grounds,
no less firm
than the rock-ribbed shores
of our own continent.
The rights of free englishmen,
wherever they may be.
And from this
unassailable vantage,
we must face the Gale.
I see the clouds which rise
thick and fast upon our horizon,
the thunder roll
and the lightning play.
And to that god
which rides the whirlwind...
Make way. Government business.
And directs the storm,
I commit my country.
We sure don't look
like no real Indians.
Not supposed to especially,
just so we don't look
like ourselves.
You can't recognize anybody,
you can't blame anybody.
Quiet ! Mr. Adams would speak.
Fellow citizens...
Governor hutchinson's
answer has arrived.
This meeting
can do nothing more...
To save the country.
Come on, lads !
7:00 on a fine night,
and all's well.
All is well tonight,
indeed.
But those seditious meddlers
who call themselves
the "sons of Liberty"...
Have given us a bad time
these past 20 days, admiral.
You know, I swear,
if I hadn't stiffened
the governor's resolution,
I believe he'd have shipped
that tea back to england.
What a misfortune
that would have been.
Allow me to offer you
a glass of port in
celebration of your victory.
Thank you. Yes,
the landing of that tea tomorrow
is a bit of a victory for me.
I daresay, Mr. Lyte.
Naturally, you'll buy it
in at the auction.
Naturally.
And at a vast profit.
Oh, I am a man
of business, sir.
But, believe me,
my real satisfaction is
in the utter defeat...
Of these radical demagogues
who have so long
corrupted Boston.
I'm convinced, admiral,
we shall hear no more prattle
of Liberty or the rights of man.
Remember your orders.
No damage to the ship,
no violence to the crew,
no harm to any cargo
but the tea.
It would seem, Mr. Lyte,
our celebration is
a trifle premature.
- To your task, gentlemen.
- Come on, lads.
Well, sir, aren't you
going to do something ?
What, for instance ?
Those ships out there are loaded
with his majesty's marines !
Bring them ashore !
I take my orders
from the governor.
Good evening, captain.
I must ask you
for your keys.
If you please, sir.
Excited, Johnny ?
This is a night I wish
I had two good hands.
You can.
I've told you before.
Anytime you'll come
to my surgery.
A few moments with a knife,
a few moments of pain,
your fingers
will be free.
We need good men, Johnny,
the best we can get.
Don't you realize, sir,
that tea is worth more than
two shillings a pound ?
And those chests weigh
near four hundredweight apiece !
A loss of more than
£40 sterling a chest !
As much as £18,000 value
for the whole cargo !
No doubt, Mr. Lyte.
But isn't it odd those
Indians seem to prefer
principle to profit.
"Shun the detested beverage
and let none...
Be landed
on these shores."
There goes
the last one.
That's it, lads.
There you are, sir.
All shipshape
in Bristol fashion.
And thank you, captain,
for the use of these.
*
Good night, admiral !
* plant the seed
in our homeland, boys *
* let it grow
where all can see *
* feed it
with our devotion, boys *
* call it the Liberty tree
* it's a tall, old tree
and a strong, old tree *
* and we are the sons
yes, we are the sons *
* the sons of Liberty
* save it from the storm, boys
* water down its roots
with tea *
* and the sun
will always shine *
* on the old Liberty tree
* it's a tall, old tree
and a strong, old tree *
* and we are the sons
yes, we are the sons *
* the sons of Liberty
* march along
with the fifer, boys *
* we were born
forever free *
* let's go pay the Piper, boys
beneath the Liberty tree *
* it's a tall, old tree
and a strong, old tree *
* and we are the sons
yes, we are the sons *
* the sons of Liberty
* pay the price
they're asking, boys *
* always pay
the tyrant's fee *
* never give up
the struggle, boys *
* fight for the Liberty tree
* it's a tall, old tree
and a strong, old tree *
* and we are the sons
yes, we are the sons *
* the sons of Liberty
* stand for the rights
of man, boy *
* stand against all tyranny
* hang the lamps
of freedom, boys *
* high on the Liberty tree
* it's a tall, old tree
and a strong, old tree *
* and we are the sons
yes, we are the sons *
* the sons of Liberty
* it will grow
as we grow, boys *
* it will be
as strong as we *
* we must cling
to our faith, boys *
* faith in the Liberty tree
* it's a tall, old tree
and a strong, old tree *
* and we are the sons
yes, we are the sons *
* the sons of Liberty
Hup, hup,
hup, two, three, four.
hup, two, three--
My name is Warren.
I have an appointment
with the governor.
Oh, yes, Dr. Warren.
General Gage is
expecting you, sir.
Dr. Warren, sir.
Oh, come in, doctor.
I trust my sending for you
was not an imposition.
Why, not at all, general.
Any service
at my command.
I have always held you
in great respect, sir.
And you will
believe my sincerity
when I tell you...
That the time has come
when we must have
an understanding.
-"We," general ?
-It has long been known to me...
That you are the most
influential voice...
In that body which you call
"the committee."
And now, doctor,
the fate of Boston lies
on this table between us.
I received today
this newspaper
from Portsmouth.
It contains an account
of lord chatham's speech
to the house of lords.
I wonder if
you have seen it ?
No, doctor.
You are an admirer
of lord chatham ?
What englishman is not ?
Lord chatham's speech
proposes an address
to the king...
With the demand that you
and your soldiers...
Be immediately withdrawn
from Boston.
I see.
May I take it, sir, that such
a decision would not be
entirely unwelcome to you ?
I have lived in these provinces
for too many years, sir,
to enjoy the responsibilities
which have now been
thrust upon me.
Chatham speaks here
of the ministry and the effects
of its colonial policy. He--
may I ?
"Resistance to your acts
was as necessary
as it was just,
"and your imperious
doctrines will be found
incompetent...
"To convince or enslave your
fellow subjects in America...
"Who feel that
tyranny is intolerable
to British subjects.
"All attempts to establish
despotism over such a mighty
continental nation...
"Must be vain,
must be fatal.
"We shall be forced,
ultimately, to retreat.
"Let us retreat
while we can,
not when we must."
Lord chatham is one
of the greatest statesmen
england has ever known.
But lord chatham
is not in office.
I am a soldier, sir,
and must take my orders
from the ministry in power.
Those orders are explicit.
I must not open this port
to any trade whatsoever...
Until the tea has been paid for
to the last shilling.
And I must stamp out vigorously
the least sign of resistance
to the ministry's policy.
In this connection, there are
certain things to which I can
no longer close my eyes:
The illegal bodies
of militia, for instance,
drilling on every village green.
They must be disbanded.
And I am also aware that
considerable stores of munitions
are being assembled.
They must be surrendered
at once.
That is why I sent for you.
I am sorry, general, but that
I do not have the power to do.
Why not ?
Because freemen will never
consent to give up the means
of defending their liberties.
Good day, doctor.
Good day, sir.
You realize, doctor,
this means that I must
enforce my orders.
I do, sir.
We have our duty.
We cannot deny you yours.
Ah, come in, my boy.
Come in.
Delightful weather
we're having.
Yes, sir.
This way.
Oh, see to it
we're not disturbed.
Well, sit down, my boy.
Sit down.
Johnny, I've decided
to go back to england.
Boston is no place
for a merchant now,
with the government
in the hands of the military,
the port closed,
trade at a standstill...
And more soldiers than civilians
in the streets.
It's a sorry situation,
isn't it ?
Yes, sir.
Why doesn't general Gage
take his redcoats home ?
But you don't understand.
Boston must first
accept responsibility
for the tea she destroyed.
Why ?
We didn't ask for the tea.
The ministry forced it on us.
That has nothing to do with it !
Do you know that
a group of loyal merchants,
myself amongst them,
offered to pay,
out of their own pockets,
the £18,000 in damages...
The ministry demands
for the tea ?
Yes, sir.
And do you know that
the political leaders
of Boston...
Have repeatedly refused
this generous and peaceable
solution...
To the plight
of the town and its people.
Yes, sir.
Well, can you sit there and tell
me that such leaders are working
in the public interest ?
- Yes, because we can't
give up our principles.
- "Principles" ? Ha !
What do beardless boys like you
or traitors like Sam Adams and
his kind know of principles ?
They're only trying to stir
the whole colony to defiance
of crown and ministry alike !
- No, they're not !
- Then what are they doing ?
They're defending our liberties,
and every freeborn englishman
has the right to do that.
Why are you parroting,
young popinjay ?
I didn't send for you
to hear the twopenny
political lecture !
Why did you send for me ?
To make you an offer I now
realize I would have regretted
for the rest of my life.
I've been at pains
to investigate your claim
of relationship to me.
I was willing to Grant
that you might, indeed,
be my dead sister's son.
I'd intended, in fact, to
take you to england with me...
And try and make
a gentleman of you.
You would have wasted
your time, sir.
I would never leave Boston.
I warn you, lad.
When the hangman comes
for your rebel friends,
there'll be no one
to whom you can turn.
Then I'll hang with them.
This cup means more to you
than it ever will to me.
Dr. Warren and Mr. Adams
and Mr. Revere...
Are upstairs
making plans right now.
I've sent for all of you
because they need help.
What can we do,
rab ?
They think general Gage
is going to make a move soon,
and they have to know
what he plans to do
before he does it.
That's where
you come in.
To watch
the general's headquarters
and the redcoats,
and to report everything
they do and say.
- What about you ?
- Some of us are old enough
to carry guns.
Captain Parker,
out in Lexington, is my cousin.
He wants us to come out
and join his minutemen
when the redcoats move.
Wait a minute. You're not
gonna leave me out of that.
There's plenty for you
to do here, Johnny.
You watch the redcoats
billeted on this street,
like the afric queen
across the way.
Dorcas,
you and the hitchbourne boys
watch the camps on the common.
Don't take it so hard, Johnny.
I'm glad you're not going
to Lexington.
I like it better
with you here.
I can carry
a gun as well as he can.
I've been thinking.
A lot of redcoats
are billeted
at the green dragon.
I can get a job
in the kitchen there...
And pick up
all sorts of things
while I'm serving them.
I don't want you hanging around
a lot of redcoats.
But that's what
we're supposed to do.
All of us.
I want you where
I can keep an eye on you
while you're watching them.
Colonel Smith
and his staff are quartered
at the afric queen.
That's a better place for you.
All right, Johnny.
The afric queen then.
You doddering old fool !
Three weeks is enough time
to make new campaign flasks
for the whole regiment.
All I wanted was
my old one repaired.
I'm sorry.
In a day or two--
oh, "in a day or two" !
I sail on the morning tide,
and I want my flask.
I beg your pardon, sir,
but has the port been
reopened...
So ships may sail from Boston
again ?
What business
is it of yours ?
I thought Mr. Lapham might
send your flask on after you
on another ship.
I go by military transport.
There'll be no other ships.
Maybe he can send it on
by me. I deliver newspapers
to most of the nearby towns.
I'd be glad--
you don't deliver newspapers
to Portsmouth, New Hampshire.
It worked !
Dr. Warren still here ?
Yes, what's up ?
I don't know.
Maybe nothing.
What's the matter, Johnny ?
The redcoats after you ?
No, sir, but I think
they're after something.
What do you mean, boy ?
Well, an officer just told
cilla and me he's sailing
to Portsmouth tomorrow.
It's hardly the move
we expected from Gage.
But a shrewd one, Sam.
Look here.
Portsmouth committee
reports a lot of crown
munitions...
Stored at fort William and Mary
there, and the Garrison
badly undermanned.
The committee thinks
the fort could be taken.
Apparently general Gage
thinks so too.
We could use
those arms and powder.
I'll be in Portsmouth
before the transport
clears Boston harbor.
Good evening,
Mr. Revere.
Not much traffic
these nights, eh, boys ?
Nor daytime either,
Mr. Revere.
It's a dead town.
That's a fact.
How about some cider...
To go with your rations ?
We've not forgot the last jug
you brought us, sir.
I've a cousin over
in Milton. Perhaps he can
spare one I can bring back.
A good ride to you.
There goes one provincial
who sits his horse
like a gentleman.
Aye, and always
as fast as he can go.
I reckon he's
the ridingest man
in Boston.
"After securing the keys
to the armory,
"the provincials
carried off 97 kegs of powder
and 110 stands of small arms.
Their whereabouts
are now unknown.
I have the honor to be--"
etc. "Henry green,
lieutenant commanding officer,
fort William and Mary."
The impudence of these
gawking yankee-doodles !
Their impudence does not
disturb me so much...
As the situation,
colonel Smith.
With arms and powder,
they can offer
a forcible resistance.
And they're certain to do so
if the ministry insists
on pressing them too far.
They've been storing munitions
in villages all around Boston.
In my opinion, sir,
we must confiscate these
contraband stores at once.
I quite agree,
but no blood has been shed
by my command thus far,
and I am determined
none shall be shed.
None will be, sir.
If I may have
a small, picked force--
say, a detachment of grenadier
and light infantry companies
from each regiment--
- I will undertake the matter.
- But if you meet
with resistance, sir ?
There'll be no resistance.
We're not dealing
with a professional army,
major pitcairn.
These are but farmers
and mechanics who spend
a few hours each week...
Playing at soldiers
on the green.
If we can move at night
with the utmost secrecy,
we'll be back in Boston
with their precious munitions
in our possession...
Before they can summon
a dozen of their men
from their beds.
Very well, colonel.
You may have your picked force.
And pray god we are right.
Put more back
into it, boy.
You'll never
get a shine to him
without your bared arm.
The colonel likes
his horseflesh, you know.
Not this old nag, he don't.
He hasn't had a saddle
on him all spring.
Well, he may any day.
And the beast's
got to be fit.
The colonel
always rides his parade horse.
A slipper for dancing,
a boot for mud.
So bear down
like I told you.
Thank you, lass.
Service has improved in this
rattrap since you came along.
Kind of you
to say it, sir.
Orders, sir,
with the general's
compliments.
Very well.
Confound it, lad ! You'll
never be a fit horse boy until
you learn the proper stroke !
Here, let me show you.
- Wait a minute, lass.
- Yes, sir ?
- Be a good girl and fetch this
to my quarters, will you ?
- With pleasure, sir.
Your back, lad !
Put your back into it !
Here, I'll show you.
Hello, Johnny.
Where is everybody ?
Most of them
have already left ?
I had to work late,
but it was worth it.
Some hot cider,
cilla ?
Thank you.
Look, a copy
of Gage's latest order.
- Is that all ?
- "All" ? Listen.
"All grenadier and light
infantry companies--"
"are detached for five days'
training in special evolution."
Most of the rest of us
have already brought in
the same thing.
- Oh, I see.
- Johnny !
Yes, sir.
We've decided to call a meeting
of the committee tonight.
The usual time ?
No, make it 9:00.
And, Johnny,
tell the members this may be
the last meeting for awhile.
We want them
all here.
Even Mr. Otis ?
Especially Mr. Otis,
if he's well enough to come.
Is that wise, doctor ?
His spells have been becoming
more violent lately.
Before that injury to his head,
James Otis was the most
brilliant mind among us, Sam.
He started the committee.
It's fitting he be here when
we end it. All right, Johnny.
Dr. Warren. This order,
it means the redcoats are
going to move, doesn't it ?
We think so.
Within the next five days.
Then isn't it time for us
to join captain Parker ?
What do you think, Sam ?
Every day that passes
will make it harder...
For men and boys
of military age
to get out of Boston.
Go ahead, rab...
And good luck.
Thank you, sir.
Come on, lads.
It's me, rab.
Oh, Dr. Warren.
Where's rab ?
He's gone on to Lexington.
- But without me ?
- You could hardly go, Johnny.
Surely you can see that.
I'd like to know
why not.
Well, let's say
I need you more here.
Is Mr. Otis coming ?
Yes, sir.
Good. You take over for me
and admit him when he gets here.
Yes, sir.
For ten long years, we've tried
to placate crown and
parliament,
and they've tried
to placate us.
The cry is peace.
Peace !
But there is no peace.
Oh, Mr. Otis,
good evening.
I tell you, gentlemen, there is
no longer any choice before us.
Good evening, boy.
The alternative
to everlasting slavery...
The others are waiting for you.
All except
Sammy Adams, eh ?
Is war.
But out of that shall come
such a country as was never
seen
on this earth before.
A free country.
For this we will fight.
Good evening, gentlemen.
Mr. Otis, this place
properly belongs to you.
Thank you,
doctor.
There you are, sir.
Now, Sammy, let's see.
You had got as far as
"for this we will fight."
I've not always agreed with you,
but you are right in that.
In all conscience,
Mr. Otis, this committee
cannot declare for war.
Determination to defend
our rights, yes.
Necessary preparations
to do so. But war ?
Only if war
is made against us.
A splendid resolve, doctor,
but it doesn't alter fact.
The fatal shot will come,
whoever is to pull
the trigger.
When it does,
then fight we must
and fight we will.
But for what ?
This is the thing
we must know,
that the whole world
must know.
For what do we fight ?
Tell me that.
To rid ourselves
of these infernal redcoats !
That's no reason
for blood on our land, Paul.
We've earned these redcoats.
We've shouted our treason...
In the press and the public
squares for ten long years
without hindrance.
And did ever an occupied city
receive better treatment
than we in Boston have had ?
Where are the firing squads,
the jails filled with political
prisoners ?
The gallows erected
for Paul revere ?
Samuel Cooper ?
Sammy Adams ?
And Joseph Warren ?
I hate the presence
of these troops of the ministry
as much as any of you,
but we are not going off
into a civil war...
Just to get them
out of Boston.
Tell me why then.
Why do we fight ?
To end tyrannous taxation.
Something more important
than our precious pocketbooks.
- But what is it ?
- The rights of englishmen.
Ah !
Now we have a glimmer.
It is prophetic that
it should shine brightest
in the eyes of youth.
Rights, yes.
But why stop with englishmen ?
Is the earth so small
there can be room
for only one people ?
Or can we here fight for men
and women all over the world ?
That
there should be no more tyranny,
that a few men cannot seize
power over thousands,
that wherever the sun shines,
a man shall choose
who shall rule over him.
The rights of englishmen,
you say, lad.
The battles we shall win
over the worst in england...
Will benefit the best in england
until the end of time.
Even as we shoot down
British soldiers,
we will be winning rights
their children shall enjoy.
And the peoples of the world--
the peasants of France
and the serfs of Russia--
shall see freedom rising
like a new sun in the west.
Those natural rights
god has given every man,
no matter how humble...
Or crazy.
They say my injury bashed
the wits from my head.
That's what you think,
isn't it, Sammy ?
Certainly not, sir.
Perhaps it's true.
Some of us
will give our wits.
Some will give
our property.
Let those of substance
among you think of that.
Gold and jewels
and fine, great houses.
Hurts, doesn't it ?
You, friend Paul--
god made you
to fashion silver,
not to make war.
There's a time
for casting silver
and a time for casting Cannon.
If that isn't in the writ,
it should be.
And you, Dr. Warren--
what use are the fine mind
and the skilled hands
of the surgeon...
When they have been
mangled in battle ?
Then others must do
what I no longer can.
And you who are so young--
some of you must die.
To die young
is more than dying.
It's to lose
so large a part of life.
My old friend, my old enemy,
how can I call you ?
Even you will give
the best you have:
A genius
for politics.
And we need you, Sammy,
for we must fight this war...
In meetinghouse and congress
and the halls of parliament
as well as on the field.
But what it's all about,
you'll really never know.
And yet it is
so much simpler
than any of you think.
We give all we have,
we fight, we die...
For a simple thing:
Only that a man can stand.
You write as good a hand
as ever, don't you, lad ?
Yes, doctor.
Thanks to you.
Address this to Mr. Adams
and Mr. Hancock at Lexington.
Good morning, Paul.
What's afoot ?
Good morning, doctor.
Oh, they're as busy
as red ants all over town.
No sign of a march yet.
The transports
in the harbor...
Are sending all their boats
way down here along the common.
Maybe they intend to row
the troops across to Cambridge.
Those boats
may be a trick.
General Gage won't need them
if he marches his troops
out across the neck.
What route do you intend taking
with our message
when the time comes ?
By way of Charleston. I have
a boat hidden at mill cove.
Good.
Billy dawes has volunteered
to try to get past
the guard post at the neck.
- One of you should get through.
- What if they don't ?
We've one messenger
they can't stop, Johnny:
The spire of Christ's church.
It can be seen
from the Charleston shore.
Friends there will be watching
for the lanterns in the belfry
tower when the redcoats march.
One if by land,
two if by sea.
Johnny, this may be
important.
The colonel was making
a to-do with Caleb
over a saddle...
When that orderly
came looking for him.
I heard the orderly say,
"the general's
compliments, sir."
Let's see if Caleb's
heard anything else.
Hello, Caleb.
That fat-bellied,
redcoat colonel.
What happened ?
When he told me he wanted
his saddle shined,
how'd I know he only
used that one for show
around town...
And he wanted this one
for some country riding
tonight ?
"Country riding" ?
We'll help you, Caleb,
but you've got to remember
everything the colonel said.
Be a lot more help if you get
old Sandy out and look him over.
I gotta have him ready too.
He's too old for much of a ride.
That's what
I told the colonel.
He said he'd be better off
tonight on a horse he can trust.
Sandy will last the 17 miles
they have to go, all right.
Hand me that rag,
cilla.
I thought you were gonna help !
*
it's tonight, all right.
They're beating to arms
in every square.
It should be Concord.
We have much
of our powder there.
But 17 mile--
wait a minute.
Johnny.
Yes, sir ?
You've ridden most of the roads
for the observer.
Suppose they did use
their boats and began
their march at Cambridge ?
How far would it be
to Concord then ?
That'd make it 17 miles.
That's it.
Priscilla, do you think you can
get to Mr. Revere's house ?
Yes, doctor.
Tell him they're marching
on Concord.
He'll have to leave
at once.
Yes, sir.
Warn him they've moved
the somers up
off barton's point.
He'll have to cross
under her guns.
Yes, sir.
Johnny, I want you
to go to Mr. Robert Newman,
the sexton at Christ's church.
You'll likely find him
somewhere about the church.
Tell him too.
He'll understand.
Yes, sir.
You, boy.
What are you about ?
I'm on my way home, sir.
Time to get home
after we've gone.
Over here
with the others.
After him !
Are you
Mr. Newman ?
Yes, lad.
- Dr. Warren sent me.
- Down this Lane, men !
How many lanterns ?
Two.
I saw you
two-thirds across.
I knew
it could be no other boat.
Not this night, Paul.
Thank heavens the watch aboard
the somers didn't have
your eyes, Mr. Larkin.
I see you brought
the horse.
How do the redcoats go, Paul ?
And where ?
There's your answer.
To Concord by sea.
Thank Mrs. Larkin
for the use of the horse.
Turn out !
Turn out your militia !
What's all the noise
down there ?
The redcoats are coming !
- Johnny ?
- Oh, it's you.
Johnny,
where are you going ?
Lexington.
But there may be
fighting there.
I know.
Oh, be reasonable for once,
Johnny tremain.
You don't even have a gun.
I'll get one.
And if you did, you wouldn't
know how to shoot it.
I'll learn then.
You'll get yourself killed.
Not if I can help it.
Bye, cilla.
Halt ! Halt !
Pull up there !
How can you eat
at a time like this ?
It was a long night,
and I'm hungry.
Where's Mr. Revere ?
He went to the Clark house
to warn Mr. Adams
and Mr. Hancock to clear out.
But where are the redcoats ?
That's what I want to know.
Ought to be along
any minute.
Major pitcairn anyway.
He's commanding ?
The advance party.
He was when I passed them.
Colonel Smith was back
with the main body.
What do you suppose
the advance party's for ?
Probably to clear us
out of here, so the rest
can get through to Concord.
*
all right, lads,
take your places.
Fall in.
*
what are you doing here ?
Same thing you are.
You haven't got a musket.
That's why
I'm standing behind you.
So the redcoats won't notice.
Turn around.
*
Let everyone of you
remember your orders.
You are not to fire
unless fired upon.
We stand upon our rights,
not upon the force of arms.
Do not molest them
unless they begin it first.
*
column... halt !
No man will fire
except on my order !
Is that clear ?
No man will fire
without order !
Take care to display column
to the left !
- March !
- *
*
To the left !
Wheel !
We'll stand by our orders.
But if they mean
to have a war,
then let it begin here.
*
halt !
Front !
Are they gonna fire on us ?
I don't think so.
Just trying to scare us.
To the left !
Wheel !
*
halt !
lay down your arms !
Disperse, you rebels !
Why don't you disperse ?
Come on !
Hold your fire !
Get back to your ranks !
- Get back to your ranks !
Hold your fire. Get back.
Return to your ranks.
Get in here.
Who fired that shot, sir ?
The first one.
One of them, one of us,
someone in one of those houses
over there.
I don't know.
What difference
does it make now ?
*
There they are.
Where are we bound ?
North bridge.
They're tearing it down.
Does it mean fighting ?
We can't let them cut us off
from Concord, can we ?
- Fall in !
- *
*
you'd better get out of this.
I'm gonna get one of those
redcoat muskets.
Fire a warning shot.
Shoulder, firelock !
Make ready !
Present !
Fire !
Fire ho !
Return to your ranks !
- Hold your ranks, men !
- Hold your ranks !
We've got 'em on the run !
Let's keep 'em running
all the way back to Boston !
*
After them !
First platoon, right !
Fire at will !
*
After them !
History holds
no parallel to it, sir.
An untrained,
undisciplined rabble,
turning an orderly retreat
into a rout in spite
of anything we could do.
They fired on us
from every tree and dunghill
the whole way back.
But never once did we
have an enemy with whom
we could close.
You see those campfires,
gentlemen ?
Yesterday we ruled over Boston.
Tonight we are besieged in it.
And still they come
from every village and farm.
Tonight, 10,000.
Tomorrow, perhaps twice 10,000.
We've experienced
more than a defeat,
more than a mere
misfortune of war.
We have been vanquished
by an idea, a belief
in human rights.
Johnny !
Oh, Johnny.
Cill...
How'd you get here ?
Are you badly hurt ?
Me ? Hurt ?
I'm tired, that's all.
Been chasin'
redcoats all day.
And I thought
you were--
that's all right, cill.
Hey, you two,
give me a hand.
Johnny,
I'm so glad it's over.
Over ? Nothing is over.
It's only a beginning,
a kindling of the flame.
Feed it, lads...
As you fed it
with your blood today.
It is the spark of Liberty
that you've touched afire,
and its light must grow
until every dark corner
has vanished...
And it illuminates
the world.
* it's a tall, old tree
* and a strong, old tree
* and we are the sons
yes, we are the sons *
* the sons of Liberty