How go the honors, Henry?
Rack upon ruin.
The way these tricky
Frenchmen overmatch us,
they must have sold
their souls to the devil,
and that one's
the very devil himself!
Oh ho, brother, so
you've changed your tune.
Yesterday, you'd sell
your sister to the French.
Only to get you
a royal husband.
And don't brother and sister
me at a time like this!
Look you, ye beef-eating,
muscle-bound, flat-footed bunglers.
How dare you
call yourselves Englishmen!
Is there no one here who can throw
me that arrogant Frenchman? Well?
I would try,
your grace.
Who is that fellow? A newcomer, my lord,
late returned
from our foreign wars.
What do you know of him? His name
is Brandon. He's a gentleman, sire,
though without title. Title
be hanged! Can he wrestle?
That I know not.
Hmm.
Why not call upon my lord of Buckingham?
He could humble the Frenchman.
That is, if he'd
hazard his finery.
With pleasure,
my lady.
We thank you,
Master Brandon.
But first the Duke of
Buckingham will try a fall.
'Tis catch as catch can, milord,
so watch out for his feet.
He broke Courtney's
neck with 'em.
Allez, Jacques!
Allez!
Watch his feet!
Hooray!
Bravo, Buckingham!
Bully boy, Ned!
'Tis well you chose
the Duke. Well, indeed.
I doubt if the newcomer could
have won for you. So do I.
And yet, I wonder how he
would fare against Buckingham.
My lord Duke. Would
you care to challenge...
Master Brandon
to a fall?
If it please
your grace.
Henry, you must
stop it.
But it's heathen cruel. It
was you who first proposed it.
You wanted to see a
Christian thrown to the lion.
Come on, milord!
Well done, fellow! You're a
credit to England. Get up, Ned.
When you've recovered from your
beating, I'll trounce you at cards.
Your Christian bore
himself right manfully.
He'd make a handsome captain
of the guard. No doubt he would,
but were I to make him such,
you'd drive him from the court.
Why so?
'Cause I like him, and if I liked
him not, you'd fall in love with him.
If you think me
so perverse,
why don't you try hating
old King Louis of France?
Very well, then,
I'll decise him.
Then I'll hate him too.
You scheming little wench! But
you'll marry him nonetheless,
and I already have
guardsmen aplenty.
Will I ever learn not to
match wits with our king?
Brandon,
can this be you?
By Jove, you do make a
handsome captain of the guard.
I, I feel more like
a pouter pigeon.
Nay. You're a brave adornment
to the house of Tudor.
An honor I did not seek. My mind
was set on fortune in the new world.
I merely wished to visit our English
court until a ship came in at Bristol.
Why go a-chasing
halfway across the world?
Dame fortune's
an unpredictable wench.
She may be waiting
for you here.
She may well have
passed me by,
deeming me naught but
a monkey in a red coat.
Dame fortune
always knows a soldier.
The queen is less perceptive.
It seems her highness
mistakes me for an elder page.
She's charged me to deliver a
message to the Princess Mary.
Well, that's
no unpleasant duty.
I pray you
help me find her.
The princess is with her
ladies in the lower garden.
Thank you, sir.
And, Brandon...
Don't fall in love with her.
I didn't leave
my wits abroad.
Ah, but you haven't met
my Lady Mary.
Oh? Will I be blinded
at the sight of her?
Most men are.
Thank you, sir.
But have no fear. We
guardsmen never look above us.
Ah!
Oh!
Behold.
Ladies.
Have I the honor to find
the Princess Mary among you?
Is the Princess Mary a person
of so little consequence...
That she is not known to a
mighty captain of the guard?
Pray forgive a blundering
stranger of the court.
Since Princess Mary
is reputed to be gracious,
I presume
she cannot be here.
Oh!
I am
the Princess Mary.
If you have a message,
captain, deliver it.
Will your ladyship inform the
princess that her highness the queen...
Awaits her coming
in the estate chamber.
Oh! Ooh!
Insolent fellow!
There's impertinence!
Grating guardsman! He
should be put in the stocks!
I have never seen the like. Nor have I.
He acted like a man.
Oh!
Was that fellow
being troublesome?
No, milord, he did but bring
a message from the queen.
What does that Spanish
woman want of you?
I do not know, but as I am
compelled to do her bidding,
the game goes
to you by default.
I'd not win that way. There's
only one game I would win from you.
Oh, pray you, sir,
no more wooing.
You waste
your eloquence.
Very well,
milady.
Since eloquence is
denied me, I'll use logic.
Would you prefer
King Louis for a husband?
So you would win
by default.
'Tis no
laughing matter.
I have no fear
of Henry.
Nor would it be the first time
he's tried to trade me off.
It may be
the last.
The king has already sent his lord
chancellor to France to conclude a treaty.
You're to be part
of the bargain.
And you would dare to
oppose the king in this?
Milady, as lord high
constable of England,
I am master
of the tower,
and he who commands the
Tower, commands London.
And maybe
the kingdom?
Dangerous words for the
proud, Plantagenet duke.
I pray you do not voice
such thoughts to Henry.
I do not covet Henry's
throne, nor would I cross him.
But if it would serve your
need, I'd risk my head.
Dear, kind Buckingham,
I wish I could say yes.
But since my heart won't let me,
will you still remain my friend?
I will.
Good morrow,
Sister Kate.
When the Princess Mary
addresses me in public,
could she not find a term
of greater deference?
I paid your highness
the compliment...
Of calling you
my brother's wife.
I shall not presume upon the
intimacy again. Thank you.
And did your grace command
me here to tell me this?
I am concerned about
your may day ball. Oh?
It has come to my attention
that Sir Anthony Denny,
Sir Thomas Lovell,
Griffith and others...
Have as yet received
no invitation.
True, your highness.
And why not?
I have not as yet
made out the list.
But now that the royal
favorites have been singled out,
I will give their names
my careful consideration.
May it please
the queen's grace.
Sir Edwin?
Good Sir Edwin, will our
master of the revels...
Prepare a list of
invitations for my ball?
I will, milady.
The usual selection?
A new face or two might
make a pleasing diversion.
A real break
with tradition, milady.
Say a captain
of the guard...
To add
a martial flavor?
I doubt if the rowdy
fellow knows how to dance.
I'll wager ten crowns
he can. Strike on it.
Supposing we settle it tonight.
If you brought him privately,
we could try out his step
in my drawing room.
Excellent, milady.
In matters of this kind,
it's always best...
To observe the fellow
at close range.
¶
I'm the richer
by ten crowns.
Will the princess forgive
my rudeness as a messenger?
It's I
who was wrong.
You could not have known me. I knew you.
Then I think you're
a very bold man.
And a very
good dancer.
Milady spoke too soon. I
have half forgotten the step.
Had you no time
between wars...
For dancing with the French
and Spanish ladies? On occasion.
But hardly
"la galliard. "
What did they dance? Why,
nothing but "la volta. "
Oh, then I must learn it.
What shall the tune be?
Can you play
a Coranto?
Oh, it's much
too difficult for me.
Let me try it.
¶
Sir! Boldness has its
bounds! I beg your pardon?
Would you turn our dancing
floor into a wrestling paddock?
On the contrary,
milady.
"La volta" has found favor
among ladies and gentlemen...
Of both the French
and Spanish courts.
But is that really
the way you dance it,
with your arm around her
- their waist?
I should not have dared to have ventured
upon such a familiarity otherwise.
Did you say
the French court?
Then as master of the revels,
I should see more of this dance.
If the princess would be so
indulgent, might not the Lady Margaret?
Milady has
no objection?
None whatever.
¶
Oh!
Sir Edwin?
Do you think me a prude? Nay, indeed.
Oh, it's just
like flying!
Whoo!
You're here as a guardsman?
As a gentleman.
Then I must ask you
to leave as a gentleman.
This is not
a common revel.
Did you hear me,
fellow?
Milord, you should know better than
to draw your sword in the palace.
As captain of the guard, I've a
mind to clap you in the gatehouse.
My lord duke!
Master Brandon did not
thrust his way in here...
But came at the personal
invitation of the princess.
Pray excuse us.
It is well you took him by surprise.
The duke's the deadliest
swordsman in the kingdom.
The Italian dueling masters
taught me a trick or two.
Room, room, room,
for the king's grace!
Ahh!
Is the princess ready
to choose her partner...
For the honor
of the opening dance?
¶
Well, sir?
Henry!
Bid the music cease!
Are the musicians
weary?
I ordered
the music stopped.
We cannot permit such
an indecent exhibition.
If your highness does not like
the way we do and dance at my ball,
you may retire
as soon as you see fit.
Will the king permit
me to be insulted thus?
I told you
she had sharp claws.
Shall I not have what music and
dances I like at my own ball?
That you shall,
sister mine!
Come, let the music
knock it!
We'll learn the step ourselves and
wear you ladies out at dancing too.
¶
Masterly.
Perfection itself,
your grace.
Master Brandon taught you
this dance, didn't he?
Yes, Brother. For mirth and
play, that fellow has no equal.
Pity he's only
a commoner.
¶
No.
You've done more than
your share today, my beauty.
She has flown enough. 'Tis
time we tried the crossbow.
Now we'll see who's been obeying
my edict to practice archery.
Ready your bows.
You too, Brandon.
Set in the dogs.
Ho, ho, ho!
Well aimed, your grace! Fine shot, sir.
Bravo! Well done, Brandon!
I was but following
the royal example.
You ride ahead.
Go on.
Master Brandon!
I fear the girth
is loose.
'Tis tight as the horse
can well bear.
It's loose, I say.
I'm afraid
you were right.
Help me down.
The way you scowl, I marvel that
you came to my rescue at all.
'Tis a guardsman's duty to
watch over the royal princess.
A duty you've been
neglecting of late.
The king has kept us
busied with the hunt.
The while our summer beauties
are left to wither and die.
Did you never gather
a nosegay for a lady?
Then it's time you did.
'Tis my royal command.
And while you're about it, I'd
have you compose me a sonnet.
A sonnet?
I would not dare.
Can this be the bold
Charles Brandon?
Were I
a better poet,
and you, perchance, a burgher's
daughter, I might be tempted.
Pretend I am
a burgher's daughter.
Oh, please, sir,
will you try?
By royal command?
And sovereign decree.
O Mary mine, if thou wert
a burgher's daughter -
O Mary mine, wert thou
Go on.
a burgher's daughter,
yet thy fair self
in every other way,
I'd take thee with me
o'er the perilous water...
To the new world,
where none could say us nay.
O Mary mine,
sole mistress of my heart,
fair jeweled star
set in the heaven above,
thou art a princess
in a world apart,
of castles, diadems,
and of courtly love
beyond my dreams,
for kings
will give thee gold,
and princes bring thee
gems from distant lands.
The only wealth
that I may ever hold...
Are these fair flowers
for thy maiden hands.
Yet fragrant they'll remain,
and richly green,
if they're remembered
by a golden queen.
Oh, Charles.
How can you be so cruel?
In order
to be kind.
Is it kind to throw my
royal station in my face?
I must not forget it, milady.
I would, if you would let me.
Help me, Charles.
Milady,
I beg of you.
Am I a statue
on a pedestal?
Milady!
The hunt has reached the
castle. You will be missed.
Ned!
What think you if I were to bestow
knighthood upon Charles Brandon?
A man of parts and quite
deserving, no doubt.
No doubt
at all.
If you did bestow knighthood
upon Charles Brandon,
I'm sure the Princess
Mary would be overjoyed.
What?
Fiddle-faddle. That's
the general epidemic...
As far as
she's concerned.
Every man at court's
been struck.
But has the Lady Mary herself
ever been smitten before?
No, by Lucifer, she
hasn't. Your highness.
My lord chancellor and the
ambassadors from France...
Beg audience
with your grace.
Send them in.
King Louis must have
come to terms.
That's the physician
to cure my little sister.
"O Mary mine, sole mistress of my heart
-"
How does it go, Charles?
The part about the star?
Oh, I've forgotten,
milady.
Then you shall make me another
verse tomorrow. Au revoir.
Good-bye, milady.
My name is Mary.
Princess Mary.
Good-bye.
And, in conclusion,
your grace,
Would signalize
the alliance...
And guarantee everlasting peace and
amity between England and France...
By taking unto himself
in marriage...
The king's own sister,
the Princess Mary Tudor.
It likes us well,
this loving offer...
From our dear brother
of France.
And how much English gold does
he want to sweeten the bargain?
My most gracious master wishes it
understood that the matter of dowry...
Is of secondary
importance.
The person of the princess, seen by
him only on this painted medallion,
bespeaks a maiden of so mild
and gentle a nature...
That our king already
anticipates a love match.
Then you'll forego
the dowry?
Not quite,
your grace.
The sum of... Half a million
crowns has been proposed.
Half a million?
Odd's death! Why doesn't that old
usurer ask me to melt down my crown!
Give me leave,
good friends of France.
A word with
my counsel first.
My lords, I'm no
huckster and no haggler.
Let's offer old goat face half of what
he asks and see if he'll accept it.
I bargained with Louis for days, sire.
400,000 is the very
least they will consider.
Even so, they wish the world to
believe the sum a half a million.
Let the world think the sum a billion,
so be it we save a fifth of the gold.
I propose you raise the
full 500,000 crowns. What?
Give them
their 400,000,
and put the odd 100,000 in your
own private coffers, my king.
Ah! Well hit, my lord chancellor.
What say you,
Ned?
Our English citizens might
prefer to see their princess...
Wedded to an English lord.
Whose sister is she?
Theirs or mine?
By my faith, Ned,
I'm all amazement.
Would you deny me
a paltry 100,000 crowns?
Nay, not so, sir!
Then you shall raise
the money.
Our citizens of London
will listen to you.
Me, milord King? Aye. Take it up
with the mayor and corporation.
They'll kick like mules at such a tax.
Why did I make you
my lord high constable?
If they refuse, clap 'em in the
tower; that'll make 'em disgorge.
And the lesser rogues
will follow their example.
'Tis settled, sir.
Wolsey will disclose the
final terms of the agreement.
Merci, sire.
And now, if I may
wait upon the princess,
I have gifts
from my royal master.
Poor though they be, they will
serve to exhibit his love and esteem.
Sir John! Go to the Princess
Mary and bring her to us straight.
Thank you. Meg, I may as well tell
you that I am mightily displeased.
A princess is not entitled
to much privacy, I know,
but certain things cannot be shared
with a prying, meddlesome Abigail.
I quite understand,
milady.
When a princess stoops
to pursue a commoner,
she must, indeed,
want privacy.
But what about
the commoner?
Would you put his neck in jeopardy
for the sake of a springtime dalliance?
Dalliance? I pray it is no more.
And what
if it is?
Then God defend you both.
Yes?
With license
of your highness,
the king commands you
to the royal presence.
The French ambassador
would offer his devoir.
Inform the king that I
am not disposed to come.
I will convey
your apologies to his grace -
No apologies. Just say
that I will not come!
Milady, you were born
to marry royalty.
The king will see
that you do.
It's time that you all
understood that Mary Tudor...
Will marry a beggar
if she chooses.
Y- your grace,
my liege.
The princess wishes me to convey
- Come, Sirrah, speak up.
She says
she will not come.
What?
Is this an answer?
Am I to be flouted under my own
roof? Defied by this titmouse?
Oh!
Odd's thunder! If she'll not
wait upon us, we'll wait upon her!
Where is she?
Milady is indisposed.
Mary!
Yes?
Come forth and receive
the ambassadors of France!
I command you!
Do you hear?
Yes, Brother dear. Are you coming?
No,
Brother dear.
Well met,
Brother.
Come in, gentlemen.
I will arise at once...
And receive you all
informally.
Cover yourself,
hussy!
Oh, nay, Brother. When the
king commands, I must obey.
Milady!
What a captain-general that jolt-head
would have made had she only been a man.
My lord king?
Huh?
A word with you
alone, sire.
Hmm!
We must forgive the Lady Mary, milords.
The sudden shock
of great events...
Has quite disordered the delicate
maiden balance of her mind.
Let us to our palace
at Greenwich...
And leave the princess
to the quiet of Windsor.
I can assure you that
when next we see her,
she will have remembered the
manifold gifts and kindnesses...
She has received
from an indulgent brother...
And the duty she owes
our royal person!
Come, let's to
Greenwich straight!
As soon as they've departed,
send word to Charles Brandon.
Tell him to meet me
in the library presently.
Milady, I beg you not to
continue in this madness.
The king will have his way in
the end. Not if I make haste.
Mary
- milady. If you won't serve me, find me a page.
You know I will
do your bidding.
Your highness.
Where is
Charles Brandon?
He resigned his place at
court and is off to Bristol,
there to take ship
for the new world.
Without a word
of good-bye?
And I thought his mention
of the new world mere poetry.
It was a decision he could
not have made lightly, milady.
Well met, Sister.
Go to her,
De Longueville.
Permit me,
most gracious princess,
that I may have the honor,
on behalf of King Louis,
to offer this
little testament...
Of his admiration
and love.
This is my answer,
sir.
Go home and tell
your silly old master...
That it is thus
I regard his suit!
Let me pass!
By the soul of my father
and holy church,
you'll marry Louis of
France within a fortnight,
or I'll have you whipped to
death on Smithfield pillory!
To horse!
There you are,
captain.
Thank you,
sir.
You'll find your quarters
of the very best, sir.
Now, if you'll just whistle up
a good westerly wind...
Come 50 days, I'll have you
in the new world.
If we get the breeze, when do
we sail? On the first tide, sir.
We'll send a boat ashore
for you all in good time.
There's no hurrying
the tide.
I'll warrant you a good five hours
before yon ship weighs anchor.
Be at your ease now, sir,
and drink your morning beaver.
Charles!
Lady Mary!
Are you alone,
my lady?
You must be mad! A
princess cannot run away.
How many hours of grace
do you think you'll have...
Before the king's officers
catch up with you?
No one saw me leave. And long
before I can be apprehended,
you and I will be on
our way to the new world.
It's out
of the question.
How can you say that?
Perhaps you do not feel
about me as I do about you.
I wish it were
as simple as that,
but the fates
are against us.
As yet no sailing master will permit a
woman on so long and perilous a voyage.
All that I know.
But any gentleman may
take his page along.
You'd hazard this
for me?
Your breeches are too
short. Untruss your points.
Now let's
see you walk.
Don't
overdo it.
That's better.
Now you must not smile.
You're far too beautiful
when you smile.
Oh, Charles!
Now scowl. That ship's master's no fool.
Here, boy,
my sword.
Now fall in
behind me.
Ahoy, maintop!
Clear off
the arm!
Haul away!
Here you are,
sir.
Now there's
courtesy for you.
Or is that what passes for
shore manners these days? Sir?
Are you wont to let your page
elbow you out of the doorway, sir?
No, by thunder!
Pardon, Master.
I forgot myself.
Very well, but I'll cuff you
if you do it again!
Does he suspect? No, but I'll feel
safer once we're out of Bristol Harbor.
Of course, he must never
know that you're a princess.
I think we may
count on THIS:
Should he discover that you're
a woman once we're out to sea,
he'll come to terms
rather than put back.
Very well, then. I'll not show
my face outside this cabin.
Weigh anchor!
Aye, aye, sir!
Oh, let me do it. I
must learn. Anchor away!
We're moving.
¶ Heave Away, Boys ¶
Oh, Charles!
Indistinct singing ]
Captain's respects, sir. All hands on
deck to drink a round to the voyage.
I'll do the honors
for both of us.
Rouse out,
ye lubbers!
Here's your
wine, sir.
Where's your page,
Master Brandon?
All must drink, sir. We'll
have no Jonahs aboard.
The poor lad's under
the weather. Sick, is he?
Well, sick or not,
let's have him out here.
I'll
fetch him.
A pint of wine will do him
more good than a drench.
Fill another bowl.
And a drink
for you, sir.
Now then,
bon aventure!
Bon aventure!
Caps
overboard!
Hooray!
Hold there, young fellow! Would you slight
an old custom and put a hex upon our voyage?
Come, lad. You're no
better than your master!
Chuck
your hat over!
Bilge and bedlam!
'Tis a wench!
A pretty lad.
Set the sails aback! Pull up
the long boat! Aye, aye, sir.
So you'd sail under
false colors, would you?
Why, with a woman
aboard my ship,
we'd be at the bottom
of Davy Jones' locker
before we're halfway
down the Channel.
Here's your passage money.
Put them ashore!
Charles
Brandon?
I arrest you in the king's
name for high treason.
I am charged to convey you
to the Tower of London.
Your royal highness will accompany
me to the royal palace at Greenwich.
A private word with
Master Brandon first.
Do not despair, Charles. You
will not languish in the Tower.
So long as I live,
my thoughts will be of you.
I know
my brother Henry.
Once he's shouted himself hoarse,
he will be reasonable enough.
Good-bye,
dear Mary.
You and I will be
together within a week,
or my name
is not Mary Tudor.
Nor can it be
otherwise...
Until I add
the name of Brandon.
My lord cardinal, good
morning. And to you, Ned.
God save your grace.
My liege, I thank you.
What's
your business?
The matter of Charles Brandon.
That traitor!
Since the abduction of a princess
is an act of high treason,
a warrant has been drawn
up for his execution. Hmm.
Hmm.
Your grace, her highness Princess
Mary has arrived and begs an audience.
She does, does she?
Tell the wanton, shameless drab
she needn't show her face to me!
Hold!
Have her in.
We'll receive her.
I hope I find
you well, brother.
Well enough.
I see
you're blooming.
Nothing like a sea voyage to
put a glow in a maiden's cheek.
Brother, what I have to say
would be better said in private.
I've no secrets
from my counselors.
Well? I am here not on my own behalf,
but to speak for
Charles Brandon.
His arrest
is unjustified.
No doubt of it.
A mere matter of high treason,
causing trouble between
England and France.
And compromising the king's
sister as a common jade!
He did nothing
of the kind.
You may accuse me of
indiscretion, but nothing more.
Thanks to
Charles Brandon.
Hmm? When you attend
the rites tomorrow,
do not fail to convey our
gratitude to Master Brandon.
Do you intend to stretch
his neck or shorten him?
A prisoner of such consequence deserves
the dignity of the ceremonial ax.
He does indeed!
You mean,
he must suffer death?
It's the usual result when the
head is separated from the body.
If there is any guilt,
it is mine.
Charles Brandon did not offer
to take me to the new world.
I forced myself
upon him.
If you are determined to
punish someone, punish me.
Your pleading comes too late.
The warrant's signed.
Please, my brother.
Spare him, and I will
do anything you ask.
Will you marry
Louis of France?
Yes...
Even that.
I wonder, your grace,
if it would be wise? Eh?
Might she not endanger our treaty
being at best an unwilling wife.
Our relations with France
are in delicate balance.
Dare we run the risk
of further insults...
Flung in the faces of those
we would embrace as friends?
My liege, if I may
make so bold.
'Tis said that when the Lady
April mates with December,
she is looking forward
to a warm July.
So, my lord, with the
Princess Mary. Louis is old.
'Twill be a world's wonder
if he lasts a 12-month.
Now, might not the lady behave
more dutifully in France,
if the choice of a second
husband could be her own?
Well and good!
You have our promise!
Anyone I may
choose?
Even the devil
himself...
So be it you hurl no coronets
while Louis lives.
And now will my dear, kind brother
let an innocent man out of the tower?
No. We will release the prisoner
when you've proven yourself a queen.
But one more trick, even an interchange
of letters between you and that fellow -
Inform the French ambassador
the marriage can go forward.
And now, if you please,
milord.
Bless you,
my daughter.
Thank you...
With all my heart.
I have but one
CONSOLATION:
And since I cannot
go to him,
will you tell him of
my bargain with the king?
I will.
My truest friend.
And most devoted.
¶
My lords, today we have added
to our fleur-de-lis...
This loveliest
English rose.
Ye noble knights, come.
Pledge with me your love.
The queen of France!
¶
Cousin Francois, since my
queen is a stranger among us,
a pleasant labor
falls to your lot.
As dauphin and my heir,
I appoint you and the
Princess Claude, your wife,
as guides and governors in all
matters that should concern...
A queen of France.
You shall find me ever
willing, sovereign lady.
You are quiet, Mary,
and you neither eat nor drink.
This kingdom of France
quite overwhelms me.
So it must,
my love.
But soon I will take you away
from all these staring faces...
Where we'll
be alone together.
Not so, majesty, our guests
have come to honor us.
If I seem to mope,
do not indulge me...
But rather show me
my duty.
Show them your duty.
Me, your love.
Sire, as your physician,
I beg of you...
That in consideration
of your delicate health -
Listen!
Old pills and plasters!
'Twas I got married today,
not you!
Hmph!
Sovereign lady,
red wine of Burgundy...
Serves the need of our
most beautiful queen.
Thank you.
Milady, please
accept another one.
Merely to watch such loveliness
waste her warm lips...
Upon the cold glass
has quite intoxicated me.
Pray keep your compliments for
she who has a right to them.
Who would live by candlelight
once he has seen the sun?
Avert the eyes!
I fear, your highness, that
under the circumstances,
I must be in personal
attendance upon His Majesty...
Throughout
the entire night.
I quite understand.
So your lordship has finally
condescended to pay me a visit.
What has prompted this
extraordinary honor?
A promise I made to Her Royal
Majesty, the queen of France,
she that was
Mary Tudor...
And is now the bride
of King Louis XII.
You find that hard
to believe?
I do.
What boundless simplicity.
Are you dolt enough to imagine
that because a princess...
Had a last fling with you
that she'd marry a commoner?
Oh, she wept,
I'll admit.
And before she accepted
the crown of France...
And the jewels
and the silken gowns,
she had an hour's remorse
over you.
In fact, she wrung a promise from me since
she could not move the king on your behalf.
It was her wish, no doubt
to still her conscience,
that you be allowed to pursue your
interrupted journey to the new world.
Most thoughtful of her. And you'll
take it on yourself to release me?
Not openly, no.
I dare not risk
the king's displeasure,
however much I may desire to
oblige the exalted queen of France.
But an escape
might be arranged.
Is the king ready? His Majesty
is now being elevated, your grace.
I love these early
hours in the park.
And the late ones in the
ballroom, dancing the night away.
The hours fleet so swiftly
when I am dancing with my king.
I like this gay life too.
I have never felt younger.
But when will we
be alone together?
We are alone
together now.
Well... Yes.
But always in sight
of others.
Others? I can see no others
when I'm with my king.
Have I ever told you how... Gallant
and commanding you look astride a horse.
How dashing!
Allons!
A moi.
Allez, venez.
Ammenez tout
de suite le roi.
At last I have caught up
with the queen of my heart.
Your queen prefers
to ride with her king.
Impossible.
Be not dismayed, Madame. Life
will not always pass you by.
One day you will have
a real king for your husband.
Never! Nor are you
worthy to be king.
Worthy or no,
you will soon make me one.
Each morning I think, "She will put
an end to that weak old man today. "
Tout passe,
tout lasse, tout casse.
And why,
as you English say,
the pace that kills.
Is he greatly exhausted?
Worse than that.
His condition gives me cause
for the deepest concern.
I did not realize how...
Very frail he is.
I pray you, Madame, it would
be malavise to disturb him now.
I will keep
you informed.
Margaret, I want you to go
on a mission to England.
At once.
Arrange for Sir Edwin to accompany
you. And leave you here alone?
King Louis is dying,
Margaret.
He may not
last the day out.
When he is gone, you know
what lies in store for me.
Dispatch you now
to London in all haste.
Seek out my trusted friend the
Duke of Buckingham at the Tower.
Milady has kept the terms
of her agreement.
She would have
her brother keep his.
Now that the French marriage
has ended,
she begs you to exert your
influence with King Henry.
Urge him to release Charles
Brandon from the tower...
And send him
straight to France.
Would that I might.
Milord?
Charles Brandon attempted a foolish
escape and was killed by the guards.
His body lies
at the bottom of the Thames.
Poor, hapless man.
And milady,
my poor dear Mary.
What will become
of her now?
We must seek the king
without delay. You cannot.
His grace is in
the north country.
Every moment increases
the danger for Mary.
Francois will scarce be crowned
before he forces himself upon her.
Then I myself shall go
to France at once.
Tell Henry when he returns
his sister's plight was such...
That I took it upon myself
to serve as his ambassador.
Me master.
Would you be Sir Edwin Caskoden? I am.
It's been a main hard
task searching you out, sir,
among the highroads and byroads
and little small lanes of London.
Day after day I watched and
asked and waited for you...
'Til I fair forget me gainful
occupation of selling Coster apples.
Thank you, sir,
and God bless you, sir.
Do you know where the man who
wrote this letter is lodged?
Lodged is the
grand word indeed.
Me pigs lie better
than that poor gentleman.
Can you take us to him?
I can, sir.
Though the sight of so a
fine lady on bankside might...
Draw attention as you might say
where 'twould better go unnoticed.
I'll go on to Greenwich
and await you there.
I pray
it is true.
Your Majesty, his grace,
the Duke of Buckingham.
My counselors inform me that my dear
brother of England wants his sister back.
He does, your majesty. And I
want her to remain here in France.
I shall make her
my queen.
But what of Your Majesty's
present wife?
The kingdom comes first.
Indeed my mind is so set upon
an alliance with England...
That I must
harrow my heart...
And set aside
my dear wife, Claude.
I know my master, sire. Henry
of England will never agree.
I know him too.
How vexed he was at the exorbitant sum
he sent to France for Mary Tudor's dowry.
But I would ease his mind
and gladden his heart.
Already I have dispatched my ambassador
to restore the full sum to his royal coffer
in lieu
of his fair sister.
Has the Lady Mary
been told of this?
The matter does not
concern her as yet.
I would speak with her. Milord,
you waste your time.
I have my orders.
My coach leaves Paris at noon.
I expect Mary Tudor
to be in it.
Even though you take her home,
Henry will send her back to me.
That's for Henry
to decide.
Tres bien.
L'audience est terminee.
Depars!
My dear, dear friend,
again you have rescued me.
Was there ever another
such as you?
And now tell me
what I want to know.
What would you hear first?
About Charles Brandon, of course.
What is it?
Would the king not
let him leave the Tower?
He left it,
but in the dead of night.
The guards,
knowing only that he was
an escaping prisoner -
Why did he do it?
My dear, he was
a most adventurous man.
So restless
a spirit...
Could never be
imprisoned.
There she is, flying
Buckingham's flag.
They're awaiting his return.
We could waylay him on the
road from Paris to Calais.
I'd rather seek him out
than wait an ambush.
Where are we? The
little church at Wimille.
You almost slept
the clock 'round.
While they're changing horses,
you shall have some refreshment.
I could not eat.
You must. Come, Father Pierre
is noted for his hospitality.
Il faut bien manger pour
affronter les crises de la vie.
Life should seem better
on a fine morning like this.
And you've a long life
ahead of you, Mary.
Are you strong enough
to face another dilemma,
almost as intolerable
as the first?
I'll face it better
in England.
You may not remain in England
unless we solve it now.
It wasn't easy to free you
from King Francis.
He let you go only because he's
certain to have you back. Never.
He's already sent to Henry
the full amount of the dowry
you brought Louis.
With it he hopes
to buy you for himself.
Henry will refuse it.
400,000 crowns?
And all for his
private coffers.
He promised me my choice
of a second husband.
You heard him.
'Twas you who proposed it.
Thank God I did.
You and I shall hold him
to that promise.
We've only to step into that little
church and Father Pierre will marry us.
Then you need fear no king
on either side of the water.
No one can take the place
of Charles Brandon.
I will not be demanding.
I will respect your grief.
Then remain my friend.
Please do not talk
of love again... Ever.
Don't touch me! You were less
squeamish with Charles Brandon.
Am I so low and loathsome? The blood
of Plantagenet kings flows in my veins,
you brat
of a Welsh farmer.
You'll have me, madam, or I'll take
you straightway back to King Francis.
Charles!
The foremost knight and first
swordsman of England...
Forgot that killing
never thrives by proxy.
Mary, you start ahead
with Sir Edwin.
Will you let me draw?
Did you let me?
I do not cross swords
save with an equal.
But I would make you
the exception.
Thank you, milord duke. Once I've seen
milady safe, I shall accept with pleasure.
Milord!
Come on!
Hurry!
They've got Her Highness
with 'em! Come on, lads.
Hold them off until
I get Mary aboard the lugger.
Have at them!
They say in Italy it is not all brawn
and hewing that makes a swordsman,
but the parry and thrust.
You need two hands
for this game.
I've the weapon for him,
sir, if you'll say the word.
Stand back.
Ain't you going to do
for him, sir?
I could not be
so merciful.
Mary!
Your grace.
Oh, Henry!
Dear, dear Henry!
If you knew what it was
like to be home again!
Come, come now.
Pardon my emotion,
Brother.
It's just the sight of
your good English face.
Ah, enough of this! You've
no cause for such display!
No cause!
Do you know what I've suffered
at the court of France?
The vile insults
I've endured...
From that licentious dauphin
now puffed up into a king?
You could not dream of the contempt
in which he holds your royal person...
Nor his palpable scorn
of our island kingdom...
Headed by
the prince of usurers.
How now, milord, think you to bribe the
king of England like some house lackey...
Or common scullion?
Permit me, sovereign lady,
I do but bear a gift of treasure
from His Majesty King Francis,
who begs of you to make him
your husband.
I already
have a husband.
Brandon!
I thought you were dead.
A false impression created by the
Duke of Buckingham, your highness.
Buckingham?
Where is Buckingham?
Your grace, I know
something of this matter.
Sir Edwin bears witness that the duke
of Buckingham paid the assassin...
And dares not show
his face in England.
We'll deal with him hereafter. With
you, Charles Brandon, now. Come here, sir
how dare you marry into the
royal house without our consent?
It was with
your consent, my king.
I had your plighted word given
before our eminent cardinal...
That I might choose a second
time as my heart led me.
Only forgive my widow's sensibility that
shunned the royal pomp and public show...
Attendant on a second wedding
and chose instead...
A simple service
at a quiet church in Dover.
You modest violet.
You shrinking,
blushful daisy.
Pray take the gold away
and tell your wicked master...
That the king of England
is not yet so mean...
That he would sell
his sister into slavery.
Mary!
Forgive my lady wife, sire, if sometimes
she is forward and forgets herself.
The gold is not yours to accept
or refuse. 'Twas given to the king.
Forgive her too for her unseemly words
against the generous king of France,
who, out of his largess, has sent your
royal person this pledge of his affection.
Should you not consider it, sire,
like the Lady Mary herself...
As a loan repaid?
Monsieur,
il faut consulter.
Hands off!
Rather than be thought churlish or
ungentle, we will accept the gold.
Convey to our dear brother of
France our heartfelt thanks!
We cry you mercy. Here
we recovered our sister...
And gained
a newfound brother.
And now we would
be alone.
Charles, we owe you much.
What do you want?
I have all I want.
I haven't.
He'd make a handsome
duke of Suffolk. Hmm?
Eh? Yes!
I'll make him duke of Suffolk!
Thank you,
Brother.
No!
I earned that money.
It was given to me!
Eh, Charles?
The title alone
will not feed us.
Very well, I'll give you 20 manors
and their rents to gild the title.
Brother, my own dear -
No!
No more! The dukedom and
20 manors on one condition!
That you take this plaguey, conniving little
baggage down to Suffolk and keep her there!
If she remains at court,
she'll wheedle my ears from me!
And, Charles,
beat her thrice a day.
Ha-ha-ha!
And now, sir,
how dare you take me to task
in front of the entire court?
I love you.