Glass of double rum.
Aah. This here is a quiet cove.
Much company, mate?
Not much, sir.
- Who'd be the owner?
- My mother.
- Where is your mother?
- In the town.
Hmm.
- What's your name?
- Jim Hawkins.
Well, Jim, you seems a likely lad.
Ever notice a seafaring man
alongside this here grogshop?
Not many come out so far, sir.
None by the name
of Captain William Bones?
Bones, sir?
No matter. Fill her up.
Jim!
- Was it a one-legged man?
- No, sir.
But he had a terrible scar.
Black Dog!
When you sees Black Dog, you lay to it.
The man with the one leg ain't far off.
Rum, Jim. Fetch me rum.
I can't, Captain. I promised Dr. Livesy.
Oh, hang all doctors! Give me rum!
No, Captain!
Please, Captain Bones.
Doctor said it'd kill you!
If you don't stop,
I'll run to town for the Doctor.
And the Squire, too.
Got to get me strength back, Jim.
Got to pull out of here.
Now, then, boy,
take me to Captain Billy Bones,
or I'll break your arm.
Straight to him, now. March!
Here's a friend for you, Bill.
- It's Pew.
- Pew as ever was, Bill.
Back with a gift
from all your old shipmates.
Boy, take him by the wrist
and bring his hand close to mine.
And now that's done.
The black spot.
They come at dark.
I know what they're after,
but they won't get it out of me.
What's rightful mine is mine!
Give me a hand, Jim.
We'll do that one-legged man yet!
Captain!
The old hulk's grounded, Jim.
Can't shove off.
Go and bring help.
And don't peach,
and I'll go shares.
If them muttonheads
that slipped me the black spot
gets here before you come back,
they won't find that on me.
Skip, now.
Luck, matey!
Rouse out, mates!
Horses coming! Run for it!
Here, sir.
Well, Livesy?
Did his doomsday. But he wasn't killed.
He died of shock, or rum.
I wonder what those rascals
wanted of him.
I think I can tell you, Squire Trelawney.
Now he's dead, I can.
Odds, my life!
Doctor!
Flint's map.
How did you come by it, lad?
Why, he gave it to me, sir,
when he sent me for help.
- He said I'd share.
- Share what?
You don't know? Pirate treasure, man!
Flint's gold! Why, everybody knows
of the ships Flint plundered.
That fellow must've been the only one
who knew where the treasure was hid.
So that's what
those scoundrels wanted.
The map of Flint's Treasure Island!
Latitude, longitude,
crosses to mark the deposits.
Money to roll in!
You're a trump, young Hawkins.
Mark my words, you will share.
Spy Glass Hill bearing south-southeast,
to Finger Trunk Tree by Devil's Rock.
Thence two cables south...
- Go on, go on!
- Bear to larboard,
due northeast to foot of White Crag,
10 paces east...
Chest of £700,000!
My servants, Livesy.
Come in, Tom Redruth!
Come in, Williams!
They got away, sir.
They had a lugger
tied up at Kitt's Hole, sir.
Aye, you gave them a run for it, boys.
They'll not be back.
Thank you, Tom Redruth.
Thank you.
Thank you, sir.
Shh.
Mum's the word.
We'll take Redruth and Williams along.
Make sailors of them.
We'll have favorable winds,
a quick passage,
and gold enough
to play duck and drake
with ever after, hey, Hawkins?
If you weren't so confounded
exclamatory, Trelawney,
we might understand you better.
Just what is it you propose to do?
Do? Fit out a ship! That's what I'll do!
With a clue like this, by Christopher,
we'll have Flint's treasure
if it takes a year!
Can't you feel the deck under your feet,
and a good trade wind filling our sails?
How preposterous. A doctor
can't go chasing across the world
and leave his practice behind him.
Hang your practice. I'm your practice.
Do you think I'd put to sea
without a ship's doctor?
Besides, it's a risky business.
We aren't the only ones
who know of Flint's map.
Those fellows who ransacked
this inn tonight are desperate men.
Surely, you don't fear them, Livesy?
No. There's only one man I'm afraid of.
Name the dog.
You, sir.
For you can't hold your tongue.
Why, confound you, Doctor.
I'm no tittle-tattle.
An adventure of this kind,
I'd be silent as the grave.
Now, then, Hawkey.
Tomorrow, I start for Bristol
to find a ship.
Once you settle your affairs here,
you and Jim can follow.
- Jim?
- Aye, Hawkins. You'll come.
You'll make
a famous cabin boy, Hawkins!
His mother may have
something to say about that.
She'd listen to you, sir,
if she knew you were going.
Until I've made up my own mind,
I don't know what I could tell her.
Tell her that in three weeks' time...
Three weeks? Two weeks! Ten days!
Jim Hawkins will be sailing
with the choicest crew
and the finest
ship's doctor in all England.
Will you, sir?
To be sure he will, boy!
I'll wager my wig on it.
Dr. Livesy! Dr. Livesy!
Look, Doctor. It's Squire Trelawney!
Admiral Trelawney, at least.
Livesy. Ahoy!
Ahoy!
And Jim.
How did you two find the journey?
Abominable roads.
The sea's the only
high road for an Englishman.
Come here.
There she rides, Livesy.
The good ship Hispaniola.
- Beautiful, Trelawney! Beautiful!
- Stout, too.
She'll bring back all the pirate gold
that we can put aboard her!
Shh. No talk of treasure
in a public place. I beg of you.
Aye, mum's the word.
Jim?
Well, Jim, don't you want to eat, lad?
If there's time before we sail, sir.
- Sail.
- When do we sail?
Better ask Captain Smollett.
Five days he's been selecting a crew.
- Six men are all he's got to show for it.
- Cautious, eh?
"Cautious"?
He pries through every seaman's past
like a judge at a quarter session.
When I threatened to step in,
he told me to hire a sea cook.
So, by Jove, I did hire a sea cook,
right out of his own tavern.
Fellow by the name of Long John Silver.
I didn't waste my time
poring over his credentials.
All the credentials I needed was a taste
of his ham and his buttered eggs.
You can judge for yourself.
- Top of the mornin', gentlemen.
- Ahoy, John Silver.
Sit ye down,
the tables are starving, if ye kindly will.
For you, sir, piping hot.
And this be for Dr. Livesy.
Asking his pardon
for being that familiar,
but Squire has told me
so much about the two of ye,
it comes natural
to call ye by name, it do.
And this will be young Master Hawkins,
I'll be bound.
Hawkins.
'Tis a proper seafaring name, too.
You run your house well, my man,
and you keep a good table, too.
Thank ye kindly, sir.
It isn't often I see fruit
in an English tavern for breakfast.
'Tis a rule of health I learned while
sailing under the immortal Hawke.
- Ah. Rest him.
- Did you hear that?
Him, sailing under Hawke!
I was with him
in '59 at Quiberon Bay.
When you shipped with the Admiral,
you never took scurvy
from the salt pork and hardtack.
Not with a barrel of apples aboard
for the men to chew on.
There's sense in that, Trelawney.
Something we could profit by.
And will, by gad.
There'll be apples on my ship, too.
You favor the Admiral yourself,
Squire, if I may say so.
Why, you and he could make up
your mind like that!
- Do I now?
- That ye do, sir. I noticed it afore.
It wouldn't surprise me none
to hear you say,
"Heave up the anchor.
We sails on the hour."
Can't sail without a crew.
With all the hemming
and hawing that goes on,
you'd think there wasn't
an honest seaman to be had in Bristol.
I begs to differ, sir,
if I may make so bold.
Why, there's a full cargo
of my old shipmates
that sailed with Hawke
becarrmed right here in Bristol.
Sound men inside,
if some of them was scarred
in the service of England.
And they with no pensions, neither.
Could a score of those foremost hands
be had on short notice?
Aye, sir, but they wouldn't be
pretty enough for the modern taste.
Nowadays, they picks the younger men
by the cut of their jib.
Not the old ones for their experience.
Appearances be hanged!
Silver, get me those men.
But it ain't a cook's place
to muster no hands.
That's captain's work.
It's an owner's place, by the hokey.
If you can bring in a crew of your
stouthearted lads come sundown,
I, for one, will be greatly obliged.
- Well, sir, if 'tis owner's orders...
- Bully boy.
But I don't like to be pushing
athwart my betters, but I'll say this, sir,
I know every seaman in these
here parts like the palm of this hand.
Did you know Captain Billy Bones?
Bones?
Billy Bones?
What ship did he sail in, matey?
He was a pirate.
Lord love ye, lad.
Didn't you know that them that
sailed with Admiral Hawke
had no speaking
acquaintance with pirates?
Lessen they boarded us.
Aye, Jim,
you're the spitting image
of me when I was your age.
Head full of pirates.
But he'll find, same as I,
that the sea be mostly hard work.
And the biggest satisfaction
a man gets is doing his duty.
Quite right, eh, Jim?
Come, Livesy. Shall we go aboard?
But I just thought
if he knew Billy Bones...
'Course you did. Of course he did.
Beggin' your pardon, Squire.
Could ye spare me the lad today?
I've more than my hands full
putting the inn shipshape
and rounding up a crew.
Sound idea.
You stay and lend him a hand, Jim.
- But, sir...
- Don't fail me, Silver. Livesy.
Come now, Jim, lad. Time be wasting.
Down there, matey.
Pieces of eight!
Pieces of eight! Pieces of eight!
Who hailed you, you old bumboat?
Belay!
Belay! Belay!
Ain't you the pretty one?
Swearing blue fire
in front of a gentleman.
Living up to her name, she be.
Captain Flint, I calls her,
after the famous buccaneer.
'Twas the pirates taught her to swear.
Now, if you want to know about pirates,
just you ask Captain Flint.
Why she can...
Well, blow me down for an old sea calf.
"Do you know any pirates?" says you.
"Not on speaking terms," says I.
Yet, here, under my nose,
is Captain Flint.
I'll wager you can't make her talk.
Pirates, Captain Flint! Pirates!
Pieces of eight! Hello, boy. Hello.
You're a smart one, Jim.
Smart as paint you are!
'Tain't everyone can make that bird talk.
Hey there!
Glass of double rum.
Black Dog! Stop him!
Stop him!
Cady. Run, catch him!
No. Not him. Him!
- Who did you say he was?
- Black Dog.
He was one of the...
He was one of the pirates.
One of them swabs? After him, all of ye!
Run him down!
And if you don't catch him,
don't you come back!
What was he doing here,
I'd like to know.
Sharks like him,
they'll give my house a bad name.
What would the new landlord say?
Why, he'd never set foot
in the place again.
Now, would he?
Black Dog, eh? I'll black dog him.
I never thought the day'd come
I'd need this pistol
against them cutthroats.
Heavy ball and a light charge of powder
works best on a touchy
little craft like this, here.
Try the balance?
See the engraving on the trigger guard?
Solid silver.
Butler of London made that there
sidearm for Admiral Hawke.
And the Admiral,
he give it to me for loyal service
aboard the old Portland.
Do ye think you could shoot one?
- Oh! Yes, sir.
- All right, then.
You are a smart one.
I might've known
you could handle a firearm.
Now, put it in your pocket
and keep it there at half cock.
But don't go waving it in the face of
every man who asks for a glass of stout.
- Oh, no, Mr. Silver.
- But if you clamps your dead lights
on that there Black Dog again,
repel boarders.
- I know, sir.
- And I knows a lad I can trust
while I'm out doing my duty by Squire.
And when I come back,
I'll have a crew and you'll have a pistol.
- You mean to keep?
- That's my meaning, matey.
You've got the word
of Long John Silver.
- Shipmates.
Boat alongside, sir.
Step lively there. Get a move on.
- Get up. Get up with us.
- Ahoy!
Line up there.
All hands muster aft.
Long John Silver,
reporting as ordered, sir.
- I see you did it, Silver.
- Like I said, Mr. Trelawney,
they ain't pretty,
but they knows the sea.
Picked up Hawke's old helmsman,
we did.
And a boatswain what
pipes man-o'-war fashions.
- Splendid, Silver. Splendid!
- Heave to!
Captain.
Well, Captain, here's your crew.
Would you care
to have a word with them?
- Mr. Arrow?
- Yes, sir.
Record the names and sailing records
of every man jack on board
for entry into the log.
- And check your watches.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Step forward, there. Step lively.
And now, sir, I'd like to have a word
with you in the cabin, if I may.
And you, Doctor.
Fetch your gear and take it below.
Captain Smollett,
here's to our speedy departure.
Thank you, sir.
Well, I have something on my mind,
and at the risk of giving offense,
I'd better speak plain.
I don't like this cruise
and I don't like the men.
Possibly, sir, you may not like
your employer, either.
Stay a bit, Trelawney. No need for ill
feeling till we hear the captain out.
I don't like secret voyages,
Mr. Trelawney,
when the only secret kept
is the one in my sealed orders.
Everybody else
about the town is saying
that we're headed for a treasure island
with a marked map to guide us.
Someone's been talking.
Well, I never breathed a word.
Livesy, have you?
In my experience, adventure
of this kind may mean life and death,
and a close run.
We may need a trustworthy crew.
Not one recruited by the ship's cook.
That ship's cook was acting
under my orders, sir!
Well, is the cook responsible
for the ship's safety?
Well, really! I...
We're all concerned
with the ship's safety, Captain.
As matters stand,
what measures would you propose?
Two. The whereabouts
of any treasure maps
to be kept strictly secret
from myself and my mate, Mr. Arrow.
The firearms removed from
the forward hold and stored aft, here.
Surely you don't anticipate mutiny?
If I did, I wouldn't put to sea at all.
The garrison arrangement's
a sensible precaution.
That's fair enough, Trelawney.
Very well. If it'll get us out to sea.
- Agreed then, sir.
- Good.
Now, Captain.
You will find I'll do my duty.
Hang it, Livesy.
Why'd you take the fellow's part?
Because I think our captain's
a very conscientious man.
I find his conduct un-English.
Downright un-English.
Weigh anchor, Mr. Arrow.
All hands on deck! Man the windlass!
Fall the topsail!
Anchors aweigh, sir!
Aloft there! Overhaul the buntline!
Well, Captain, what do you
say about our crew now?
Oh, they're seamen of sorts, sir.
A shade better than Lord Mayor's men,
and no worse than dock-wallopers
brought aboard by the press-gang.
- Mr. Arrow, brace your foreyard!
- Aye, aye, sir.
Lee fore brace!
Avast!
- Mr. Arrow.
- Concealed weapon, sir.
Bring that man aft.
- What's your name?
- George Merry, sir.
I suppose you sailed
with Admiral Hawke, too?
Aye, sir. Master gunner.
You brought your own cannon aboard?
Men accustomed to warfare
do arm themselves.
Not when engaged on peaceful,
commercial enterprise.
Any further offense, 12 lashes.
And that goes for all the fo'c'sle hands.
- See to it, Mr. Arrow.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Dismissed.
I'll have to turn mine in, too.
Here.
- You ain't let no one see it, have ye?
- No, sir.
Then it would go hard with Long John
if you was to turn it in now.
But why?
Well, here's a captain with a suspicious
turn of mind,
and here's Long John handing
out firearms,
to an able-bodied seaman like yourself.
But I'd do no harm with it.
- Would you keep it out of sight?
- Yes, sir.
You ain't given to rum drinking, are ye?
Oh, no, sir.
Nor quarrelsome,
like some I could name?
I don't want no mate peachin' on me.
You shouldn't have crossed
him, George.
Now he can take away our rum ration.
- You knows his reputation.
- And drink it all himself.
Why did you give him the
chance, then?
You heard the orders.
Seamen knives is all, and them
in full sight.
Well, Israel Hands,
here's one he don't get.
Ain't that a beauty, now.
Why, a knife like that'd bring
down a gull.
Devil burn ye, John Silver,
and don't think ye come that over me.
Time you learn, George Merry,
just who is captain
aboard this here
commercial enterprise.
A captain's was a captain
wouldn't have that mate around
sticking his nose into fo'c'sle business.
You lay a finger on Mr. Arrow,
and you'll answer to me.
Mr. Arrow be a friend
of Long John Silver's
and I plans to take care of him.
Be that clear, George Merry?
You know, matey, if you and me
was worth our salt,
we'd think out a way to
sweeten Mr. Arrow's disposition.
I knows what'll do him.
- Plum duff.
- Oh, my mother made that!
Tasted proper on a cold night, didn't it?
Did your mother ever put a drop of
rum in it?
Good and strong,
so the smell went up your nose.
Aye, it's too bad we ain't got none.
Plum duff ain't no better
than bilge water without rum.
Can't you get rum for cooking?
And have Captain suspect me of
sneaking double grog?
I could ask Squire for some.
Without Captain knowing?
I'm sure I could.
Blow me down, so ye could.
You have an egress and regress
to the gentlemen in the cabin,
but, uh, can you keep
that many secrets?
Aye, aye, sir.
You're a good 'un, Jim.
I seen that from the start.
A-yo, ho, ho and a bottle of rum
Starboard watch on deck!
Mr. Arrow?
Could ye spare a minute
afore you go topside again?
Plum duff. I made it special for you, sir.
And that's what gives it the flavor.
Sweeten to suit your taste.
Right there, you big monkey.
You'll need your sea legs
up there tonight, sir.
Have ye forgot, George?
I'm the one what's taking care
of Mr. Arrow.
And it shall be entered in the log
that Mr. Arrow, mate on the Hispaniola
was washed overboard in a storm
on the night of May 14,
and his body not recovered for burial.
Unto Almighty God we commend
the soul of our brother departed
and commit his body to the deep.
Amen.
Do you think we'll ever
sight land again?
- We will.
- When?
Ooh, there are signs.
What signs?
Sailors' vapors, mostly.
Crew always gets quarrelsome
towards the end of a voyage
when all the beer's gone
and the water keg's crawling
and all you've got left is
salt pork and boiled beans,
and boiled beans and salt pork.
There's a few apples left.
And when the last apple's et,
we'll sight land.
- Then I'm going to eat 'em all up.
- Good.
- Hey, fetch me one.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- What do you think, George?
- We can take this ship right now.
- Then what are we waiting for?
- That's what I wants to know.
Since me and Norton joined you,
the only crew left
on Captain's side
is Gray and Joyce and Hunter.
And I say, cut their throats!
And I say there'll be no killing
till I give the word.
What's come over you, John?
When you were sailing with Flint,
it was cut and rip.
John's gone too genteel
for bloodletting.
You thickheaded swab!
Who got rid of Arrow so quiet
that no one suspected?
Not even young Hawkins,
who brought be the rum for the job.
And who'll get ye firearms
in the same way when the time comes?
Nobody's crossing you, John,
but we still would like to know
what we're waitin' for.
We're waiting while a first-class
navigator like Captain Smollett
sails this here bumboat
to our destination.
We can steer a course,
but who's to set one?
You'll get plenty
of cut and rip when the time comes.
But until I gives the signal, lay to.
Well, we'll wait, but it won't be easy.
Well, I want some pickles and wine
and a mouthful of rum, I do.
When a thirst is on ye,
bite into a pippin real savage.
It staves off the desire.
Land ho!
Long John Silver. I just can't believe it.
I'd never have questioned his loyalty.
Everything he told us was a lie.
I've been a fool, sir.
You're not the only one, lad.
Captain Smollett, I own myself an ass.
- You were right, I was wrong.
- No more wrong than I, Squire.
I'm the man that signed
Scully and Norton
and they've turned against me.
Precious few of us left now.
Counting Joyce, Gray, Hunter,
Redruth, Williams,
that makes us eight. Nine.
Nine against 20? Pretty heavy odds.
We have all the firearms.
Can't we surprise them?
That's my plan when
I get them all ashore.
Did Silver give any hint
when he meant to start the mutiny?
No, sir.
Well, here's my view.
We've got time ahead of us,
at least till we find the treasure.
Yes, but can Silver keep
his men in check that long?
If he can hold them back for 24 hours,
I'll have every one of
the mutinous dogs in irons.
Well, here's our course. Lay to,
and give them no cause for alarm,
otherwise they'd strike at once.
In the meantime,
we'll arm the faithful hands
and keep a sharp lookout for them.
If you hear any murmurs
against Silver, report to me.
Jim warned us once.
I wonder if he could do it again.
Jim, could you play a part
you don't feel?
Keep your ears open,
and stay friends with Silver?
Stay friends with him?
Yes, sir. I'll stay friends with him.
'Tis a sweet spot
for a young lad ashore.
You'll climb trees and hunt goats,
you will.
And when you've a mind
to do a bit of explorin',
just you ask ol' John, and he'll put up
a bit of grub for ye to take along.
What's come over ye, lad?
Cat got your tongue?
All hands.
Any of you seen that land before?
I have, sir.
I was cook on a trader
that watered here.
- Where's the anchorage?
- Yonder, sir, through that inlet.
- Can it be entered at low tide?
- Aye.
There's a kind of passage
been dug there
in a manner of speaking, by nature.
You give me a strong pull
with a long boat, sir,
and I'll guide her in like a lamb.
Good. Stand by to lower the boats.
Can I come along in the boat?
- Captain Smollett?
- Yes?
Young Hawkins here wants
to try his hand on a tiller.
Permission granted.
Now that we've got here,
what are we waiting for?
We're waiting till
I decide the time be right.
Be that plain enough, George Merry?
Lower away.
- You're to have the helm, ain't you?
- Aye.
- See Redruth on guard there?
When I give ye the signal, jump on him
so's we can rush the aft cabin
and get them muskets.
Cast off your forward lines.
Stand by to weigh anchor.
Five fathoms!
Good anchorage here, sir.
- Ready to drop anchor.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- Rush him!
- Boys, get on deck fast!
Belay! Lay to!
Get below, you scum. Double quick.
Get down. Get down.
- Lash down the hatch.
- Now we're for it.
Cast off the lines
and pull for the shore. Lively!
None of that, my men. Turn about.
Come alongside.
Fire that musket, and I cuts his throat.
Merry, you blundering squid.
Can you hear me?
Aye, I hear ye.
Lie low till a treaty be made.
And this time, follow orders.
As for you, Mr. Smollett,
I'll give ye one hour
to send a boat ashore with Flint's map
and give yourself up to Mr. Merry.
So be it if you want to
see young Hawkins alive.
Pull for the shore. Lively!
By Jove, sir, we've got to save that boy.
Now then, matey,
don't ye take it so hard.
Why, it is lucky you came along,
or old John here, he'd
have had nothing to bargain with.
But that don't mean I'd harm
a hair of your little head.
Liar! You let go of me.
There, now, see? Here, here!
Come back here.
- Come here, you.
- After him, you swabs.
Come on! Go on! Go on!
Come on! There he goes.
After him! After him!
- Which way, Scully?
- Pipe down. I thought I heard him.
A hang good job of sighting you did.
Ah, he must have
doubled back. Beat to the woods, mates.
After him!
No, no, no! Don't shoot!
You wouldn't harm Ben Gunn?
Poor Ben Gunn, I am.
And I haven't spoke with a Christian
these five years.
Five years! Were you shipwrecked?
Nay, mate. Marooned.
Tell me, mate, would that be
Flint's ship?
No, Flint's dead.
The master of that ship's
a gentleman, Captain Smollett.
"Gentleman," says you.
"Flint's men," says I.
I've seen 'em.
Some of them are Flint's men,
but they got aboard by a trick.
Is there a man with one leg among 'em?
- Long John Silver.
- Nay, if you were sent by him
I'm as good as pork, and I knows it.
No, you don't understand.
He's trying to take me as hostage.
I hate John Silver.
"And fear him, too," says you.
Everybody feared Flint's quartermaster.
It was him has marooned me here.
I ain't had a mouthful of Christian diet
these five years.
Marooned five years!
And lived on goats and berries.
Many is the night
I dreamed of cheese.
Toasted, mostly.
You wouldn't have a rind of cheese
about you, would you, now?
There's cheese by the hundredweight
aboard ship.
Now, if you could
help me row a long boat...
"Boat," says you.
"Ben Gunn's your man," says I.
What might ye call yourself, mate?
- Jim.
Jim. Well, now, Jim,
you just follow Ben Gunn.
A little more west, sir.
There it is.
With that stockade as a base
for our operations ashore
we stand a better chance
of rescuing that boy.
That's all.
Keep a sharp watch,
one stem, the other stern.
You'll be relieved in good time.
Let us out of here, you dogs!
Don't be afraid of those bilge rats,
but don't underestimate them either.
Shove off.
Made it with me own hands
out of bamboo and goatskins, mostly.
"And a trim little craft," says you.
- Will she hold us both?
- That she will.
"But first," says you, "we'll see if
the coast is clear of Flint's men."
No sign of 'em.
Look! The jolly boat!
They're coming for me!
Let us out of here, you dogs!
Open up, you swab!
Let us out of here!
Open the hatches!
Come on. Let us out of prison!
Stop that, or I fires.
Break! Break!
Pull, boys. Pull for the shore.
Stop that!
Blast away!
Blasted!
Aye! Ahoy there.
Now we'll all be marooned.
Aye, we can give that captain
a proper welcome ashore.
Avast. Pay no heed to them. Make
for the ship. We want them muskets.
- Captain...
- No, no, matey.
- Do you want John Silver to hear us?
- But Captain won't know where I went.
No need to. Ben Gunn knows
where your captain's headed for.
There be your friends, sure enough.
Come on. Come along.
If your captain wants to see Ben Gunn,
tell him to come tonight, alone,
to the top of Spy Glass Hill.
I'll tell him.
And tell him them as hides can find,
and them as finds can hide!
Yo, ho, ho
and a bottle of rum
Give me the full one, George.
Yo, ho, ho and a bottle of rum
Changed your quarters,
have ye, George?
Aye. I took the ship for you, didn't I?
- I can't remember asking ye.
- You said when the time was right.
Clap him in irons.
Clap him in irons!
I'll carry out your orders, John,
but I'm speakin' in open council
for you to give George Merry
another chance.
George here ain't the one
to lay plans, but if you aims
to take this stockade,
well, George is a good man in a fight.
Too good to be rotting down below.
- That's right, John.
That's very civil spoke, Israel Hands.
And now we'll put it to Mr. Merry,
if I'm to take any more of his sauce.
- I'm with ya, Captain.
- Aye, aye, Captain.
All right, then.
If I'm captain, then this is orders.
All hands ashore
except Israel and Haggott here.
The two of you remain on board
and guard the ship.
Aye, aye, sir.
If you're in trouble, you can signal me
by firing the cannon.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- And when you're doing sentry, though,
just ease off a point on the rum.
Hear that, Haggott?
Now, which is it, drink or fight?
Fight! Fight!
Then would you say, Jim, from what
you saw of this Ben Gunn, is he sane?
Well, yes, I shouldn't wonder.
A man who's been biting his nails
for years on a desert island
can't be expected to appear
as sane as you or I.
Why did he want you
to come after dark, Captain?
Safety, of course. But frankly,
I've no craving for his company.
If he knows as much about the island as
he says he does, I may pay him a visit.
Later, perhaps. Right now,
we may expect visitors ourselves.
- Can you load, Jim Hawkins?
- Yes, sir.
Good. When they come,
we must have their rations ready.
Let them come, by Jove.
They'll find me ready.
Once I've had my brandy.
Quarters!
Flag of truce!
Hold your positions.
I'll go and have a look.
Flag of truce!
What do you want
with your flag of truce?
Captain Silver to come aboard
and make terms.
Captain Silver? Who's he?
Me, sir. These poor lads here
have chosen me captain
after your desertion, sir.
My man, I've got no desire
to talk to you.
But if you want to talk to me,
you can come aboard.
There'll be no treachery,
unless it's on your side.
The word of a gentleman
be good enough for Long John.
It may be a trick.
Gray, Joyce, Hunter, keep stations!
That's far enough. Sit down.
Very well, sir, but one of you'll
have to give me a leg up again.
A sweet, pretty place
you have here, to be sure.
And there's Jim.
How be my little matey?
And Squire and Doctor.
My service to ye, gentlemen.
If you've anything to say,
you'd better say it.
You're right, Captain.
Well, the long and the short of it be this.
I want Flint's map, and I can
risk half my crew to get it.
But that ain't Captain Silver's way.
"Try reasoning first," says I.
I never was one to see poor
seamen shot down needless like.
You are not in Parliament yet,
John Silver. Come to the point.
You're a good man, Doctor.
I've never seen a better.
And I'd hate to see the likes of you
skewered on the end of a pike.
So here be my terms.
You give us that there map and you
can stay here and keep your lives.
We'll divide stores with ye, man to man,
and I gives you my affidavit
to stop the first ship I sight
and send 'em here to pick you up.
- Your word, Silver?
- Handsomer you couldn't ask.
And I hopes all gentlemen present
will over all my words,
for what be said to one be said to all.
- Is that all?
- Every last word, by thunder!
Very good. Now hear my terms.
If you come up here,
one by one, unarmed,
I'll engage to clap you all in irons
and take you home
to a fair trial in England.
You can't find the treasure.
You can't sail a ship.
And your cowardly scum can't fight.
Now, bundle out of here, double quick.
- Give me a hand up, will ye?
- Not I.
Who'll give me a hand, I say.
So be it!
But 'fore an hour's out,
you'll be begging help from me.
Them that die'll be the lucky ones!
Truce be over!
Cutlasses, you swabs!
They've opened fire here from the east.
They'll board from all sides at once.
Slash them down!
Burn 'em, boys, burn 'em!
Burn 'em, you swabs.
Aah!
Musket.
Out, lads. Fight in the open.
Keep those muskets loaded. Here.
Cut that captain down!
They're on the run.
Take cover before they reload.
Come back here, you lubberly Turks.
Oh, for 10 toes!
- Quick, Doctor!
- Bar the door.
Jim, my case. My case.
Think they'll attack again?
I don't know, Jim.
It's hard to foresee the end of this.
Jim, take this map. I want you to have it.
Just a precaution.
It's yours by right, you know.
And if the worst comes to the worst,
don't hesitate to buy your life with it.
Water.
How many of them fell?
Five or six at least,
that I know of.
Better odds now. They won't
drive us out of here in a hurry.
- They may not try to.
- Why not?
At flood tide tomorrow,
nothing's to hinder them
from bringing the ship close in shore.
Once within cannon range,
they could level this fort.
- By Jove, I hadn't thought of that.
- Will they think of it?
Silver might, blast him!
They've got all the boats.
Otherwise, we could slip out,
cut the hawser,
and the ship might beach herself.
- I could swim for it, sir.
- Can't spare you.
Just nuisance firing, that's all.
You heard what he said!
Ease off a point on the rum!
- No, you don't.
- But I want my ration
and none of your sour looks neither.
Stand clear of that rum.
You'll get no more till we're relieved.
And if you don't keep off it,
I'll fire that cannon
and get a proper watch aboard.
- Oh, will ya?
- Yeah!
So it was you had Flint's map.
- Not another step.
- Jim.
Jim.
I reckon I'll have to strike my colors.
That comes hard
from a master mariner to a...
To a ship's younker like you, Jim.
But you're like Silver said,
smart as paint.
One more step, Mr. Hands,
and I'll blow your brains out.
Now, now, matey.
Matey.
Dr. Livesy?
Dr. Livesy.
Doctor?
Matey.
Pieces of eight! Pieces of eight!
- Pipe down!
- Aye, 'tis the cabin boy.
Someone's pinked him, for certain.
Blood poisoning, I shouldn't doubt.
Save me cutting your throat,
you little swab.
- Avast, George Merry.
- Avast, is it?
Little matey, is it?
Maybe a touch of this here would show
Master Hawkins which side he were on.
And some others I could name.
Maybe you thought
you was captain here.
Fetch the water bucket!
I don't have to be captain
to know my rights.
And askin' your pardon, this here crew
would lay a sight more confidence
in a captain as allowed us our say
about enemy prisoners.
Prisoners be one thing,
hostages another.
We has the ship. We has the fort.
What good is a hostage,
and him bad hurt?
Why, you knot head.
With him bad hurt, they'll part
with the map to save his life.
We'll hoist the flag of truce
and hail that doctor.
Or would any man jack of ye
care to give me
an argument to the contrary?
So that's your sort, is it?
You're great hands to talk, you are.
But when it comes to fightin',
that boy there
be a better man than any two of you.
Before this crew takes anymore orders
from you, Long John,
we claims our rights
to step outside for a council.
- According to rules.
- Let's go, council.
You! What are you doing here?
Doctor? Squire?
They gave us the slip last night, matey.
When we walked in here,
they was gone.
Now you lay still.
You're going to be cared for proper.
Old John will fetch that doctor here.
Flag of truce!
Ahoy!
Doctor?
We have Jim Hawkins!
Ahoy!
Doctor!
Step up, lad. I won't
hurt no member of a deputation.
The black spot!
Well, shiver my timbers.
What be this?
This here was cut from a Bible.
- What fools cut a Bible?
- What did I say?
- "No good'll come of that," I said.
- Was it you, Job Anderson?
Now Job can say his prayers.
He's had his slice of luck, Job has.
- Cut a Bible! You'll all swing now.
- Belay that talk, John Silver.
This crew has tipped you
the black spot in full council.
The rules is, you turn it over in
duty bound, and see what's wrote there.
Thank ye, George.
You always was brisk for business.
"Deposed." And very pretty wrote.
Your handwriting, George?
You're getting quite a leading hand
in this here crew.
You'll be captain next,
I shouldn't wonder.
You can't fool
this crew no more, John Silver.
Step down off your perch and vote.
John Silver!
There'll be no voting till the business
of this here map be disposed of.
Till then I'm still captain, and
your black spot ain't worth a biscuit.
Map or no map, we ain't
givin' up no hostage
till we lays hands on the treasure itself.
Am I right, mates?
How ye going to find that
treasure without the map?
Silver!
- John Silver!
- Top o' the morning, Doctor.
Will ye come aboard and take a look
at young Hawkins' wound?
No more of your tricks, Silver.
If Jim Hawkins is there, bring him out.
You want to see that doctor,
don't ye, Jim?
If I take ye as far as the stockade,
will you give me your affidavit
not to slip your cable?
- Word of honor?
- Word of honor.
Right, then.
Stand by here while I parleys with him.
And keep a sharp lookout on all sides.
I'll keep a weather eye
out for a man what's trying
to get a foot in each camp,
and he with only one leg.
You'd better come back with that map
and the hostage, Captain Silver!
Doctor!
Steady, lad. Steady, Jim.
Aye, he's had a rum go of it, sir.
- Taking to knifing boys, eh, Silver?
- Not me, sir.
Why, if it hadn't been for Long John,
he'd have had his throat cut.
Bite hard on that bullet, Jim.
This will have to be opened.
You could cut my good leg off 'fore I'd
raise a finger against that there lad.
Why, when he comes crawling into
the fort half dead, I says to myself,
"You've got to save
that dear boy, John."
Captain would wish it,
Squire would wish it and you'd wish it.
So Captain Silver is minded
to join us again, eh?
I'll be honest and open with you,
as I always am.
When I climbed the fort
and seen the Hispaniola
flying that Union Jack,
I knew I'd been taught a lesson
by my betters.
I thinks gold dust of this dear boy.
I've took to him like pitch.
You'd have killed me yourself
if you'd had that map.
But you'll not get it. I'd die first.
You're a mite late to talk of dying.
No, old John, he ain't human, he ain't.
He didn't care about
saving his little matey's life, not him.
- All he wanted was this here map.
- Very well. You have the map.
But what good is the treasure
without a ship to haul it?
And what good be a ship if 'tis
only to haul me to execution, Doc?
I be no coward, Doctor,
but the thought of them there gallows
gives me the shakes.
Now, if I was to
save young Hawkins' life,
do ye think ye could
save mine into the bargain?
- You save him?
- I could guard the boy
while I plays at treasure hunting
with them scum.
But they'll not give him up
till they sees the treasure dug.
Now, wouldn't that
warrant a good word to the captain?
- I want to speak with the boy alone.
- Speak and welcome,
and make a note of that, too, but go
on with your doctoring while you talks.
One false move, and they'll fire.
Jim, I don't know how you
managed to save us that ship.
- But I lost the map.
- The map's not important to us now,
but your safety is.
So you're not going back
to those fellows. Now, listen carefully.
I'll make a quick break to draw their fire.
The moment I do, you fall flat.
Then before they've time to reload,
you're up and running and
we both head for the woods. Right?
- I can't!
- Why not?
I gave Long John my word.
They'd have killed me
if it hadn't been for him.
Perhaps you're right, Jim.
Silver!
I want to give you one piece of advice.
Stay close to that boy,
and this I promise you,
if we get out of this wolf trap alive,
I'll do my best to save you,
short of perjury.
You couldn't say more,
not if you was my mother.
Heaven forbid! Good luck, Jim.
- It's the map!
- By Jove, he's got it!
And now, by thunder, I resign.
Elect anyone you please
to be your captain.
I've done with ye.
- No, no!
- John Silver for me, yeah!
Take it back, George Merry,
and tear it up.
Put it back in the good book, mate.
Poor roving seamen, the likes of you
needs every scrap
of scripture he can get.
Mind what I say,
Master Hawkins
and don't try to fly the coop again.
Appearances, matey, appearances.
March now, you little spritsail.
To Finger Trunk Tree
by Devil's Rock
bearing a point to the north
of north-northeast.
There she be!
Come on!
Hey! Now, who might that be?
He were a seaman, all right.
- Leastways, this be good sea cloth.
- Like enough.
You wouldn't look to find a bishop here.
- What did he die of, I want to know?
- He died of Flint's hand,
as did five other men Flint took ashore.
That would be Darby McGraw.
- Mind old Darby, Morgan?
- Aye, I mind him.
Owed me money, he did.
I don't like the way he's stretched out.
Ain't natural. Ain't nice.
I've a notion. Where's that map?
As I thought. Right in line!
By thunder! It makes me go
cold inside to think of Flint.
This one he hauled here
and laid down by compass
to point the way to the doubloons.
Fetch ahead now!
There it is!
Where is it?
It's gone!
Gone? Dig!
Rip it up, you swabs!
Stand by for trouble.
One dirty guinea!
There's your £700,000!
Hardly worth dividing, is it, George?
So you did make
a bargain with the doctor!
Look at his face, mates!
You can see it wrote on his face!
Be you standing for captain again?
Aah!
- Dr. Livesy!
- Jim, are you all right?
Thank ye kindly, Doctor.
You came in the nick of time
for Hawkins and...
Ben Gunn.
How do, Mr. Silver? "Pretty well,
I thank ye," says you.
Ben, to think 'twas you that done me.
"What happened to Flint's gold?"
says you.
"Ben Gunn's cave," says I.
Them as hides can find, Mr. Silver.
"But not when them that finds
has hid it," says I.
John Silver! Now what have you
got to say for yourself?
Well, sir, by your leave, sir,
John Silver's come back to do his duty.
Hmm.
And happy I am to think, sir,
that I had some small hand in
saving young Master Hawkins
when he was within
half a plank of death.
And does that clear you
of the crime of mutiny?
Please, sir, he did save my life.
Jim's right.
Silver kept his side of the bargain.
Then you're both free
to testify on his behalf.
He'll have a fair trial in England.
Squire Trelawney, while the doctor's
helping me down to the beach,
I suggest you get a load
aboard the ship.
Take John Silver along
and put him in irons.
Aye, aye, sir.
Now, then, Silver,
none of your monkeyshines.
Jim, lad, would ye do a favor
for your old shipmate?
Would ye take Captain Flint?
I've tried caging her before,
but this old bird,
she can't abide a prison.
There ain't much in nature as can.
I couldn't, Long John. I'd like it,
but I fear she'd just remind me...
Well, no matter, though I'd dearly love
to leave you a trinket to a lad I respect.
All right, Silver,
enough of that.
Beggin' your pardon, Squire,
you should caulk her
while she's heeled over.
Jump now, and swim for it.
And you, too, Squire.
Why, if you think that you...
If I may make so bold, sir,
I'll borrow your boat,
but I ain't takin' you to Jamaica.
- Lively, now!
- You monster!
Heads up!
I can't swim so far!
My service to you, Squire.
Might be as you care to float.
Belay!
You steer me a true course
through the channel
and I'll put ye off on yon spit of land.
Hey! Hey there, avast!
- Shove me off!
- I'll take no orders from you.
You put me on here.
Now you'll shove me off
or by the powers,
you'll get what I gave George Merry.
- Hurry, Livesy!
- Coming, Squire.
Shoulder to it, Jim.
That's it!
Shove her nose out.
Thank ye, Jim. I might have known
you'd never let 'em
hang your old shipmate.
Pull out. Pull back. Overhaul him.
Harder.
Ah, well, the sharks may do for him yet.
Goodbye, matey!
Good luck to ye!
Blast him. I could almost find it
in my heart to hope he makes it.