The ancient seas,
home to so many
wondrous creatures.
Creatures both small,
and very, very large.
Millions and millions
of years ago,
these creatures swam
in the warm oceans
that covered most of our planet.
The oceans were strange,
mysterious,
and very dangerous.
And the world above
was dangerous, too.
Creatures were at risk, not only from
the predators who would eat them,
but also from the ever-changing
weather patterns
and natural disasters
that plagued their world.
But even during this time of heavy
rains and harsh natural disasters,
there was a place that dinosaurs
could live in peace and harmony,
the Great Valley.
But the Great Valley was also
having some very bad weather.
When is all this
skywater gonna stop, Grandpa?
I don't know, Littlefoot.
Grandma and I have never
seen so much of it before.
Me neither, especially all
over the ground like this.
Gee, what if it never stops?
Oh, it will, little one.
It always does.
Though I'm beginning
to have my doubts.
Oh, look.
Wow! The sky colors!
Yes!
May I go play
with my friends now?
Please?
Of course, Littlefoot.
Yay!
Just don't go too far,
until we know what all this
skywater has done to the valley.
I won't.
See you later.
Ya-hoo!
Hey, Cera! Want to race me
over to Ducky's and Spike's?
I can't, Littlefoot.
I've gotta help my
father move this tree.
It fell right on top
of our sleeping place.
Cera. Sorry, Littlefoot.
I could help.
Well, thanks for the
offer, Littlefoot,
but my daughter and I
are fully capable
of doing the job ourselves.
Okay, Cera.
Then I'll see you later?
Uh-huh.
Okay, well, bye.
I'll just have to race myself
over to Ducky and Spike's.
Ready, set, go!
Hey, Ducky, Spike,
where are you guys going?
Hi, Littlefoot.
Mama says we have to move
because the skywater
has made our nesting
place too squishy.
See?
Me and Spike really like it.
Well, maybe when you're done moving,
we can all do something together.
Oh, yes, like play
in all this squishy mud.
Squishy, squishy, squishy.
Then I'll see you later?
Uh-huh.
Squishy, squishy, squishy.
Squishy.
Squishy, squishy.
Ducky, Spike, stop squishing
in that mud and come along.
We have a nest to build.
Uh, um, coming, Mama.
Squishy, squishy, squishy.
Hello? Petrie?
You up there?
Me up here, Littlefoot.
But me no can play today.
Me got sniffles
from having wet feet.
Oh, me got to learn
how to fall softer.
Gee, do you think you'll
be feeling better soon?
Oh, yes. Me feel
much better by tomorrow.
Oh.
Or maybe not.
♪ It's boring, boring
Really, truly boring
♪ When you have to be alone
♪ When you need some friends
♪ To play Let's Pretend
♪ But they have to stay at home
♪ It's time for an adventure
♪ And you want to go exploring
♪ But it's just no fun
♪ To be the only one
♪ No, it's really, truly,
very boring
♪ It is boring, boring
Really awfully boring
♪ When you have
to build your nest
♪ When you push and shove
from below and above
♪ And you don't have
any time to rest
♪ When the friends
you want to be with
♪ You have to keep ignoring
♪ It can make you sad
♪ It can make me mad
♪ 'Cause it's very,
very, very boring
♪ When there's nowhere
you can go
♪ And there's nothing fun to do
♪ Then the day goes by so slow
♪ And you feel like
your feet are stuck in goo
♪ It's boring, boring
Very, very boring
♪ When you have a cold
in your beak
♪ When you have the sniffles
♪ And your head is
full of whiffles
♪ And you can't be
flying for a week
♪ When all you do is sneeze
♪ And lay around all day snoring
♪ There's nothing you can say
♪ But just for today
It's very, very
♪ Very, very
♪ Almost extraordinary
♪ Really, truly
♪ Very boring
I'm bored.
Oh, I'm bored.
Here, Littlefoot.
Have a treestar.
All that skywater has made
it deliciously moist.
Thanks, Grandpa, but I don't want a
treestar. I want to have some fun.
But, Littlefoot, you have a whole
valley out there to entertain you.
Yeah, but what's the good of that if I
don't have anybody to share it with.
There's no one
who wants to have fun.
I wish my mom had
given me a brother.
Then I'd always have
someone to have fun with.
Now, little one,
your mother would have loved to have
given you a brother, Littlefoot.
Yes, but because
you were her only child,
you were very, very
special to her.
What's so special
about being all alone?
Ah, but that's just it,
Littlefoot.
None of us are ever
really alone.
But I feel alone.
Yes, Littlefoot, I understand.
But look around you. Our Great
Valley is so full of life.
It really is a special place.
Filled with so many
special creatures.
We've got fliers,
and swimmers.
And landwalkers of all kinds.
Oh, we even have these
annoying buzzing creatures.
Wondrous, isn't it?
And just think, Littlefoot.
There might be other kinds of creatures
out there just waiting to be discovered.
Really?
That's right.
So, you see, Littlefoot,
in a world so full of life,
you're only as alone
as you choose to be.
Do you understand, little one?
Well, no.
Don't worry.
You will someday.
Yeah, but what do I do
for fun until then?
It's not fair.
There's nobody
to have any fun with.
Oh, hey!
Hello, Littlefoot.
What would you like to do today?
I don't know, Littlefoot.
What do you want to do?
Hey, no fair.
I asked you first.
Okay.
Let's go have some fun.
Yeah!
Gee, the skywater has really
changed the land around here.
Think it's
safe to go on, Littlefoot?
Sure it is.
Maybe we'll find some new kind
of creature, like Grandpa said.
Okay, but we have to be careful.
Aw, don't be
such a scaredy-egg.
Whoa!
Look at that!
There's so much water.
I think we've gone
too far from home now, Littlefoot.
Yeah, you may be right.
Over here, Grandpa.
It's this way.
Oh, my!
We were all afraid
this might happen.
What do you mean, "all"?
I wasn't afraid.
Look.
The skywater has
caused flooding in our valley.
Yes, and all the
new water must have come
from over those mountains.
From the Mysterious Beyond.
Oh, dear!
Oh. Well, then, who knows what terrible
creatures it may have carried with it.
Which means I don't want
Cera anywhere near it.
Little one, you
must stay closer to home
until we know more about what the
skywater has done to our valley.
Okay, Grandma.
Come, everyone. I sense more
skywater is about to fall.
Gee, I don't sense anything.
Aah! Wait for me!
Huh? What was that?
Probably nothing.
There it is again. I've never
heard anything like it before.
I better check it out.
Off a bit early
this morning, Littlefoot.
Well, I can't sleep,
and I, uh...
Really, really
want to go out and play.
All right.
Uh, just be careful.
I will.
Sounds like it's coming
from out there somewhere.
Maybe it's something new, just waiting
to be discovered, like Grandpa said.
Huh?
It's a swimmer.
Wow! I've never seen one
like him before.
Hello? Hello? Don't be afraid.
I won't hurt you.
Hello out there.
Hey!
Huh?
Ooh. Aah.
Wow!
No, don't go! Please.
Hey!
Okay, very funny.
That really looks like fun.
I wish I could do that.
Who are you?
I'm Littlefoot.
"Yittlefoot"?
No, Li-Li-Littlefoot.
"Yi-Yi-Yittlefo-o-o-t"?
Well, that's pretty close.
What's your name?
Mo.
Nice to meet you, Mo.
Mo no got
landfoot like Littlefoot.
Mo got wa-a-a-terfoot!
See?
Yeah, I see.
Do you like
to have fu-u-u-u-n?
I sure do!
Hee-hee!
Hey!
I'll get you.
Littlefoot.
Littlefoot!
Littlefoot. Come out, come
out, wherever you be.
Maybe Littlefoot is hiding
from us because he is mad.
Why would he be mad?
We didn't do anything.
Well, we not play with him.
It wasn't our fault
we couldn't play.
Now, where is he?
Hey, maybe Littlefoot swim off.
There plenty of water.
Petrie, Littlefoot is not a swimmer.
And you are not
a swimmer either.
No, no, no.
If me see any
more water, me gonna...
Gonna... Ah-choo!
Be more wet.
What's so funny?
That is Littlefoot's laugh.
It sure is.
And it sounds like he's having a
bunch of fun without us. Come on!
Okay. Me walk, too.
Wow! Look at that.
Hmm?
It is just like
the grown-ups said.
It is big, new water.
Come on.
Let's go find Littlefoot.
But, Cera, my mama said
not to go near the new water.
She said, "Do not go there.
It could be dangerous."
Yeah, my dad said that, too.
But, like that's
stopped us before?
Besides, Littlefoot's laughing.
So how bad can it be?
Mmm-hmm, mmm-hmm, mmm-hmm.
Just because they go,
no mean me have to.
Me think for myself.
Petrie?
Coming.
Littlefoot?
Is that you?
Oh, hi, guys. Guess what. Mo and
I just became mud brothers.
Mo?
Who Mo?
Yeah. Mo who?
He's my best friend.
Best? What do you mean, "best"?
Yeah. I thought we
were your best friends.
Well, I just mean that he's my
newest best friend because he
lives in the new water.
Do you guys want to meet him?
A new friend?
Oh, yes!
Yes, yes, yes.
But, Ducky, remember what the
grown-ups said about the new water?
Oh, yes, that is right.
Since Mo is from the new water, we
have to be very careful because
he might be dangerous.
Right, Spike?
Spike?
Spike does not seem worried.
Then, come on. Wait till you meet him.
He's so much fun.
Newest best friend.
So much fun, hmph! I probably
won't even like him.
So, where is he?
I... I don't know.
Mo!
Sounds to me like you
just made him up.
No, I didn't.
Sure, you didn't.
Well, I didn't!
I wouldn't talk to
an imaginary friend.
Why not? Me talk to imaginary
friend all the time.
♪ Me have a friend
A very special friend
♪ And nobody can see or hear him
♪ We play every day
He do anything me say
♪ And he make me happy
when me near him
What kind of friend
is your friend?
♪ He a sharptooth!
He must be very scary.
♪ Oh, no He short and he nice
♪ And he have no teeth
♪ And, best of all
♪ He imaginary
Imaginary?
♪ Imaginary
♪ Oh, imaginary friends
are very good friends
♪ Ready when you want to play
♪ They happy when you happy
♪ Sad when you are sad ♪ And they
always believe everything you say
♪ Imaginary
♪ Why would you want
an imaginary friend?
♪ I think it just sounds dumb
♪ He's not really there You're
just talking to the air
♪ How can nobody be any fun
♪ But imaginary friends
think you very, very smart
♪ They never, ever fuss or fight
♪ Wherever you want to go
they go
♪ And whatever you do
♪ You're always right
Wow, I like that.
♪ Oh, imaginary friends
are magical friends
♪ Big and small and fast
and slow ones
♪ Yes, imaginary friends
are wonderful friends
♪ And everybody
♪ Everybody
♪ Everybody ought to know one
♪ Imaginary
It's fun.
Oh, looky.
Come on, everybody.
It's Mo.
Mo, these are all my friends.
This is Ducky. Hi, Mo.
I am a swimmer, too.
A swimmer and landwalker?
You special!
Oh, yes, yes, yes, I am.
I guess.
And this is Spike.
Spike is very special, too.
Especially good at eating.
This is Petrie.
Me a flier. See?
Ta-da!
And this is Cera.
You're not from
around here, are you?
Then just where are you from?
Mo from Big Water.
Big Water?
But how you get here when
Big Water way over there?
Ooh. Skyplace make
lots and lots of skywater.
Make big waves in Big Water.
Mo scared.
So Mo swim into small water
path, then p-u-u-u-h-wish!
Mo do like th-i-i-i-i-s!
Then, f-a-a-a-a-a-ll!
All the skywater must have washed him
over from the Mysterious Beyond.
Oh. Poor, poor Mo.
Did you get washeded over
all by yourself?
Mmm-hmm. Mmm-hmm,
mmm-hmm, mmm-hmm.
And you're sure that
no one else came with you?
Mo all alone.
But now, Mo have new friends!
Have fun.
Mo sound funny.
Run for it!
That was a very
big sharptooth swimmer.
And it not imaginary!
I knew
the grown-ups were right.
We should have never
gone near the new water.
Come on.
We're going home.
But, Cera, we can't
just leave Mo.
He's my mud brother.
Some brother! He thinks
this whole thing was funny.
No! Mo's just happy
to see us.
He tried to warn us.
We don't know that for sure. We
don't know anything about him
other than he's so much fun.
But we can't just leave him in
the new water with that monster.
We've gotta help him.
But how, Littlefoot?
We are very little, and that swimming
sharptooth is very, very big.
Mmm-hmm.
Well, we could...
We could figure something out.
Yeah? Like what?
Like, we could...
Help him get home.
Yeah. We could help Mo get
back to the Big Water.
What?
Why not?
We've been there before.
But, Littlefoot, Mo cannot
walk with us to the Big Water.
He is a swimmer and has no feet.
Besides, we only know how to get there when
we turn right at the smoking mountains.
And we are nowhere near them.
Well, if you won't help me,
I'm sure the grown-ups will.
You can't be serious.
We're not going to
the Mysterious Beyond
to help some strange creature.
That's absurd!
Now, now, Mr. Threehorn.
There's no need to be so gruff.
Littlefoot was just asking. And there's
no harm in that.
Well, that's true.
I'm sorry, Littlefoot, but...
Littlefoot? Kids?
I don't care what anybody says.
Mo's my mud brother
and I'm going to help him.
But, Littlefoot!
Ooh, I think my tummy is making
its hungry sound.
No, I do not
think that is my tummy.
Earthshake!
Aah! This way!
Over here!
Look out!
I guess we won't be going
back this way anymore.
But how will we get home?
Me fly across
and get grown-ups.
They find way.
Hot!
Never mind.
Do not worry, Spike.
We will find a way home.
Oh, dear!
This isn't like him at all.
This way. Their tracks lead right
in the direction of the new water.
Which you know can mean
only one thing.
Littlefoot has led our children
into trouble once again.
Now, now, Mr. Threehorn. We don't
know anything yet for sure.
If our kids did go back
to the new water,
I'm sure they're trying to find
a way home this very minute.
Until then, we must find a
way around this land break.
We'll keep looking
until we find them.
Mo! Mo, are you
out there?
Me here, Littlefoot.
Oh, I was hoping you'd be okay.
That earthshake was really bad.
No, earthshake good.
It trap bad swimmer.
He no leave ever never.
Wait a minute. If he's trapped in
that cave, then he can't get us.
And if he can't get us, it'd be
safe for us to help you get home.
Home? Yeah, back
to the Big Water.
You do want to go there,
don't you?
Uh-huh, uh-huh, uh-huh.
Then stay right there.
Ho-o-o-me.
And, since we can't
get home the old way,
maybe we can find a new way
home by going that way.
And, while we're at it, we could
take Mo to the Big Water.
What do you say?
Well, I say yes.
Yes, yes, yes, yes,
yes, yes, yes.
And what about you, Spike?
Uh-huh.
Count me in, too.
What you say, Cera?
Well...
Great.
Petrie, you fly 'round and see if there's
any water paths that lead to the Big Water.
Okay.
You'll see, Cera. Mo will
make this trip so much fun.
Yeah, right.
Me find water paths to Big
Water and be big hero.
Whew. That's some big wind.
Got to pull up.
Pull up!
Oh! Me sure glad that over.
Now me can get back
to being hero.
Oh, too bad Cera, Littlefoot,
Ducky and Spike not fly.
Wait, imaginary friend can fly.
There.
Now, he got wings.
♪ Imaginary
Me like to sing. How about
you, imaginary friend?
Good.
♪ Imaginary
Louder, friend.
Me can't hear you.
Whoa! There Big Water.
Now me go back and tell others.
Great job, Petrie. You found
the way all by yourself.
Not by myself, Littlefoot.
Imaginary friend help.
Oh, brother.
Mo this and Mo that. Hmph!
Hey!
Fun!
Littlefoot, would you please
tell your mud brother
that this is no time
to be having fun?
Getting him and us home
is very serious. Hmph!
Um, Mo, maybe you should stop
playing around for now, okay?
I think you're kinda
getting on Cera's nerves.
Nerves?
Huh?
Surprise!
Now Mo bubble-face, too.
Hmph!
What?
And just how do you expect
Mo to swim over this, Petrie?
Sorry, but big boulder
look like little,
tiny boulder from up there.
Do not worry. Maybe Mo can
swim under the boulder.
I will go see.
It is Mo. He is stuckted,
and I cannot pull him out.
No, guys.
You are not swimmers.
You cannot go down there.
Surprise! Huh?
Did anybody see him?
Sorry, me too
busy swallowing water.
Hello, friends!
Mo, you're not stuck!
You're all right!
Ooh, Mo not really stuck.
Mo just having...
Fun.
Face it, Littlefoot.
Mo doesn't really want help.
He just wants to have fun.
Wait a minute, Cera.
That's it!
What's it? Mo thinks
jumping is fun, right?
Right.
Right!
So, he can jump right
over the big rock.
But, if Mo not make it, he
get all squished.
But, Petrie, maybe he would
not get squishted too badly.
Hmm, maybe.
It sound fun!
Mo try it.
I'll wait for him on
top, just in case he needs help.
Uh-oh. Here comes
the squish part.
I got him!
Wheee-hee-hee-hee.
Yay!
Way to go, Mo.
Way to go, Littlefoot.
We do again?
Maybe. Who knows
what we're gonna run into next?
Come on, guys.
Oh, when we gonna get there?
We'll get there
when we get there, Petrie.
My grandpa and grandma
always say that, too.
My mama always tells my brothers and
sisters and me to sing to pass the time.
♪ Big, Big, Big, Big Water
Come on, guys.
Singing will make you feel
much, much, much, much better.
♪ Big, Big, Big, Big Water
See? I am feeling so much
betterer already.
♪ We're looking for
Big, Big, Big, Big Water
♪ It's deep and dark
and dangerous
♪ It's scary
and it's strangerous
♪ And things could
rearranger-us
♪ In that Big Water
Sing it again.
One more time! ♪ We went
there once some time ago
♪ And now we going back you know
♪ And this time we are taking Mo
♪ To that Big Water
Now we're all feeling betterer.
That was fun!
Why Mo make that awful noise?
Maybe he's sick.
Ow. Now I am
feeling sick, too.
Littlefoot, make him stop!
Aah!
What just hopped on me?
I'm not sure.
But I think it was one of them!
Do not worry, Spike.
I will protect you.
Oh, no!
Now they after Mo.
What are they doing?
Talking?
What did they say, Mo?
Flying bugs tell Mo we
getting close to Big Water!
And...
They especially liked
Mo's singing.
Huh?
Singing? Oh, so that is what
you were doing.
Petrie, thanks
to you, we're lost.
Hey, we no lost.
Everyone else is getting
so, so grumpy.
But I am not grumpy.
I am hap...
Hap...
Happy! That we are
all together
and finding a way home.
Hmm?
Ooh! What that?
Come on.
Spike will find her.
We're coming, Ducky!
Hello, Spike. Thank you for saving me.
What happened, Ducky?
I was hopping, and then I
felled, and then it was dark.
Wow! Eggs.
Ducky fell into someone's nest.
Which is why we'd
better get out of here.
The mama of these eggs might not be too...
Friendly.
We are sorry,
Mrs. Mama,
but we would not
hurt your babies.
Oh, no, no, no.
Now...
Why, you aren't much more
than babies yourselves.
Not much more than babies?
Why, I'm practically
all grown up.
See, the big earthshake
cut us off from home,
so we're trying
to find our way back.
Home.
You little ones are very brave.
Is there any way
I can be of help?
Well, even though we are very brave, we
would like a safe place to spend the night.
Hmm.
Littlefoot. Psst.
Littlefoot.
Hmm?
What is it, Mo?
Look.
They look like stars.
What are they?
They're starswimmers.
Starswimmers?
So you see, Littlefoot,
in a world so full of life
you are only as alone
as you choose to be.
♪ No one has to be alone
♪ In this world we live in
♪ You don't need to feel
♪ There's no one by your side
♪ Everything you see
♪ Is a gift you're given
♪ Anywhere is home
♪ And no one has to be alone
♪ There is so much
that surrounds us
♪ There are friends
we've yet to find
♪ There are dreams
to be discovered
♪ And dreams to leave behind
♪ All the wonders up above us
♪ And splendors down below
♪ There is so much
more to everything
♪ Than we can ever know
♪ You don't have to be afraid
♪ Of being lost and lonely
♪ Everything you need
♪ Is right before your eyes
♪ Each bright and shining day
♪ Is waiting for you only
♪ Make this world your own
♪ And you'll never be
♪ Alone
♪ Remember
♪ No one has to be
♪ Alone
My grandpa was right.
I don't think I'll ever
feel alone again.
It's late. Wherever they are, we
aren't going to find them tonight.
Oh, dear. That's not good.
But we will find them.
You'll see.
Thank you for letting us
spend the night, Mrs. Mama.
Yeah, thanks a lot.
Yes, thank you.
Thank you. Anytime, little ones.
Journey safely.
Don't worry. We will. I'm
old enough to see to that.
Good-bye.
It's so hot. Me like
skywater better than this.
Maybe we could stop and go for a swim.
Uh-huh.
Whee!
The water feels
so nice and cool.
Ew. But it tastes yucky.
Huh? That must be because we're
getting close to Big Water.
Come on. Let's celebrate
by cooling off.
Yay!
Huh?
Hey, let's show Mo
how much fun we are.
Uh-oh.
Get him. Yeah!
Come on.
Get in!
Ow! I just stepped
on something.
What is that weird
looking thing?
Cera, what is that on your nose?
I don't know! Just get it off!
Get it off!
It's stuck.
Let go! Let go! Let go!
Wow. Good going, Mo.
Yeah. Me wanna learn
to squeak like that.
It'd sure come in handy.
What did you say to it, Mo?
Right. Which means?
Let go.
Oh, well, yeah, I knew that.
Mo swim ahead. Go see which water
path take us to Big Water.
Be back soon.
Oh, great.
More skywater.
Well, nothing could possibly
make my day any worse.
Except for that!
Hurry! We've gotta get as far
away from the water as we can.
It's sure quiet out there.
Maybe he go home.
I'll go check.
No, Littlefoot. For all we know
that thing could be waiting for us.
No, we just have to stay here and not...
Let's get outta here!
It's too late!
Good-bye, friends.
Mo! No!
Mo.
Hmm? Littlefoot?
Littlefoot, are you okay?
Everything's been my fault.
All I wanted was someone
to have fun with.
I never should have gone
near the new water.
I never should have made
you guys be friends with Mo.
You not make me
be friends with Mo.
And you did not make me.
Thanks.
Sometimes bad stuff
just happens.
But there was something
good that happened.
Really? Uh-huh. We all
got a new brother.
Mmm-hmm. Mmm-hmm.
Even me.
But, Cera, I thought
you didn't like Mo.
Well, I did like him, kind of.
Hmm?
Okay, I didn't like him.
But it was just because you
thought he was so... So...
So what, Cera?
So fun.
I mean, I'm fun, too.
I know that, Cera.
You're lots of fun.
I am?
Ah. Then what was I all jealous for?
Beats me.
And, Cera, you 'specially should not
have been jealous of Mo's singing.
It was not good.
Oh, no, no, no.
Yeah. Me sing
much better than him.
Hey, I'd know
that squeak anywhere!
Come on, guys!
Mo!
Something's caught in there.
It's Mo, and he's all right!
Mo!
Hi, friends.
How you get away? Oh, make
bad swimmer chase me.
And Mo do like that. Then hide
in land plant like see you do.
He means that hollow tree.
Uh-huh, uh-huh, uh-huh.
Hollow tree.
Bad swimmer no see Mo.
Get mad.
Then bad swimmer
stop and smell air, like this.
Bad swimmer forget all about Mo...
And swim that away.
I wonder...
It smells like...
Big Water!
The sharptooth swimmer
must have gone home.
Yes!
There it is.
It's Big Water!
Hurry, everybody!
It's big Big Water!
Well, you're home now, Mo.
So, I guess it's time
to say good-bye.
No! Mo no say good-bye.
Friends stay with Mo.
But we cannot stay here
with you, Mo.
Big Water tastes yucky,
to us, I mean.
And even Spike cannot eat
the green food here.
Ducky's right, Mo. This isn't a
place where our kind can live.
Then Mo go with friends.
You know you can't do that, Mo.
You belong here.
Besides, you and me
will always be brothers.
No.
Mud brothers.
Littlefoot, that Mo's water kin.
Mo home now,
but how friends get home?
We're gonna have to find a way
to the smoking mountains.
Yeah, we know the way
home from there.
Wait, wait.
Mo ask water kin.
Old ones smart. They will know
way home for landwalkers.
What he doing now?
You know Mo.
It's always something.
Me get it.
Mo sending water signals.
Look. Now
we get water signal back.
Old ones right. Other water
kin tell Mo the way.
Friends can go home now.
Home!
Wow. I think they like me.
Littlefoot! Littlefoot!
Before you go home,
you want see where Mo lives?
Do I ever!
Whoa!
Littlefoot!
Hello! Littlefoot!
There they are.
Littlefoot, are you all right?
Don't worry.
I'm fine.
It was amazing, guys. I've never
seen anything so beautiful.
Your world beautiful too,
Littlefoot.
And fun!
I know. Thanks, Mo.
Good-bye, Mo.
Good-bye, friends.
Good-bye.
Good-bye, Mo.
See ya later, Mo.
And so following the way
given to them by Mo's water kin,
Littlefoot, Cera, Ducky,
Petrie and Spike began
the long journey home.
We know way from here!
We sure do.
Hurry, Spike.
Yeah, 'cause last one home
is a rotten egg.
And when at last Littlefoot
and his friends did reach home,
each was greeted
with great relief.
Grandma! Grandpa!
Oh, Littlefoot!
Ah.
Daddy.
Joy...
Mama!
And love by their families.
This adventure was at an end.
Still, Littlefoot, Cera, Ducky,
Petrie and Spike
knew in their hearts
that there would be
many more adventures
yet to come.
♪ No one has to be alone
♪ In this world we live in
♪ You don't need to feel
♪ There's no one by your side
♪ Everything you see
♪ Is a gift you're given
♪ Anywhere is home
♪ And you don't have to be alone
♪ There's so much
that surrounds us
♪ There are friends
we've yet to find
♪ There are things
to be discovered
♪ And things to leave behind
♪ All the wonders up above us
♪ And splendors down below
♪ There is so much more
to everything
♪ Than we can ever know
♪ You don't have to be afraid
♪ Of being lost and lonely
♪ Everything you need
♪ Is right before your eyes
♪ Each bright and shining day
♪ Is waiting for you only
♪ Make this world your own
♪ And you'll never be
♪ Alone
♪ You don't ♪ Remember
♪ You never have to be alone
No, no, no
♪ There is so much
that surrounds us
♪ Oh, yeah ♪ There are
friends we've yet to find
♪ There are things
to be discovered
♪ And things to leave behind
♪ All the wonders above us
♪ And splendors down below
♪ There is so much more
to everything
♪ Than we can ever know
♪ There is so much
that surrounds us
♪ There are friends we've yet to
find ♪ That we've yet to find
♪ There are things to
be discovered ♪ Yeah
♪ And things to leave behind
♪ All the wonders up above us
♪ And splendors down below