[Dramatic instrumental music]
MALE NARRATOR:
The planet Earth.
A world of constant change
and unpredictable weather.
Our home.
Millions of years ago,
it was home...
...to the dinosaurs.
Although these great
beasts seem so unlike us...
...in some ways they
weren't so different at all.
Like people,
they came in all sizes...
...and shapes and colors.
Some could jump.
Some could climb trees.
Some could swim...
...and some couldn't.
Some could even whistle.
And just like all
of us sometimes...
...some had a hard
time getting to sleep.
[Spike snores]
DUCKY: Whoa!
Move over, Spike.
I do not have room.
You sure do take
up a lot of space.
Every sleepy time,
it is the same thing!
DUCKY: Whoa!
Spike? Spike!
Please, not tonight.
Do not make the sleep rumbles.
I am so tired.
Please, please, please!
MR.
THICKNOSE: Long, long ago...
...further back than
anyone can remember...
...great creatures
first crawled up...
...from the murky
ooze onto the dry land.
And thus began
the Age of the--
LITTLEFOOT:
Excuse me, Mr. Thicknose?
MR. THICKNOSE:
I beg your pardon?
Well, if it's too far back
for anyone to remember...
...then how do you
know it even happened?
I...
Well, we know it happened.
Well, if it hadn't,
we wouldn't be here.
Duh!
Yeah, but how do you know
the first ones came
from the murky ooze?
Me flier!
Family maybe come
down from high hills!
And Ducky's
family are swimmers.
Maybe they swam right
up from the big water.
Wonder where
Spike's family come from?
Wherever it was, it
must've been a long walk...
...because he's awful tired.
Young ones, please!
Ducky,
was your herd up all night
gathering tree stars?
No.
Then please try to stay awake.
[Spike chuckles]
That is so not fair!
You were asleep, too.
Why does he pick on--
MR. THICKNOSE: Ducky!
Could you please be
a little quieter, like Spike?
[Spike chuckles again]
Now, where was I?
You were explaining
where we came from.
Oh, yes. Well--
I said, "How do you
know that?" And you said--
I remember.
Perhaps we should talk
about something else.
Food gathering.
I have had the opportunity
to study the many methods...
...used by different herds...
...to gain sustenance
from the green food...
...which surrounds us here
in our fertile Great Valley.
Spike tails and three horns...
...employ
the cranio-impactus method...
...ramming trees
with their heads...
...to make tree stars fall.
Fliers use their wings
to fly to
the tiptop branches--
I know how longnecks do it!
Yes, Littlefoot, so do I...
...but I am not talking
about longnecks at the moment.
Now, where was I?
Three horns,
longnecks, spike tails...
Oh, yes.
MR. THICKNOSE:
But perhaps the most--
DUCKY: No, no, no!
-What is it now?
-Spike ate my
special tree stars.
My mom gave them just to me.
[Spike burps]
All these interruptions.
I can't think straight!
Here, you two move
away from each other.
Ducky, you go here.
Spike, over there.
And a perfect example of
what I was just relating.
Notice that some of
the spike tails graze...
...while others are using
the cranio-impactus method...
...I spoke of earlier.
These spike
tails are wanderers.
They come to the Great Valley
every now and then
on their travels...
...searching for food.
Luckily, we have
plenty here for all...
...and peaceful
visitors are welcome.
To continue. Food gathering.
Perhaps the most interesting
technique of all...
...is that used
by hollow horns.
They bellow so
loudly through the horns
on their heads...
...that tree stars
just fall all around them.
Of course, some trees
will not give up their
green food so easily.
Perhaps the most
reluctant is this one here,
just above me.
Its broad,
pointed, leafy greens...
...though
succulent to the taste...
...often prove too
frustrating to the--
[Loud blast, Mr.
Thicknose yells]
[All yell]
What do you know?
It works!
LITTLEFOOT: I don't know why
Mr. Thicknose even
bothers to talk to us.
-We just seem to upset him.
-What do you mean, "we"?
You really think Mr.
Thicknose upset?
Well, how would you feel
if someone dropped a big old
piece of fruit on your head?
Me don't know.
Me do now.
Come on, Littlefoot.
Forget it.
Pass the ball!
Well...
Over here!
[Dinosaurs all laugh]
What's wrong with you?
I do not know.
I feel funny.
Funny good or funny bad?
Funny bad. In here.
You think maybe you're sick?
I feel like there is
something inside my tummy...
...which is hot, hot, hot...
...like the bubbling waters
inside the mountain
that blows its top.
Oh, that!
-You're not sick.
-Oh, good.
Then what is wrong with me?
Nothing. You're just mad.
-Mad?
-Yeah.
Really?
What do you know? I am mad.
-Who am I mad at?
-Don't you know?
DUCKY: Well, let me see.
LITTLEFOOT: There it goes!
PETRIE: Me got it!
LITTLEFOOT: Spike, no!
PETRIE: Over here!
PETRIE: Me get another one.
[Spike burps]
I know, all right.
I am mad at Spike.
-What do I do now?
-You came to the right place.
If there's one thing us
three horns know about,
it's being mad!
[Lighthearted
instrumental music]
Hiya!
Now remember,
Tippy, bolt your food.
That way, you can eat more.
Look, Mama! Friend!
Why, hello there.
I didn't know there
were any spike tails
around here. How nice!
We just arrived ourselves.
You and your family
must come over and see us.
-Friend!
-Yes, he seemed very sweet.
[Ducky makes growling sounds]
That's not too bad.
Only make your mouth
go down more at the sides.
It does not go
down any farther.
Look, if you're
going to feel mad...
...you have to
look mad and act mad.
But I do not know how.
I can see we have to
start at the beginning.
"When your tummy
feels all sticky and hot
"Like it's
filled with bubbly goo
"And those fuzzy,
buzzy things inside your head
"Make you sad and blue
"Don't go around pretending
"That there's
nothing wrong with you
"When you feel that
prickly ick-ily thing
-"Do what the three horns do"
-What do you do?
"We get mad"
How do you do that?
"First, make your face
all squirmy and scary
"Don't raise up your head
"Hold your breath
until you're blue
"And make your eyes turn red
"Squint your face up,
wrinkle your beak
"Like you just
smelled something bad
"Turn your smiley
face upside down
"That's the way you look
"when you're mad
"Now,
put your hands on your hips
Shoulders back
"Stomp your feet in the dirt
"Kick some rocks,
but not too hard
"'Cause that can really hurt
"Pretend that
you're a sharp tooth
"I could pretend I am your dad
"Grumble and mumble
and growl real loud
"That's the way you sound
"When you're mad
"When there's mad
inside you or sad inside you
"You've got to let
what's inside out
"Give a big old snort,
and stamp your feet
"Stick up your beak and shout
-"Say, 'No!'
-"No!
-"Say, 'Grrr!'
-"Grrr!
-"Say, 'No! Grrr!'
-"No! Grrr!
"Now you're angry!"
And once you get mad,
you've got to stay mad.
Don't give an inch.
-But what if I
start to feel better?
-No!
-You hold your
grudge until they grovel.
-Until they what?
-Grovel!
-Oh. All right,
then, but I do not--
"And when you're really,
really, really, really mad
"And you've got
to let off steam
"Take a deep breath
"Throw back your head
"Stand on your toes
"And scream"
She's mad at somebody.
See?
I did not know being
mad was such hard work.
[Lively instrumental music]
Hey, Grandpa, I...
Oh, no.
He seems quite bright,
but regrettably...
...I find that he has
a very negative attitude.
He doesn't seem
to realize that...
...I am the oldest and
wisest in the Great Valley.
He needs to
learn some respect.
Littlefoot, is that you?
Yes, Grandpa.
GRANDPA:
Your grandmother was
beginning to worry.
I'm sorry.
Are you mad at me, Grandpa?
Why would I be mad
at you, Littlefoot?
I saw you talking to Mr.
Thicknose.
Oh, Littlefoot, I know
you're not disrespectful.
But for some reason, you've
gotten off on the wrong foot
with Mr. Thicknose.
I don't know why.
I try to listen and
ask good questions.
Sometimes I think he
just doesn't like kids.
Yet, Mr.
Thicknose volunteered...
...to share his wisdom
with you young ones...
...to give you the benefit
of all the knowledge...
...that he's gained
through the years.
I know.
[Littlefoot giggles]
You know, Littlefoot...
...Grandma and I have you...
...but Mr.
Thicknose has nobody.
Really, he has
nothing but his dignity.
Dignity? What's that?
It's the feeling
that you're appreciated.
That you have
something to offer,
and others know it.
It's a very important feeling,
Littlefoot.
You should never do anything
to rob someone of it.
I won't, Grandpa.
And I won't say anything
to Grandma about this.
It'll be our little secret.
Thanks, Grandpa.
[Sound of snoring]
[Mystical instrumental music]
LITTLEFOOT: Wow!
Wow!
[Littlefoot laughs gaily]
So beautiful.
What's that?
Frozen sky stars
falling on your head?
And when you touch them,
they turn to water.
[Chuckling]
Now, Littlefoot, really.
Such a thing is
not unheard of...
...but never in
the Great Valley.
Only in distant places
that far walkers come
here to get away from.
But I saw it! I...
Okay. Sorry.
Very well.
Now, to return to our
previous discussion.
You believe me, don't you?
Oh, sure. Me believe you.
But then, me believe anything.
[Laughing] Roar!
Look at me!
[Laughing] Roar! Roar! Roar!
[All dinosaurs laughing gaily]
I am a swimming sharp tooth.
Roar!
[Spike sighs sadly]
[Dinosaurs continue
laughing playfully]
[Melancholy
instrumental music]
Ducky,
I think Spike feels left out.
I cannot help it if I
can swim, but Spike cannot.
I am a swimmer, and he is not.
No, no, no.
Hiya! Hiya!
Well, hello there.
We meet again!
And where is
your family, dear?
DUCKY'S MOM: Hello.
-I'm his mother.
-Really? How nice!
Well, you see,
Spike lost his parents and--
Spike! Is that his name?
-Spike, Spike, Spike!
-Yes. Anyway...
...there were no
other spike tails
in the Valley, and--
-Until now.
-Well, yes.
-And so you took him in?
-That's right.
-Oh, I think that's wonderful.
-Well, of course,
it hasn't always been easy.
Hey, look out, you two!
Move over! Watch it!
Mama! Mama!
DUCKY'S MOM:
Oh, Ducky, just swim, dear.
TIPPY'S MOM:
It just occurred to me...
Do you think Spike
would enjoy visiting my herd?
Yeah, yeah! Visit!
-Why, I don't--
-Well, no. I mean,
just for the day. He could...
Well, he could see
how his own kind live.
Oh.
Would you like that, Spike?
Uh-huh.
Goodie! Goodie!
Well, I'll have him back
before the great
circle leaves the sky.
Come along, boys.
[Spike mumbles gratitude]
Visit! Fun!
And if you enjoy
your day today...
...perhaps you
could even stay longer.
[Reflective
instrumental music]
Shall we go back
in the water, Ducky?
Maybe later.
[Spike and
Tippy laugh merrily]
[Playful instrumental music]
[Poignant instrumental music]
[Spike and Tippy
laugh and chuckle]
That's right.
Spike lost his parents...
[Touching instrumental music]
[Sound of dinosaurs snoring]
[Mystical instrumental music]
DUCKY: Mama, what is it?
DUCKY: Am I dreaming?
DUCKY'S MOM: No, dear.
DUCKY'S MOM: It's real.
DUCKY: It is all sparkly.
DUCKY'S MOM: It's beautiful!
Do you think Spike can see it?
DUCKY'S MOM:
I'm sure he can, Ducky.
[Puzzled sounds from Spike]
I told them! Wow!
[Littlefoot laughs gaily]
Have you ever seen
this before, dear?
No, but I've heard of it.
This is what the wanderers
come to the Great
Valley to escape.
And now it's come here, too.
We need to talk to Mr.
Thicknose.
MR. THICKNOSE: Well...
I've never
known this to happen
in the Great Valley.
-In all my years--
-So why is it happening now?
This stuff is horrible!
It's everywhere!
I'll say. It's so slippery...
...I almost couldn't make it
up the hill from my nest.
Yeah! He slid
backwards right into my nose!
[Laughing] It
was really funny.
See?
White sparkles from the sky,
just like I told you!
CERA'S DAD: What did you say?
Go ahead, Littlefoot.
I just...
...saw the white sparkles fall
the other night, and told--
Told who? Who did you tell?
My friends. And Mr. Thicknose.
[General mumbling]
You knew this
stuff was falling?
The boy said something...
...but it seemed so unlikely--
We're really
disappointed in you.
We thought you
knew everything.
So did I.
GRANDPA:
Here come the spike tails.
[Dinosaurs
greeting the newcomers]
You folks are wanderers.
You must've seen
this stuff before.
Oh, yes. When
the frozen sky stars fall,
well, that's when we leave.
But that's just us.
You know, we pretty
much eat all the time...
...and green stuff is
a bit harder to find
under all this.
TIPPY'S DAD: Oh, yeah.
TIPPY'S MOM: I think
here in the Great Valley...
...they will turn
to water very soon.
Cut it out, Spike!
I do not like that.
Hey, that look like fun!
[Dinosaurs laugh delightedly]
Watch it, kid!
Me sorry.
[Spirited instrumental music]
I'll get you for that!
Keep them coming, guys!
Hey!
-Good shot, Mom!
-Happy to help, dear.
Hey, longneck, here it comes!
[Child
dinosaurs laugh merrily]
Well,
time to head for the nest.
PETRIE:
Good night, Littlefoot.
LITTLEFOOT: 'Bye.
CERA: Good night. See you.
PETRIE: Good night, Ducky.
DUCKY: Good night!
PETRIE: Good night, Spike.
This was a good day.
Yep.
Come on, Spike.
Let us go home.
If you'd like to stay
another night, it's okay.
Yay! Yay!
TIPPY'S MOM:
Well, come on, boys.
Let's go home.
[Poignant instrumental music]
I like the white
ground sparkles,
don't you, Grandpa?
Yes, Littlefoot, I do.
[Loud wind blows]
Do you still like the ground
sparkles, Littlefoot?
Maybe not as
much as I thought.
Wait, Littlefoot.
I see something you will like.
CERA'S DAD:
Back off, Thicknose!
But I'm so hungry.
So what? Everyone's hungry.
There's almost no food left,
and if you ask me,
it's all your fault!
Mine? But I...
Come, now.
You can't blame Mr.
Thicknose for the weather.
Well, maybe not.
But if he's so smart,
why didn't he know...
...that
the white ground sparkles
brought such cold...
...that it
killed all the food?
Why didn't he warn us to store
away some tree stars
until warmer weather?
But I couldn't!
I mean, how could I...
This has never
happened in the Valley before.
Why would you expect him
to know what it would be like?
Well, everybody says
he's been everywhere
and he knows everything.
If you ask me,
he doesn't know much at all.
I don't think he
should be allowed...
...to confuse the young ones
with his crackpot ideas!
-Gosh.
-Really, Mr. Three Horn.
I think you're
being unreasonable.
Well, I can't help it.
I'm hungry!
That's why we've
decided to leave.
Now, don't get me wrong.
Just because I was
yelling at him...
Nobody said you have to go.
I know, but there's
hardly enough food...
...for those who
live here all the time.
We spike tails eat
more than our fair share
as it is.
Besides,
we're used to moving around.
And we'll be gone tomorrow
before the great
circle is high in the sky.
GRANDPA: Good luck.
I hope you find food.
TIPPY'S DAD: Well,
we can't do worse than here.
-Hey, wake up.
You hear the news?
-What?
The spike tails are
leaving the Great Valley.
Yes!
GRANDPA: Good luck to you all.
Do not worry, Spike.
I am sure they will
come back someday.
TIPPY:
[Laughing happily] Spike!
I'm sorry this happened.
Not all of us want you to go.
We'll be all right.
We're wanderers.
I don't know
quite how to ask this,
but would he...
What? Why,
no, I'm sure he wouldn't.
I mean, we're his family.
He...
I'll ask him.
Do you want to go
with them, Spike?
We'll understand if you do.
DUCKY'S MOM:
We just want
what's best for you.
[Poignant instrumental music]
If it is so hard to figure
out, I will do it for you.
Go!
Oh, boy!
Good-bye, Spike.
We'll miss you.
We'll come back someday soon,
won't we, Spike?
When the white ground
sparkles are all gone.
Why, we'll see each
other before you know it.
[Spike laughs]
[Poignant
instrumental music continues]
I do not understand why Spike
would leave his own family.
I mean,
then what is a family anyway?
"Is it someone
who looks like us?
who acts like us?
"Is it someone
who sleeps beside us
"In a nest?
"Is it someone
who speaks like us?
"Has a tail or beak like us?
"Or is it someone
that we like the best?
"I think family, family
"Is more than being friends
"When you're family, family
"The loving never ends"
I can't believe
Spike is really leaving.
Maybe he wants to go
with them. After all,
we're not his family.
"He doesn't look like us
"He doesn't eat like us
"Yes,
but he still likes to play
The way we do
"He doesn't walk like us
"He doesn't talk at all
"But just think
of all the things
"That we've been through
"He's family, family
"Though he may go away
"He has always been our family
"And family he'll stay
"I guess someone that you like
"Can make you angry
"That's something that
we have to rise above
ALL: "Though
families are different
"One thing stays the same
"At the heart of every family
"Is love
"And a family, a family
"Is something strong and fine
"You will always be
part of his family
DUCKY: "And he will always be
"A very, very big part
"of my
"family"
DUCKY'S MOM:
Ducky, it's for his own good.
Spike needs more
food than we do.
DUCKY: I know.
DUCKY'S MOM:
Besides, they'll be back.
-You heard what
Tippy's mom said.
-I know.
DUCKY'S MOM: He's never
had a chance to spend time
with other spike tails.
DUCKY'S MOM: He needs
to be with his own kind.
DUCKY: I know!
And it's clear
that they love Spike.
They're patient and kind and--
-I know, okay? I know!
-Ducky!
I am sorry, Mama.
That's okay, dear.
I understand.
We told Mr. Thicknose...
...we would meet
with him one last time.
-Is it all right for me to go?
-Of course, dear.
[Dramatic instrumental music]
Oh, me sure gonna miss Spike!
Yeah. Me, too.
Hey, if he found some
friends he liked better,
that's his business.
I'll bet it won't be long
before we forget
what he even looks like.
Well, maybe not.
DUCKY MOM: Hi, kids.
-Hello, Ducky Mom.
-Hi.
Where's Ducky?
Is Mr. Thicknose gone?
Huh?
I was so glad when Ducky
told me he was meeting with
you children today.
It's given her something
to think about besides Spike.
-You miss him, too.
-We sure do.
Yeah. So do I.
Well, I should go.
She's probably already waiting
for me back at the nest.
-'Bye, kids. Stay warm.
-'Bye!
Why would Ducky tell her mom
we were meeting
with Thicknose?
That not true!
I don't know.
Maybe she didn't
want her mom to know
where she was going.
Where was that?
I bet I know.
DUCKY: Spike!
[Dramatic instrumental music]
I did not think spike
tails could walk so fast.
No, no, no.
Careful. Slippery here.
[Spike sighs sadly]
Tippy, Spike, don't lag.
[Spike and Tippy crying out]
[Lively instrumental music]
What is going on back...
Fun, fun, fun!
[General groaning]
[Dinosaur in group] My back!
So, if Ducky's
gone after Spike...
...why don't we
just tell her mom?
I may be wrong,
and there's no point in
getting her all worried.
CERA: Earth-shake!
What do you
think you're doing?
Mr. Thicknose?
Oh. Hello, children.
What are you doing up
here all by yourself?
Please, Littlefoot.
No more questions.
Littlefoot, come on.
We have to find Ducky
and get back before
the grownups miss us.
Yeah, okay.
LITTLEFOOT: 'Bye, Mr.
Thicknose.
[Melancholy
instrumental music]
Yep.
Ducky come this way for sure.
Well, here we go.
MR. THICKNOSE: Children!
CERA: Mr. Thicknose?
Am I correct in
understanding...
...that you are going
into the Mysterious Beyond...
-...without your
parents' permission?
-No.
-Yes.
-Maybe.
Okay, yes, but we've got to.
Ducky's out there somewhere.
I absolutely cannot allow it.
LITTLEFOOT: But--
MR. THICKNOSE:
If your families found out...
...that I let you leave
the Valley unsupervised...
...I could never show my
face around here again.
Therefore,
I'm coming with you.
-You are?
-Huh?
Great.
MR. THICKNOSE: Children...
...wait up, please.
I'm not as young
as I used to be.
-He's not as young
as anybody used to be.
-Don't be mean.
Why do we have to
let him come along?
Because if we don't,
he'll tell the grownups.
Besides, he's been everywhere
and seen everything.
He can help us find our way
through the Mysterious Beyond.
Me sure hope so.
-There it is.
-Here are
the spike tails' tracks.
Looks like Ducky followed
them out of the Valley.
Then let us follow
those tracks as well.
The spike tails
can't be too far ahead.
They move
awfully slow, you know.
Yeah, unlike us.
Me got idea.
Me fly up, look,
see if I spot Ducky up ahead.
I was just about
to suggest that.
-No see nothing yet.
-Fly higher!
Still no nothing.
Getting real cold up here.
[Petrie chitters]
-What's
the matter with Petrie?
-He's sure flying funny.
Gracious. There's
frozen water on his wings.
Wings so heavy.
Can't move them.
Petrie!
[Petrie cries out]
I can't look!
[Dramatic instrumental music]
-He made it!
-Yes!
Oh, my. That was a close one.
Me okay!
[Sound of creaking]
What is that noise?
Don't look at me.
[Loud rumbling noise]
[Petrie yells]
LITTLEFOOT: Look out!
CERA: Run!
LITTLEFOOT: Come on! This way!
CERA: Let's go!
LITTLEFOOT: Move!
LITTLEFOOT: Faster! Faster!
Are you all right, children?
-Yeah.
-Me, too.
Me, three.
-Oh, my goodness.
-What?
The pass into the Valley.
MR. THICKNOSE: It's gone.
CERA: We're trapped out here?
And so are Spike and Ducky.
DUCKY: I will just say,
"That is all right, Spike.
I forgive you."
And he will come back with me.
But what if he
does not forgive me?
Oh, no, no, no.
At least spike tail foot
holes are easy to follow.
Whoa!
These are not
spike tail foot holes.
I hope whatever
made these foot holes
just kept on going.
Yep, yep, yep.
It sure is lonesome out here.
[Echoing] Spike!
Hey! That is funny.
A talk-back. Spike!
Even my walking
has a talk-back.
[Loud thudding]
[Ducky screams]
[Dramatic instrumental music]
Look at those rock formations.
Can you imagine
how long they've
been standing there?
Almost as if they've
been waiting for us.
I know just how they feel.
MR. THICKNOSE:
Beautiful. Simply beautiful.
I've never seen
anything like it.
-Never?
-Why, no. I...
That is...
Mr. Thicknose,
I hate to ask this...
...but is this your first trip
to the Mysterious Beyond?
Why, I, well, I...
[Ducky screaming]
Ducky!
[Suspenseful
instrumental music]
MR. THICKNOSE: Oh, dear.
Petrie, Cera, help me!
[Suspenseful
instrumental music continues]
LITTLEFOOT: Hey, ugly.
Want to play?
CERA: Mr. Thicknose!
Get out of the way!
I beg your pardon!
Oh, I see.
[Whoops of joy and laughter]
Well done!
I am so happy to see you.
Yep, yep, yep. Except you.
This is all your fault.
You told me to be angry,
and now look what happened.
Me? But I just told you
to express your feelings.
I know.
And my feelings were mad.
I am sorry. I do not want
to be mad at you either.
I do not like being mad.
No, no, no.
Well, did you find Spike?
Well, at least Mr.
Thicknose is here
to help us find our way.
Yes, well, I'm afraid that...
That is...
I think the time has
come for me to confess.
You see....
How should I put this?
The actual extent
of my experiences...
...outside
the Great Valley is...
...somewhat less than
I've led you to believe.
You mean, you not
been in Mysterious Beyond
as much as everyone think?
-That is correct.
-How many times
have you been out here?
Counting this trip? Once.
[Gasps of disappointment]
LITTLEFOOT: How could
things get any worse?
CERA:
You had to ask, didn't you?
Why, no, dear. We
haven't seen Ducky anywhere.
DUCKY'S MOM: I'm so worried.
It's getting late.
GRANDPA:
Would you like me
to help look for her?
No. You just rest
and try to keep warm.
She's probably with
Littlefoot and the others.
GRANDMA:
Oh, I hope they
haven't wandered far...
...in weather like this.
DUCKY: Spike!
Ducky!
Cera!
Petrie!
Littlefoot!
I'm glad that's over.
Me cold.
-And hungry.
-And thirsty.
I would love some
water right now.
Me, too.
There is water.
That water is hard.
Hey. This like
what got on my wings.
[Mr. Thicknose cries out]
Mr. Thicknose! Come back!
Wait for us!
[All crying out]
DUCKY: No, no, no!
PETRIE: Stop, stop, stop!
That's not good.
[All shouting and screaming]
My goodness.
This is quite warm.
And not deep.
I'm standing on the bottom.
Me, too! Well, sort of.
This feels so good.
Why is it all warm
like this, Mr. Thicknose?
Why, it appears to be
some sort of
underground spring.
See? There's hot water
just bubbling up down there.
Even the rocks are warm.
Mr. Thicknose, have you
ever seen a place like...
No, I guess not.
I regret to say I haven't.
But I've heard of them
from wandering herds who've
passed through the Valley...
...and I seem to recall...
...that where there
is warmth and water...
MR. THICKNOSE:
...there is likely to be--
CERA: Green food.
Not bad.
-Mr. Thicknose?
-Yes, Littlefoot?
How come you tell
all those fibs...
...about how
you've been everywhere
and seen everything?
You know, Littlefoot,
I never intended to
become such a fibber.
It just...
...happened.
"When I was young,
I was very shy
"Never seen or heard
"But when wanderers
told of the Great Beyond
"I remembered every word
"As I grew older
"I told those stories as
if I had lived them, too
"In everyone's eyes
"I was good, I was wise
"To everyone
"But you"
That is why I had
such a hard time
with you, Littlefoot.
You're so curious, so bright,
you asked such good questions.
I was afraid you
would catch me in a lie,
discover my secret.
-Rob you of your dignity?
-Yes, I suppose so.
You see, "Everyone
wants to be important
"Everyone wants to be heard
"Everyone wants to be
the center of the circle
"Where friends are
hanging on your every word
"No matter how
close you are to an egg
"Or how old you grow to be
"Everybody needs
somebody to listen
"Even somebody like me
[Slow but rhythmic
instrumental music]
"Everyone wants
to be respected
"Everyone wants to be liked
"Whether you've got
three horns on your head
-"Or a beak that's sharp
-"Or a tail that's spiked
"When you want to
be more fascinating
"You might say things
that aren't quite true
"Everyone's
tempted to fib sometimes
"Even someone good like you
ALL:
"We want folks to admire us
"We want someone to care
"We want to make a difference
"And to know that
others know we're there
"But everyone has
their own importance
"That's what I've come to see
"Everyone has
their own special place
-"In the nest
-"In the herd
"In the family
"Respect's not a thing
"You can make someone give you
"It's something
you have to earn
"Who would've thought
"After all this time
"There were more
things I had to learn"
And thank you all
for teaching me.
"You're never
"too old
"to learn"
I wish
the grownups could be here
and eat this food.
-And Spike.
-Yeah. And Spike.
I bet there's enough green
food to last us all until
the ground sparkles go away.
But pass in the Valley closed.
Remember?
The grownups are
all trapped inside,
and we are stuck out here.
And lost.
No. Not lost.
I know that tall, rocky place.
That is, I've never
seen it, of course...
...but it's been
described to me
by many a traveler.
The Valley is just
on the other side.
I know exactly where we are.
Not that it does us any good.
ALL: Huh?
Wait.
You're not thinking that--
[All murmur accent]
But we can't!
I mean, our type of
creature doesn't...
We can't climb
something like that!
Can we?
[Loud wind blows]
It's no use. After that storm,
I'm completely lost.
And exhausted.
Oh, don't cry, Tippy.
We'll find food.
Just you wait.
Oh, Spike.
You, too? I'm so sorry. I...
[Spike makes sniffing sounds]
Do you smell something, Spike?
You smell food?
Do you think you can find it?
[Spike mumbles accent]
TIPPY'S MOM:
Spike knows where to go.
I say we follow him.
Follow him? He's just a kid.
What have we got to lose?
Okay, Spike, lead the way.
TIPPY: Spike, wait for me!
Oh, it's no good.
Why don't you
just leave me here?
-We can't do that.
-I'm slowing you down.
And frankly, I don't
think I can go another step.
Of course, I could be wrong.
[Suspenseful
instrumental music]
[Dinosaurs screaming]
What going on down...
LITTLEFOOT: Cera, hurry.
Let's go!
CERA: I'm hurrying, okay?
What am I doing?
I should be
protecting these young ones...
...not running like a ninny.
[Dinosaurs screaming]
[Tyrannosaurus bellows]
That gotta hurt.
Mr. Thicknose?
Thanks.
I'm delighted to
have returned the favor.
We owe that sharp
tooth our thanks as well.
He provided just
the boost I needed
to get to the top.
We made it!
Over there. The pass!
Through the mountains!
Why, yes.
Just beyond that rock bridge.
We could walk to it.
So what? It's all
blocked up, thanks to Petrie.
No go there.
We are almost home.
But how do we get our
folks to the hot springs?
Grandma and Grandpa
could never
climb this mountain.
If only there were
a way to clear the pass.
Oh, me no want to
hit mountain again.
Maybe you won't have to.
Mr. Thicknose?
Do you remember teaching us
about the way hollow
horns make tree stars fall?
Brilliant!
Littlefoot!
-Any sign?
-I can't find them anywhere.
[Dinosaurs
calling out in distance]
That's funny.
Sounds just like Ducky.
And Littlefoot.
Cera?
[Shouting for attention]
It not working.
We're not loud enough.
DUCKY: But you are.
Cera, get mad at
the white ground sparkles.
Huh?
Get really mad.
Really, really mad.
Oh, yeah. Okay.
[Cera shouts loudly]
Up there!
-You went where?
-You did what?
It's okay.
Mr. Thicknose was
with us the whole time.
Oh, yeah.
I'm sure he was a big help.
He was.
After all, he's the oldest
and wisest of us all.
[Adults gasp]
-Sorry.
-That's okay.
You've still got
some explaining to do,
young lady.
I know, Daddy.
But wouldn't you
rather listen while you eat?
CERA'S DAD: Did you say "eat"?
-How are you feeling?
-Better than I have in ages.
Thanks to
Littlefoot and his friends.
Yeah, you kids did okay.
-You too, Thicknose.
-How gracious of you.
Mr. Longneck,
I take back all that I
said about Littlefoot.
He's quite
a remarkable young one.
-You should be very proud.
-We are.
Thanks, Mr. Thicknose.
You wish Spike
were here, don't you?
I would not even complain
when he hogs the nest.
No.
If only he could...
[Spirited instrumental music]
Spike?
LITTLEFOOT: Spike!
DUCKY: You're back! All right!
My goodness!
Is there enough to share?
Now, you...
Of course. You're welcome.
[Dinosaurs laugh and chatter]
I never thought I'd see them
playing together again.
It's a wonderful sight.
Whoa!
LITTLEFOOT: Spike! Be careful!
Spike!
DUCKY: Oh, no, Spike!
CERA:
The water is deeper there!
DUCKY: Spike cannot swim!
GRANDPA: Somebody help him.
[Suspenseful
instrumental music]
Mama!
[Gasps loudly]
LITTLEFOOT: She got him! Yes!
[All dinosaurs cheer]
That is my mama.
My mama did that.
Yep, yep, yep.
[Spike coughs]
Mama, you did it!
You saved him!
Of course I did. He's my boy.
It's obvious who
Spike's real family is.
We'll always be grateful
that you saved our herd.
And you can visit
us anytime you like.
Right, Tippy?
Tippy loves Spike!
Ducky loves Spike, too.
From now on,
you can make all
the sleep rumbles you want.
And I will never get
mad again. No, no, no.
[Dinosaurs all
laugh and cheer]
MALE NARRATOR:
The families
would be happy here...
...until the great circle
began to warm
the land once more...
...melting
the white ground sparkles...
...and allowing new
life to spring up...
...turning
the Earth green again.
Then they could return
to the Great Valley...
...where they could all
get a good night's sleep.
Even Ducky.
[Climactic instrumental music]
[Soft
instrumental music plays]