Through the snow and
sleet and hail...
through the blizzard,
through the gale...
through the wind and
through the rain...
over mountain, over plain...
through the blinding
lightning flash...
and the mighty thunder crash...
ever faithful, ever true...
nothing stops him.
He'll get through.
Look out for Mr Stork
that persevering chap.
He'll come along and drop
a bundle in your lap.
You may be poor or rich
It doesn't matter which.
Millionaires, they get theirs
like the butcher and the baker.
So look out for Mr Stork and
let me tell you, friend.
Don't try to get away He'll
find you in the end.
He'll spot you out in China
or he'll fly to County Cork.
So you'd better look
out for Mr Stork.
Look out for Mr Stork
He's got you on his list.
And when he comes around
it's useless to resist.
Remember those quintuplets
and the woman in the shoe.
Maybe he's got his eye on you.
All aboard! All aboard!
All aboard! Let's go!
Casey Junior's
comin'down the track.
Comin'down the track
with a smoky stack.
Hear him puffin'
comin'round the hill.
Casey's here to thrill
every Jack and Jill.
Every time his funny
little whistle sounds.
Everybody hurries to
the circus grounds.
Time for lemonade
and CrackerJack.
Casey Junior's back
Casey Junior's back.
Oh. My, my.
Now let me see.
Must be right around
here somewhere.
I hope. Ah, watch it there.
On the treetop.
Where are we here? Oh, here.
Highway 61, four miles
to the gas station.
Turn left Da-da da-da-da de.
Ah. That must be it.
Well, little fella,
let's get going.
Mrs Jumbo. Oh, Mrs Jumbo.
Calling Mrs Jumbo.
Mrs Jumbo?
Oh. My.
Mrs Jumbo!
- Oh, where's that Mrs Jum...
- Yoo-hoo! Yoo-hoo!
- Over here.
- This way, boy.
- In here! In here!
- Yoo-hoo!
- This is the place.
- Whew! At last.
Which one of you
ladies is expecting?
- Hmph! Not me.
- The very idea.
Certainly not. Over
there, of course.
Yes, of course.
Right over there.
Oh. Of course.
Here is a baby with
eyes of blue...
straight from heaven
right to you.
Or: Straight from
heaven up above...
here is a baby for you to love.
Sign here, please.
Uh, yeah. Well... Oh. Mrs Jumbo.
Uh, one moment, please. This
is still part of the service.
Happy Birthday to you.
Ah, Happy Birthday to you.
Ah, Happy Birthday, dear.
Ah, dear Dear me.
What's his name?
Jumbo. Junior.
Oh. Jumbo Junior, huh?
Ahem. Jumbo Junior.
Happy Birthday,
dearJumbo Junior.
Happy Birthday.
To-oo-oo-oo-oo-oo-oo-oo.
You.
- Oh, do hurry, dear.
- I'm on pins and needles.
- Isn't it thrilling?
- I'm all a-flutter.
Ah, this is a proud, proud day.
- Well, hurry and open it, dearie.
- I'm just dying to see.
- Oh!
- Look at him!
Look at him!
Oh, what a... Oh, look!
- Oh, you sweet little thing.
- He is cute, isn't he?
Oh, he is a darling little baby.
Adorable. Simply adorable.
Did you ever see
anything so cunning?
Isn't he a darling!
Kootchy, kootchy, kootchy,
kootchy, kootchy, kootchy.
- Oh!
- Is it possible?
- Isn't there some mistake?
Just look at those, those...
E-A-R-S.
Those what? Oh, ears!
These! Aren't they funny? Oh!
- Oh, my goodness.
- What a temper.
Oh, what did I do?
Well, tell me.
- Did I say anything?
- Perfectly harmless remark.
I just said that they're
funny, and they are funny.
- They certainly are.
- After all, who cares...
about her precious little Jumbo?
Jumbo? You mean Dumbo.
Dumbo.
- Dumbo, I say.
- That's good.
- Dumbo! That's good.
- Dumbo.
I think I can. I think I can.
I think I can. I think
I can. I think I can.
I thought I could. I thought I could.
Whoo-woo!
Hike, ugh, hike, ugh
hike, ugh, hike.
We work all day We
work all night.
We never learned
to read or write.
We're happy-hearted roustabouts.
Hike, ugh, hike, ugh
hike, ugh, hike.
When other folks
have gone to bed.
We slave until
we're almost dead.
We're happy-hearted roustabouts.
Hike, ugh, hike, ugh
hike, ugh, hike.
We don't know when
we get our pay.
And when we do we
throw our pay away.
When we get our pay we
throw our money all away.
We get our pay
when children say.
With happy hearts It's
circus day today.
Then we get our pay just
watching kids on circus day.
Muscles aching Back
near breaking.
Eggs and bacon's what we need.
- Yes, sir!
- Boss man hounding.
Keep on pounding.
For your bread and keep.
There ain't no letup.
Got to set up.
Pull that canvas.
Drive that stake.
Want to doze off Get
them clothes off.
But must keep awake.
Hep! Heave! Hep! Heave!
Hep! Heave! Hep!
Swing that sledge
Sing that song.
Work and laugh the
whole night long.
You happy-hearted roustabouts.
Pulling, pounding
tying, grounding.
Big top roundin'into shape.
Keep on working
Stop that shirking.
Grab that rope, you hairy ape.
Pounding, pounding.
Oh.
Jostling and juggling.
Fifteen minutes!
Step right up and get your
tickets. Hurry, hurry now.
Hurry to the big sideshow. That's
why you go under the big top.
Fifteen big attractions that you can't
see anywhere else in the world!
The greatest collection
in the entire world.
And the greatest comedies are featured
and assembled for your entertainment.
Ain't that the funniest thing
you ever saw? Look at his ears.
Hey, guys, look it!
Smitty's an elephant!
- Aw, let me see!
- Boo!
- You can't hide him from us.
- Yeah, his ears are still sticking out.
- Come on!
- We wanna see him!
- We wanna laugh.
- Sure, that's what we came for.
Hey, the biggest
slingshot in the world.
- Hey! Cut that out!
- Hey, let's get out of here.
- You're hurting me! Help!
- Here, you! What's going on?
Down. Mrs Jumbo, down!
Surround her. Tie her down.
Get down!
Calm down! Tie her down!
Darling, it was so funny.
Oh, my dear, can you bear it?
When she doused the ringmaster,
I just thought I'd die.
Well, personally, I think
she went a bit too far.
After all, one mustn't
forget one is a lady.
- Oh, you're right, dear. Yes.
- Oh, that's very true.
Oh, well, I suppose
that's mother love.
But it's certainly no
excuse for what she did.
Mother love might cover
a multitude of sins.
It's true, my dear, and she
has such a streak in...
A guy can't eat in peace.
Yes, but mother love does...
Gab, gab, gab. Always gossiping.
Girls, girls! Listen!
Have I got a trunk full of dirt.
- Well, darling, tell us all.
- Go on, go on.
Well, I heard today that they have
put her in solitary confinement.
- No!
- You don't mean it!
Oh, how awful for her!
Well, I-I must say, I-I don't
blame her for anything.
You're absolutely right. It's
all the fault of that little...
F-R-E-A-K.
Yes, him with those ears that
only a mother could love.
What's the matter with his ears?
I don't see nothing wrong with
'em. I think they're cute.
Ladies, ladies! It's no
laughing matter at all.
Oh. Oh, she's right, girls.
Don't forget that we elephants
have always walked with dignity.
His disgrace is our own shame.
- Yes, that's true. That's very true.
- Oh, indeed it is.
Well, frankly, I wouldn't eat at
the same bale of hay with him.
- No. Right.
- Me either, dearie.
- I should say.
- Nor I. That's just how I feel about it.
Here he comes now.
Hmm. Pretend you don't see him.
Shh.
How do ya like that? Giving
him the cold shoulder.
Poor little guy.
There he goes, without
a friend in the world.
Nobody to turn to.
Oh, I'll do something
about this.
A mouse!
So ya like to pick
on little guys, huh?
Well, why don't you pick on me?
A proud race.
Overstuffed hay bags!
Boo!
Still afraid of a mouse.
Ho-ho, boy. Wait'll I
tell the little guy.
Where is he? Oh. Hey, Dumbo.
You can come out now.
Golly. Maybe I scared him too.
Look, Dumbo. I'm your friend.
Come on out, won't ya?
You're not really afraid
of little me, are ya?
Ya are? Must've
overdid it in there.
Don't know my own
strength sometimes.
Dumbo. Look what I got for ya.
Uh-uh-uh-uh. Ya gotta
come out first.
Too bad ya don't trust
me, 'cause I thought...
uh, well, you... you and me, uh, we
might get your mother out of the clink.
Oh, but I guess you wouldn't
be interested. So long, Dumbo.
Well, that's more like it.
Ya know, your ma ain't crazy.
She's just broken-hearted.
It ain't nobody's fault
you got them big ears.
Uh-oh. Boy, I stepped
in it that time.
Aw, gee, Dumbo. I think
your ears are beautiful.
Sure. As a matter of fact, I
think they're very decorative.
You know, lots of people
with big ears are famous.
Ho-ho, boy. All we gotta
do is build an act.
Make ya a star. A headliner!
Dumbo the Great!
Uh-oh. The great what?
Ya know, Dumbo, we
gotta get an idea.
Not just any idea. Something
colossal, like, uh...
Have I got an idea!
What an idea!
Huh. He never had an
idea in his life.
Just visualize: One
elephant climbs up...
on top of another
elephant until finally...
all 17 elephants...
have constructed an
enormous pyramid...
of pachyderms.
I step out.
I blow the whistle.
- Yeah.
- The trumpets are trumpeting.
- And now...
comes the climax!
Yeah? What is the climax?
Hmm. I don't know.
I knew he never had nothing.
Well, maybe it comes to me...
in a vision while I dream.
- Good night, Joe.
- Good night, Boss.
Climax.
Climax! Dumbo, you're a climax.
I'll be back in a minute. I'm
gonna take care of your future.
I am the voice of your
subconscious mind.
Your inspiration.
Now, concentrate.
Remember? Your pyramid
of elephants...
are standing in the ring
waiting for a climax.
- Climax.
- You are now getting that climax.
- How's the reception?
Coming through okay? Good.
Suddenly, from the sidelines,
comes your climax.
- Climax.
- Galloping across the arena.
- Arena.
- He jumps from a springboard...
to a platform.
At the very pinnacle of your
pyramid, he waves a flag...
for a glorious finish!
- Finish?
- And who is your climax?
The little elephant
with the big ears!
The world's mightiest
midget mastodon! Dumbo!
What?
- Dumbo.
I got it! I got it!
Ladies and gentlemen...
we will now present for
your entertainment...
the most stupendous,
magnificent...
super-colossal spectacle.
On this tiny...
little, insignificant ball...
we will construct for you...
a pyramid, not of
wood, not of stone...
To hear him talk, you'd think
he was going to do it.
- But a living, breathing...
- The stuffed shirt.
Pyramid of ponderous,
pulsating...
pulchritudinous pachyderms!
I give you the elephants.
Aren't we a bit clumsy?
Gaining a little weight,
aren't you, honey?
You're no cream puff
yourself, dearie.
Quiet up there. Tend
to your work, girls.
Take your foot out of
my eye, clumsy ox.
Steady, girls.
Boy, that was a close one.
They're almost ready now, Dumbo.
Don't forget to wave that flag.
Okay, okay. Don't wave
it no more. I saw ya.
Now, look. All ya gotta
do is run out, see?
Jump on the springboard.
All right, now show me just
how you're gonna do it.
That's it. Attaboy. That's
the stuff. Come on.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh,
oh, oh, oh! Dumbo!
Oh, those ears. We gotta
do somethin', quick.
Ladies and gentlemen...
you have now seen
the impossible...
accomplished in front
of your faces.
Seven jungle giants...
each one weighing not...
That windbag!
- Why doesn't he come to the point?
- 7,500 pounds!
And now, I present...
the world's smallest
little elephant...
who will spring from
this springboard...
in one spring...
to the top of this pyramid,
waving his little flag...
for a grand climax!
Ladies and gentlemen...
I give you Dumbo!
Go on! Get goin'!
What's the matter with you?
Dumbo! That's your cue!
You're on, Dumbo.
Out of my way, assassin!
- Dear!
- Ohh.
I never thought I'd live
to see the big top fall.
Because of that Dumbo, I never
can show my face there again.
Oh, look at my beautiful tail!
I'd just like to spank the
daylights out of him...
Ah! Oh! Oh! Ohh.
Oh, that won't be
necessary, dearie.
They fixed him good.
- What do you mean?
- Wh-What did they do?
- Did they beat him?
- What is it, darling?
- Tell us.
- Come, come. I demand to know.
Oh. Well, they've
gone and made him...
- Oh, dear, I just can't say it.
- Out with it!
Made him a clown.
A clown?
- No!
- Yes.
Oh, the shame of it.
Let us take the solemn vow.
From now on, he is no longer...
an elephant.
Please! Help me
save my poor baby!
Whoo! Save my child!
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Where are you? Yoo-hoo!
Yoo-hoo! Yoo-hoo!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Save my ba...
- Come on! Jump!
- We'll save you. Hurry up!
- Hurry up!
- We'll save you. Go on.
- Jump!
- We'll save ya.
Whew! Boy, oh, boy, did
we wow 'em out there!
- What a performance!
- Are we good?
Thirteen curtain
calls. Thirteen!
Yeah, sure brought down
the house, all right.
Oh, Mama, did we panic 'em. Ask
me, Joey. Go ahead. Ask me.
You said it. We rolled
'em in the aisles.
- Boy, oh, boy, what a act.
- Oh, "what a act" is right.
Stupendous, I calls it.
They'll have more respect
for us clowns now.
- Yeah, yeah, you bet.
- Here, boys.
This calls for a real
celebration. Come and get it.
- Poison! Am I thirsty.
- I could use one of them myself.
- This one's on Dumbo.
- Yeah, Dumbo.
- Dumbo!
- Here's plaster in his eyes.
See? They're drinking
a toast to ya.
Yeah. You're a big hit.
Why, uh, you're terrific.
Oh, you're colossal. Stupendous.
Come on. Alley-oop. I gotta
wash behind your ears.
You ought a be proud.
You're a success.
Look. A peanut!
Come on. Eat it. Got
lots of vitamins.
Give ya a lot of, uh, pep.
Oh-ho-ho. I forgot to tell ya.
Why, we're goin' over
to see your mother.
I made an appointment for
ya. Didn't I tell ya? Huh!
Just like me. I must have
forgot. Come on. Get your hat.
Oh. Right over there.
Cosy little place, ain't it?
Mrs Jumbo. I hope she's in.
Someone to see ya.
Baby mine.
Don't you cry.
Dry your eyes.
Rest your head.
Close to my heart.
Never to part.
Baby of mine.
Little one.
When you play.
Don't you mind.
What they say.
Let those eyes.
Sparkle and shine.
Never a tear.
Baby of mine.
From your head.
To your toes.
Baby mine.
You're so sweet goodness knows.
You are so - Baby, baby, baby.
Precious to me - Mine.
Cute as can be baby of mine.
Baby mine.
Here ya are. Pour it
in me slipper, Joey.
Boy, I can't get over the way
we rolled 'em in the aisles.
- Just wait'll we hit the big town.
- This gives me an idea.
Let's raise the platform
the elephant jumps off of.
Yeah! If they laugh when
he jumps 20 feet...
they'll laugh twice as
hard if he jumps 40 feet.
- Yeah, that's right. That's right.
- Simple mathematics.
- Let's make it 80 feet.
- Don't be a piker. 180.
- Make it 300.
- A thousand.
- Yeah, that's good.
- Hey, be careful.
- You'll hurt the little guy.
- Aw, go on.
- Elephants ain't got no feelings.
- No, they're made of rubber.
This idea is sensational.
Let's go tell the boss.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Come on. Let's go.
Hey, hey! Let's hit
him for a raise.
Yeah, sure. This is
worth real dough.
Oh, we're gonna hit the
big boss for a raise.
Yes, we're gonna hit the
Oh, we're gonna get more money
'cause we know that we're funny.
We're gonna hit the
big boss for a raise
I know how ya feel, Dumbo, but you
gotta pull yourself together.
What would your mother think of ya,
if she saw you crying like this?
Remember, you come
of a proud race.
Why you're a-a-a...
a pachyderm...
and pachyderms don't cry.
What's cryin' get ya anyhow?
Nothin' but the hiccups.
There. Ya see?
Well, ain't nothing a
little water won't cure.
Oops-a-daisy. We'll have
ya fixed up in a jiffy.
Come on.
Here. Take a trunk full.
Listen, little fella.
We may have had a lot of
hard luck up till now...
but you and me is gonna
do big things together.
Hold your breath. Why, your
mother's gonna be so proud of ya.
I'm gonna be proud of ya too.
The whole circus is gonna be proud of
ya. Now, what do ya think of that?
Swallow it.
Ho-ho. They can't keep us down.
Oh, I guess you had one
little one left over.
Dumbo, we'll bounce
back so ha...
Hey, what's the matter with you?
What kind of water
is this, anyhow?
Balloonies.
Hiya, George.
Whee!
That's a pretty
schstrick schlick.
All right. Let's see ya
blow a square one, pal.
Say, that's very, very clever.
Now blow a great big one.
That's a pretty sh... Hey!
Dumbo.
You see what I see?
Look out, look out Pink
elephants on parade.
Here they come Hippity-hoppity.
They're here and there
Pink elephants everywhere.
Look out, look out.
They're walking around
the bed on their head.
Clippity-cloppity
Arrayed in braid.
Pink elephants on parade.
What'll I do - What'll I do.
What an unusual view.
I can stand the sight of worms
and look at microscopic germs.
But Technicolour pachyderms
is really too much for me.
I am not the type to faint.
When things are odd
or things are quaint.
But seein'things you
know there ain't.
Can certainly give
you an awful fright.
What a sight Chase 'em
away, chase 'em away.
I'm afraid, need your aid
Pink elephants on parade.
Hey, hey, hey - Pink elephants.
Pink elephants.
- Well, looky here, looky here.
- My, my.
Why, this is most irregular.
Well, I just can't
believe my eyes.
- They ain't dead, is they?
- No. Dead people don't snore.
Or do they?
Uh, wh-what's all the
ruckus? Come on.
Step aside, brother. Uh,
what's cooking 'round here?
What's the good news?
What's frying, boy?
- Just look down there, brother.
- And prepare yourself for a shock.
- Well, hush my beak!
- Go ahead. Wake 'em up, brother.
Yeah. Find out what
they're doing up here.
- Yeah.
- And "ax" them what they want.
Okay, boys. Leave it to me.
Ohh! Those pink elephants.
Ho! Pink elephants? Mm-mmm!
What's so funny? What are you
boys doing down here, anyway?
What are we doing down here?
Well, hear him talk.
Go on. Fly up a tree
where you belong.
- Say, look here, Brother Rat.
- Brother Rat?
Now listen. I ain't your brother
and I ain't no rat, see?
Uh-huh. And I suppose you...
and no elephant ain't
up in no tree, either.
No! No, me and no tree
ain't up no... Huh?
Tree?
Yo!
Dumbo.
Dumbo. Wake up.
Wake up, Dumbo!
Don't look now, but I
think we're up in a tree.
Aw, don't pay no attention
to them scarecrows.
Come on, Dumbo. Let's
get back to the circus.
So long, boy!
But I wonder how we ever got
up in that tree, anyway.
Now, let's see.
Elephants can't climb
trees, can they?
Nah, nah, that's ridiculous.
Couldn't jump up.
Mm-mm. It's too high.
Hey there, son. Maybe
you all flew up.
Maybe we flew up.
Yeah, maybe we...
That's it! Dumbo! You flew!
Boy, am I stupid. Why didn't
I think of this before?
Your ears. Just look at 'em,
Dumbo. Why, they're perfect wings.
The very things that held ya down are
gonna carry ya up and up and up!
I can see it all now.
Dumbo, the Ninth Wonder
of the Universe!
The world's only
flying elephant!
Did you ever see
an elephant fly?
- Well, I've seen a horsefly.
- Ah, I've seen a dragonfly.
- Hee-hee. I've seen a housefly.
- Yeah!
See, I've seen all that too.
I've seen a peanut stand
and heard a rubber band.
I seen a needle that
winked its eye.
But I be done seen
about ever'thing.
When I see a elephant fly.
- What'd you say, boy?
- I said when I see a elephant fly.
I seen a front porch swing
heard a diamond ring.
I seen a polka-dot
rail road tie.
But I be done seen
'bout ever'thing.
When I see a elephant fly.
- Da da-da-da.
- Da-da-da do-do-dow wow.
Da da-da-da - Hey, wow.
I saw a clotheshorse
He rear up and buck.
And they tell me that a man
made a vegetable truck.
I didn't see that I only heard.
Just to be sociable
I'll take your word.
- I heard a fireside chat.
- I saw a baseball bat.
And I just laughed till
I thought I'd die.
But I be done seen
'bout ever'thing.
When I see a elephant fly.
Bo Sho Ba-da-do-do.
But I be done seen
'bout ever'thing.
When I see a elephant fly.
With the wind.
When I see a elephant.
Fly.
All right, you wise birds.
This has gone far enough.
Quiet, gentlemen.
The Reverend Rodent
is gonna address you.
You ought a be ashamed
of yourselves.
A bunch of big guys like you...
picking on a poor
little orphan like him.
Suppose you was torn away from your
mother when you was just a baby...
nobody to tuck you
in at nights...
no warm, soft, caressing
trunk to snuzzle into.
How would you like to
be left out alone...
in a cold, cruel,
heartless world?
And why? I ask ya, why?
Just because he's got those big
ears, they call him a freak.
The laughing stock
of the circus.
Then when his mother
tried to protect him...
they threw her into the clink.
And on top of that,
they made him a clown!
Socially, he's washed up.
Ah, but what's the use of talking
to you cold-hearted birds?
Go ahead. Have your fun.
Laugh at him. Kick him,
now that he's down.
Go on!
We don't care.
Come on, Dumbo.
Hey, brother, w-w-wait a minute.
Uh, don't go away
feeling like that.
We done seen the light.
You boys is okay.
Please, you've done enough.
Well, but we's all fixing to help
you. Uh, ain't that the truth, boys?
- Well, it sure is.
- Uh, yeah, that... You're right.
You wanna make the
elephant fly, don't ya?
Well, you gotta use a lot
of'chology. You know, psychology.
Now, here's what you
do. First, you, uh...
Uh, bu...
And then, right after
that, you, uh...
Use the magic feather. Catch on?
The magic feather?
Yeah, I gotcha.
Dumbo! Look! Have I got it!
The magic feather!
Now you can fly!
Let's go. Let's go.
- Heave ho. Heave ho.
- Let's go, Dumbo.
- Let's go. Let's go.
- Come on now.
- Up, down. Up, down.
- Heave ho.
- One, two, One, two. One, two.
Faster, faster. Get
up flying speed.
Retract your landing gear.
Raise your fuselage.
Take off.
Aw, it's no use, Dumbo.
I guess it's just another
one of their... Look!
Hot diggity! You're flying.
You're flying!
Uh, why, he flies
just like a eagle.
That's better than a aeroplane.
Brother, now I've
seen everything.
But I be done seen
about everything.
When I see a elephant fly.
With the wind.
When I see a elephant.
Fly.
Dumbo, I knew you could do it!
Wait'll we get to the big town.
Boy, them city folks is
sure in for a surprise.
Poor baby! Whoo!
- Come on! Jump! Come on!
- We'll save ya.
- Hurry up!
- We'll save ya!
- Come on! Jump!
- Come on!
Look at that house. Dumbo,
you're standing on the
threshold of success.
Don't look down. It'll
make you dizzy.
Boy, are they in for
a surprise. Ho-ho.
Got the magic feather? Good.
Okay. Contact!
Take off!
Uh-oh. The magic feather!
Dumbo, come on. Fly.
Open them ears.
The magic feather was
just a gag. You can fly.
Honest, you can.
Hurry! Open 'em up!
Please!
Whee! We did it! We did it!
Let's show 'em,
Dumbo. Power dive.
Now, loop the loop.
You're makin' history!
I've seen a peanut stand
heard a rubber band.
I've seen a needle
that winked its eye.
But I be done seen.
About everything.
When I see an elephant fly.
Oh, my - When I see.
When I see.
When I see an elephant fly.
- Mmm, look at him go!
- When I see an elephant fly.
- Happy landing, son.
- Yippee!
When I see a elephant fly
I wish I'd have got
his autograph.
Oh, man, I got his autograph.
Well, so long, glamour boy!