original uploader .... ''strucni_prevodi''
SO DEAR TO MY HEART
The greatest wealth
a man may acquire...
is the wisdom
he gains from living.
And sometimes out of
the small beginnings...
come the forces
that shape a whole life.
So dear to my heart
That Septembery day
When that old shady lane
We strolled
Was just turning
scarlet and gold
So dear to my heart
That Decembery day
When that first touch
of frost
And snow
Had painted each tree
In the road
So dear to my heart
I still can picture
the flowers in a shower
And that picnic in July
And I still treasure
Each and every hour
Of those years
That had to fly
They're locked in my heart
In a corner apart
While I tenderly hold
The key
As long as I live
They will be
So dear
To my heart
I can still see
the old Kincaid homestead...
just the way it was then--
the split-rail fence,
the red barn...
and the chinked log cabin
with its little loft bedroom...
where I used to do
my dreaming.
And I can still see Granny
out there in the field...
and General Jackson
pulling her plough.
And just a mile or so away,
Fulton Corners...
the crossroads
of my small world.
At Grundy's General Store,
you could get most anything...
from jackknives
to fishhooks or candy.
That is,
if you had the money.
And if you didn't...
why, free for nothin', you might get
to see Old 99 go highballin' through.
She's blowin' for a stop.
Uncle Hiram, come on!
Hey, Pa, she's a-stoppin',
she's a-stoppin'!
Well, I'll be.
Stoppin' right here.
Now, folks, you'll have to stand back.
Stand well back, please.
Give us plenty of room.
All right, Fred,
bring him out.
- Hang on to that dog, boy.
Stand back, folks.
- Quiet, Trumpeter. Quiet, boy.
I can hardly believe my eyes.
Dan Patch himself.
The greatest racehorse
in the world.
Of course, I'd collected
a lot of pictures of him...
from calendars and magazines,
but I never dreamed
I'd get to look right at him!
Yet here he was,
right in Fulton Corners.
And they'd stopped the Limited
just so he could get some exercise.
- Loose nail on his shoe, Abe.
- He must have pawed it loose,
Mr Burns.
- He gets restless travellin' so far.
- He'll have that shoe off
time we get to Louisville.
- There a blacksmith in this town?
- I'm a smith, sir.
- Could I get you to clinch
a new nail in his shoe?
- Sure.
- Bring your tools, Abe.
- Yes, sir.
Steady, boy.
- He wants your apple, kid.
- All right. He can have it.
Ain't wormy, is it?
All right.
You can give it to him.
I can still feel the touch
of his soft, black nose...
and his warm breath
on my hand.
And I couldn't help thinkin'
how wonderful it'd be
to own a horse like him.
What do I owe you?
- I'll just keep this nail.
- Thanks very much.
All right, boys, let's get rolling.
Stand back, folks, please.
Board!
Oh, get out the way
for old Dan Patch
De diddle di diddle do
Dan Patch
Get out the way
for old Dan Patch
Git, git
git out of the way
Bet you wouldn't
take $ 1 00 for it.
- Heck, no!
- City folks been payin'
as much as 50 cents...
for just a single hair
out of his tail.
- My goodness!
- Know what?
- What?
- I'm gonna get me a colt...
and raise him up to be
a world's champion like Dan Patch.
- Betcha Granny wouldn't let ya.
- Don't know why not.
I'd make a lot of money,
'cause he'd win all the races, I bet.
I wouldn't be too sure about that.
I'm afraid your horse'd
have quite a handicap.
- Why?
- Well, knowin' your granny...
I'm afraid he'd have to do
all of his racin' with a plough
hitched onto his tail.
I knew what Uncle Hiram meant,
all right.
For Granny's job was more
than just raising me.
She had to run a farm single-handed...
and what with ploughing
and planting...
raising sheep,
spinning wool...
she had little time or patience
for my daydreams.
So, as I added today's big idea
to the collection in my scrapbook...
I knew my chances
were pretty slim.
Granny'd probably say no.
- But as the wise old owl put it:
- Yes, we'll gather...
''Nothing ventured, nothing gained.''
- at the river
The beautiful, beautiful river
Gather with the saints
at the river
- That flows by--
- Granny!
Land sakes,Jeremiah Kincaid.
You still awake?
Why don't we trade
General Jackson for a mare?
What's the matter with old General
Jackson? We don't need no mare.
If we had a mare,
we could get a colt.
We don't need no colt.
Don't see why
we couldn't trade him off.
What good's
an old mule anyhow?
A mule is steady and reliable...
and he earns his livin'
by doin' honest work...
and that's the last time
I wanna hear you criticizing
poor old General Jackson.
- Do you hear me?
- Yes, ma'am.
- You get on back to bed.
- Can't sleep.
Well, you try countin' sheep instead
of colts, and you'll go to sleep.
Yes'm. Reckon the lambs
were born yet?
The lambs'll be born
in the Lord's good time.
I reckon I had better go and see.
Lemme go with you, Granny.
Please?
Well, I reckon.
As long as you're so wide awake
and full of ginger.
- Put on your boots.
- Yes, ma'am!
- Put on your jacket!
- Yes'm!
- Granny, they've come already!
- Yes, sir.
Three brand new ones!
All pert and sassy too.
Fetch me that pitchfork.
Granny, look!
Jezebel's got twins!
Gee! Ain't he a beauty?
Black as a lump of coal.
Look, Granny.
He ain't a bit afraid.
Nothing's born afraid.
Nice boy.
You hungry, little fella?
Hold still,Jezebel.
This little fella's hungry too.
Help me hold her, Granny.
What's the matter with you,
you fool sheep?
Hold still,
you ornery critter, you.
What's the matter with her?
Is she crazy?
Oh, sometimes
they're like that... with twins.
Especially when one of them's black.
You mean she won't take him?
- You mean she's gonna let him die?
- Well.
Maybe she'll take him
after we get outta here
and she can't see that he's black.
Here. Better wrap the little critter up
against the cold.
But, Granny, suppose she don't.
Suppose she don't take him.
Well, that's in the hands
of the Lord.
They're his critters, and their ways
are the ways he give 'em...
and there's nothin'
we can do about it.
The ways of nature
seem cruel sometimes and hard...
but there's a plan behind it all.
Oh, he knoweth
every sparrow that falleth.
Jeremiah, fetch me
another one of them flower sacks
for this little critter.
Jeremiah! I said
to fetch me one of them--
Tarnation.
Jeremiah Kincaid,
I'm puttin' my foot down.
I mean it.
If you think I'm gonna have
my kitchen smellin' like a stable,
you got another think comin'.
It ain't civilized,
it ain't sanitary and it--
Well. One of
my best dish towels.
It's got to be boiled anyway.
If you want to get it warm,
you'd better take it in by the fire.
- You mean I can--
- I mean that you can get it warm...
before you take it
back out where it belongs.
If we bottle-raise that lamb,
it'll get to be a pet.
Come time to market it,
you'll wanna keep it.
Besides, it's black.
I don't fancy black wool.
Never did.
And you know well as I do
we can't afford critters around here
that don't earn their keep.
Hard enough
to make ends meet as it is.
I'd take care of him, Granny.
I'd feed him and take care of him
and everything, Granny.
Oh, he'll grow up
to be underfoot.
I know the nature
of them black sheep.
Especially a ram.
He'll be into everything.
It ain't practical.
It just don't make sense.
You wouldn't be bad.
Would you, boy?
Might as well
warm his insides too.
Look at his face, Granny.
Hasn't he got
a cute little face?
Wicked little face,
if you ask me.
You gonna let me keep him?
Well, we'll see.
So, that's how it all came about.
I'd traded my dream of owning
a champion racehorse...
for a measly
little old black lamb.
As the wise old owl put it...
''A bird in the hand
is worth two in the bush.''
Of course, I--
I knew Granny would never
let me keep him for good.
Not if he turned out to be
just an ordinary sheep.
Danny would have to
amount to something.
Something extra special.
A champion, for instance.
Hey, if you're aimin'
to carry that wreath around,
you better keep your chin up...
and your feet
on the ground.
There.
That's better.
Makin' a champ
out of a critter like you...
won't be an easy thing to do.
Well, let's see now.
Come over here, Danny,
and we'll take a look.
Maybe get some help
from the wisdom book.
You know, just 'cause you're
a little old sheep...
don't mean you can't
get to the top of the heap.
Where there's a will,
there's a way.
Every dog has his day.
Yes. It sounds kinda corny,
I'll admit...
but we oughta find somethin'
that'll help a bit.
''A rolling stone--''
Nah, that don't fit.
Here we are, Danny.
This is it.
It's what you dew--
Eh? Oh! Y-Yes.
It's what you d-o
do with what you got that counts.
Yes, sir.
It's what you do
with what you got
And never mind
how much you got
It's what you do
with what you got
That pays off in the end
You gotta start with
with what you got
If what you got
ain't such a lot
To make the most
of what you got
Here's what I recommend
You start by a-tryin'
And applyin'your best
If you try
there ain't no denyin'
There's a way
to feather your nest
- Hey!
- You gotta add how what you do
And multiply
by what you do
You think you can't win
but you do
And you get back dividends
It's what you do
with what you got
And never mind
how much ya got
It's what you do
with what you got
That pays off
in the end
It's the means
you ''applyeth''
That raises your stock
Look what David
did to Goliath
With a little old
hunk of rock
It's what you do
with what you got
And never mind
how much you got
It's what you do
with what you got
That pays off
In the end
Now lookee here, son
Stop a-sittin'
Gettin'somewhere
takes some gettin'
You can't sit and 'spect
- To get it
- Do oo-oo do oo-oo
Now the road to fame
takes muscle
Lots of work
and lots of hustle
So start right in
and hit it
Now if at first
you don't succeed
A lot of spunk
is what you need
Or someone else
will take the lead
So try, try, try again
Just get up
when you fall down
And don't be forlorn
Look how Joshua
busted that wall down
With a little old measly horn
It's what you do
with what you got
And never mind
just how much you got
It's what you do
with what you got
That pays off
in the end
In the end
You ornery critter.
That's the last damage you're gonna do.
You got no business
bein' a pet anyhow.
You're just a sheep.
And you're gonna stay
where sheep belong.
He won't do it again, Granny.
Honest he won't.
It's not only what he's been doin'.
It's what you ain't been doin'.
Night and day
from the time he was born...
you've had nothin' else
on your mind 'cept that critter.
- Ya ain't been doin'
the weedin' or the hoein'.
- But, Granny, I was gonna--
And winter cord wood
ain't been pilin' up like it ought to.
From now on, you're not to be
neglectin' your chores.
And that critter's not to be
runnin' around loose.
- Do you understand?
- Yes'm.
Aw, gee whiz, Danny.
Granny, she don't understand.
She thinks you're
just an ordinary sheep.
Ya know what?
I'm gonna build you a pen...
so's you'll have lots of
sunshine and exercise...
and fresh air.
I saw some real wire fencing
at Grundy's store...
and I'm goin' down there right now
and see how much it costs.
This ain't as though
you were runnin' around loose.
Promise to behave
if I take ya?
Danny! Danny!
Get him out!
Go on, now!
- Look out! Get him out!
- Watch out, Danny! watch out!
- Infernal thing!
- Danny!
- Get out!
- Danny! Danny!
If you ever bring that
black varmint in my store again...
I'll draw and quarter him!
I will, so help me Hannah.
Look at my screen door!
I'll get it fixed,
Mr Grundy!
You're mighty right you will!
Wasn't Danny's fault. He was just
standin' there lookin' at the candy.
Old Fud Grundy snuck up and shot him
with a bean blower or something.
He jumped a little bit,
and some eggs fell out of a basket.
It was Mr Grundy
knocked over the flour barrel...
and he chased Danny
through the door.
Who chased him
through this door?
- Granny?
- Aw, gee whiz, Uncle Hiram.
All anybody ever sees
is the bad things.
Nobody ever notices
all the good things he can do.
- For instance.
- Well...
he can jump higher
and run faster...
than any other lamb
in Pike County, I'll bet.
If he was a horse,
he'd be a world's champion...
when he grows up.
- Uncle Hiram.
- Mm-hmm.
Horses get to be champions
by winnin' races.
- What about things that don't race?
- What kind of things, for instance?
Well, um--
Pigs, for instance, and cows,
and roosters, for instance.
And maybe sheep,
for instance?
Well, sheep, you'd take them
to the county fair.
Now, you take like
that ram of yours.
And, uh, make like
that I was the judge...
at the county fair,
for instance.
Stand him up there,
Mr Kincaid...
- so that I can look him over.
- Yes, sir.
Stand back, folks.
You too, little girl.
Keep a tight hold on that rope,
young man. That animal looks
to me like he's a killer.
I got him,Judge.
Chest:
1 2 feet and 1 1 inches.
Height to shoulder:
twenty-two feet
and four inches.
Teeth like a buzz-saw.
Eyes like shootin' stars.
Mr Kincaid...
you've got quite
an animal there.
Yes, sir, and as judge
of this county fair...
it's not only my privilege and honour
but my bound and duty...
to present you
with the grand champion blue ribbon...
and...
the cash award.
Thank you,Judge.
Gee, look at all the clover.
Oh, boy! If he eats enough clover,
he'll get to be a champion.
A champion? Him?
I'm gonna take him to the county fair
and win the blue ribbon and cash award.
- You are not.
- I am so.
- Did your granny say you could go?
- Haven't told her yet, but I will.
If I helped you feed him
and everything...
maybe I could go
to the fair too. Huh?
Here she comes!
- Danny! Danny!
- Danny!
Danny! Danny!
Granny don't like black sheep
She grabbed him
by the throat
Looks like
this here black sheep
Is a-gittin'Granny's goat
Baa, baa, black sheep
Oh, what trouble
you've put Granny through
- Baa, baa, black sheep
- It ain't so much what the lamb
is doin' to me...
as what it's a-doin' to the boy.
Ya needn't say a word about it,
'cause I made up my mind.
- I didn't say a word.
- Well, I know what you're thinkin'.
Outright disobedience is
one thing I won't stand for.
But, Granny, the boy
ain't exactly disobeyin' you.
I'd like to know what ya call it.
The barn door's open, ain't it?
The lamb's gone,
and so is the boy.
The lamb ain't
a-runnin' around loose.
The boy's got him
under control. Now.
I don't wanna be hard
on the boy, and...
I don't wanna sell the lamb,
less'n I have to...
but you don't know the half
of what we've been through...
and the very next time
that little varmint busts
something or gets into some--
What's that?
Under control, eh?
I'll get him, Granny!
I'll catch him!
Oh, give me strength.
Goodness' sake!
Go that way! Head him off!
Danny!
Gee whiz, Danny.
Aw, gee whiz.
The lamb'll be better off.
Mr Turner'll stop by in the morning
and take him away...
and find him
a good home somewhere.
It ain't as if
I was sellin' him on the market.
Do you hear me?
And it ain't as if I was goin' back
on my word,Jeremiah...
'cause I never did say
you could keep the lamb.
I said we'd see.
So don't you go
feelin' mean...
and put out with your old granny
about it either.
You hear me?
Jeremiah!
Jeremiah?
What's a body gonna do?
Granny Kincaid made a vow
to get rid of that lamb
She didn't know how
She changed her mind
by a happenstance
Gonna give that black lamb
one more chance
If you get outta this pen
you ornery critter
You'll end up
a fried lamb fritter
If you don't be good
and settle down
You'll be roasted
a golden brown
See that, Danny?
You can't squeeze through anywhere.
- Nor butt it down neither.
- And you better not,
or you'll spoil everything.
There it is-- hogtied,
horse-high and... bull-strong.
Gee, Uncle Hiram, look how big
his chest and shoulders are gettin'.
He's lookin' more like
a champion every day.
When are ya gonna ask Granny,Jerry?
When are ya? Huh,Jerry?
Well, she hasn't quite forgave him
for bustin' her rockin' chair.
Don't worry about that.
I got it fixed already as good as new.
- You have?
- Yeah. I tell ya what.
Suppose when I
take it back tonight...
that I just accidentally
happen to mention something
about the county fair.
And before she knows
what's goin' on...
I'll put it over.
Lavender's blue
Dilly dilly
Lavender's green
If I were king
Dilly dilly
I'd need a queen
Who told me so
Dilly dilly
I told myself
I told me so
If your dilly dilly heart
feels a dilly dilly way
And if you answer yes
In the pretty little church
on the dilly dilly day
You'll be wed
in a dilly dilly dress
Of lavender blue
Dilly dilly
Lavender green
Then I'll be king
Dilly dilly
And you'll be
My queen
Oh, where have you been
Billy boy, Billy boy
charmin'Billy
I have been to seek a wife
She's thejoy of my life
She's a young thing
and cannot leave her mother
Is she often seen in church
Billy boy, Billy boy
charmin'Billy
Yes, she's often
seen in church
With a bonnet
white as birch
She's a young thing
and cannot leave her mother
Can she bake a cherry pie
Billy boy, Billy boy
charmin'Billy
She can bake a cherry pie
Quick as a cat
can wink its eye
She's a young thing
and cannot leave her mother
- How old is she--
- How old is she
Billy boy, Billy boy
How old is she
charmin'Billy
Three times six
Four times seven
Twenty-eight
and eleven
Oh, she's a young thing
and cannot leave her mother
She's a young thing
And cannot leave
her mother
Do do dee dee doop
Boop-boop boop-boop
Do you know what that is,Jerry?
That's the tune you most usually hear
on a merry-go-round.
That's a funny thing, that tune
making me think of merry-go-rounds.
You know, the last time
that I heard a merry-go-round
was at the county fair.
You know somethin', Granny?
I know we ain't goin'
to no county fair...
if that's what all this rigamarole's
leadin' up to.
Who said anything about
goin' to the county fair?
You was fixin' to.
These children washin' dishes
without bein' told.
- I wasn't born yesterday.
- Now, wait a minute.
Haven't you got a notion about
takin' that black sheep of yours
to the county fair,Jeremiah?
- Well, I--
- Now, wait a minute, Granny.
I was a-thinkin' about
these ''kiwers'' of yours here.
Thought maybe you'd like
to let the outlanders see what
a kiwer really looks like.
Sometimes I think you ain't
a day older than these young 'uns...
with all the tomfool notions
you get in your head.
Lots of folks don't think
county fairs are such tomfool notions.
All the best kiwer makers
in Pike County...
will more'n likely
take their kiwers.
And one of them kiwers
is gonna win the blue ribbon...
and the cash award.
Well, it won't be my kiwer,
'cause I ain't goin'.
Aw, Granny.
Why not?
'Cause I ain't a traipsin' woman
in the first place...
and I don't make my kiwers
for the sake of blue ribbons
and cash awards.
I make 'em
'cause they pleasure me.
Mama's already sent away
for the pattern for my new dress.
- What's that got to do with it?
- I was gonna wear it to the fair.
Tsk. Honey.
It's time you learned
not to go settin' your heart
on the daydreams of menfolks.
Well, it was just an idea.
Maybe I shouldn't have
brought it up in the first place.
Ya, when folks get old,
it's best they sit around the fire
and bake their shins.
Meanin' me.
- You ain't no spring chicken, Granny.
- I'll live to dance on your grave.
I'm afraid, Granny,
that your dancin' days are over.
I can dance you down any day!
Jeremiah, go turn on
''Cricket On The Fryin' Pan.''
- Yes'm. Excuse me.
- Get to your feet,
if you dare, Hiram Douglas!
That's right sassy talk
for a granny-woman!
''Old,'' huh?
I'll show you who's old.
''The Soldier's Joy''
played by the Kentucky Quintet.
A Morning Glory record.
Well, buckle your belts
and tighten your traces
All clap hands
We're off to the races
Right hands cross
How do you do
Left hand back
And how are you
Take your honey
and give her a swing
Allemande around
the great big ring
Tra la la la la la la
Tra la la-la la-la
Swing old Adam
Swing old Eve
Swing your own
before you leave
Chase a rabbit
Chase a squirrel
Chase that pretty girl
'round the world
Now the possum
Now the 'coon
Chase that pretty boy
'round the moon
Promenade eight
till you get straight
Better hurry up, boys
And don't be late
Swing your partner, swing your dog
Swing that girl from Arkansas
Swing your grandma 'cross the hall
She ain't been swung
since way last fall
Swing her high, swing her low
Wanna keep on swingin'that calico
When you get to your gal again
Swing your sweetie
with a once and a half
Jeremiah, turn on
''Fire In The Briar Patch.''
- No, don't do it,Jeremiah!
- Well, then turn it off.
Take it back. Get to your feet
and dance, or eat them words
and eat 'em proper.
You're as spry as a chickadee...
and can outdance anybody
at the county fair!
- We're gonna go!
- We're goin'!
Now, now. Come on.
Let's tidy up a bit, huh?
That's it.
We'll ride on the merry-go-round,
the Ferris wheel and everything.
And when Danny wins a blue ribbon
and the cash award...
and get off the train
at Fulton Township,
everybody'll be there.
And old Fud Grundy,
he'll turn green as a summer pickle.
Now hold on a minute,Jeremiah.
I didn't say that we were going
to the county fair.
In the first place, it costs money
to ride on the train...
and it costs money
after you get there.
Well, maybe I could,
uh, kinda help out in that direction.
Well, maybe you could,
but I've always paid my own way...
and I hope Jeremiah'll
always pay his.
I was talkin' about a little loan.
We'll have plenty of money
when Danny wins the cash award.
The Kincaids never spend money
they ain't got...
and we've no way to get it...
so just best forget
the whole thing.
But we can
get it somehow, Granny.
I know we can.
We can pray for it.
In this house,
we don't pray for cash money...
only for things
of the spirit.
Come on, Tilda. We better be gittin'.
It's time you were in bed.
Goodnight,Jerry.
- Goodnight.
Hey. Hey there!
Don't tell me you're givin' up?
Now where there's a will
there's a way to do it
But you'll never get there
if you don't stick to it
Now let me tell you about a fella
who had the right stuff...
and wouldn't give up
even when the goin' got rough.
Now, uh--
Christopher Columbus
a-livin'in Spain
Showed capacity
for usin'his brain
Studied his geography
Had it down pat
Said I'm gonna prove
that the world ain't flat
Because she thought he was right
Queen Isabella one night
Gave him three small boats
One, two three
Now, uh, the boats were kinda leaky
Started to sail
Came a hurricane
A furious gale
Waves were a-lashin'
Future looked black
- Sailors started yellin'
- Chris, turn back
On that eventful day
what did Columbus say
Why, I said
stick-to-it-ivity
If you got that stuff
Called stick-to-it-ivity
You're gonna do all right
Old man adversity's
Gonna have his bluff called
Stick-to-it-ivity
Never lost a fight
- Yes siree
You can clear the deck
for opportunity
By applyin'
stick-to-it-ivity
If ya got that stuff called
Stick-to-it-ivity
- You're gonna do all right
- Land ho!
We're gonna do all right
Now, don't think Columbus
was the only one...
who did what folks said
couldn't be done.
So when folks say,
'''Taint no use''...
Remember
Robert Bruce
Now, Robert was the bravest king
Scotland has ever known.
Came the enemy
to threaten his throne
Twice he went to battle
Twice he met defeat
Headed for the Highlands
in retreat
He thought he'd give up the fight
but it so happened one night
He saw a spider at work
Back and forth and back
Up and down and up
Spider kept a-swingin'
Swingin'on his thread
Tried to hook it
to a limb overhead
Spider kept a-missin'
every time he tried
- You're never going to make it.
- Robert cried
On that eventful day
What did the spider say
Says I, Robert, me lad:
Stick-to-it-ivity
If ya got that stuff called
You're going to do all right
Old man adversity
Going to have his bluff called
Stick-to-it-ivity
Never lost a fight
- Yes siree
You can clear the deck
for opportunity
By applyin'
stick-to-it-ivity
If you've got that stuff called
Stick-to-it-ivity
- You're going to do all right
-Aye
We're gonna do all right
Aye! Aye! Aye! Aye!
Yes siree
You can clear the deck
for opportunity
By applyin'
stick-to-it-ivity
If you've got that stuff called
Stick-to-it-ivity
You're going to do all right
You're going to do
All right
Old Jeremiah
the sassafras man
He'd eat sassafras
fast as he can
Oh, another batch
of sassafras, huh?
Yes, sir.
- Well, that's 1 8 pounds.
- How much does it come to, Mr Grundy?
Two cents a pound
comes to thirty-six cents.
- I mean all together.
- Well, this here's June,July...
and thirty-six cents
in August is nine, eight--
That's $2.1 4.
- Is that all?
- Well, cipher it for yourself.
I mean,
it's not gonna be enough.
What you savin' all this money up for,
Jeremiah? Goin' to college?
Mr Grundy! Mama wants
a pint of wild honey.
Aunt Margaret's cough's come back
on her, and Mama wants to make
some wild honey cough syrup.
I ain't had a drop of wild honey
in this store in I don't know how long.
Must be three years or better.
Go ask your mama
if tame honey won't do!
Now there's an idea
for you,Jeremiah.
You wanna get rich quick, go out
and find yourself a wild bee tree.
Pay you ten cents a pound,
cash money.
How do you find
a wild bee tree, Mr Grundy?
Hmm? Why, just find a bee
and follow him home.
Thanks a lot, Mr Grundy!
You don't care how you waste
that boy's time, do ya?
What's time to a boy?
King it.
Watch him now.
Watch which way he goes.
He's just flyin' around in circles.
Maybe he ain't got no home.
Every bee's got a home.
There he goes. He's flyin'
straight ahead. Come on!
He's headed for the swamp. That's six
of'em that's headed in the same way.
- Well, we can't go in there.
- Why not?
'Cause. Nobody ever goes in there.
It's full of bog holes
and briers and everything.
That's just it. That's where
I'd hide my honey if I was a bee.
- Wouldn't you?
- I guess so, but--
We've looked everywhere else,
haven't we? It's gotta be in there.
Look!
What's that?
Aw, just some old bones.
- Whose bones?
-Just an old cow or somethin'.
What killed it?
Nothin'. It just died.
- How do you know?
- I just know, that's all.
If you're afraid of snakes,
go on home.
- I'm not afraid.
- Then come on!
-Jerry!
- Hey, look out!
See that?
That's a bog hole.
If you fall in that,
you never would get out.
Don't you step anywhere
I don't step.
Don't take such long steps.
What's that?
Aw, just some old dogs
huntin' a rabbit or somethin'.
Maybe it's that pack of wild dogs,
the sheep killers. And maybe they--
They won't bother us.
We ain't no sheep.
Papa said the wolves have all
been killed off around here long ago.
Uncle Hiram said so too.
So did Granny.
There goes a bee.
It's gettin' late. Why don't we
come back tomorrow,Jerry?
Papa said sometimes it took
bee hunters-- grown men even--
two or three years
to find a bee tree.
Hey, there goes another one!
Wasn't nothin'
but an old dragonfly.
Come on. Guess we
might as well go home.
Look!
There's a redbird.
Redbird, redbird...
where, where?
He said, ''Here, here.''
Oh, them crazy old redbirds
don't know nothin' about bees.
There's a martin!
They eat bees.
Come on!
Listen.
- There it is!
- Where?
In that old redwood tree!
I found it! I found it!
Jerry Kincaid followed a bee
till he come to a cottonwood tree
Sawed that tree off to the ground
Two tons of honey is what he found
Get outta the way, we ain't braggin'
So much honey the wagon's saggin'
Hope them axles don't break down
before we get this load to town
This load of honey
means money for the fair
Jerry Kincaid is a millionaire
Grundy's payin'ten cents a pound
Get along, hoss, we're goin'to town
Get out your cash, Old Pete Grundy
Here we come on a lucky Monday
We got sweet stuff, yellow as gold
Aged in a bee tree 1 2 years old
- Look what we got, Mr Grundy!
- All that honey outta one tree?
- Well, I'll be darned.
- Weigh it up, Pete.
Seventeen, eighteen, nineteen...
twenty, twenty-one,
twenty-two.
Thank you, Mr Grundy.
I always knew that young 'un
was a smart one; always said so.
- My lands, look at the cash money.
- How does it feel to be rich,Jeremiah?
What are you gonna do
with all that money?
I'm takin' my prize lamb
to the county fair.
The only prize he'd win
would be the booby prize.
I'm takin' my lamb
to the fair, not you.
Think you're smart, don't ya?
You durn fool!
Hold still there!
Don't worry, folks.
I'll send this tub to the city.
Tildy!
- Is that you, Granny?
- That's Granny, all right.
Whoa.
- Have you seen Tildy?
- What's wrong?
I been trampin' them woods for an hour
and callin' till I'm hoarse as a rain crow.
Do you know how much money
I got here?
Oh, my land, not now. I'm tryin'
to tell you that Tildy is lost.
- What happened?
- But, Granny, look how much--
Hush,Jeremiah. She brought a wagonload
of clover up there to feed that fool lamb...
- and when she opened the gate,
it bolted.
- She let Danny get away?
The critter hightailed it
for the deep woods...
and the poor child run after it
trying to catch it.
What business she have openin'
that gate? What'd you let her do it for?
-Jeremiah!
- Which way did Danny go?
Down by Indian Creek. But they ain't
there now. I've searched every inch of it.
Come back here,Jeremiah!
Oh, drat that boy.
All he cares about
is that fool lamb.
Uncle Hiram!
Thank heaven!
Oh, goodness gracious, child.
You had me that worried.
Oh, Granny, I looked everywhere
and called and called.
Oh, my, you're soakin' wet.
I fell down in the creek too.
Well, let's get her home right away
and into some dry things
before she gets a chill.
- What about Jeremiah?
-Jeremiah can take care of himself.
Jeremiah!
Granny!
Oh, Granny! Now I can find him
with the lantern--
Land sakes, boy,
you're just soaked to the bone,
and you're shakin' and shiverin'.
- Come along!
- I gotta find him! I just got to!
- I heard the dogs!
- Now, listen to me!
You can't find him at night
and in this storm. Now, come along now.
- But, Granny--
- Now!
You hardly touched
your supper.
I thought maybe
you'd get hungry later.
Maybe. Said your prayers?
Oh, I know.
It's a vexin' thing.
It's a cruel thing,
havin' your lamb run away.
Maybe Danny found
a holler log and crawled into it...
where the dogs
couldn't find him.
Maybe he's snuggled up
under the roots of a big old tree.
However it is,
it's beyond our power to help.
All you can do is
just hope for the best...
but be prepared
for whatever happens.
He ain't dead.
He ain't dead!
I didn't say he was. I'm only
tryin' to tell you to remember...
that the Lord giveth
and the Lord taketh away.
Well, he can't have him.
He can't take Danny.
You're not tellin' the Lord
what he can do or can't do.
The Lord'll do the tellin'.
Oh, this is all my fault.
I've seen it comin'.
I've seen it comin' all along.
You've turned your heart away
from the things I've taught you...
ever since you were
a little baby.
No,Jeremiah,
you can't do this.
It's one thing,
blamin' poor little Tildy
for letting your lamb get away...
when all she was tryin' to do
was to help you feed him.
And it's one thing,
blamin' me.
But it's another thing when
you start blamin' your maker.
Started out by lovin' the lamb,
and that's why I let you keep him.
True love ain't a harmful thing.
True love's a good thing.
It's good for the spirit.
But you don't love
that lamb any more.
What you love is blue ribbons
and cash awards.
That's all you're thinkin' about--
things that are vain, things of this world--
until you forgot all about
the things of the spirit.
And when you can't have your own way,
you start burdenin' the Lord.
You ain't thinkin' of that lamb.
You're just thinkin' about yourself.
You know what's right,Jeremiah...
but you'll have to find it in your own
heart to do what's right.
Danny!
No luck.
It's like lookin' for
a needle in a haystack.
Ain't laid eyes on the boy,
much less the lamb.
Well, there's one thing you can
be sure of. The boy ain't lost.
There's more ways of bein' lost
than in the woods.
Ah, but he's just
a young 'un, Granny.
Maybe he is gettin' a little big
for his britches, but--
Granny! Granny!
He found him! He found him!
Uncle Hiram!
Look! He found him!
Must've been a guardian angel
somewhere in them woods last night.
Happened one was more needed
right here in this house last night.
Well, they don't look much the worse
for the wear, either one of'em.
That's good.
Figurin' on takin' 'em
to the county fair?
I reckon it won't make
much difference.
All we have to do is get the foxtails
out of his wool...
and he'll be
just as good as ever.
He was way over
on the far side of the swamp...
all snuggled up in a holler log,
Granny, just a-waitin' for me.
You hungry, boy?
How about some oatmeal mash?
Well, come on.
Mama's got my new dress almost finished,
and a ribbon and a hat to match.
I'll stop by in the morning
and pick up the tickets.
I've already got a crate for the lamb.
That is, if you say so.
I mean, if it's
all right with you.
I reckon.
- What's the matter, Tildy?
- We're not going to the fair.
What's that?
H-He said he wasn't
going to the fair.
Why not?
H-He wouldn't tell me.
He just said, ''God.''
He's got plenty
of foxtails on him.
Yes'm, but he ain't got
a scratch on him.
Tildy was cryin'.
She can go to the fair,
and you and Uncle Hiram.
You don't figure to go?
- Changed my mind.
- You did?
Promised God if he let me find him,
I wouldn't take him to the fair.
And he did!
Well-- Well now...
if this ain't a fine how-de-do.
It happened that--
Well, it happened
that I made a promise too.
I-- I promised God that...
if he did let you find him,
that we would go to the fair.
And since I've known him
longer than you have, I reckon...
it'll be all right with him
if I keep my promise.
Go get them cardin' combers.
We've gotta take these foxtails outta him.
Yes'm.
Forgive me, Lord.
I meant to tell you before.
Had it in the back
of my mind all the time.
Ho-dee-I, ho-dee-ay
What a great big wonderful day
Not a care in the air
Everybody you know
from Matilda to Joe
Will be there at the county fair
Ho-dee-ay, ho-dee-I
What a great big beautiful sky
All the clowns like the crowds
You can bet will be dressed
in their brightest and best
For their stay
At the county fair
The teenage misters
will be shooin'little sisters
To the Ferris wheel up above
And they'll be gettin'
their best gals for pettin'
In the Tunnel of Love
- Ho-dee-I, ho-dee-ay
- Hi-dee-oh-ay, hey-dee-oh-ay
Come and throw your troubles away
Just a grin gets you in
On this day of the year
when there's nothing but cheer
To share at the county fair
Congratulations.
The judging for
the champion ram lamb...
of the Pike County
Agricultural Livestock Fair...
will now take place
in this arena.
- Is that us, Granny?
- I reckon it is.
You know somethin', Granny?
I got the same kind of feelin'
I had just before I found the bee tree...
and just before I found Danny
in the holler log.
All ram lambs in the
judging ring at once, please.
Where in the name of time
is Hiram with that neat's-foot oil?
- Well, here it is.
- Took you long enough.
- Now it's too late.
- Granny, look what Uncle Hiram won...
just by throwing hoops
over walking canes.
I better give you a hand
in there, Granny.
Well, there ain't no hoops
or walking canes in here.
Besides, you'd just get in the way.
All ram lambs into the judging
ring at once, please.
What do I do, Uncle Hiram?
When I get in the ring, I mean.
Well, I'll tell ya. Main thing
that you gotta remember is--
Main thing you remember,
Jeremiah, is that only one
of them lambs is gonna win.
The rest are gonna lose.
But, Granny, he will win.
I just know he will.
Hope he does.
But happen he don't...
I want you to come out of that ring
like a Kincaid, walkin' proud.
Please, all contestants
in the ring!
Remember the county fair.
Buy your pennants right here.
One-tenth of a dollar.
One dime.
Buy your pennants here.
Step right up and get your pennants.
Get your pennants--
- McGrew.
- Lynn County.
- Sire and dam?
- McGrew's Shropshire, 52 80.
His dam is McGrew 1 2 861 ,
and his sire is Kerr Sage of Green Acres.
Thank you, sir.
- Walker.
- Brown County.
- Sire and dam?
- Romney Marsh, sir.
And out of ewe number 4 7 8
and sired by Starks Prince Perfect.
Thank you, sir.
- Holloway.
-Johnson County.
- Sire and dam?
- Rambouillet number 692...
out of Bramburg 62,
and his sire is the Duke of Crenshaw.
Thank you, sir.
Marshall.
Pike County.
- Sire and dam?
- Marshall's Hampshire, number 1 084.
Out of Highland Lassie Queen.
- By national grand champion
Golden Thorn.
- Thank you, sir.
Kincaid. Kincaid!
- F-Fulton Corners.
- Sire and dam?
Speak up, sonny.
What's his breedin'?
Danny ain't none of them
fancy breed kind of lambs, mister.
His ma's name was Jezebel.
But I don't know
who his daddy was.
- Lewis.
-Jasper County.
- He's Southdown, isn't he, son?
- No, sir.
But in a fight, he could whip them
other lambs any old day of the week.
- What've you been feedin' him, son?
- Oatmeal mash, sir.
Nice strong back.
Good job of blockin'.
Granny did that.
Remember the county fair.
Buy your pennant right here.
Your judging committee
has awarded the blue ribbon...
to Mr Marshall.
Congratulations,
Mr Marshall.
It's all right, Danny.
It's all right, boy.
Just a moment, son.
That's a fine lamb you have there.
I wanna compliment you on him.
As fine a grade of wool
as I ever come across.
The only trouble, it's-- it's black.
There ain't much market for black wool.
Kinda puts your lamb
in a class by himself.
I'm not tryin' to be funny, folks.
This lamb is in a class by himself.
And while he has no pedigree...
it just goes to show what
extra special care will do...
in the raising of fine livestock.
It's what you do with
what you've got that counts.
This little lamb is a champion
in every sense of the word.
Therefore, it is the unanimous decision
of your judging committee...
that there be awarded
the breeder a special prize...
which we have not given
in four years--
a special award of merit...
to Jeremiah Kincaid.
Congratulations,
Mr Jeremiah Kincaid.
Aw, gee whiz, Danny.
Aw, gee whiz.
Hey, Pa!
She's a-blowin' for a stop!
Folks, you better stand back now
and give us plenty of room.
We got a prize lamb here
that won the special award.
Welcome home,Jeremiah.
Welcome home.
Fulton Corners is proud of ya.
Thank you, Mr Grundy.
As I was about to say
on this auspicious occasion...
when it comes to winnin' awards,
there ain't no flies on Fulton Corners.
Yea!
I got two cases of soda pop
and six watermelons in my icebox...
and everybody's invited
over to the store, and it's my treat.
Yea!
- But what'll I do with Danny?
- Bring him along. It's his party.
Yippee! Hurray!
Oh, get outta the way for Jerry's ram
Hi-ditty-lo for Jerry's ram
Get outta the way for Jerry's ram
Git, git, git outta the way
Oh, git, git, git outta the way
So dear to my heart