♪ Waking up to sunshine ♪
♪ Buttery and bright ♪
♪ The way
Today is starting off ♪
♪ Is better than all right ♪
♪ Stirring up a good time ♪
Huh? What?
Uh... Good morning, George.
Careful, lots of important
work here that can't...
get messed up.
Sorry, George,
but Pancake Wednesday
is tomorrow.
I... I don't have time
to make them right now.
Okay, I could use
a good breakfast too.
♪ Say hello to morning ♪
♪ A day that's
Fresh and fine ♪
♪ All you see around you
Wears a rich and golden shine ♪
♪ Anything is possible ♪
♪ Nothing's out of line
In a perfect world ♪
- Mmm.
- ♪ Ooh, a perfect world ♪
♪ A perfect world ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
A perfect world ♪
♪ Some people
Just don't seem to see ♪
♪ Happiness is theirs
For free ♪
♪ Well, they hustle
And hurry ♪
♪ They wish and they worry ♪
♪ Constantly ♪
Ah!
♪ What about tomorrow ♪
♪ Don't have to have a plan ♪
♪ Feeling fine
And fancy free ♪
♪ Since today began ♪
♪ All we need is just to have
As much fun as we can ♪
♪ In a perfect world ♪
♪ Ooh, a perfect world ♪
Okay, I'm off to my meeting.
Don't play with your food,
George.
Be a good little monkey
while I'm gone.
Bye-bye.
Ah...
♪ It's a perfect world ♪
♪ A perfect world ♪
Ah!
George?
Aah!
Uh-oh.
George, you can't just do whatever
you want, whenever you want.
Oh. Oh, okay.
Now, I have an
appointment with my shower. Again.
...and next
time, we'll explore
secrets of
the mighty Triceratops.
Hey! Do you want to
have fun?
- Huh?
- Do whatever you want, whenever you want?
Ah!
Then come on over to Castleland
and live like royalty!
- Ooh.
- You can plunge down the Spiral Staircase...
- Ah.
- ...spin on the Swinging Chandelier...
- Ooh.
- ...or jump on Ye Old Water Wheel.
Aha!
You can even ride
noble horses.
Enjoy making messes? Go ahead.
Partake in
a raucous medieval feast.
Listen, George,
I'm sorry I got angry.
It's just... I was asked to take
over this important meeting.
I'm a little unprepared.
Mmm.
Hey, after the meeting, I think we
deserve something fun. What do you say?
Everyone has a coronation,
and every guest
is treated like royalty.
Oh, okay.
Really? Oh, wow. Thanks.
All right,
I'll see you at the museum.
We're in luck, George.
My friend, Sophie, works at Castleland,
and we're going to be
her guests.
- Huh?
- Yeah.
She's gonna pick us up
right after my meeting.
So you're coming with me
to the museum.
But you need to be
on your best behavior.
Oh. Mm-hmm.
Ooh, horses.
Your Monkeyness, isn't it
wonderful to be out of the castle?
Well, I think it's fun
to be out with everybody.
Philippe has a point,
Isabel.
Nothing good comes from
mixing with the common folk.
Now, Ana, can you please...
Fill you in on our host?
Of course. Just...
over here.
Here he is, Your Majesty.
We'll see the Simiana Exhibit,
and then he'll give us a brief tour.
Hmm. Do you really think
a man wearing a hat like that
can be trusted
to take care of our...
Precious artifacts?
Well, he looks a little bit...
unusual,
but as you know,
the royal family's popularity
among the people
is at an all-time low.
- Hmm.
- However,
this exhibit, combined with Princess
Isabel's upcoming coronation,
is sure to
bring you back on top.
I hope so.
For Isabel's sake.
Papa! Look.
Hmph.
Isabel, you know music
is simply not dignified.
And certainly not appropriate
for royalty.
Yes, Papa.
Quick, George.
I can't be late.
Hey, George.
Love the crown.
Ah. Ah.
Lots of royalty
coming through today.
Don't tell me the King
of Simiana's already here.
Judge for yourself.
Isn't he kingly?
Oh, brother.
Ooh.
Oh, ah.
Come on.
This way, George.
George, stay right here
and don't move a muscle.
As soon as I'm done,
we're off to Castleland. Okay?
Oh.
Huh.
Hmm.
Ah...
Uh, um...
Your Highest Highness.
Wait, no, no.
That's wrong.
- Uh... Mmm.
- Um, Your Majesty's Royal...
No, no, no, no.
That's off, that's off...
Wow, it's a miniature version
of home.
And they have a copy
of our Book of Customs.
And our host?
Only three minutes late.
Tardiness is not
one of our honored customs.
I'm here! I'm here.
So sorry I'm late.
Welcome to
our Royal Treasures exhibit.
Your privilege.
It's a great Majesty...
No, no, no, I mean, I mean,
it's a great Highness... Ah... I, ooh...
May I introduce
his Royal Majesty,
King Gustavo Hernando
Fernando Heraldo V.
And the Princess Isabel Hortensia
Florencia III, of the kingdom of Simiana.
Uh... Ted.
I'm Ted... the first.
Oh, is that...
The most precious artifact
in all of Simiana,
which the king has graciously
loaned to your museum?
Yes.
A monkey. Incredible.
The monkey
is our national symbol.
- It is?
- Yes.
Centuries ago,
one saved a young king's life.
We treat them
like royalty.
Oh, that's amazing.
I happen to be very fond of monkeys too.
Well, one in particular.
How fascinating.
As you can see, our Philippe...
Ana, where's Philippe?
Yuck.
Argh.
Huh?
Oh.
Ah. Oh? Ah.
Oh. Ooh.
Aw. Hmm.
Uh-oh!
Whoa.
Hey!
Ooh, ooh.
And don't worry
about a thing.
If there's one thing I know
how to take care of, it's a...
Monkey?
Oh! Whoa! Uh, oh!
What just happened?
Nothing.
I mean, nothing
that will ever happen again.
Hmph.
Uh, I can see you're upset.
So... let me just, um...
show you
all the museum's devices
which will keep
your precious artifact safe.
But first,
I just need one minute.
Ugh.
This is a disaster.
I've changed my mind.
The exhibition is off.
Oh, I understand,
Your Majesty,
but perhaps we could just
give them a second chance.
Giving second chances is not an
honored custom. We're leaving.
- George?
- Ooh?
You were supposed to
stay in the office.
Hi. Sophie, Ted here.
I need a huge favor.
- Doris?
- Hmm?
Can you watch George until the
car from Castleland gets here?
My friend Sophie
is picking him up.
Check. I'm on it.
George, I have to stay here
and straighten things out.
So you stay with Doris
until Sophie gets here.
I'll come to Castleland as soon as I
can, all right?
I printed out
this Castleland brochure.
You can study all the rides
on your trip.
Ooh.
Now, be a good little monkey.
Bye.
And I need...
Your car.
It's on the way.
You're leaving?
Wait.
Can we talk about this?
Good day, Mr...
Man with the Yellow Hat.
Come. We're going home.
But where's Philippe?
Apparently, he had the
good sense to wait outside.
Sophie, I'm really sorry,
but George and I
are gonna have to reschedule.
Huh?
Huh.
Hmm.
Hmm?
Hmph!
Ugh, what was I thinking?
This is what happens
when you take chances.
There you are,
Your Monkeyness.
Oh.
Uh-oh.
Ooh.
Isabel, let me help you out.
Ana, we need to find...
Right away, Your Majesty.
There you are.
Hi.
I hope you weren't hurt.
Oh. Uh-uh.
Oh, my goodness,
where's your vest? Oh.
Oh...
There.
Now you look like yourself.
Uh-huh.
Ready to go back to the Castle,
Your Monkeyness?
Comin'. Hold on.
Hold on.
Doris, what happened?
Please tell me it didn't involve George.
What part don't you
want to know first?
The part where George
climbed on top of the canopy?
Or the part where it fell
right on the royal family?
What? Oh...
George.
Are you okay?
Huh?
The king
and the princess left.
Huh?
Oh, yes, they did.
So the exhibit's off,
and you're coming home with me.
Ugh.
We'll have to go to the castle
another day.
Hmph.
So you're going to give me
the silent treatment?
Well, fine.
But you still need to come with me.
Ah!
Ah. Ooh.
What's the matter, Your Monkeyness?
It's time to go.
You know what the problem is?
I've been too nice.
Well, things are going to be
different from now on.
Back from the castle already?
Welcome, Your Highness.
Okay.
Chop, chop. We've got
a lot to work on, buddy.
From now on,
you're playing by the rules.
Well...
Okay, then.
I'll be out here.
Looking for
a new museum exhibit.
Ah...
Does Your Monkeyness
require anything else?
Ah...
Nah...
Very well.
Ooh.
Uh-huh!
Ah!
Mmm, mmm!
Ooh! Aha.
Oh. Ah.
Hmph.
I'll take care of this,
Your Majesty.
Your Monkeyness, I'll take you to your room.
Ooh.
I encourage you to rest, Your Monkeyness.
It's been a long trip.
Oh.
Ah!
♪ When you look out
The window ♪
♪ And ponder the view ♪
♪ And you hear sweet music ♪
♪ From out of the blue ♪
♪ When you feel the morning
Calling to you ♪
♪ There's only one thing
You can do ♪
- Aah!
- ♪ You got to ride that ride ♪
- ♪ Jump right in, get up And go with it, ride that ride ♪
- Whoa!
- ♪ Swing and sway and groove And flow with it ♪
♪ Ride that ride ♪
♪ Rise with the tide ♪
♪ When you ride, ride, ride ♪
Ah!
♪ It'll lift you up ♪
♪ It'll let you down ♪
♪ Oh, the wheel of life ♪
♪ Gonna spin you round ♪
♪ It'll take you places ♪
♪ You never could guess ♪
♪ And all you gotta say
And all you gotta say ♪
♪ Is yes, yes, yes ♪
♪ And ride that ride ♪
♪ Slip and slide and move
And flow with it ♪
♪ Ride that ride ♪
♪ Get up, get out
Get on and go with it ♪
♪ Ride that ride ♪
♪ What comes next
You'll never know ♪
♪ Till you ride, ride, ride ♪
♪ Ride that ride ♪
♪ Slip and slide and move
And flow with it ♪
♪ Ride that ride ♪
♪ Get up, get out, get on
And go with it ♪
♪ Ride that ride ♪
♪ What comes next
You'll never know ♪
♪ Till you ride, ride, ride ♪
♪ Till you ride that ride ♪
♪ Slip and slide and move
And flow with it ♪
♪ Ride that ride ♪
♪ Get up, get out
Get on and go with it ♪
♪ Ride that ride ♪
♪ What comes next
You'll never know ♪
♪ Till you ride, ride, ride ♪
♪ Get up, get out, get on
And go with it ♪
♪ Ride, ride, ride ♪
Ah... Your Monkeyness,
shall we proceed to the banquet hall?
Lunch is about to be served.
Ah! Aha!
This, my friend,
is a copy of the Simianan Book of Customs.
Yep, today, you're going to
learn proper eating etiquette.
It says here,
"When sitting down,
take your napkin
and place it on your..."
Yeah. Okay.
That... that was good.
"Don't scoop your food.
The knife can be used
to help guide food
onto your fork.
And avoid placing your elbows
on the table at all times."
Huh.
This is harder
than I thought.
"And finally,
when you're done,
don't forget to use
your napkin."
Wow. Look who joined
the Clean Plate Club.
And the Clean Table Club.
We should have done this
a long time ago.
Ah! Ah.
Ah.
Lunch is served.
Wow.
Ooh.
Aw.
Well...
You wouldn't understand.
Huh? Ah.
Ah.
So, Mr. Mayor,
how are the preparations going?
Everything is in order
for tomorrow,
when we celebrate Princess
Isabel's junior coronation.
The coronation of the heir apparent.
Ooh!
Your Monkeyness,
you seem surprised.
But you know
that tomorrow is the day
Princess Isabel becomes an
official member of the Royal Court
and begins
her many royal duties.
Oh, please
don't remind me.
I want to enjoy
my last day of freedom.
Now, Isabel...
There's just
one last piece of business.
I'm afraid the people still
insist on having their
horse race as part
of the big day.
But I've seen to it
that the people's derby
will be over
well before the coronation.
Did you say there's
a horse derby tomorrow?
Why didn't I know about this?
Can we go?
Oh, well, that's not
on our itinerary.
Isabel, these events
are unseemly,
and we will certainly
not attend.
Aw.
The mayor's point
is that it won't interfere
with your coronation.
That's good news, my dear.
Thank you, Mr. Mayor.
What are you doing?
The Royal Monkey
is clearly not himself today.
Allow me, Your Majesty.
Your Monkeyness, I can see you might
enjoy a rest after your long journey.
I trust Your Monkeyness will feel
more like himself after a bath.
Yeah.
Yah!
I see.
Well, I'll leave you to it.
Bye-bye.
How's Philippe?
He's, uh, bathing. So
I think it's best if we just...
Ana, Philippe never behaved
like this before that trip.
I blame that...
that yellow hatted man.
Well, yes, the Royal Monkey will
be back to his well-behaved self
in no time, Your Majesty.
He has such a critical role
in Isabel's coronation.
He's crowning her, for goodness sake.
Nothing can go wrong.
Oh...
Absolutely.
To make sure of it,
I scheduled an extra rehearsal today.
But we've rehearsed
a hundred times.
I know, my dear,
but this is quite important.
Perhaps
we should leave Philippe
so that the bath can have
the full soothing effect.
I'm sure he'll join us
as soon as he's done.
Hmm. No doubt you're right.
Huh?
Your next lesson today:
taking a bath
without making your usual mess.
Now, I know
that's a big step, but...
What? What's the matter?
Oh.
Look at that.
Okay, well, uh, we've got lots
of towels to choose from...
Hmm. Huh? Yeesh.
- Hmm.
- Huh?
Uh... yes, sir.
What just happened?
Okay, young monkey,
that bathroom had better be...
Spotless?
Wow.
Ahem.
Oh. Sorry.
Wow. Perhaps I pushed George
too hard.
Is Your Monkeyness ready
for the coronation rehearsal?
Uh-huh.
Okay, we're picking this up from
the princess already seated.
Excellent.
Now, cue the drummers.
And now, the royal trumpeters.
And now, the Royal Monkey,
bearing his royal scepter.
The Royal Monkey enters!
Oh, come on,
where's the Royal Monkey?
Aha!
Ooh!
Huh?
Did everyone suddenly forget
the king's no-music policy?
Huh?
Your Monkeyness. Please.
We need to continue.
Places, please, places.
And here we go.
Drummers...
Now, carrying the crown,
the Royal Monkey performs
the traditional royal march.
Okay...
The Royal Monkey proceeds...
...with great formality...
and presents the crown
to the princess.
Ooh.
Okay.
I think you have rehearsed
quite enough for one day.
What has gotten into
you two?
Ooh.
Don't worry, Ana.
We're just tired
of rehearsing.
We've done it
perfectly before,
and we'll get it right
tomorrow too.
Well... see that you do.
Oh...
What am I going to do,
Philippe?
Huh?
Oh, this is too awful.
Hmm.
Mm-hmm. Mm-mm-hmm.
Mm-hmm.
This barge should be first
and this one last.
Uh, no, wait...
Uh, this should be first and...
Ugh, this is complicated.
Uh, yes, enter, enter away.
Ah, good. You've brought...
The Royal Monkey,
as you requested.
Thank you, Ana.
That will be all.
Your Monkeyness, I wanted
to speak with you myself.
Ooh.
Oh. You like the boats?
Ah. I made them myself.
See, I added the flags.
And here,
the itty-bitty bunting.
Ooh.
Aah.
Uh-uh, not so fast.
The Royal Barge is on your tail.
And it's a tie!
Ooh.
Yes, uh, well,
I was just finalizing the plans
for Isabel's coronation tomorrow.
Ha-ha.
Uh, which is why
I sent for you.
You see, you were just not
acting like our Royal Monkey.
Oh.
No. You must straighten up.
I'm counting on you
to make sure
absolutely nothing goes wrong
tomorrow that would embarrass Isabel.
Her future, in fact,
the future of the whole kingdom...
depends on it.
Oh.
Hmm.
Hmph.
Hmm?
Hmm.
Huh?
Oh, wow.
Your Monkeyness?
I've never seen you at the stables before.
Huh? Hey!
I'm glad we're done
with those boring rehearsals.
I know my coronation's
important, but after tomorrow,
I'll never be allowed
to have any fun.
Well, you know,
it's not like it is in fairy tales.
Just boring meetings all the
time once I'm a real princess.
Papa says there will be
no time to ride El Fuego.
Your Monkeyness,
you're acting so strange.
Why did you come to see me?
Huh?
I didn't know you and
Fernando were friends.
You seem so different
since our trip.
I like the new Philippe.
Whoa.
Huh?
Oh, dear. Hyah.
Where are you going?
Philippe,
we shouldn't be here.
Ah.
Hmm.
You know, I've never ridden El
Fuego outside the castle gate.
Hyah!
♪ Funny how in just a moment ♪
♪ Everything can change ♪
♪ Doors and walls
That closed you in ♪
♪ You watch them rearrange ♪
♪ Now your world
Is open wide ♪
♪ The sky above is blue ♪
♪ And with a good friend
At your side ♪
♪ You found a brand-new you ♪
♪ Now you know ♪
♪ Anything is possible ♪
♪ Today belongs to you ♪
♪ Now you know ♪
♪ All the dreams
You locked away ♪
♪ They just might come true ♪
♪ Yesterday you did not know ♪
♪ You could shine
With such a glow ♪
♪ You didn't know it then ♪
♪ Now you know ♪
♪ Now you're racing
With the wind ♪
♪ You're learning how to fly ♪
♪ Won't you let
The laughter in ♪
♪ You wave the past good-bye ♪
♪ As your heart
Lifts off the ground ♪
♪ Who knows
Where you will go ♪
♪ This is freedom
That you found ♪
You wanna race to that tree?
♪ Now you know ♪
Uh-huh.
I'll give you
a head start.
Hyah!
♪ Might come true today ♪
♪ Yesterday you did not know ♪
♪ You could shine
With such a glow ♪
♪ You didn't know it then ♪
♪ Now you know ♪
Oh, thank you.
Did you know El Fuego
is a champion racehorse?
Ooh.
This is the last
announcement that the people's derby
will start tomorrow
at 11:00 a.m. sharp.
Everyone, young and old,
is welcome to enter.
Just gather your noble steeds at the
starting line after the bugle call.
It's going to be a grand event.
The derby. I'd give anything
to ride in it just once.
And I bet
El Fuego would too.
You think we should?
I... but I...
Huh?
You're right.
This is my last chance.
El Fuego and I
are running in the derby.
But we'd better
get back to the castle.
Papa will be wondering
where we are. Hyah!
Ride like the wind,
Your Monkeyness!
♪ Now you know ♪
♪ Oh, now you know ♪
Okay, buddy.
After all that hard work,
you deserve a little fun.
So, go ahead, have fun!
Eh.
Huh?
Oh, come on.
This is your favorite park.
Hey, how about climbing?
Oh, you love climbing trees.
Oh, here I go. Look at me.
I am climbing.
Oh, my goodness, this is so much fun!
Hey, come on up!
Hey, so, uh...
how do you get down
from one of these things?
This really isn't necessary.
- Yes, sir.
- You see, it's George,
he's like a different monkey,
and it's all my fault.
Yeah.
Whatever you say, sir.
I just want
my old monkey back.
Argh.
I hope that means
you forgive me.
Mmm?
Hmm. I could use a snack.
How about you?
Hmm.
Mm-hmm.
Mmm.
Is this really necessary?
But, Your Majesty,
studies show
that the more people
watch the coronation,
the better for
the national image.
No, no, I mean makeup.
Oh, it...
brings out your eyes, Your Majesty.
Very well.
In three, two...
Uh, my fellow citizens
of Simiana.
It is my pleasure
to invite you
to my daughter's coronation
tomorrow.
Race you.
Isabel will assume
her official...
Papa?
...with dedication and...
Argh.
Uh-oh.
...to witness our country's
most solemn ceremony.
Ooh-oh!
Aaah!
Well, I think that about
wraps up the interview.
Isabel, what happened?
I'm sorry, Papa.
And, Philippe,
you were supposed to look after her.
Papa, I know I probably
broke every rule...
Riding outside the castle?
And riding a goat?
What if
someone had seen you?
We were just out
trying to have some fun.
Hmm.
Isabel, you don't know how
quickly the people can turn on you
if you go against custom
and look silly.
What do you mean?
Uh, let's not
talk about this anymore.
Ana, see to it that the
princess and Royal Monkey
get to the coronation
on time tomorrow.
- Aah.
- I should have never gone riding with you!
Huh?
Your Monkeyness, I'll see you
at the coronation tomorrow.
Huh?
♪ Can't find the sun
Fun isn't fun like before ♪
♪ Everything's wrong
Nothing seems right anymore ♪
♪ Try to be good
But somehow it all goes bad ♪
♪ Can't see the light
Try as you might ♪
♪ Nothing seems right anymore ♪
♪ No help in sight
Nothing seems right ♪
♪ Anymore ♪
Okay, we're in for a treat.
I made pancakes.
Hey, you wanna play
hide-n-seek?
Mmm.
How about checkers?
Uh-uh.
Okay...
How about a movie?
And now for light news
from around the world.
There was a minor mishap in a
little known country, Simiana.
Simiana?
With the upcoming coronation
of their new princess,
they held a press conference and
things did not go quite as planned.
I hope you will
join us tomorrow
to witness our country's
most solemn ceremony.
Oh.
It looks
like that little monkey
caused quite a mess.
In other news...
Hey. That monkey
looks just like you, George.
And he kind of acts like
you used to.
Wait a minute.
Okay, this may sound crazy,
but are you, by any chance,
the Royal Monkey of Simiana?
Uh-huh.
Uh... Wait.
Did you come to the museum
with the king and the princess?
- Uh-huh.
- Oh, boy.
Uh, you... Uh...
So, George is in Simiana
and I didn't break my monkey!
I mean, uh, no offense, Your Magician...
Majestration...
Uh, Mr. Monkey, sir.
We need to get you
back home.
And I've got to get George.
Huh?
I'm going to miss you,
El Fuego.
Huh?
Your Monkeyness.
Ah.
Yeah.
The derby will start soon.
You know I can't.
I have to leave all this behind.
I know,
it would be so much fun.
But apparently fun is a luxury for
ordinary people, not a princess.
If fun is for ordinary people...
then let's be ordinary.
Hey! Can you give us a hand?
I can't believe we're doing
this, Your Monkeyness.
We're really doing this.
Riders, approach the
starting line. The derby's about to begin!
Hyah!
Your Highness?
It's almost time to go.
Princess?
Ah, she must be there already.
Probably couldn't wait for her big day.
That must be it.
That better be it.
Please let that be it.
Oh, here you are,
little boy.
Huh? Ah.
Huh?
Riders, on your mark,
get set... go!
Yeah! Come on! Whoo!
Go, go, go!
Ooh.
Huh?
Uh-oh.
Oh! It's the Royal Monkey.
The Royal Monkey.
The Royal Monkey's
in the race.
Aah!
Huh?
The princess is in the race?
Princess Isabel is in the race!
- It's the princess!
- Princess Isabel!
Huh?
Turn it on, El Fuego.
Hyah!
Why, it's Princess Isabel
gaining on the lead!
♪ Sometimes
There are miracles ♪
♪ The world can be brand-new ♪
And the riders
are on the final stretch!
♪ Anything that's
In your way ♪
♪ You can ride right through ♪
♪ Yesterday you did not know ♪
And the winner, by a nose,
is Princess Isabel!
♪ Now you know ♪
Thank you, El Fuego.
Congratulations,
congratulations!
You won the derby, Princess.
I can't believe that your
father granted you permission
to join us, with your
coronation happening so soon.
My coronation!
I almost forgot!
I'm so sorry.
We have to go.
Eh... but your prize,
Princess!
What a beautiful country
you have.
Hmm.
Your Monkeyness.
Oh.
Entry
by royal invitation only.
This is not good.
Hey, you climbed a tree.
Oh. And now it's my turn.
Argh!
Oh, boy! Ah, an intruder!
Over there!
Hey, stop!
Halt in
the name of the king!
Come in.
Ooh.
I think I'm ready
for my coronation now.
Uh-huh.
George? George?
Over here!
Eh...
I think
I've got this backwards.
Your Highness?
Your Monkeyness?
George!
Aw.
I'm so confused.
Are there two Philippes?
- Uh-huh.
- George, I am sorry it took me so long to get here.
I thought you were him
and he was you,
but I'm so glad
that you're not.
Er, no offense, Philippe.
Oh, George,
I missed you so much.
Don't ever stop being
my fun little monkey.
Aw.
- Philippe?
- Uh-huh.
Yeah, back at the museum,
you left Philippe with me,
and you took George home
by mistake.
George, you really spiced
things up around here.
- Ah.
- He has a way of doing that.
And I loved it.
Aw.
Philippe, I'm glad you're
home safe and sound.
Mmm.
Ah.
The intruder's this way!
Oh, yeah.
I'm the intruder.
- Over here!
- Come on. We'd better hide you.
Clear down this hall!
Check around that corner!
- What now?
- Shh. Let's just hope they won't come in.
Uh, George,
best not to touch anything.
Uh-huh.
Ooh.
A secret passage?
Over here!
Check the king's quarters!
I got nothing.
Copy that.
I think they're gone.
Oh!
Uh-huh! Uh-huh!
- What's going on?
- Intruder in the castle, ma'am.
If you see a man wearing a yellow
hat, let us know.
Argh.
What is this place?
Papa has a secret room?
Did you know about this?
Uh-uh.
All these
old pictures of Papa.
I never saw any of them.
He was so happy.
I don't think
I've ever seen him smile.
Uh-uh.
Look, Papa played the horn.
Not for a long time
from the looks of it.
I wonder why.
Ooh.
Hey, look.
Papa's coronation.
Look, Philippe,
it's your father.
Aw.
And now,
Prince Gustavo
will perform
his original composition
for the people of Simiana.
He's good.
Uh-huh.
Huh? Uh. Argh!
Oh, my goodness.
What a shocking development.
The prince has taken a tumble.
Such an embarrassment.
Poor Papa.
Oh.
That's why he's so scared
of anything ever going wrong.
He's afraid
people will laugh at us.
My coronation.
I can't be late.
I don't want Papa to be embarrassed again.
How are we going to
get out of here?
What are you thinking?
Oh, boy.
Huh?
Is that...
Oh, no, no, no, no, no...
Princess!
Here we go.
- Aaah!
- Whoo!
- Look out!
- Whoo-hoo!
Oh, oh, my goodness!
Princess, are you okay?
Never better.
Philippe? Philippe?
Hmm.
Uh, hi, I'm Ted.
From the museum.
You're hard to forget.
Ana, I'll explain everything later.
Right now, we have to
get to the barge. Come on!
We're too late!
Ted, grab that rowboat.
Yes!
Philippe, other monkey, man the oars!
Better yet, monkey them!
Uh, anyone have some
horn-removal oil?
Greetings, citizens of Simiana.
Let the Royal Coronation begin.
Huh?
Where's Isabel?
A little closer,
a little closer.
Oh, boy.
Isabel?
Philippe?
This is a disaster.
This can't be happening.
Not on Isabel's big day!
Papa?
Isabel.
I'm sorry, Papa.
Oh, there she is!
Congratulations!
I don't understand.
Princess!
You ran off without this,
Princess.
Whoa, whoa. Aah!
Congratulations!
The derby?
You raced.
And won!
Two Philippes?
And you?
Hi. Yes, it's me,
Your Majesty.
And this is Philippe.
But this is George.
Uncanny.
Is that my horn?
Papa, I know
about your coronation.
You saw?
You played music so well.
And you loved it.
- Yeah.
- Uh-huh.
People laughed at me.
I didn't want that for you.
You should give the people
another chance.
Let them get to know you, Papa.
And you shouldn't let fear stop
you from doing what you love.
George taught me that.
Then you are
a very special monkey.
And you are
a very wise princess.
- Aw.
- Mmm.
Uh-huh!
♪ I've been trying
To keep it down on ♪
♪ All this workin'
Be uptight ♪
♪ I guess how it looks
Everywhere I go ♪
♪ But if following my heart Is
wrong I don't want to be right ♪
♪ See, I'm a wildfire
But all I do is glow ♪
♪ I can't hold it in no more
I can't bite my tongue ♪
♪ I'm gonna sing like
I'm a song that must be sung ♪
♪ I can't hold it in no more
My time has come ♪
♪ I'm gonna shine like
I'm a diamond in the sun ♪
♪ Shimmy, shimmy Shine with me now
Hey, whoa, oh ♪
♪ I say
♪ Shimmy, shimmy Shine with me now
Hey, whoa, oh ♪
♪ I say hey, whoa, oh ♪
♪ Shimmy, shimmy Shine with me now
Hey, whoa, oh ♪
♪ I say
♪ Shimmy, shimmy Shine with me now
Hey, whoa, oh ♪
♪ I say
♪ Hey
So world, you best get ready ♪
♪ There is no one
quite like me ♪
♪ No copies of my soul
That I've seen ♪
♪ And I'm
On the surface something ♪
♪ And that something
is unique ♪
♪ Falling in line
♪ Is not the kind I wanna be ♪
♪ 'Cause in my heart I got
A marching band ♪
♪ And a beating drums
Singing ♪
♪ You've been quiet
for much too long ♪
♪ And tensions rise
And I'm about to blow ♪
♪ I can't stay in the back
Too late for me, no, no ♪
♪ I can't hold it in no more ♪
♪ I can't bite my tongue ♪
♪ I'm gonna sing
like I'm a song ♪
♪ That must be sung ♪
♪ I can't hold it in no more
My time has come ♪
♪ I'm gonna shine like
I'm a diamond in the sun ♪
♪ Shimmy, shimmy Shine with me now
Hey, whoa, oh ♪
♪ I say hey, whoa, oh ♪
♪ Shimmy, shimmy Shine with me now
Hey, whoa, oh ♪
♪ I say
♪ So, I'm-a shine ♪
♪ Oh, I'm-a shine on through ♪
♪ Whether you Like my shine
or not At least it's true ♪
♪ I can't hold it in no more
I can't bite my tongue ♪
♪ I'm gonna sing like
I'm a song that must be sung ♪
♪ I can't hold it in no more
My time has come ♪
♪ I'm gonna shine like
I'm a diamond in the sun ♪
♪ I can't hold it in no more
Just having fun ♪
♪ I'm gonna sing like
I'm a song that must be sung ♪
♪ I can't hold it in no more
My time has come ♪
♪ I'm gonna shine like
I'm a diamond in the sun ♪
♪ Shimmy, shimmy Shine with me now
Hey, whoa, oh ♪
♪ I say
♪ Shimmy, shimmy Shine with me now
Hey, whoa, oh ♪
♪ I say hey, whoa, oh ♪
♪ When you look out
The window ♪
♪ And ponder the view ♪
♪ And you hear sweet music ♪
♪ From out of the blue ♪
♪ When you feel the morning
Calling to you ♪
♪ There's only one thing
You can do ♪
♪ You got to ride that ride ♪
♪ Jump right in, get up
And go with it, ride that ride ♪
♪ Swing and sway and groove
And flow with it ♪
♪ Ride that ride ♪
♪ Rise with the tide ♪
♪ When you ride, ride, ride ♪
♪ It'll lift you up ♪
♪ It'll let you down ♪
♪ Oh, the wheel of life ♪
♪ Gonna spin you round ♪
♪ It'll take you places ♪
♪ You never could guess ♪
♪ And all you gotta say
And all you gotta say ♪
♪ Is yes, yes, yes ♪
♪ And ride that ride ♪
♪ Slip and slide and move
And flow with it ♪
♪ Ride that ride ♪
♪ Get up, get out
Get on and go with it ♪
♪ Ride that ride ♪
♪ What comes next
You'll never know ♪
♪ Till you ride, ride, ride ♪