(SINGING) Choo-choo
Choo-choo-doo-doo.
Choo-choo.
Choo-choo-doo-doo
(LITTLE ENGINE TOOTING)
(GASPS)
Huh?
LITTLE ENGINE: Morning!
(SCOFFS) Little Engine!
Up early again?
Just getting a jump on the day.
(SINGING) You wake up
and you just can't wait.
To see how far you'll get today.
You're ready
and you're steady, yeah.
As strong as you can be.
You'll get the part
You'll set the pace.
You'll be the star
You'll win the race.
(Tooting)
'Cause life is just a thousand
shining possibilities
(ALL YAWNING)
And every day
you'll start to see
(SNEEZES)
(GASPS) EW! EW! EW!
(GIGGLING)
Little me, big dreams
I can be whoever I believe.
It's not the place
that you start.
But where you reach
with your heart.
That changes everything.
Little me, big dreams.
(GAS PS) Where's the caboose?
TOWER: All right,
all right, all right.
We've got a schedule to keep.
No lagging,
dragging or sagging.
And smile!
We are delivering dreams,
not nightmares, people.
(SINGING)
Every day's another page
(SNORING)
You write the story
your own way.
You take a chance and try
(TOOTING)
(EXCLAIMING)
You might not have
the biggest part.
But it's a job and it's a start.
And there's no stopping
when you open up your mind.
Engine 35, you are now
cleared for departure.
But I don't have my caboose.
(GASPS) Lime Engine?
LITTLE ENGINE:
I'm on it, boss!
(TOOTING)
(CHUCKLES) Hey,
you coming with us?
To the Real World?
Oh, I'd give anything to see
a child get their wish.
(CHUCKLES) Maybe someday.
Little Engine!
Uh, I gotta go.
Take it easy, kid.
Have a good trip!
Big Locomotive, you're next.
You'll be delivering wishes
and dreams on track 19.
Well, sure. As soon
as I get my boxcars.
We need that hunter!
(SINGING) You never
win by thinking small.
Today's the day
you might just have it all.
Little me, big dreams
I can be whoever I believe
(EXCLAIMS HAUGHTILY)
It's not the place
that you start.
But where you reach
with your heart.
That changes everything.
Little me, big dreams.
Little me, big dreams
(PANTING)
TOWER: (SIGHS) Little Engine, how
many times do I have to tell you?
You're only supposed
to pull one at a time.
You're little.
You can't pull what
a Dream Hauler can pull!
Uh, I'll take it from here,
Little Engine.
Sorry. Let's just pretend
this never happened.
And that's why they
call it a Choo-Choo!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Oh, Rusty, you're too funny.
Hey, Little Engine.
Perfect timing.
Say, can you move Freight
Train's cars over here?
Happy to.
I've just had
back-to-back runs.
Rusty has offered
to deliver my load.
These kids and their
dreams have me beat.
Thanks again, Rusty!
So, uh, kid, I saw you earlier.
You almost got Big Locomotive's
whole load to the depot.
Don't remind me.
It's the last time
I try something like that.
RUSTY: Hey, hey!
You'll never be a Dream Hauler
with an attitude like that!
(GRUNTING)
Come on.
Everybody knows
I'm just a hunter.
I move boxcars around the yard.
Shunters don't haul dreams.
Says who?
Now tell me you don't think about
pulling a load yourself someday.
Okay, maybe I do.
A little.
But that doesn't change anything.
I'm just too small.
(GASPS)
Girl, listen to me now.
If you think you can,
you will.
If you think you can't,
you won't.
Either way, you're right.
You really believe that?
I know it.
See you, kid!
(TOOTING)
Watch your torque
on those turns!
(SIGHS) Next stop,
the Real World.
(ECHOING) The Real World.
The Real World.
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
See? It runs now.
My dad couldn't
believe I fixed it.
Wow, Richard.
Is it real silver?
Yeah. My grandpa worked for
the railroad his whole life.
Well, you've got your
presentation nailed.
I got stuck bringing
my grandpa's dentures.
(GASPS) EW, Marcus,
that's gross.
(RETCHING) I know.
And if I don't get them home
by noon, it's soup for lunch.
(GASPS)
(WHISPERING) Danger!
Two o'clock! Let's go!
(GRUNTS)
Whoa!
(GASPS)
Hey, Stretch, check it out.
Richie-Boy just gave me this.
I did not!
Sure you did. See?
(BOTH LAUGHING TAUNTINGLY)
Give me that!
It's not...
You can't take it!
That's my grandpa's watch!
You... You better...
Give me... Give you what?
A punch?
(BOTH LAUGH)
No! I...
You run home and tell
your daddy about this,
your face meets my fist every day after
school for the rest of your life.
(GRUNTS)
(BOTH LAUGHING MOCKINGLY)
Man, Marcus. When my dad finds out I lost
the watch, he is not gonna be happy.
But you didn't lose
the watch. Scott has it.
Yeah, like I'm ever
getting it back.
Well, you gotta try.
I mean, the watch is
important to you.
Maybe it's time
you stand up to him.
Are you crazy?
He's big, he's strong,
and he likes to inflict pain.
Hmm. You could
sneak into his locker!
Or... Ooh!
Take karate!
(GRUNTING)
Forget it, Marcus.
I don't need any of your dumb suggestions.
Fine! Well, then,
you figure it out.
FATHER: Richard,
is that you?
(SIGHS) What am I gonna do?
(EXCLAIMS)
What?
Train tracks?
That's weird.
There is no train in the park.
(GASPS)
Okay.
There is a train in the park.
(SHIVERING)
(GRUNTING)
Huh?
Oh, boy, taking a nap on the job.
What was I thinking?
(SIGHS) Maybe I shouldn't
have taken that extra load.
(TOOTING)
Hey! Hey!
(GRUNTS)
Whoa! Oh!
Where are we going?
(GASPS)
Stop this thing!
(EXCLAIMS)
(SCREAMING)
(RUMBLING OMINOUSLY)
Huh? What's going on?
(GASPING)
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
(GRUNTS)
(GASPING)
Oh, no.
I better tell the Tower!
(DINGING)
(CLATTERING)
(TRAINS TOOTING)
(GASPS)
Repair team to the station.
Shunters, where are you?
Clear the tracks!
Emergency crews, report in.
Dream Land is going crazy!
(GROANS)
Apologies, peanut roaster.
Is your buggy sore?
Uh, just a tap.
What's going on?
Besides the general pandemonium
and ominous state of affairs?
Not a clue.
The tunnel! It's gone!
Caved in! Collapsed!
(GASPS) what?
Not possible.
The sun comes up,
the sun goes down,
and the tunnel's always open.
Well, it's a pile
of rubble now!
But how could
that happen, Rusty?
I mean, just like that?
Out of the blue?
All right, everybody!
Just settle down.
First thing we gotta do is figure
out why the tunnel collapsed.
Whoa!
TOWER: Rusty, did you see anything
or hear anything unusual?
RUSTY: No. I was just going through
and it started collapsing!
TOWER: (GROANS) That
doesn't make any sense.
There's got to be
an explanation!
RUSTY: I don't know!
(GASPS) Hello
(EXCLAIMS)
(ALL GASPING)
What the heck?
(PANTING NERVOUSLY)
Oh, it's just a boy.
(EXCLAIMING) A boy?
(STAMMERING) You're
a talking train?
Um, yeah.
(SCREAMING)
What's... What's...
Where... What's...
(RICHARD EXCLAIMING)
Whoa!
(SCREAMING)
What is this place?
A real boy?
In Dream Land?
(EXCLAIMING)
Here's the problem!
You've caused bedlam
around here.
You're from the Real World.
You ripped a hole in the
dream-reality continuum!
What, me? But I just... I was...
There was all this
snow and wind,
and then this train.
I just climbed in and...
Huh? Train? What train?
(GASPS)
(SIGHS)
it's my fault.
Rusty?
Rusty! You?
(ALL MURMURING) Well, see, I...
I guess...
I must have closed my eyes
for a second or two.
How could you let this happen?
GIRL TRAIN: What were you thinking?
A real boy in our world?
What a train wreck!
Excuse me.
Where exactly am...
Wow!
I've never seen
a real boy before.
Shine your light on him,
Freight Train.
(GASPS)
EW! He's all soft
and fleshy.
Yeah, kind of
creepy-looking.
All right, enough!
We all know what this means.
Dream Land won't recover
unless the boy goes back.
Yes! The boy
must go back!
We're going to have
to dig out the tunnel!
But that could take
months! Or years!
Well, we need to get
to work on it now!
Freight Train, Big Locomotive, Shiny
Passenger Train, you're the first shift. Go.
It's always the pretty ones
that get picked.
TOWER: And you...
Suddenly not so fun
to be popular, is it?
Oh, Tower, you know what?
I think I have something here.
Back when there wasn't
any tunnel,
Dream Haulers went over the
mountain to the Real World.
Whoa!
Over the mountain?
(SCOFFS) That's just
an old smoke story.
But it's true! And what if the
old tracks are still there?
We don't have time
for a wild goose chase.
We got a big job ahead of us.
Not you, Rusty.
What do you mean?
Listen, you fell asleep
on the job.
(STAMMERING) I don't
have any other choice.
I gotta demote you.
You're a track cleaner now.
Somebody bring him a broom.
Track cleaner? But Rusty's
a Dream Hauler!
(SIGHS) No, she's right, kid.
I messed up.
This is the price
I have to pay.
So sorry, Rusty.
You can't do this to Rusty!
You have to give him
another chance!
He made one little mistake!
Look around.
I'd say it was more
than a little mistake.
Um, ma'am?
If he's not taking me back,
then what's going
to happen to me?
Hang on. We're working
on getting you back home.
Stay here.
I'll be right back.
Hey, Rusty!
What were you saying
about those old tracks?
(SIGHS) Well,
nobody remembers now,
but long ago, in the beginning,
the trains went over the
mountain, not through it.
It was grueling and dangerous.
Sad to say, some trains
never made it back.
It was clear, the trains
needed a safer way
to deliver wishes and
dreams to the Real World.
So, they decided to try
and go through the mountain.
It wasn't easy,
but after years of hard work,
the trains finally
dug out the tunnel.
But before the tunnel,
there was another way?
Yep. And I'm guessing those
old tracks still exist.
They used to say the turnoff's
just a little north
of the tunnel.
So somebody could take the real
boy back over the mountain!
That's what I was trying
to tell the Tower.
Don't worry, Rusty.
I'll make the Tower understand.
All right, listen up now.
We're on a new schedule.
Every Dream Hauler will
take one shift a day,
and then I will...
Um... Pardon me.
What? Not now.
But Rusty says
that someone can...
(EXCLAIMS)
Can't you see I'm busy?
The first shift is on
their way to the tunnel.
We'll start the second
shift exactly at sunset.
We need to have...
But, ma'am!
Please, I'm trying...
Enough!
Dream Land is a mess!
I do not have time for you!
Now, where was I? Second shift, get
ready to head out as soon as...
What if I can fix Dream Land?
Then can Rusty
have his job back?
Sure!
You fix Dream Land, and not only
will I give Rusty his job back,
I will throw him a ticker
tape parade as well.
(TRAINS LAUGHING)
Now, if I could just finish
without any more interruptions...
Come on, Real Boy.
I know how to get you home.
Wow! Really? Awesome!
Are you sure that Tower
said this was okay?
Absolutely. She gave me
the green light.
So, what's the plan?
Those Dream Haulers won't be
happy digging out the tunnel.
So, we'll just zip over there and
tell them about the old tracks.
You watch. They'll jump at the chance
to haul you over Dream Mountain.
Wait a minute.
Dream Mountain. Dream Haulers.
Now I get it!
Get what?
This is a dream!
I'm at home in my bed,
sleeping!
Badly.
No, you're not.
You're here.
(GAS PS) And look!
Everything Rusty said
is true! It's so... So...
RICHARD: Girly! Rainbows
and flowers and...
Where are the superheroes
and monsters?
This isn't a dream.
It's a nightmare!
(LAUGHS) You're not dreaming.
I told you, this is Dream Land.
Where do you think
dreams come from?
Well, if this isn't a dream,
then how could I do this?
Uh, you really
shouldn't be doing that.
(WHOOPING)
(LAUGHING)
Awesome!
Oh, this must be a chase dream!
A what?
Yeah! Look!
(TOOTING) (GASPS) The
Evening Express?
He's way off schedule!
EVENING EXPRESS:
Coming through!
All right!
This is when we fly!
I can't fly!
Well, maybe you can't.
But I can!
LITTLE ENGINE: No! Don't!
(WHOOPS) I'am flying!
Ah! I'm falling.
(GROANS)
Aren't you kind of far
from home, Real Boy?
(EXCLAIMS) Ouch!
(GROANS) That actually hurt.
If I'm feeling pain,
then that means
I'm not dreaming!
(HORN BLOWING)
Okay. No pressure,
but you might wanna go faster.
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
I'm trying!
RICHARD: Oh, and I've
got some bad news.
You are not going
to outrun him.
I think I can!
I think you can't!
Hang on, Little Engine!
I can't stop!
(LITTLE ENGINE SCREAMING)
EVENING EXPRESS: Sorry!
(SCREAMING)
Uh, remember how
you wanted to fly?
Well, buckle up, Real Boy!
(SCREAMING)
(WHOOPING)
(LITTLE ENGINE LAUGHING)
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
Wow! Wasn't that exciting?
No, that was insane!
(GROANS)
But I flew off the tracks!
Yeah. I know.
I was there.
I was the one screaming,
remember?
So, I'm not dreaming.
That's right.
And I'm in some
sort of Dream Land.
That's also right.
(SIGHS) I wish Rusty
could've seen me.
You gotta admit,
I'm doing pretty well for my first
time out of the train yard.
Your first time?
Great! I'm never
gonna make it!
Don't be silly.
It's a straight shot
to Dream Mountain.
Nothing will go wrong.
(HISSING)
(GASPS)
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Just a little loose
here or there.
(POOPING)
LITTLE ENGINE: Whoops!
A little?
We'd better deal with this
or we aren't going anywhere.
(GRUNTING) Almost got it.
That feels tight, Real Boy.
(GRUNTING) There!
And by the way, my name is Richard.
Richard, huh? Funny.
You don't look like a Richard.
Then what do I look like?
A real boy.
Better?
Much better. Thank you.
Where'd you learn that?
I'm into building models.
You know, airplanes, cars.
And somehow, there's always
one of these left over.
Keep it. Now, let's roll.
Whoa!
This must be Mushroom Forest.
It's just like Rusty described.
(GRUNTING)
What are you doing?
Getting a better look.
Careful!
Whoa!
Hey, look at that one.
Ooh!
Stop, stop!
I wanna get a closer look.
Awesome!
They'll never believe
this back home.
Yoo-hoo!
Hello! Hello! Stop!
(GASPS)
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
(EXCLAIMING)
Hey, hey, hey, stop!
(EXCLAIMS IN FEAR)
(GASPING) Sorry.
Is everyone all right?
Well, let's hope so!
Okay, okay, nobody panic!
Follow the sound of my nose.
(HONKING)
Major reporting, Sir!
At ease, Major.
And for the record,
I'm not a sir. I'm a ma'am.
Yes, of course, Sir...
Ma'am... Sir!
Ace! There you are.
You okay?
JILLIAN: Oh!
Jillian, is that you?
(EXCLAIMS) Pardon me.
My caboose is showing.
Lou? Bud?
Whoa, Bud! Check it out!
The world's tipped over!
Everything's sideways!
(LAUGHS)
Hey, thanks, bro.
Head bump!
Where's Hudson?
Has anyone seen Hudson?
Hudson! Hudson!
You don't have to shout,
Beverly. I'm right here.
Oh, Hudson!
Okay. Trains
and toys talk?
In Dream Land they do.
Hey!
You're the real boy!
We heard about you
from a couple of trains on their
way to dig out the tunnel.
No doubt he's the reason
for our sudden derailment.
Derailment? Your train
came off the tracks?
I'm afraid so. The switcher started going
crazy and he ran off into the ditch.
Maybe we can help.
(LAUGHING)
Oh, no! Oh, no!
(LAUGHING) Oh, no!
Can you cut it out already?
You're rattling my windows!
I can't help it.
I'm ticklish. (LAUGHING)
Sorry. I can't fix it.
This can't be happening.
Stranded miles from
the Real World! Oh!
Mission unaccomplished, Sir.
Well, we'll have to
think of something.
If we don't make it
to the Real World soon...
I can take you to Dream Mountain,
where the big engines are.
Really? That would be great!
(MOUTHING)
Oh, sure! Go ahead!
Leave me behind!
(SADLY) Everybody else does.
You can come, too.
Have you popped your rivets?
You're too little.
She won't last five minutes out
there with a load to haul.
Hold on. We're on the brink of disaster.
Not really in the position to quibble!
Are you nuts?
You barely made it this far.
And now you wanna
haul all this?
What if another
express comes by?
Not likely.
BEV: Abra-ka-dizzle and shizza-ti-sham.
Don't look around...
But we don't even
know these toys!
I mean, what about that clown?
What is she hiding
behind her back?
Ta-da!
(ALL EXCLAIMING EXCITEDLY)
Now you're being silly again.
Well, it just seems
kind of risky.
Some things are worth the risk.
Hey, Richard!
How do I look?
Uh, you look like a train?
But I feel different.
I'm hauling toys!
Hey, go see
if they need anything.
I say there, Richard,
could I have a moment
of your time?
Sure. I'm not
going anywhere.
Am I fun?
Entertaining? Lovable?
What will my child think of me?
Come on, Hudson.
Don't ask me.
But you're a child,
so you must know,
and I want to know so badly.
Really, I mean, what do you think?
Really? Really?
Well, honestly,
I think you're
kind of annoying.
What? Oh, no,
no, no, no! No!
What's going on?
(SOBBING)
Hudson asked me
what I thought of him.
And I'm annoying, apparently.
Kid's got a point, dude.
Look, you're a stuffed animal.
I'm sure your kid
will like you.
Well, how can you be so sure?
I mean, I am annoying!
Because I had one.
Until my dog
ripped his head off.
(ALL GASP)
Huh! Gnarly.
It's okay, though.
My mom sewed his head back on.
All hail the great Mum!
(SHUDDERS) The Real World
sounds kind of scary.
(SIGHS) It is.
There are bullies who take your
stuff and don't give it back.
Then you can't go home because
you're afraid to tell your dad.
And then you end up
in Dream Land.
You mean we're stranded because
you couldn't face some bullies?
(RUMBLING)
(ALL EXCLAIM)
(STEAM HISSING)
I'd better go see
what's going on.
You okay?
Look! We're almost there!
(ALL CHEERING)
All right. Back in.
Let's roll.
Are we there yet?
Guys?
Anyone?
Hello!
(BRAKES SQUEALING)
Way to haul, kiddo.
Yeah. Nice work,
Little Engine.
Thank you!
I said, "Honk, honk!"
And then...
Now, you guys stay here.
I'll be right back with a big engine
who will haul you over the mountain.
SHINY PASSENGER TRAIN: And there
she was, right in front of me.
Sol rolled up to her
and said, "Honk!"
And then she said,
"Honk, honk!"
And then I said,
And then she said,
"Honk, honk."
And then I went,
"Oh, no, you honk, honk!"
I have no idea what
you're talking about.
(CLEARS THROAT) Excuse me.
Oh, my gosh!
What are you doing here?
You look a little lost, peanut roaster.
Train yard's that way.
Oh, I'm not lost.
I brought the real boy so you
can take him over the mountain.
Then you won't have to dig anymore
because Dream Land will be fixed
and Rusty can be
a Dream Hauler again!
I am so confused.
Rusty told me
about the old tracks.
The old tracks?
Yeah, you know, the ones
that go over the mountain.
Huh? Hmm? Hmm?
(ALL LAUGHING)
BIG LOCOMOTIVE:
Did she say over the...
RICHARD: They're laughing.
You think that's a good thing?
Hmm. I'm a clown.
Laughing always sounds good to me.
Look, those old tracks are a myth.
They don't exist.
But Rusty said...
Oh, please.
He's totally desperate.
He'll try anything
to get his job back.
Now, you better take the real
boy back to the train yard.
(SNIFFLES) where
he's supposed to be.
We got work to do here.
But, what about those trains?
Don't even think
about asking them.
They've got to dig, and we've
gotta rest for the next shift.
So, go on now.
Move your caboose.
Well?
They don't believe
the tracks exist.
So, they're not going to
take us over the mountain?
It's okay. We'll just wait here until
we find a big engine who believes us.
You'll get to your kids.
It'll just take a little time.
You don't understand.
The children have already wished
for us, and now we're late.
And that's one step away
from being forgotten.
You see, for us, once we're
forgotten, we disappear.
Well, what about you, Little Engine?
Could you take us?
Oh. I don't know.
But don't worry.
You'll find someone bigger, stronger.
A real Dream Hauler.
We don't have time, Little Engine.
There's nobody else.
Listen, I was wrong about you.
Look how far you've come.
You can handle
that old mountain!
(HESITANTLY) I...
I think I can.
(ALL CHEERING)
Now, let's go find
those old tracks.
888, 889, 890, 891...
CABOOSE: Nine, eight, seven, six...
...892, 893,
894, 895...
...five, four, three, two...
(ALL SHUSHING)
Oh, uh, sorry.
899, 900.
Rusty said there should be some old switch
rails here so we can change tracks.
I say! I think
I see something!
Where? I don't
see anything.
(GASPS) Epic news!
We see something, straight ahead.
(SINGING)
It's a beautiful kind of day.
When you're suddenly
on your way.
Somewhere that you
only dreamed was true.
It's a magical kind of sight.
When the thing you want most
is right before your eyes.
And it's yours to find.
So pick up your feet
and let's get going.
You've got the steam
to just keep rolling on.
And on.
Here we go, in that glow.
Feel that feeling taking over.
When you know it's your
time and it's your chance.
And you're finally on your way.
Watching the whole world
start to change.
In that moment when you say
I think I can.
There's a smile
that's on your face.
When you finally find that
place you're meant to be.
Where your heart's so free.
And you know that
you won't slow down.
When there's so many
sweet surprises to be found.
Makes you laugh out loud.
So pull up the brake
and let's keep riding.
Pick up the pace
and just keep climbing on.
And on.
Here we go, in that glow.
Feel that feeling taking over.
When you know it's your
time and it's your chance.
And you're finally on your way.
Watching the whole world
start to change.
In that moment when you say
I think I can
(BRAKES SQUEALING)
(WIND HOWLING)
(ALL GASP)
(ALL SHUDDERING)
Uh, it looks sturdy enough.
Don't you think?
Sure, if by "sturdy" you mean
"rickety, old and falling apart."
Well, we really don't
have much choice.
There's no other way across.
I'll be careful.
Yeah, very careful.
(CREAKING)
(SWALLOWS) I got a bad
feeling about this.
(CREAKING)
You're doing great.
Just keep it up.
That can't be good!
(GASPS)
(SCREAMS) whoa:
Richard! Hang on!
Hold tight, kiddo!
Dude, don't look down!
(RICHARD EXCLAIMS)
I said "don't"!
Don't look down!
(RICHARD EXCLAIMING IN FEAR)
LITTLE ENGINE: Hold on, Richard!
I'll pull you up.
(GRUNTING)
(METAL SCREECHING)
(LITTLE ENGINE GRUNTING)
(BOTH PANTING)
(EXHALES IN RELIEF)
(SIGHING IN RELIEF)
Whoa, that was close!
(PANTING IN EXHAUSTION)
Thanks.
Please don't do that again.
(PANTING) it's a deal.
So, now what?
I mean, we can't get across.
Well, um...
There's the answer!
What? That
broken-down pole?
It's a yardarm for cargo.
Somebody could tiptoe across the track,
yank out the yardarm from its base,
lay it across the broken track,
and we'll use it
as a makeshift rail!
(LAUGHING) Who's crazy
enough to do that?
(HUMMING CIRCUS MUSIC SOFTLY)
No clowning around
out there, Bev!
Kind of goes with the outfit.
(WHOOPING)
Be careful!
(MIMICS SQUEAKING)
(GASPS) Ooh, I can't look.
Uh, Sir?
The mission, Sir?
Om Right.
Look at me go!
Look at me go! Aha!
Ta-da!
(ALL EXHALE IN RELIEF)
(GASPS)
(CREAKING)
Hey, we're in luck!
It's loose!
(GRUNTING)
I'll just... Whoo!
Whoa!
Help!
LITTLE ENGINE: Oh, no, Bev!
Someone's got to help her!
Well, maybe I should go. Whoa!
Yes! Yes! Good idea!
Really?
Help!
LITTLE ENGINE:
Yeah! You can do it!
BEV; om
(GULPS)
BEV: I'm a little
in trouble!
Don't be nervous.
One step at a time.
LITTLE ENGINE: Rusty says, "if
you think you can, you will."
That's it!
There you go.
You're doing it!
(EXCLAIMING)
(ALL GASP)
(CONTINUES SCREAMING)
Come on, Richard.
You're almost there.
(GULPS)
LITTLE ENGINE:
You made it!
Whoa! Whoo-hoo-hoo!
Gotcha!
(GASPING IN RELIEF)
(ALL CHEERING)
Way to go, Richard!
I knew you could do it!
My hero.
(BEV HUMMING)
Mission accomplished!
Do you think it will hold?
We're about to find out.
(CREAKING)
Please, please, please,
please, please, please...
(GASPS)
(SHUDDERING)
(ALL CHEERING)
Way to haul, Little Engine!
(EXHALES IN RELIEF) One catastrophe down.
Hopefully no more to go.
Yeah, well...
(SIGHS) Let's go.
Oh, dude. This place is making
my neck hairs stand up.
A soldier fears nothing, Sir.
But if he did,
this might be it, Sir.
(GRUNTING)
You doing all right?
(BREATHLESSLY) l just...
I'm kind of...
That can't be good.
(STRAINING) Lost power.
Hit the emergency brake.
(STAMMERING UNCERTAINLY)
How about the lever?
It looks brake-y.
(ALL CLAMORING)
Not the brake-y one.
(SCREAMS)
Try the knob.
The knob!
The other knob!
This is all wrong.
I like the view better from behind!
Au right!
(GASPING) The big red one!
Oh! The red one!
Why didn't you just say so?
(CABOOSE EXCLAIMING IN TERROR)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(BRAKES SQUEAKING) Brakes, brakes,
brakes, brakes! More brakes!
(EXCLAIMS)
(CABOOSE WHIMPERING)
(SIGHS)
(EXHALES)
(WHOOPS IN RELIEF)
(ALL SIGHING)
LOU: (GROANING) Who
turned out the lights?
(EXHALES IN RELIEF)
Times like this make me
want a lifetime warranty.
Tell me about it.
Bad news.
There's a hole
in your water tank.
(GASPS)
Oh, no!
No wonder I overheated.
With a leak,
I'm not going anywhere.
Lost?
(ALL GASP)
Where'd you come from?
Just what I was
going to ask you.
(GASPS) isn't that a real boy?
Yes. And I have to get him
over the mountain.
But I'm stuck.
Why didn't you just
use the tunnel?
It kind of collapsed.
'Cause of me.
I see.
Of course it did.
What a shame.
But over the mountain?
It's difficult for me!
No wonder you didn't make it.
I... I thought I could.
And look where it got you.
Broken down.
Stranded.
Helpless.
But, not to worry.
Allow me to take them.
I'm about to take a run
over the mountain anyway.
(GASPS) To the Real World?
I do it all the time.
It's no trouble.
Besides, I don't see
any other options. Do you?
I... I guess not.
Listen, everybody!
We're in luck!
You've got a new ride
over the mountain!
We can't just leave you.
Don't worry about me.
You need to get home, and...
And you need
to get to your kids.
(BANGING)
All aboard!
But, how will you get back?
Once they realize I'm gone,
I'm sure they'll send
someone for me.
Go!
Well, but...
it's okay. Go!
(CREAKING)
(DOOR SLAMS)
(ALL GASP)
(LAUGHING EVILLY)
Who are you?
(LAUGHING CONTINUES DISTANTLY)
(RATTLING)
I want my friends back!
But that's not going
to happen, is it?
(GASPS)
I'm keeping them here with me.
As long as the real boy is in
Dream Land there's no tunnel,
and I'm the only train
who can deliver dreams.
My kind of dreams.
Scary, creepy dreams.
You're the Nightmare Train?
Aren't you the little genius.
Please let my friends go!
(ENUNCIATING) Not gonna happen!
(GASPS)
Now these are wishes that
will never be delivered!
(LAUGHING EVILLY)
(TRAIN HORN BLOWING)
(GASPS)
Sweet dreams!
(LAUGHING EVILLY)
(GRUNTING)
Trapped? (GASPING)
Somebody do something!
The important thing
is not to panic.
Good. That's
a good plan.
And to think of a way out.
Right. Hmm...
ALL: Hmm.
(GASPS)
Sir? We are
not alone, Sir.
Hey, Richie-Boy.
(ALL GAsPING)
(STAMMERING) How come you're...
What are you doing here?
I'm here to introduce
your face to my fist!
I beg your pardon!
Is there a problem here?
You bet there's a problem,
chimp!
(INDIGNANTLY) Chimp?
Oh, that's funny.
See, technically I am a monkey.
Sock monkey, to be precise.
Actually...
Put a sock in it.
(WHIMPERS) Yes, sir.
Uh, not a problem.
Uh, luckily I'm nicely
equipped for such a request.
(MUFFLED) see?
Um... Uh...
Pie in the face.
Nothing in the world
that can't be solved
with a good pie in the face.
Bev, this is serious!
I'm in trouble here.
We're your worst nightmare.
(GULPS)
(ZOOMING)
Ace! Dude!
(GROWLS)
Oh! This is not good.
We're on the Nightmare Train,
stuck in the middle
of a nightmare.
It's a nightmare within a nightmare,
which in itself is a nightmare!
(PENSIVELY) Nightmares.
You're not real!
You're nothing!
You're bogus!
Pretend! Fake!
You don't exist!
In fact...
Bev?
Ta-da!
Huh?
(SHRIEKS)
(LAUGHING)
(ALL CHEERING)
A commanding show
of bravery, Sir.
You're right. Pies do
make everything better.
Subtitle by HyugA http://subscene.
Com/user/Profile.aspx? UserlD=506319
I was such a fool to trust him.
Well, I don't know
about being a fool.
Naive, maybe.
Gullible, certainly.
Did I mention naive?
(SIGHS) I'm just
a scrawny little hunter.
What made me think
I could go over the mountain?
I've ruined everything.
Hey! Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Whatever happened to Little Miss
"l think I can, I think I can,"
et cetera?
I guess she knows now.
She can't.
(ZOOMING) (GASPS) Ace?
(ZOOMING)
How'd you get away?
Where's everybody else?
(GRUNTS)
(SIGHS) I can't make it.
You heard her. It's over.
We're done. Finished. Kaput.
I'm sorry. I can't.
If you think you can,
you will.
If you think you can't,
you won't.
Rusty?
Either way, you're right.
Maybe I can still do something!
Oh, but I'm out of water.
Uh, would a water tower help?
What? Where?
CABOOSE: Water tower.
Right here.
Too bad it's out of reach.
You have an idea, Ace?
(HORN TOOTING)
There you go. That's my girl.
Back it up!
(CABOOSE IMITATING
TRAIN WHISTLE)
(BLOWING WHISTLE)
(GRUNTING)
Okay. We got tracks.
We got tracks!
We ain't got tracks.
How do you feel about flying?
Uh, why do you ask?
Whoo-hoo!
(SCREAMING)
Way more fun the second time.
Second time?
Lead the way, Ace.
(BANGING)
(GRUNTING)
Whoa! Dude!
(EXCLAIMING GROGGILY)
Whoa!
Look at that, Bud!
It worked!
The little guy was right!
We just needed
to use our heads.
(LAUGHING)
(CONTINUES LAUGHING
UNCERTAINLY)
(STIFLING LAUGHTER)
This is it. He's slowing down.
I think I can unhook us.
(GRUNTS NERVOUSLY)
(GRUNTS)
(SHRIEKS)
(GRuNTING) Almost got if...
Oh!
Hey!
(SIGHS)
Uh, you know we only have two
chances of finding them.
Slim and none.
(GASPS) Richard!
Little Engine!
Thank goodness!
Oh, look at me.
Instantly wrong.
You got away!
Where are the toys?
They're still on
the Nightmare Train.
We can catch up
to them if we hurry.
(GASPS)
There he is!
He's too far away.
(GASPS)
A shortcut! I can
catch up to him!
Um, are you looking
at the same track I am?
Switch the track!
Hurry!
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
Hold tight!
Uh, we're not gonna
fly again, are we?
(WHIMPERING)
RICHARD:
Little Engine?
Have you thought about what we're gonna
do when we catch the Nightmare Train?
(PANTING) Nope.
No idea.
(CLANKS) Whoa!
Hang in there, Little E.
(PANTING) Almost there!
(TEETH CHATTERING)
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
Uh, guys?
Hello! Anyone!
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
Where is he?
Can you see him?
RICHARD: No!
He must be up ahead!
Ace, fly ahead and see if you
can spot the Nightmare Train.
Hang on!
Ace?
(GASPS)
Looking for me?
Did you really
think... (GASPS)
Is that the real boy?
But...
How did you...
I want the boy back!
Well, you can't have him.
Oh, grow up!
Wait, you can't.
Because you'll
always be little!
(GASPS)
You're just a dinky
little engine who's failed!
I may belittle,
but I haven't failed.
And I have news for you.
I'm taking my friends
over this mountain,
and I'm not letting some creepy
old train stand in my way!
Done?
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
I say! That's
Little Engine!
She's coming for us!
We gotta bust out of here!
Let me lay it out for you.
I'm not letting the boy
anywhere near the Real World!
Catch my drift?
(LITTLE ENGINE SCREAMS)
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
(ALL GROANING)
(GROANS) Huh?
Perhaps I could climb
through this hole.
(GASPS) I think I can
reach the latch!
You haven't the sense
to give up when you should!
So here's a lesson
for the future!
(LAUGHS EVILLY)
Oh, that's right.
You won't have one!
(GASPS)
Richard! See the switcher?
Get ready.
Got you.
(LAUGHS) Where do you
think you're going?
Away from you, creepy!
What? (GROWLING)
We're going the wrong way!
Richard!
Switch it now!
(HORN HONKING)
it's stuck!
NIGHTMARE TRAIN: No!
(ALL CHEERING)
Let's never do that again!
Great job, Little E.
Not so bad yourself, Richard.
We're losing water fast.
(GASPS) oh, no!
We've gotta fix this leak.
Oh, we must have something
that will fill that hole!
Oh, maybe we could
fold you up and...
That is not an option!
This should work, Sir.
Are you sure?
We must complete the mission.
Thank you, Major.
(CLATTERING)
I think you look
better without it.
Oh, thank you, Ma'am.
Oh, please.
Call me Jillian.
Yes, of course, Jillian, ma'am.
RICHARD: There.
That feels better already!
All right, everyone.
All aboard!
Oh, yeah!
Yeah!
The patch is holding.
You're gonna be okay.
Come on, Little Engine.
Just remember what Rusty said.
If you think you can, you will.
I think I can.
(STEAM HISSING)
what?
(ALL GASP)
Little Engine, you're
starting to heat up.
I'm okay. I'm okay.
(PANTING)
(TIREDLY) I think I can.
I think I can.
(HAIL CLATTERING)
Ow! Ow, ow, ow!
Hailstorm!
(PANTING) I think I can.
I think...
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
LITTLE ENGINE:
I think I can.
I... (PANTING EXHAUSTEDLY)
You're overheating.
I have to keep going.
But your boiler could blow.
Dream Haulers never give up.
(PANTING) I...
(PANTS)
(GRUNTING)
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
(SCREAMING)
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
(EXHALING IN RELIEF)
Come on, Little Engine.
I believe in you.
I know I can.
(GRUNTING) I know I can!
I know... (GRuNTING)
(EXHALES)
(SIGHS)
I knew I could!
(ALL CHEERING)
Way to go, Little E!
You're a real Dream Hauler.
I always said you could do it!
(GIGGLES) No, you didn't!
Oh, sure I did.
Just now.
Uh, Sir? What's that?
(ALL GASP) ooh!
LITTLE ENGINE: That must be
the way to the Real World!
Oh!
Wow!
Isn't it amazing, Hudson?
Uh, Hudson?
Uh, has anyone seen Hudson?
Hey, Hudson.
Dude! What's wrong?
We're gonna make it, buddy.
I'm still nervous.
After all, I am the annoying,
borderline irritating
sock monkey!
Oh, man.
Hudson.
You are neither annoying
nor irritating.
You are a unique sock monkey
dreamed up by a wonderful child,
who will love and cherish
you for years to come.
(LAUGHS)
Did you hear that, everyone?
I'm not annoying!
I am unique!
(LAUGHS) You certainly
are, Hudson.
All right, everybody!
Next stop, the Real World!
(ALL CHEERING)
(WHISTLES)
I knew I could.
I knew I could...
I knew I could!
(BRAKES SQUEALING)
Did you see how happy those kids
were when we delivered their toys?
Yeah. Pretty cool.
I'm gonna miss them.
Hey. What about me?
(CHUCKLING) You too.
It's like I never left.
It's exactly like
you never left.
Dream Time doesn't work
like Real Time.
You sure you don't want
me to take you home?
No. I've got something
to finish here.
Bye, Little Engine.
Dream of me sometime, Real Boy.
Count on it.
See you, kid.
(BANGING)
(LAUGHS) Hungry?
RICHARD: I knew you guys
would still be here.
I came for my watch.
You think you can take it
from me, Richie-Boy?
Yeah, I think I can.
Not only that, I can stop
letting you push me around,
and I can tell my dad
you're a thief!
Now, give me back my watch!
(EXCLAIMING)
Ow. Ow! Ow, ow!
(VENDING MACHINE RATTLING)
Help! Ow! Ow!
Stretch!
Help... Help!
Ow! Stretch!
Help me out!
Ow! Ow!
Make it stop! Make it stop!
What button is it?
Help me out! Stretch!
Hey, how do I... Ow!
(SOBBING) Stretch,
make it stop!
Oh!
Here you are!
You two are supposed
to be in detention!
Inside, right now.
You're looking at trouble.
Big trouble.
MARCUS: Richard!
Marcus?
What are you doing here?
I forgot my math book.
Hey, you got your
watch back! How?
It's kind of like you said.
I thought I could, and I did.
That's it?
Anything else will make me
seem like a crazy person.
We still friends?
Come on! Of course!
Great. Last one home's
a rotten egg!
(RUMBLING)
(ALL EXCLAIMING IN ALARM)
What's happening?
LITTLE ENGINE: Whoo-hoo!
Is that...
The squirt?
FREIGHT TRAIN: Little
Engine, come back here!
I'll see you at the station!
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
(BRAKES SQUEALING)
(TOOTS)
Little Engine?
Where did you come from?
I just got back
from the Real World!
What?
(ALL GASP)
The tracks do exist!
They sure do, Rusty.
I just took the boy
back to the Real World
on the old tracks
Rusty told me about!
Huh?
It was no picnic,
let me tell you.
Wait a minute!
You're saying
you went over Dream Mountain?
Nobody can do that.
Not even me!
RUSTY: (CHUCKLING) Apparently, our
newest Dream Hauler just did.
(TRAINS EXCLAIMING IN AWE)
Not bad for a little squirt.
Mighty impressive,
peanut roaster.
Oh, you should've seen her!
Wow!
Incredible!
That's amazing!
Rusty gets his job back, right?
(STAMMERING) You promised!
Well... Um...
(CLEARS THROAT)
Yeah! It seems I owe Rusty
a ticker tape parade, too.
Looks like you were right
all along, Rusty.
TOWER: And an apology
for not believing him.
But I'm still puzzled.
You're just a little engine.
And that's one tough mountain.
How did you pull this off?
(GIGGLES) it's simple, really.
I thought I could.
Well, well, well.
I guess that makes you.
The Little Engine that Could!
(WHISTLES)
(ALL CHEERING)
CABOOSE: Way to go,
Little Engine!
(ALL WHOOPING)
CABOOSE: Way to go!
TOWER: Good job, guys!
Good job!