Subtitles by explosiveskull
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(MAN 1 CHUCKLING)
Hey!
And if we just,
like, download it,
it would be a lot easier
than if you stream it.
You know?
That's what I've learned.
(LOUD CRASH)
(GASPS)
(PEOPLE EXCLAIMING)
MAN 2: What's going on?
(GROWLS)
(ROARS)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Wakey-wakey!
It is I,
the inflated destroyer,
Balloon Man!
(ALL GASP)
(STRAINING)
(GRUNTS)
(LAUGHING)
Time to inflate
my bank account.
(GRUNTING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Hello.
(LAUGHING)
(UPBEAT ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
- (GUNS FIRING)
- Aah!
(INHALES)
(ALL YELLING)
(SIREN WAILS)
Titans, go!
(ROBIN GRUNTING)
(BALLOON MAN GRUNTS)
(DEVICE TRILLS, BEEPS)
Oh, yeah! Scabadoosh!
(GASPS)
Booyah!
(GROWLS)
BALLOON MAN: Ha-ha!
Who wants a balloon animal?
(GASPS)
Kitties!
(STARFIRE GRUNTING)
- (SOFT MEWING)
- (SIGHS)
(GASPING)
(BALLOON MAN GRUNTS)
(RAVEN GRUNTS)
(BALLOON MAN GROWLS)
(BALLOON MAN STRAINING)
(GRUNTING)
Stop hitting yourself.
(LAUGHS, SIGHS)
I'mma pop you, fool!
(GROWLS)
(GRUNTS)
(FARTING)
(FARTING CONTINUES)
BALLOON MAN: Oh!
(LAUGHING)
He farted!
BALLOON MAN:
That wasn't a fart.
That was just air
leaving my butt.
Which is a fart.
(TITANS LAUGHING)
BALLOON MAN: Shut up! You guys are
awfully immature for the Justice League.
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Do we look
like the Justice League to you?
I don't know.
I thought you were maybe
some of
the lesser-known members.
BEAST BOY: This fool thinks
we're in the Justice League?
CYBORG: Man, we ain't
no Justice League.
BALLOON MAN:
I recognize you now.
You are
the Guardians of the Galaxy!
(STARFIRE GASPS)
Uh, that's a different
superhero universe.
I am the insulted.
All right, all right.
Then who are you?
Yo, Cy. This guy
don't know who we is.
Oh, really? Then I think
it's time we tell him.
♪ Go, Teen Titans, go
Go, Teen Titans, go
Go, go, go, go, go
♪ T-double-E-N-T-I-T-A-N-S
♪ We the real heroes
Takin' down the big menace
- ♪ Teen Titan flows
- ♪ Teen Titan knows
♪ Where there's
real trouble, baby
♪ Teen Titans go
♪ Go, Teen Titans, go
Go, Teen Titans, go
BALLOON MAN: Ugh. Morons.
♪ Beast Boy I can turn
straight up into an animal
- ♪ Animal?
♪ Yes, any animal
♪ Boom, pow
Yeah, I'm a kitten now
TITANS: Aw!
♪ Check out my kitten meow
♪ The star, the fire
The live, the wire
♪ The alien princess
in my alien attire
♪ The energy blasts
The supersonic speed
♪ Is she down with the Titans?
♪ Oh, the yes indeed
♪ Booyah, booyah
Go my cannon blaster
♪ Cyborg, whoo, baby
Mr. High Tech Master
♪ What, what, what?
♪ Mr. Meatball Disaster
♪ Mr. Boom Boom Blaster
♪ Teen Teen Titans
The Titans, the Teen Titans
♪ Boom with the smoke bombs
and birdarangs
♪ Bow staff hittin' steady
Doin' my thang
♪ Robin, Robin, the leader
Robin, Robin, in charge
♪ Show 'em your baby hands!
♪ No Robin, Robin's are large
Nah, but for real, man. Those
some super-small baby hands.
No, they're not. Whatever. Just
keep going, just keep going!
♪ Go, Teen Titans, go
Go, Teen Titans, go
♪ Raven is here to drop it
On you even harder
♪ There's no darker than me
I'm as dark as can be
♪ Check it
Azarath Metrion Zinthos
♪ Teleportin', magical powers
We adios
♪ Teen Teen Titans
The Titans, the Teen Titans
♪ Teen Teen Titans, the Titans
The Teen Titans
♪ Teen Titans Go! ♪
(SQUEAKS)
- Oh, yeah! We are so tough!
- (TITANS CHEERING)
Sorry, Justice League.
You're too late.
Our song was so sick,
it took down Balloon Man.
Sure it did.
Since you came all this way,
you guys wanna hang?
Yeah, well, we'd love to,
but we gotta get
to Batman's movie premiere.
(SIGHS) It's always been
my dream to have my own movie.
Well, it is important
to have dreams, I guess.
What do you mean by that?
Well, you know, they only make
movies about real heroes.
I am a real hero. I even
have my own superhero team.
You guys are goofsters.
You know, with the farts.
Always cracking your jokes.
You mean, people
think we're jokes?
Why do you think there's never
been a movie made about you?
Well, has there been
a movie about you?
So many. And more to come.
It took a while, but yeah,
I have my own now.
There was a Green Lantern movie.
But we don't talk about that.
Problem is, you guys are never
actually doing anything heroic.
Man, please. That ain't true.
What about that time we
discovered that sweet diner?
And they had that food?
- STARFIRE: Oh, yes. It was most delicious.
- (OVERLAPPING CHATTER)
That wasn't even a crime
and you didn't save anything.
This guy thinks
we didn't save anything.
We saved room for dessert!
- (EDM PLAYING)
- Right in your face!
Titans, if you keep
playing the fool,
you'll never be seen
as real heroes.
Only as jokes.
(TOY CHICKEN SQUEAKS)
- CYBORG: Got him! (LAUGHS)
- Somebody save me.
Anyway, we gotta
get going. Ta-ta!
Is it true?
Are we not the real heroes?
Of course we are.
We just took down Balloon Man.
I believe we have
a premiere to attend.
Teen Titans, go...
To the movies!
(FANS CHEERING
AND SCREAMING)
- MAN 1: Batman! Batman!
- (CAMERAS CLICKING)
MAN 2: Superman, over here!
Supergirl, who are you
wearing tonight?
Plastic Man.
Hey, John, how are you?
WOMAN: Over here!
MAN 4: Show us the bracelets!
(FANS GASPING)
Oops. My bad.
The Atom has arrived.
Thank you!
Behold...
(ATOM GRUNTING)
Behold, Titans!
This is every
superhero's dream,
to have your own movie!
This burrito is my dream.
Titans, are you ready
to walk the red carpet?
CYBORG: Oh, yeah!
BEAST BOY: Oh, yes! I'm ready.
Let's go in!
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
Hold it.
This premiere is for superheroes only.
Who are you?
Who are we? (CHUCKLES)
- Who are we?
- (BEAST BOY CHUCKLES)
This fool don't know
who's we is.
Perhaps this will remind you?
♪ Teen Teen Titans
The Titans, the Teen Titans ♪
Stop! You're not on the list.
But we're superheroes.
Hello.
We're the Challengers
of the Unknown.
We're here
for the motion picture.
Challengers, Challengers.
Ooh! Right this way.
The Challengers of the Unknown
are on the list?
That is the obscure.
No one knows them!
They's unknown!
It's in the name. "Unknown."
It's in the name!
Man! How's we
supposed to get in now?
I do have the ability to open
portals to any feasible location.
- STARFIRE: Oh, yes!
- That's right. I always forget about that.
Portal it is!
(BLOWS)
(SCREECHING)
Oh, man. There's no seats.
What about those?
I can hardly wait for the
motion picture to begin.
But that's where the Challengers
of the Unknown are sitting.
Dude, no one's
gonna miss them.
Yeah! They's unknown!
Exactly.
Challengers, we seem to be drifting
in a void of complete darkness.
Nothing waits for us here
but madness. Madness!
ANNOUNCER: Super-ladies and
gentlemen, put your hands together
for the biggest superhero
movie director in the world,
Jade Wilson!
- (AUDIENCE CHEERING)
- Whoo!
All right!
Who's ready to watch
a Batman movie?
(ALL CHEERING)
Give it up
for the Bat himself.
No, you deserve it.
Yes, you do. Yes, you do.
FANS: Batman!
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
You know who else deserves it?
All of you!
(CHEERING)
It doesn't matter
how obscure you are.
You're all getting a movie!
You want a little sneak peek?
ANNOUNCER: Coming this summer.
From the shadows of Batman...
It's happening?
...emerges a hero.
They're finally going to make
a movie about me!
Alfred The Movie.
The ultimate grime fighter.
When the dust settles,
only one man
will be left dusting.
Coming broom.
(LAUGHTER)
Don't worry, brah.
If Alfred got a movie,
you must be next.
(SCOFFS) Right. My movie must
be slated for next summer.
ANNOUNCER: Coming next summer.
A new hero
will light up the night.
Please be me! Please be me!
It's the car.
Oh! They did the car
before you, bro.
(EXCLAIMS) This is ridiculous!
ANNOUNCER:
Batmobile The Movie.
Coming vroom.
- That actually does look pretty good.
- I'd go see it.
I do love
the Batman's automobile.
They must be saving the best
for last then.
I'm sure my movie
is next, next summer.
ANNOUNCER:
Coming next, next summer.
The story of Batman's
greatest ally.
That's me! That must be me!
And best friend
in the whole wide world.
(SHUDDERING)
Finally!
Thank you for making
a movie about...
ANNOUNCER: Utility Belt...
What?
ANNOUNCER: ...The Movie.
You put things in it.
(LAUGHING) He thought the
movie was about him!
(ALL LAUGHING)
MAN 1: He's just a sidekick.
MAN 2: He's a nobody.
Sidekick! Sidekick!
(WHIMPERS)
(SOBBING UNCONTROLLABLY)
(PANTING)
(SNIFFLES)
Aw, man. Forget those fools.
Who cares what
other people think?
We have the each other
and that is all that matters.
Star's right, bro.
What do those big-shot
superheroes know anyway?
They know having a movie is the
only way to be seen as a real hero.
You are the real hero to us.
Yeah. You put
this team together.
Without you,
we'd be all alone.
That's right.
Without you, bro, I'd be living
in a dumpster eating garbage.
(RETCHES)
RAVEN: And I'd have
to enslave entire dimensions
with my evil dad.
STARFIRE: And I would be forced
to return to my life of fighting
in the pit of
the intergalactic gladiator.
CYBORG: And I'd be playing
professional football.
It sounds good, but you're
forgetting the concussions.
The bad knees, going broke,
and having to be on one of those
awful dance reality TV shows!
But why don't they
take us seriously?
We've got the cool costumes,
gadgets, and the powers,
and the sweet kung-fu moves.
Ooh-hah!
What are we missing?
Well, what about
an archnemesis?
An archnemesis?
Oh, yeah. An archnemesis is like a
status symbol in the hero world.
Yeah, bro.
Every superhero's got one.
Super bad dudes
with super scary names.
That are fun to say
in a dramatic way.
Superman's got
(DRAMATICALLY) Lex Luthor!
TITANS: Ooh! Lex Luthor.
Green Lantern's got Sinestro.
TITANS: Ooh! Sinestro.
And the Flash has
the Rainbow Raider!
He rides upon the rainbows!
That is pretty scary.
If you can get a crazed lunatic to
devote himself to taking you down,
it means you
really are a top hero.
You know, the kind they make
movies about.
How do we get an archnemesis?
(ALARM BLARING)
(GASPS)
It's a crime alert.
A crime alert?
A mysterious figure
breaking into S.T.A.R. Labs.
This could be it.
The key to a movie about me!
Titans, let's go get ourselves
an archnemesis.
(ALARMS BLARING)
- (MEN GRUNTING)
- (BLOWS LANDING)
(GUNFIRE)
(GRUNTS)
(TIMER BEEPING)
(EXPLOSION)
The Justice League
will stop you.
Sorry, my pathetic friend, but the
Justice League won't be coming.
Because they're
watching a movie.
And as considerate moviegoers, I'm sure they
would've turned off their mobile devices.
Unlike some people.
The Ditronium Crystal.
The perfect plot device.
(GRUNTS)
Stop right there,
Deadpool?
Deadpool? What?
I'm not Deadpool.
I thought Deadpool
was a good guy.
Why does everybody
think I'm Deadpool?
You got them guns!
And the swords.
Yeah, well, lots of people
have guns and swords, okay?
On the way here, I passed, like,
25 people with guns and swords.
By the way, he should be
saying that he's not me, okay?
'Cause I came out, like,
way before he did.
Nah. I'm pretty sure
you're Deadpool.
Look into the camera and say
something inappropriate.
Oh, I'm not Deadpool.
I am the greatest,
most feared,
most nefarious,
most ultimate supervillain
the world has ever seen!
I am Slade!
Slade.
Wow. His name is really fun
to say dramatically.
Slade.
BOTH: Slade!
- Slade!
Slade!
Silence!
What is the point of all this?
We're in need of an archnemesis and
we think you'd be a great fit.
(CHUCKLES)
You gotta be kidding me.
You guys are a joke.
Everyone knows that.
Besides, how could you be my
archnemesis when you've already lost?
(TITANS GASP)
Because no one can withstand
my powers of...
Mind manipulation!
Look at this.
An ordinary pencil made of
rigid wood and graphite.
Held together
by a polymer adhesive.
Topped off with
a delightful eraser.
And what's your point?
Can a solid pencil do this?
- What? It's so rubbery!
- Yo, that be witchcraft!
SLADE: That's just
the start of it.
You may think you have a grasp
on reality,
but how can you even begin
to explain this?
ALL: His thumb?
SLADE: Yes.
An ordinary, opposable thumb connected
by flesh, tendons, and muscles.
But what you're
about to witness
may very well pull the rug
of empirical science
from underneath your feet!
(TITANS SCREAMING)
(SLADE LAUGHS)
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
Wait. Just stop it. These are just
tricks and optical illusions.
(STUTTERING)
What's that over there?
- Don't listen to him.
- What is that?
He's just trying to trick you again.
It's absolutely nothing.
SLADE: Oh, my gosh.
No, seriously. I've never...
What is that?
Is that even a...
Don't look!
There's nothing over there.
Even if one of you looks, and the
other ones close your eyes...
There's probably nothing over here.
He's lying!
Look it, guys,
I'm serious. Look!
(STRAINED) Don't do it.
(TITANS STRAINING)
I can't resist.
Must look behind me.
There's nothing there.
SLADE: Made you look.
CYBORG: What?
See you later, losers.
Give me a call when you guys learn
how to be real superheroes.
He's right.
We're not real superheroes.
(ANCHOR CLANGS)
(DOOR BEEPS)
GUARD: This premiere is
for superheroes only.
SUPERMAN:
You guys are goofsters.
CYBORG: Oh! They did the car
before you, bro.
♪ Heroes
Superheroes
♪ Come check this out
♪ Go, go check it out
♪ Oh, you gotta check this out
- ♪ Superheroes across the land
- ♪ Come see this
♪ Check this out
♪ Check it out
Check, check it out ♪
(INDISTINCT ANIMALS' CRIES)
What? We all gathered
out here for this?
CROWD: Boo! Loser! Loser!
He's just a sidekick!
(WHIMPERING)
- (CROWD JEERING)
- THE FLASH: You're the worst!
(ROBIN SCREAMING)
(GASPING)
What a nightmare.
Yo, Robin. Come peep
this out, my man.
(SIGHS)
Not now, Beast Boy.
I'm not in the mood.
Trust me, dude. You's not
gonna wanna be late for this.
(SIGHS) Beast Boy,
what are you talking about?
Why am I sitting
in this cardboard box?
It's a limo, dude.
Here we are. Let me help
you with the door, sir.
What are you guys doing?
Have a seat, my dude.
Don't forget
your overpriced candy.
And the corn of popping.
Now sit back, relax,
and enjoy Robin The Movie.
What?
BEAST BOY: Yo. This is a story
about a dude.
And this is not
an ordinary dude.
No, sir.
This dude's got
a name and it's Robin.
(TITANS CHEERING)
Robin was just a little baby
boy that lived at the circus.
Doing acrobatics and things.
- Come on. This is embarrassing.
- Shh!
BEAST BOY: But then he grew up
and he wasn't a baby no more.
But he still had them
baby hands, yo.
(LAUGHTER)
Coming up is the part
that is the best.
Oh. Great movie, guys.
Very funny.
We worked hard on that, yo.
We were just trying
to cheer you up.
By making fun of me?
Perhaps if you
continue to watch...
No! I want a real movie!
Then let's just go get one.
Oh, like it's that easy.
No one's gonna make
a movie about me.
(SIGHS) I'm just a joke.
You know what you need?
You need an upbeat,
inspirational song about life.
♪ Are you feeling down?
♪ Like you just
can't do it today
♪ I can see your frown
♪ But it's all gonna be okay
♪ So believe in yourself
♪ There's no giving up
♪ The power's inside
♪ Yeah, that's what's up
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
♪ It's the kick in the pants
♪ You needed
♪ This song will
open up your eyes
♪ It's the feeling you
can't be Defeated
♪ It's an '80s song
with synthy vibes
♪ And you know it's super
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ It's time to get
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ The groove is sounding
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ By now you're feeling
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ It's an upbeat inspirational
song About life
♪ I can do it all
♪ This type of song will
make you feel that way
♪ No, there's no stopping me
♪ I feel the fire inside
♪ This type of song
will get you energized
♪ I love
this motivating melody
♪ And you know it's super
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ Your life is lookin'
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ Don't tell me this ain't
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ Yeah, now I'm feelin'
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ It's an upbeat
inspirational song about life
I feel like I can do anything.
Even get my own movie!
Hollywood, here we come! Ha-ha!
Road trip!
(UPBEAT MUSIC
CONTINUES PLAYING)
♪ And you know it's super
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ It's time to get
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ Let's make this party
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ Everybody's gettin'
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ I know you're feelin'
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ Don't tell me this ain't
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ Your life is lookin'
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ This song has got us
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ It's an upbeat inspi... ♪
(GASPS)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(SHUDDERS)
I think his dad is a cop!
TITANS: Run!
Here it is.
The studio!
Once we pass
through these gates,
our lives will change forever.
Now, Titans, are you ready
to be movie stars?
♪
Who are you?
(GROANS) This guy? Really?
(CHUCKLES)
You don't remember us?
Perhaps this will remind...
Stop. You're not on the list.
Great. Now how are we
supposed to get in?
Uh, portal.
- Right.
- Yeah, portal, of course.
Wow! Look at this.
Standing on the back lot. This
is where the magic happens.
- Oh, man, I love this.
- Ooh!
That is where
the Animaniacs live.
CYBORG: Ooh! It's that
car from that car movie.
(BATS SQUEAKING)
This place is amazing, yo.
They're really making movies
about every superhero.
And it's time they
make one about me.
Come on. Jade Wilson's soundstage
must be around here somewhere.
Hey, everybody, look at me.
- I'm Stan Lee doing my subtle cameo.
- (DISCO MUSIC PLAYING)
Excuse me, Mr. Stan.
(WHISPERS INDISTINCTLY)
This is a DC movie? Oh, gee.
I gotta get outta here.
Oh, rad! Check it out!
(TITANS GASP)
- (BUZZER SOUNDS)
- All right. Quiet on the set.
Lights! Cameras!
No moving around.
Closed set, please.
Take one,
Batman v Superman Part Two.
And just have fun with it.
Follow your instincts.
Magic.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(BOTH STRAINING)
What's your mother's name?
Martha.
My mommy's name
is Martha, too.
Wait. What's
your father's name?
Jonathan?
- Mine's Thomas!
- (BOTH GRUNTING)
Cut! Clark, Bruce,
that was amazing!
Ooh, am I not supposed to use
your real names? (LAUGHS)
Relax. It's not a big deal.
Everybody knows.
- Let's run it again in five.
- (BUZZER SOUNDS)
The performances
were the amazing!
Well, what are you
waiting for, bro?
Go, Robin.
The destiny awaits.
You... You really think she's
going to give me a movie?
Give?
When Batman wants vengeance, do
bad guys just give it to him?
No.
That's right.
Batman takes that vengeance.
All cracking skulls and putting
fools up in the hospital.
Leaving them
with the permanent injuries.
It's the same with movies.
She won't just give you a
movie, you have to take it.
Now what do you want?
A movie.
- Say it loud.
- I want a movie!
- Again!
Then take it!
I'm gonna take it!
Hey! Jade Wilson.
(GASPS)
(CLEARS THROAT) Would you
please make a movie about me?
(IN HUSHED VOICE)
Was that too aggressive?
No. It was good.
A Robin movie. Hmm.
What would that even be?
♪ It would be so awesome
♪ It would be so cool
♪ It would be the most incredible
superhero movie the world has ever seen
♪ The screens would light up
♪ With real explosions
and special effects
♪ Like tons and tons
of special effects
♪ My super sweet cape would be
special effects
♪ And it would blow your mind
♪ 'Cause it's my movie
My movie
♪ My superhero movie
It's all about me
♪ Yeah, it's all about me
♪ It's my movie
My movie
♪ My superhero movie
♪ They'll be lining up to see
a movie all about me
♪ No longer a sidekick
No, that's not me
♪ Picture my booty up in 3D
♪ I'll shake my booty
♪ In my own movie
♪ It's my movie, my movie
My superhero movie
♪ They'll be lining up to see
a movie all about me
♪ I'd have the most impressive
♪ Cool and scary
♪ Big, mean, hairy adversary
♪ But not to worry
♪ I'm the man in charge
♪ Yeah, I'd have an alter ego
♪ I'd be a billionaire
♪ Standing tall
with adult-sized hands
♪ And gorgeous hair
♪ Gorgeous hair
♪ 'Cause it's my movie, my
movie My superhero movie
♪ It's all about me
Yeah, it's all about me
♪ It's my movie, my movie
My superhero movie
♪ They'll be lining up to see
A movie all about me
♪ No longer the sidekick
♪ Sidekicks are lame
♪ Now I'm the superhero
Putting villains to shame
♪ R-O-B-I-N is the name
♪ Ooh, and I'd have
my own hero music, too
♪ It'd go Bum bum bum
bum bum bum bum boom
♪ It would play every time
that I entered a room
♪ Then I'd say my sweet
and ominous Catchphrase
Crack an egg on it.
Ca-caw!
♪ It's my movie, my movie
My superhero movie
♪ It's all about me
Yeah, it's all about me
♪ It's my movie, my movie
My superhero movie
♪ My movie
♪ They'll be lining up to see
A movie all about me
♪ Yeah, it's all about me ♪
Robin. Wow.
(CHUCKLES) Wow.
You just reminded me
why I decided not to make a
Robin movie in the first place.
I'm afraid it's gonna be a no.
I'm so sorry.
Why can't I have a movie?
Oh, it's not you.
Well, it is you.
No one wants to watch a movie about
a sidekick without an archenemy.
I mean, the only way I'd even consider it
is if there were no other superheroes.
At all.
But thanks so much
for coming in.
And I promise not to keep you
in mind for future projects.
(SIGHS)
Oh, I am the sorry,
friend Robin.
Don't be.
Wow, you're taking this
surprisingly well.
Of course I am.
Didn't you hear what she said?
That she would make a movie about us if
we were the only superheroes around.
So, all we have to do is...
Kill all the other
superheroes!
Close, but no.
I want us to save them
from becoming superheroes
in the first place.
Every superhero is born from a
tragic life-changing event.
I propose
we travel through time
and stop those tragic events
from taking place.
Robin,
this is the excellent plan!
Ha-ha! Let's do
some time-traveling, yo!
To the Time Cycles!
Time Cycles?
What's wrong with
our usual time machine?
(FLIES BUZZING)
It's boring.
We need something
more cinematic!
Raven, summon the Time Cycles.
Azarath Metrion Zinthos!
- Ooh!
- All right!
Man, these bikes
ain't gots no power.
Where are we gonna find Libyan terrorists
to sell us plutonium at this hour?
We don't need plutonium.
These Time Cycles
are powered by radness.
Are you ready?
Then let's go back
to the future!
I mean, the past!
(TAKE ON ME PLAYING)
This isn't rad enough.
Titans, bust some sick moves!
ANNOUNCER: Sick!
Gnarly!
We're still not
rad enough, bro!
Titans, deploy time streamers!
♪ Take on me
ANNOUNCER: Rad!
Engage!
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
Yeah!
- Whoo-hoo-hoo!
- (GAGGING)
♪ In a day or two ♪
(RUMBLING)
(PLAYING NOTES
AND HUMMING ALONG)
(GROANS)
That's not good at all.
(SHATTERING)
Oh.
Honey, I'm sorry.
We're pretty much all dead.
(GURGLING)
(CRASHING)
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Hold it right there.
Yeah. Shooting a baby
into space.
What kind of people are you?
You are the horrible parents!
But we have no choice. The
crystals are not harmonized.
The planet is collapsing. I've
tried all tonal combinations.
Fool, if you wanna save the planet,
you gots to play the right music.
Yeah. Let us show you
how it's done.
(PLAYING EDM)
(BOTH GASP)
(SQUEALS AND GIGGLES)
(COOING)
(CRYSTALS HUMMING
HARMONIOUSLY)
Yes! That's how we do it.
ALL: Yeah!
Now let's go stop some more
superhero origins.
(THUNDERCLAP)
♪ Back in time
- (SPLUTTERS)
- (YELPS)
♪ Gotta get back in time
(WHIMPERS)
♪ Get me back in time
(CAR HORNS HONKING)
Golly, thanks for taking me
to the movies
in this
dangerous neighborhood, Dad.
(CRACKLING AND WHOOSHING)
Whoa! Stop!
You can't go down there.
That is Crime Alley,
you dum-dums!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
May I suggest
you take a shortcut
through
Happy Lane instead?
♪ Get me back in time
Ah, we made it.
We're back in the present
and there are
no more superheroes.
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
Art, art, art, art!
(LAUGHS EVILLY)
What happened, yo?
Without superheroes, the world
has become a horrific wasteland.
But are they still
making superhero movies?
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(BALLOON MAN LAUGHING)
No movies. Only suffering.
(GRUNTS ANGRILY)
Titans! Back to the future!
I mean, the past!
♪ Get me back in time ♪
(CRASHING)
(SOBBING)
(GASPS)
(LAUGHING)
(GASPING AND CHOKING)
Yay!
(MARTHA SCREAMS)
Well, altering the space-time
continuum didn't work.
Who saw that coming?
Then we have
no choice, Titans.
We have to prove to Jade
Wilson we aren't a joke.
How's we gonna do that?
(ALARM BLARING)
This is how! It's Slade.
Slade!
- The Slade!
- Slade!
Slade!
If we can make him
our archnemesis,
then Jade Wilson will see
that we're worthy of a movie.
So, no songs, no jokes,
and whatever you do,
don't fall prey
to Slade's mind manipulation.
CYBORG: You got it!
BEAST BOY: Yeah, boy!
Titans, go!
ROBOTIC VOICE: Item acquired.
Charging Ditronium Crystal.
(CRACKLING)
(BANG)
Ditronium Crystal energized.
(SHRIEKS, BLOWS)
Ooh, that's hot.
Burned my little fingies.
ROBIN: Drop it.
Well, well. If it isn't
the "Teeny Titans."
I see you're all
gluttons for punishment.
The party's over, Slade.
BOTH: Slade!
Stop it. The party has
actually just begun.
And I'm about
to thoroughly enjoy
disposing of your
inferior intellects
(DRAMATICALLY)
with mind manipulation.
While I am typically
not a man of sympathy,
I will pity you fools after I
finish eviscerating your...
Oh, my gosh!
What's that over there?
ALL: It's a wall.
Whoa! Whoa!
Impressive. Good for you.
I knew it, too, obviously,
'cause I showed you.
Put it to rest, Slade.
We're not falling
for your mind tricks anymore.
Okay, I am noble enough
to admit when I'm wrong.
And oh, man, what is that
on your shirt right there?
Anyway, what
I was saying was...
And I'm serious,
because it doesn't look great.
It's, like, eye-grabbing. It's
like your eye goes right to it.
So, if I were you, I wouldn't
go in public like that.
Even, like, a lick-and-rub would work.
If you just wanna, you know...
On your finger, just
kinda moisten it a little.
I don't know
how that's possible.
I'm not even
wearing a shirt!
- (GASPS)
- Give it up, Slade. It's game over.
Titans, go!
(TITANS ROARING)
(TITANS GRUNT)
(TITANS YELP)
(TITANS GROANING)
Impressive.
(TITANS GRUNTING)
(BEAST BOY GROWLING)
CYBORG: Booyah!
(RAPID FIRING)
(STARFIRE GRUNTING)
Ca-caw!
(STRAINING)
(SLADE GRUNTS)
(ALL COUGHING)
- Hello.
- How's it goin'?
What up, Deadpool?
I'm not Deadpool!
Steady.
We got him boxed in. Fire!
(IMITATES GUNFIRE)
Can't get a clean shot!
We got this!
Yeah, we do!
Booyah!
(CYBORG GRUNTS)
- Ha!
- (SLADE GRUNTING)
(LAUGHING)
(GASPS)
- Get off me! Get off me!
- BEAST BOY: I'm over here. Here I am.
- Too slow, fool!
- Got him!
(GASPS)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Facial scan accepted.
(BEEPING TO THE TUNE
OF TEEN TITANS THEME)
Vault access granted.
Item secured.
Crystal secure.
Ha-ha! You'll never get it
now, Slade.
No one can
penetrate our vault!
Nice job, Titans.
(WEAPON WHIRRING)
(BOTH GASP)
(ALL GASP)
Raven, Starfire, save them!
I'll take care of Slade!
(STARFIRE GRUNTS)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
STARFIRE: Gotcha.
- Get up.
- (COUGHS)
Stop milkin' it.
- Rae-Rae?
- Don't call me that.
You saved me.
Let's not make it a big deal.
(GRUNTS)
(YELLING)
Crack an egg on it.
Ca-caw!
Oh. What a cool
and ominous catchphrase.
You truly are
a worthy archnemesis.
Archnemesis? Really?
You mean it?
I think you and I are destined
to do this forever.
Until next time, Robin.
There's not going
to be a next time.
You're going to prison.
(CHUCKLES)
That's not how having
an archnemesis works.
I get away and you foil my next
plan in an even more heroic way.
That's what happens in a great
superhero (ECHOING) movie.
A movie?
(SHUDDERS) Nice try, Slade.
Where'd he go?
Curse those Teen Titans
to the power of a million.
They've stolen my device
and locked it in their vault.
They're stronger
than I thought.
Not too strong. Actually,
fairly weak compared to me.
Definitely my cardio
is superior.
(PUFFING) Knees up,
knees up, knees up.
No matter!
All I need to do
is divide and conquer!
(SHRIEKS)
Oh, man!
I'm never letting you
fly my body again.
Where is the Slade?
He, uh, (CLEARS THROAT) got away.
But we'll get him next time.
It's Jade.
She wants to see us tomorrow
morning at the studio.
- Come on!
- It's the outrage!
- We should be on the list!
- This guy!
Whoa! It's the Teen Titans!
Oh, wow! Wow, wow, wow,
this is an honor.
You guys are the best.
I, uh... I can't. Whoa.
You know who we are?
Yes, sir. Everyone is talking about you.
You're on the list.
TITANS: We are on the list!
It's about time.
Right this way.
That is the more like the it.
(GIGGLES)
Welcome to the studio,
my stars.
Now, that battle with Slade,
I mean, it was electric.
Thanks, Miss Wilson.
Just doing our jobs.
Robin, you have proven to me that
you are more than a sidekick.
Now, let me show you
something marvelous.
The Teen Titans movie set!
TITANS: Whoa!
Robin, your dream
is coming the true.
ROBIN: Wow.
Incredible.
(LAUGHS)
It's really happening!
Dope, right?
This set seems so real.
Even the toilet, yo.
Well, the toilet isn't real.
Uh, yeah, it is.
I pooped in it.
- You what?
- I pooped in it.
Hoo doggie, do not go in that bathroom,
'cause I just wrecked it, baby.
(LAUGHS) That's what's up.
(AIR HORN TOOTING)
- We pooped in the toilet!
- (EDM PLAYS)
Stop that!
You are pooping
in a prop toilet!
I don't know, bro.
Looked real to me.
Ah, there is nothing quite like doing
the poops in the new bathroom.
(AIR HORN TOOTING)
- She pooped in the toilet!
- (EDM PLAYS)
No one should
be using that bathroom!
There is no plumbing. There is
nowhere for the poops to go.
Hey, keep it down.
I'm trying to poop in here.
(GRUNTING)
Robin, do your friends know
that's a fake toilet?
- Wow. Do not go in there.
- Oh, wow.
You really did. You pooped in
the fake toilet. (CHUCKLES)
You pooped on my set.
Miss Wilson, I am so sorry.
It's cool. I deal with people
like this all day.
Now, let me introduce
you to your co-star.
- Slade?
- TITANS: Get him!
(GRUNTS)
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Guys! I'm just
playing Slade in the movie.
It's me, Shia LaBeouf.
Oh, it's Shia LaBeoufs.
That's even worse
than being a villain.
(TITANS GRUNTING)
Titans! Stop!
(GRUNTS)
Argh! Didn't you hear Jade?
Everything here is fake.
Robin, if your team is going to poop
on the props and beat up the actors,
this isn't going to work.
Ugh. Maybe this
was a mistake.
No, no, no! It's not.
Please. Just give me a second.
Guys, this is my dream.
We finally have a chance
to prove we're real heroes.
That I'm a real hero.
Please promise me
you'll take this seriously.
(SIGHS) We will do it, Robin.
Because it is your dream.
Yeah, bro.
We'll do it for you.
Yeah, man. We got this.
Whatever.
Miss Wilson,
the team and I discussed it
and we promise from now on,
we'll behave ourselves.
That's what I like to hear. You're
gonna be a big star, Robin.
As long as your team doesn't
get into any more shenanigans.
Anybody up
for some shenanigans?
- Shenanigans!
- (ALL CHEERING)
- All right!
- This is gonna be fun!
♪ We're all gettin'
into shenanigans
- ♪ Shenanigans
♪ Shenanigans
(CRASHES)
(GROANS)
- ♪ Shenanigans
- ♪ Shena-na-na-na-na-nenigans
♪ Shenanigans
♪ Shenanigans ♪
(DOLPHIN CLICKING)
(AQUAMAN GRUNTS)
(GASPING)
BEAST BOY: Whoa, they gots
that good food in there, yo.
But how can we
get past the Superman?
We can exploit
his number one weakness.
(THEME FROM SUPERMAN
RINGTONE PLAYING)
Hello?
(HIGH-PITCHED VOICE)
Superman, it's me.
- Your girlfriend, Lois Lane.
- (STARFIRE GIGGLING)
Well, hello, Lois.
- (TITANS GIGGLING)
- How are you, my sweet little dewdrop?
How am I?
I'm terrible.
You gotta save me from Gene
Hackman's real estate scheme. Ahhh!
Oh, my goodness.
No, that sounds terrible.
(HIGH-PITCHED VOICE)
Oh! You's better hurry, fool.
Or no more smoochie smoochies.
Mwah! Mwah, mwah, mwah, mwah.
(GASPING)
I'm coming, Lois.
I'm coming, Lois!
ALL: Whoa!
Looks at all
that opulence, yo.
It is so the fancy.
The table
is wearing the dress.
Whoa!
Let's dig in!
- ♪ Shenanigans
- ♪ Shena-na-na-na-na-nenigans ♪
(BURPING)
(GRUNTING AND MUNCHING)
(TITANS GRUNTING AND MUNCHING)
- (DOOR OPENS)
- (ALL GASP)
THE FLASH: Jade says we need to
finish construction by tonight.
This smells of the fish.
(TITANS GASP)
(CRUNCHING)
What happened to all the food?
Let's steal some
from the Spider-Man set.
Doomsday device?
Let's destroy it.
With pleasure. Booyah!
I knew you were goofsters.
But using Lois and now this?
- It's too much!
- (EXPLOSION)
I don't know why
you're working with Jade.
But one way or another,
we're destroying that device.
(LAUGHS) Stop it. How are you
going to get past me? I mean...
By exploiting
your other weakness.
TITANS: Kryptonite party!
(FUNK MUSIC PLAYS)
(STARFIRE HOOTING)
(TITANS CHEERING)
BEAST BOY: Yeah, boy!
CYBORG: Yeah, baby!
(CLATTERING)
JADE: So...
I see you've discovered
my secret plan.
Titans! Why did you
do that to Superman?
He's a national treasure.
We're on to you, Jade.
Yeah. You've done some kind of
mind tricks on them superheroes.
So they'd help you build
a doomsday device.
The shame upon you, Jade.
The shame, the shame,
the shame!
Is it true? Are you building
a doomsday device?
It's not a "doomsday device."
It's my DOOMSDAY...
Oh, oh, oh...
Oh, I see the confusion.
DOOMSDAY stands for
"Digitally Ordering
Online Movie
"Streaming Directly At You."
In retrospect, we should have
gone with a different acronym.
But trust me, it's going to
revolutionize the movie industry.
Once finished, it will
broadcast my superhero movies
onto all screens
everywhere in the world.
Movie theaters,
televisions, phones,
tablets, smartwatches,
microwaves, you name it.
The population of Earth will be
able to watch superhero movies
anywhere, anytime,
all the time.
Wait, that thing's just
a big movie projector?
The Teen Titans movie
was going to be
the first movie delivered
by the DOOMSDAY Device.
What do you mean "was"?
I'm killing
the Teen Titans movie!
(TITANS GASP)
(SOBBING)
Miss the Wilson, please
do not murder the film.
It is friend Robin's dream.
Believe me, I did
not want to do this.
But you guys are jokes. You
can't take anything seriously!
That's why I won't make
a Teen Titans movie.
But I would make a...
A Robin movie.
A Robin movie?
All about me?
All about you.
But I know
you would never do it
because your friends
are too important to you.
You are correct.
The friend Robin
would never leave us.
- He would...
- I'll do it!
(ALL GASP)
Bro, is you
for reals gonna ditch us?
But, Robin, we have done
all of this for you.
Done all of what?
Make me look like a joke?
We have to face it. No one takes
us seriously when we're together.
Maybe we should just go
our separate ways.
It's never easy
to tell the truth, Robin.
But I am deeply touched
by what you've just done here.
And you four, it was so nice
to meet you, but not really.
And I'm sure we'll work together
again in the future, definitely not.
I'm sorry, guys.
But it's what we need to do.
Fine. Go make your own movie.
I'm going home to Dad.
(SOBBING)
Well, the dumpster it is.
I guess I'll have to be
a pro football star after all.
RAVEN: That really
doesn't sound that bad.
Good luck to you, Robin.
I hope to one day
see your movie.
I think it will be very good.
- Star...
- Don't be sad, Robin.
You don't need
your old friends anymore.
You'll find that fame is worth
so much more than friendship
because you are going to be
a big Hollywood star.
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(CAMERAS CLICKING)
(CHUCKLES) Wow.
(DEVICE SCANNING)
(BOTH LAUGH)
And action!
No longer a sidekick.
- That's not me!
- (THUNDERCLAP)
Oh, that was electric!
(GIRLS SQUEALING)
(SHRIEKS)
(SAD PIANO MUSIC PLAYING)
(SIGHS) I wonder
how they're doing now.
They're doing great.
- Really?
- I called them
to see if they wanted
to make cameos in the film,
but they're all too busy
with their fabulous lives.
Maybe splitting up
was for the best.
I couldn't agree more.
Now focus, because we are
about to film
the final scene
of your movie.
(SWITCHES CLICKING)
Picture this.
You just defeated Slade.
So in this scene, whoo,
you're gonna love this,
you return
to the tower vault
so you can lock away his evil device
along with the pain of your past.
And then,
(IMITATES FANFARE)
you emerge as a new man!
Robin, the superhero!
Think you can act that?
Act it? (SCOFFS)
I've lived it.
And magic!
(DISTANTLY) Robin? Robin?
Robin, can you hear me? Robin.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
What? What... What happened?
Oh, thank goodness. A light
fell and knocked you out.
- (GRUNTS)
- Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Let's just wrap for the day
so you can recover.
And we'll start
fresh tomorrow.
No, no, I'm fine.
Let's finish this movie.
And that's what makes you
a real hero.
Okay, let's do this!
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Facial scan accepted.
Whoa. These effects
are pretty impressive.
This is just like our vault.
Why, thank you.
I've designed it with
meticulous attention to detail.
Now please type in the code.
AUTOMATED VOICE: Invalid code.
JADE: No, no.
It has to feel authentic,
so go again.
- AUTOMATED VOICE: Invalid code.
- Focus. Again.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Invalid code.
No. Be in the moment!
Make it look real!
(GRUNTS) All right.
(BEEPING TO THE TUNE
OF TEEN TITANS THEME)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Code accepted.
- Vault access granted.
- (SOFTLY) Yes!
And cut! That was perfect.
Robin, thank you.
You're a genius.
Wow, these sets are amazing.
They look so real.
- Well, because it is real.
- (CHUCKLES)
No, really. While you were knocked
out by our lighting accident,
I moved you to the actual Titans Tower
so you could open the real vault for me.
(CHUCKLES) Good one. That would
make a great villain plot.
We'll do it in the sequel.
Whoa! Robin, what is that?
Huh? I don't see anything.
There's nothing there.
JADE: Made you look.
No!
(GRUNTS)
(WHIMPERS)
So, everything, the movie,
turning me against my friends,
it was all just...
SLADE: Mind manipulation.
Slade.
You were wearing a lady-director mask
over your Slade mask the whole time!
Didn't you get
really sweaty under there?
It gets stupid sweaty.
And I've had
a bunch of rashes...
Anyway, it doesn't matter!
Now I can complete
my mind manipulation device.
- The other superheroes will...
- Will stop me?
Is that what
you were gonna say?
They're too busy
making movies to stop me.
It was all part
of my master plan, Robin.
I gave all the superheroes
movie deals.
And while those dum-dums
were distracted filming,
I stole valuable pieces of tech from
the cities they once protected.
(LAUGHS) Now, with my fully
energized Ditronium Crystal,
I will have the power
to encrypt your movie
with my patented
mind manipulation!
It will stream to every screen
in the entire world!
And everyone
will be mine to control.
People will rob banks for me.
People will build
monuments of me!
And if I tell them to pick me up
from the airport on short notice,
- they will pick me up.
- (CAR HORN HONKS)
You know what
a hassle that is.
And once they've watched
your entire movie,
the effects of my mind control
will be permanent.
Thank you, Robin.
You were so desperate
to be in a movie,
that you turned your back on
everything important to you.
Even your own friends.
This shall be
your final scene.
Magic.
- (BEEPS)
- (GASPS)
(GRUNTING)
How could I have been so stupid?
I'm not a hero.
I'm a failure with no friends.
And tiny, little baby hands.
(GASPS) Baby hands!
(STRAINING)
Baby hands!
(GASPS)
(WHIMPERS)
(COUGHING)
(GRUNTING)
(YELLS)
- (EXPLOSIONS)
- (PANTING)
(SCREAMS)
(GASPS)
(SAD MUSIC PLAYING)
(GLASS SHATTERS)
Titans, it's Robin.
I don't know if you'll get this
transmission, but I need your help.
I know you're all happier
in your new lives
and I know I said we were
holding each other back,
but I was wrong.
I thought we needed a movie
to be real heroes,
but we were
already real heroes.
Because we were a team.
And I threw that all away.
I'm going to Hollywood
to set things right.
If I don't make it back,
I'm sorry.
I never meant to let you down.
(BLOWING NOSE)
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
(SOBBING) I just get so emotional when
it comes to these types of scenes.
You're back!
Of course we're back, fool.
The friendship will always
bring us back together.
I can't believe it!
Listen, we need
to get back to Hollywood.
This is going to sound crazy,
but Jade Wilson...
Is actually Slade.
And the superhero movies are part
of his plot to take over the world.
(EXPLOSION)
Saw it coming a mile away.
(LAUGHS) Let's go
save the world, yo!
Titans, go!
Super-ladies
and super-gentlemen,
I am thrilled to present
my latest film,
Robin The Movie!
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
And with the help of my fully
operational DOOMSDAY Device...
It's a bad name,
I know.
The entire population
of Earth
will experience the mind-blowing
story at the same time!
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
Unfortunately, our star
can't be here tonight
because he has
explosive diarrhea.
- (AUDIENCE GASPS)
- But he insisted
that tonight
was too important
and the show must go on!
So without further ado,
sit back, relax and...
Enjoy us ruining your plan!
Oh! My man
finished yo sentence!
Give it up, Wilson.
Your plan ends here.
Wow. Fighting through explosive diarrhea.
What a champ.
I do have
something explosive,
but it's not diarrhea.
It's the truth!
Why don't you tell everyone
who you really are, Jade?
Or should I say...
(AUDIENCE GASPS)
Slade!
(GASPS) Slade!
ALL: Slade!
Game over.
You've gotta deal with us and
every superhero in the world.
Sorry, Robin,
but you're too late.
(DEVICE POWERING UP)
(TREMBLING)
(TITANS SCREAMING)
Now that they're under my full mind
control, they'll do anything I want.
Destroy the Teen Titans.
(TITANS PANTING)
(TITANS SCREAMING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
We have to destroy
that DOOMSDAY Device.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(CHUCKLES)
I think we lost him.
(GRUNTS)
(YELLING)
Ooh! There is no
stopping the Batman.
(TEEN TITANS GASPING)
Halt for the mighty...
(ATOM EXCLAIMS)
(ALL SCREAMING)
STAN LEE: Hey.
TITANS: Stan Lee?
I'm back. I don't care if it's a DC movie.
I love cameos.
Not now, Stan Lee!
(GRUNTS) Excelsior!
We can't shake them.
You guys keep
the superheroes distracted.
I'm going after
that DOOMSDAY Device!
(YELLING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(ALL GRUNT)
How are we supposed to defeat the
world's greatest superheroes?
Portal.
CYBORG: Oh, yeah. Right, right, right.
STARFIRE: Oh, the yes!
Challengers, we're saved!
(CHALLENGERS SCREAMING)
(GRENADE BEEPING)
(YELLING)
(BEEPING RAPIDLY)
(GRUNTS)
(ROBIN YELLING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
(YELLS AND GRUNTS)
Look at it, Robin.
No!
Oh, it's so awesome.
It's so cool.
It's the most incredible superhero
movie the world has ever seen.
- No.
- It's got special effects.
Like tons and tons
of special effects.
Even your super sweet
cape is special effects.
It'll blow your mind.
Just take a quick peek.
It's your movie, your movie,
your superhero movie.
It's all about you.
(GRUNTING)
Come on, Robin,
let's take this fool out.
(LAUGHING)
(ALL GASP)
It's time to eliminate them.
(DISTORTED VOICE)
Must eliminate.
Robin, stop! Snap out of it!
You've always held me back.
What are you talking
about, bro?
- (BEAST BOY GRUNTS)
- (RAVEN GASPS)
Beast Boy!
Fight it, man!
- Come on!
- (BOTH GRUNTING)
Robin, this is not the you.
- (GROWLS)
- (SCREAMING)
Finish them, Robin.
Kill!
Wait! The please!
There's another
Robin movie you must see!
Yeah. The real one.
BEAST BOY: Then he grew up and
he wasn't a baby no more.
But he still had them
baby hands, yo.
You always thought
I was a joke.
But when there's
crime happening,
Robin is the dude who keeps
fighting till he wins, yo.
He's like a bulldog.
Sinks his teeth into that crime
and won't nevers let go!
STARFIRE: Before the
Robin, we were all alone.
(BEAST BOY CRYING)
STARFIRE: But he brought us
together to be the team.
He may not have superpowers,
but he is a superhero.
RAVEN: Our hero.
Titans?
Oh! He is the back!
You were never a joke to us.
You are our leader.
Our hero.
Our friend.
(SLADE CRIES MOCKINGLY)
Under the mask,
my other eye is crying.
We're taking you down.
Together.
(LAUGHS) Robin. Don't you know
anything about archvillains?
We always have
a backup plan, girlfriend.
(ALL GASPING)
(TITANS GRUNTING)
(LAUGHING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
- Portal?
- Portal!
(GRUNTING)
What?
SLADE: That was weird.
(ALL GASP)
You're never gonna beat me
now that I'm a giant robot.
Give up. This is dumb. Now
you're wasting everybody's time.
We'll stop you, Slade.
How are you gonna do it?
How are you gonna beat me?
You haven't done it yet. You keep
talking about how you're gonna do it.
What are you gonna do?
Are you gonna fart on me?
You wanna have a dance-off?
You gonna annoy me to death
with your waffles?
You guys are jokes.
Total jokes!
- You're right.
- (ALL GASP)
We are jokes.
We're not like the other
superheroes, and never will be.
(LAUGHING)
But the thing is, that's okay.
What?
I'm proud to call myself a Teen Titan!
And so are my friends!
ALL: Yes!
So laugh at us all you want, but
we're still going to take you down!
With what?
One of your stupid songs?
Exactly.
Teen Titans, go!
♪ Go, Teen Titans, go
Go, Teen Titans, go
♪ Beast Boy I can turn
straight up into an animal
♪ Animal?
♪ Yes, any animal
♪ Boom, pow!
Yeah, I'm a kitten now
(ROARING)
♪ Check out my kitten meow
♪ The star, the fire
The live, the wire
♪ The alien princess
in my alien attire
♪ The energy blasts
The supersonic speed
(SLADE CHUCKLES)
♪ Is she down with the Titans?
♪ Oh, the yes indeed
♪ Booyah, booyah!
Go my cannon blaster
♪ Cyborg, whoo, baby
Mr. High Tech Master
♪ What, what, what?
♪ Mr. Meatball Disaster
♪ Mr. Boom Boom Blaster
♪ Teen Teen Titans
The Titans, the Teen Titans
♪ Boom with the smoke bombs
and birdarangs
♪ Bow staff hittin' steady,
Doin' my thang
♪ Robin, Robin, the leader
Robin, Robin, in charge
CYBORG:
♪ Show 'em your baby hands!
♪ No Robin, Robin's are large
(SLADE GRUNTS)
♪ Raven is here to drop it
On you even harder
♪ There's no darker than me
I'm as dark as can be
♪ Check it
Azarath Metrion Zinthos
♪ Teleportin', magical powers
We adios
♪ Teen Teen Titans
The Titans, the Teen Titans
(ROARS)
♪ Teen Titans Go ♪
(EXPLOSION)
That song was
monumentally dope.
(GROANS)
Our song was so sick,
it blew up Slade's robot.
- Oh, yeah! We are so tough.
- BEAST BOY: Yeah! Wow! We did it!
- Yes!
- (ALL WHOOPING)
BEAST BOY: I said wow!
What about
the other superheroes?
Oh, yeah.
CHALLENGER:
Challengers, we're free!
Oh, drat!
Whoa. You guys
took down Slade.
And saved the world.
Hey, I guess you aren't
such goofsters after all.
(BATMAN CLAPPING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
Fellow heroes, I've learned
something important today.
You don't need to be super
to be a superhero.
You just need to be yourself.
(CROWD CHEERING)
(CROWD SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
And expanding on that thought.
We should never forget that...
Uh, dude? Why are you
still talkin'?
I'm simply trying to highlight
the lesson we all learned.
No one wants
to hear that, man.
Dude, the movie's wrapping up. People
are trying to get out of here.
But I need to say my
important takeaway message
- from this experience!
- CROWD: (CHANTING) Credits! Credits! Credits!
You know, something kids can talk to
their parents about on the drive home.
Credits! Credits! Credits!
I am sorry, the friend Robin.
But this is not that type of movie.
To the credits!
(EXCLAIMING) Wait!
Kids, ask your parents
where babies come from!
♪ T-double-E-N-T-I-T-A-N-S
♪ They the real heroes
Takin' down the big menace
♪ Teen Titan flow
♪ Teen Titan know
♪ Where there's real trouble,
baby, Teen Titans go
♪ Go, Teen Titans, go
Go, Teen Titans, go
♪ Beast Boy can turn
Straight up into an animal
♪ Animal?
♪ Yes, any animal
♪ Boom, pow!
Yeah, he's a kitten now
ALL: Aw!
♪ Check out my kitten meow
♪ The star, the fire
The live, the wire
♪ The alien princess
in her alien attire
♪ The energy blasts
The supersonic speed
♪ Is she down with the Titans?
Oh, the yes indeed
♪ Booyah, booyah!
Go his cannon blaster
♪ Cyborg, whoo, baby
Mr. High Tech Master
♪ What, what, what?
♪ Mr. Meatball Disaster
♪ Mr. Boom Boom Blaster
♪ Teen Teen Titans
The Titans, the Teen Titans
♪ Teen Teen... ♪
(SONG DISTORTING)
BEAST BOY: Is it working?
CYBORG: Almost got it.
STARFIRE: Hurry!
There is not much time.
RAVEN: They need to know
we're still here.
CYBORG: Booyah!
We're transmitting.
This is the Teen Titans.
Can anyone hear us?
We think we found a way back.
♪ Are you feeling down?
♪ Like you just
can't do it today
♪ I can see your frown
♪ But it's all gonna be okay
♪ So believe in yourself
♪ There's no giving up
♪ The power's inside
♪ Yeah, that's what's up
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
♪ It's the kick in the pants
♪ You needed
♪ This song will
open up your eyes
♪ It's the feeling you
can't be Defeated
♪ It's an '80s song
with synthy vibes
♪ And you know it's super
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ It's time to get
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ The groove is sounding
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ By now you're feeling
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ It's an upbeat
inspirational song about life
♪ I can do it all
♪ This type of song will
make you feel that way
♪ No, there's no stopping me
♪ I feel the fire inside
♪ This type of song
will get you energized
♪ I love
this motivating melody
♪ And you know it's super
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ Your life is lookin'
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ Don't tell me this ain't
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ Yeah, now I'm feelin'
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ It's an upbeat
inspirational song about life
(UPBEAT MUSIC CONTINUES)
♪ And you know it's super
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ It's time to get
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ Let's make this party
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ Everybody's gettin'
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ I know you're feelin'
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ Don't tell me this ain't
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ Your life is lookin'
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ This song has got us
♪ Upbeat
Upbeat
♪ It's an upbeat inspirational
song about life ♪
♪ T-E-E-N-T-I-T-A-N-S
♪ Teen Titans
Let's go
(RECORD SCRATCHING)
♪ T-E-E-N-T-I-T-A-N-S
♪ Teen Titans
Let's go
♪ T-E-E-N-T-I-T-A-N-S
♪ Teen Titans
Let's go
♪ T-E-E-N-T-I-T-A-N-S
♪ Teen Titans
Let's go
♪ T-E-E-N-T-I-T-A-N-S
♪ Teen Titans
Let's go
(TECHNO MUSIC PLAYING)
(VOCALIZING)
♪ T-E-E-N-T-I-T-A-N-S
♪ Teen Titans
Let's go
♪ T... T... T...
♪ Teen Titans
Let's go ♪
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
Challengers, I believe we may
have missed the motion picture.
Subtitles by explosiveskull