# This is the night
# It's a beautiful night
# And they call it bella notte
# Look at the skies
# They have stars in their eyes
# On this lovely bella notte
# So take the love
# Of your loved one
# You'll need it about this time
# To keep from falling like a star
# When you make that dizzy climb
# For this is the night
# And the heavens are right
# On this lovely
# Bella notte
# Bella notte #
# Silent as a snowflake in the night
# Holy is the spirit of this night
# All the world is calm and peaceful
# All the world is bright and joyful
# Spirit of love
# And child of peace
# Love unending
# That shall not cease
# Peace, my children
# Of good will
# Peace be still #
[man] It's for you, darling.
Merry Christmas.
Oh, Jim, dear.
It's the one I was admiring, isn't it?
- Trimmed with ribbons?
- [Whimpering]
[Jim] Well, it has a ribbon.
[Gasping]
Oh, how sweet.
- [Jim] You like her, darling?
- Oh, I love her.
What a perfectly beautiful little lady.
Come on, Lady. Over here.
That's a girl.
There, now. A nice little bed for you.
[Darling] But Jim, dear, are you sure
she'll be warm enough?
[Jim] Why, of course, darling.
She'll be snug as a bug in a...
Uh-oh!
Almost forgot something.
There.
[Jim] Good night, Lady.
Now, now, don't worry, darling.
She'll go right to sleep.
No, no, Lady.
This is where you belong, right here.
- [Whimpering]
- [Darling] Oh, look.
She's lonesome.
Don't you think maybe?
Just for tonight?
[Jim] Darling, if we're going
to show her who's master,
we must be firm from the very beginning.
[Whimpering]
[Jim pounding on ceiling] Lady!
Stop that now!
Stop it!
[Whimpering]
[footsteps]
[whimpering]
[Jim pounding on door] Lady!
[Jim] Quiet, now. You hear me?
Back to bed!
Quick, now.
Not one more sound.
[Chiming]
[scraping]
[snoring]
- [whimpering]
- [Darling] Jim, dear.
[Groaning]
[whimpering]
Aw, Jim.
[Jim] Hmm? What?
[Whimpering, howling]
[Jim yawning]
[Jim] Oh, all right.
But remember, just for tonight.
[Rooster crowing]
[chiming]
[Darling groaning]
[yawns] All right, Lady. All right.
I'm up. I'm up, Lady.
Oh, no!
[Darling] What's wrong, Jim? What is it?
Can't you explain to Lady about Sundays?
[Barking]
[growling, barking]
[bicycle bell rings]
[Jim] Have you noticed,
darling, since we've had Lady
we see less and less
of those disturbing headlines?
[Darling] Yes, I just don't know
how we ever got along without her.
[Jim] Say, she must be
about six months old.
We'd better be getting her a license.
Hope it fits.
My, but it does look nice.
So grown up.
Won't Jock and Trusty be surprised?
[Humming]
# Four steps straight
and then to the left
# And right to the place
where I marked it
# With a bonnie, bonnie bone
that I buried for me own
# In my bonnie, bonnie bank
in the backyard #
A-ha, that's a grand sight.
[Lady] Jock!
Oh, Jock!
Hello, Jock.
Oh! Oh, it's you, lassie. [Chuckles]
Notice anything different?
Eh, uh... You've had a bath?
No, not that.
You've had your nails clipped?
[Lady] Mm-mmm. Guess again.
Well, I wouldn't a-be knowin'.
Why-o, lassie.
A bonnie new collar.
- Do you like it?
- Aye. [Sniffs]
Mmm. It must be very expensive.
- Have you shown it to Trusty yet?
- No.
Ah, we'd best go at once.
You know how sensitive
he is about these things.
[Snoring]
[whimpering]
[snorting, howling]
He's dreaming.
[Jock] Aye.
Dreamin' of those bonnie bygone days
when he and his grandfather
were trackin' criminals
through the swamps.
- [Lady] They were?
- That was before...
Before what?
'Tis time you knew the truth, lassie.
[Jock] It shouldn't
have happened to a dog.
But, well...
Trusty has lost his sense of smell.
- [Lady gasps] No!
- [Jock] Aye.
But we must never let on
that we know, lassie.
It would break his poor heart.
Uh... Which way did he go?
Which way did he go?
- Go?
- [Trusty] Yeah, big fella.
About, uh, six-foot-two.
[Sniffs] No, uh, three.
Wore a striped suit. No collar.
Why, Miss Lady.
You have a collar.
Mm-hmm. And a license.
My, my.
- How time does fly.
- Aye.
It seems only yesterday she was
cuttin' her teeth
on Jim Dear's slippers,
and now there she is, a full-grown lady.
Wearin' the greatest honor
man can bestow.
The badge of faith and respectability.
That's right, Miss Lady.
As my grandpappy,
Old Reliable, used to say...
I don't recollect if I've ever
mentioned Old Reliable before.
Aye, you have, laddie.
Oh, yeah.
- [Whistling]
- Ooh, it's Jim Dear.
Please excuse me.
Hello, there, Lady.
Come on, beat you home.
Oh, you win again.
Steady, now.
Steady.
Well, what have we here?
Oh, big girl now, huh?
All right.
Oh, ladies first.
You know, darling, with Lady here
I'd say life is quite complete.
[Darling] Yes, dear.
I don't imagine anything could
ever take her place in our hearts.
[Steam hissing]
[train whistle blows]
[train chugging]
[stretching]
[shuddering]
Ah! What a day!
Well, now to dig up some breakfast.
Hmm? [Chuckles]
Aw, cute little rascals.
Cootchie-cootchie-coo.
Now. That breakfast, let's see.
Bernie's?
Mmm... no.
Francois...
No, no.
Nope. Too much starch. Ah!
Tony's. Oh, that's it.
I haven't been there in a week.
[Tony] # A beautiful day
to make pizza
# Hey, still we call it bella notte #
[scratching]
Well, buon giorno, Butch.
You want-a your breakfast, eh?
OK. The boss, he's a-saving
some a-nice bones for you.
Breakfast comin' up from a-left field.
[Chuckles] Good catch!
[Man whistling]
[man] Whoa, boy, whoa.
[Whistling continues]
[man humming]
Hey. Psst. Psst.
Blimey.
- Look, Peg, it's the Tramp.
- [Tramp] Shh.
Hiya, handsome.
Come to join the party?
All right. No time for wisecracks.
I've got to get you out.
I'm telling you, the pressure's on.
Signs all over town.
- Gee, thanks.
- You're a bit of all right, chum.
- OK, OK, get going.
- [Man] Hey! What's going on there?
Scram. And be careful.
- [Snarling]
- Why, you mangy mutt.
Hey. Let go. Let go of me.
Well. Snob hill. Ha!
Hi, gals. How's pickings?
Pretty slim, eh?
Yeah. I'll bet they've got
a lid on every trash can.
Uh-oh. And a fence around every tree.
[Chuckles] I wonder what
the leash and collar set
does for excitement.
Lassie. Lassie!
Oh, Miss Lady, ma'am.
Miss Lady!
[Jock] Ah! Good morning, lassie.
'Tis a bonnie, braw, bright day. Uh...
...day.
Why, Miss Lady.
Is something wrong?
Aye. Tell us, lassie.
- If somebody's been mistreatin' ya...
- Oh, no, Jock.
It's something I've done, I guess.
You?
It must be.
- Jim Dear and Darling are acting so...
- [Darling humming]
[humming continues]
- Jim Dear and Darling?
- Hush, lad.
Now, lassie,
get on with the details.
Well, I first noticed it
the other day
when Jim Dear came home.
[Clock chiming]
[barking]
Down, Lady, down!
Darling, darling!
Are you all right?
[Darling] Of course I am.
Why shouldn't I be?
[Jim] I just can't help worrying.
After all, in your condition,
alone here all day,
and walking that dog...
- That dog!
- That dog?
He's never called me that before.
Well, now, lassie,
I wouldn't worry
my wee head about that.
Remember,
they're only humans, after all.
That's right, Miss Lady.
As my grandpappy,
Old Reliable, used to say...
I don't recollect if I've ever
mentioned Old Reliable before.
Aye, you have, laddie.
- Frequently.
- Oh, yeah.
But now Darling is... Well...
We've always enjoyed
our afternoon romp together.
But yesterday...
[chiming]
[barking]
[humming]
[whining]
No, Lady. No walk today.
[Humming continues]
[barking]
No, Lady.
Not now.
Lady!
Drop that, Lady.
Drop it, I say.
It didn't hurt, really.
But Darling has
never struck me... before.
[Chuckling] Now, lassie.
Do not take it too seriously.
After all, at a time like this...
Why, yes, you see, Miss Lady,
there comes a time
in the life of all humans when, uh...
Well, as they put it, uh...
Birds and the bees?
Or... Well, uh...
The stork. You know. Uh, no?
- Well, uh...
- What he's trying to say, lassie,
is Darling is expecting a wee bairn.
Bairn?
He means a baby, Miss Lady.
Oh.
What's a baby?
[Jock] Well, they resemble humans.
[Trusty] But I'd say a mite smaller.
[Jock] Aye. And they walk on all fours.
[Trusty] And if I remember correctly,
they bellow a lot.
Aye. And they're very expensive.
You will not be permitted
to play with it.
But they're mighty sweet.
And very, very soft.
Just a cute little bundle. [Chuckles]
[Tramp] Of trouble.
Yeah. They scratch, pinch, pull ears...
Aw, but shucks.
Any dog can take that.
It's what they do to your happy home.
Move it over, will you, friend?
Homewreckers, that's what they are.
Look here, laddie.
Who are you to barge in?
The voice of experience, buster.
[Chuckles] Just wait
till junior gets here.
You get the urge for
a nice comfortable scratch,
and, "Put that dog out!
He'll get fleas all over the baby."
You start barking
at some strange mutt.
[Barks]
"Stop that racket.
You'll wake the baby."
And then!
Then they hit you in the
room and board department.
Remember those nice, juicy cuts of beef?
[Tramp] Forget them.
Leftover baby food.
And that nice, warm bed by the fire?
[Chuckles]
[thunderclap]
A leaky doghouse.
- Oh, dear.
- Do not listen, lassie.
No human is that cruel.
Of course not, Miss Lady.
Why, everybody knows
a dog's best friend is his human.
[Tramp laughing]
Oh, come on now, fellas.
You haven't fallen
for that old line, now have you?
Aye. And we've no need for mongrels
and their radical ideas.
Off with you, now. Off with you!
- OK, Sandy.
- The name's Jock.
- OK, Jock.
- Heather Lad of Glencairn to you!
OK, OK, OK.
But remember this, Pigeon.
A human heart has only so much
room for love and affection.
When a baby moves in,
the dog moves out.
[Jim] Uh-huh.
Oh, let's see. That'll be about...
Oh, well.
[Pounding]
[Jim] Darling?
There isn't any way we can tell for sure
what it's going to be, is there?
[Darling] I'm afraid not.
Nobody ever knows for certain.
All we can do is hope.
[Chiming]
[footsteps]
[yawning]
[wind howling]
[door closes]
Darling, are you sure
you want watermelon?
[Darling] Mm-hmm.
Oh, and some chop suey too.
Chop su...
[sighs] Oh, all right, darling.
[Door shuts]
[women giggling and chattering]
[woman 1]... the cutest thing.
- [Woman 2] Those booties!
- [Woman 3] That bonnet.
- [Woman 4] Adorable.
- [Woman 5] Don't you love showers?
[Woman 6] I've never seen
you more beautiful.
[Woman 7] Isn't she radiant?
[Woman 8] That's just
what I told Bill.
"Bill", I said, "Darling
looks positively radiant."
In all my days,
"I've never seen anyone as radiant."
[Men laughing]
[man 1] Aw, Jim, you look terrible.
[Man 2] Absolutely horrible.
[Man 3] I never saw you look worse.
[Man 4] Cheer up, Jim. Old Doc Jones
has never lost a father yet.
[Laughter]
[thunderclap]
[Jim] Yes, Aunt Sarah, it's a boy.
Uh-huh, a boy. And...
What's that?
Eyes?
Oh, what color are they?
Well... Oh, gosh.
I-I forgot to look.
A boy. It's a boy, it's a... Doctor!
Doctor, it's a boy!
Yes, yes, I know.
Uh-huh, a boy.
Oh, boy, oh, boy!
It's a boy, it's a boy, it's a boy!
[Aunt Sarah on phone]
Hello? Hello, Jim?
Are you there, Jim?
Central, we've been cut off.
Hello? Hello?
Hello!
[Baby crying]
[crying continues]
[thinking] What is a baby?
# I just can't understand
# It must be something wonderful
# It must be something grand
# Cos everybody's smiling
# In a kind and wistful way
# And they haven't even noticed
# That I am around today
[Jim whistling]
[thinking] What is a baby, anyway?
[Baby crying]
# Oh, what is a baby?
# I must find out today
# What makes Jim Dear and Darling
# Act this way? #
[Baby cooing]
[Darling humming]
# Oh, my little star sweeper
# I'll sweep the stardust
# For you
[humming]
# Little soft, fluffy sleeper
# Here comes a pink cloud
# For you
[humming]
# Little wandering angel
# Fold up your wings
# Close your eyes
[humming]
# And may love be your keeper #
There, now.
Little star sweeper.
Dream on.
Well, that should do it.
We've got enough here
to take us halfway to China.
[Grunting]
[Jim] Darling. Darling!
We haven't much time.
[Darling] Jim, I just can't leave him.
He's still so small and helpless.
[Jim] He'll be all right.
Now come on. If he wakes up
we'll never get away.
Jim, I feel so guilty
deserting him like this.
[Jim] Nonsense.
[Jim] Hey.
What's the matter with Lady?
[Darling] She thinks
we're running out on him.
[Jim] Oh, don't worry, old girl.
We'll be back in a few days.
[Darling] And Aunt Sarah will be here.
- [Jim] With you here to help her...
- [doorbell rings]
[Jim] There's the old girl now.
Coming, Aunt Sarah. Coming!
[Sarah panting] Sorry I'm late, dears.
Hope I haven't kept you waiting.
- [Jim] Let me take your things.
- No, no.
No fussing. I know my way around.
On your way, now.
Mustn't miss your train.
Have a good time,
and don't worry about a thing.
Goodbye, dears. Goodbye, goodbye.
[Jim and Darling] Goodbye.
[Sarah] Now to see
that big nephew of mine.
- Cootchie-cootchie-coo.
- [Cooing]
Oh, you adorable little...
[gasps] Good gracious!
What are you doing here?
Go on, now. Shoo, shoo.
Scat. Get out of here.
- [Baby crying]
- Aw, there, there.
Aunt Sarah won't let
that dog frighten you anymore.
No, no, no.
[Baby crying]
[Sarah] # Rock-a-bye, baby
on the treetop
# When the wind blows
# We are Siamese
if you please
[purring]
# We are Siamese
if you don't please
# Now we looking over
our new domicile
# If we like we stay
for maybe quite a while
[barking]
Do you seeing that thing
swimming round and round?
Yesss.
Maybe we can reaching in
and make it drown.
If we sneaking up upon it carefully...
# There will be a head
for you, a tail for me
[crashing]
[baby crying]
Do you hear what I hear?
[Purrs] A baby cry.
# Where we're finding baby
there are milk nearby
# If we look in baby buggy
there could be
# Plenty milk for you
and also some for me #
[growling]
- [screeching]
- [barking]
[Sarah] What's going on down there?
[Gasps] Merciful heavens! My darlings.
- My precious pets.
- [Yowling]
Oh. Ooh, that wicked animal.
Attacking my poor,
innocent little angels.
[Man] Good afternoon, ma'am.
What can I do for you?
I want a muzzle.
A good, strong muzzle.
Oh, yes, ma'am.
Now here's our latest.
Combination leash and muzzle.
Now, we'll just slip it on like this,
and... No! No, no, no.
Nice doggy. No, don't wiggle.
Steady, now.
Now... Now, now.
Careful, you little...
[Sarah] Watch out.
- [Man] Careful, doggy.
- [Sarah] Come back!
Get over here, I say.
Come back here.
[Horn beeping]
[horn beeping]
[streetcar bell ringing]
[barking]
[snarling]
[growling]
[whimpering]
[panting, snorts]
Hey, Pige, what are you doing
on this side of the tracks?
I thought you...
Wh?
Aw, you poor kid.
Oh, we've got to get this off.
Hmm.
I think I know the very place.
Come on.
Well, here we are.
- The zoo?
- Sure.
No, no. This way.
Follow me.
[Guard humming]
- [Lady] Oh.
- What's the matter, Pige?
- We can't go in.
- Why not?
- [Lady] The sign says...
- [Tramp] Yeah, well, that's...
- That's the angle.
- Angle?
Look. We'll just wait for the right...
Uh-oh. Here we are now.
Just lay low.
[Whistling]
[barking]
- [guard] Hey, you!
- I beg your pardon.
- Were you addressing?
- What's the matter? Can't you read?
Why, yes, in several languages.
Oh, a wise guy, eh?
All right, now,
what's this creature doing here?
- He's not my dog.
- Oh, he's not, eh?
Go away. Get down.
Go on. Why, certainly not, officer.
I suppose you'll be tellin' me next
it was the dog that was whistling, eh?
- [Man] I'm certain I don't know.
- Oh! So I'm a liar now, am I?
Well, you listen to me.
A-ha! Resisting an officer of the law.
You're gonna pay.
Ow!
Pull a knife on me, will you?
Trying to assassinate me, you are.
Carrying concealed weapons.
[Arguing continues]
Come on, Pige.
The place is ours.
[Arguing continues]
We better go through
this place from A to Z.
Apes.
No, no. No use even asking them.
They wouldn't understand.
They wouldn't?
Uh-uh. Too closely related to humans.
Uh-oh.
[Tramp] Alligators.
Now there's an idea.
Say, Al, do you suppose you
could nip this contraption off for us?
[Echoing] Glad to oblige.
Whoa. Whoa!
[Hysterical laughter]
Ha! If anybody ever needed
a muzzle, it's him.
- [Animal] Timber!
- Pigeon, look out!
Now what harebrained idiot would...
Hey, look. A beaver.
There's the answer to our problem.
Let me see here.
Six-foot-six
and seven-sixteenth inches.
Pardon me, friend.
- I wonder if you'd do us a little...
- Busy, sonny. Busy.
Can't stop to gossip now.
Got to slide this sycamore
to the... [straining]
...swamp.
Well, this will only take a second.
Only a second? Listen, sonny.
Do you realize every second,
70 centimeters of water
is wasted over that spillway?
- [Tramp] Yeah, but...
- Gotta get this log movin', sonny.
Gotta get it moving.
Think the cuttin' takes the time?
It's the doggone haulin'.
[Straining]
[Tramp] The haulin'. Exactly.
- Now, what you need...
- I'd better bisect this section here.
What you need is a log puller.
[Shouting] I said a log puller!
I ain't deaf, sonny.
There's no need to...
Did you say log puller?
And by a lucky coincidence
you see before you,
modeled by the lovely little lady,
the new, improved,
patented, handy dandy,
never-fail little giant log puller.
The busy beaver's friend.
You don't say?
Guaranteed not to wear,
tear, rip or ravel.
Turn around and show
the customer the merchandise.
And it cuts
log-hauling time 66 per cent.
Sixty-six per cent, eh?
[Giggles] Think of that.
- Well, how's it work?
- Why, it's no work at all.
You merely slip this ring
over the limb like this,
and haul it off.
Uh, say...
You mind if I slip it on for size?
Help yourself, friend.
OK. Don't mind if I do.
How do you get the
consarned thing off, sonny?
Glad you brought that up, friend.
To remove it, simply place
the strap between your teeth...
Like this?
Correct, friend. Now bite hard.
You see?
It's off.
Say, that is simple.
Well, friend,
we'll be on our way now, so...
Uh-uh. Not so fast now, sonny...
I'll have to make certain
it's satisfactory
before we settle on a price.
Oh, no, it's all yours, friend.
You can keep it.
I can, eh?
I can?
Uh-huh. It's a free sample.
Well, thanks a lot.
[Chuckles] Thanks ever so...
Say!
It works swell.
[Lady] But when she put
that horrible muzzle on me...
Say no more. I get the whole picture.
Aunts. Cats. Muzzles.
Well, that's what comes of tying
yourself down to one family.
Haven't you a family?
One for every day of the week.
The point is, none of them have me.
I'm afraid I don't understand.
It's simple.
You see... [sniffing]
Hey. [Sniffing]
Something tells me it's suppertime.
Come on. I'll show you what I mean.
Now take the Schultzes here.
Little Fritzie,
that's me, Pige,
makes this his Monday home.
- Monday home?
- Ach, ja.
[With German accent]
Monday is Mama Schultz
cooking der Wiener Schnitzel.
Mmm.
Delicious.
[Irish accent] O'Brien's
is where little Mike,
that's me again, Pige,
- comes every Tuesday.
- Every Tuesday?
Begorra. And that's when they're havin'
their darlin' corned beef.
You see, Pige,
when you're footloose and collar-free,
well, you take nothing but the best.
- [Singing in Italian]
- Hey!
Tony's!
Of course.
The very place
for a very special occasion.
This way, Pige.
I have my own private entrance.
Wait here.
Just one minute. I'm a-comin'. I'm...
What's a-matter? Somebody's
a-makin' da April Fool with...
[barking]
Oh, hello, Butch.
Where you been so long?
Hey, Joe, look who's here.
Well, what do you know? It's Butch.
Hey, hey, hey!
Joe, bring some bones
for Butchy before he eat me up.
- [Chuckling]
- OK, Tony. OK.
Bones a-coming up.
[Barking]
Huh?
Ahh!
What's this?
Hey, Joe, look.
Butchy, he's got a new girlfriend.
Well, a son of a gun!
He's a got a cockerel Spanish a-girl.
Hey, she's a pretty sweet kiddo, Butch.
You take-a Tony's advice
and a-settle down with this-a one, eh?
"This a-one"?
This one. This... Oh!
Tony, you know.
He's a-not a-speaking
English a-pretty good.
[Chuckles, clears throat]
Now, first we fix-a the table.
- Here's your bones, Tony.
- OK, bones. Bones?
[Tony] What's the matter with you,
Joe? I break-a your face.
Tonight, Butch,
he gets the best in the house.
[Joe] OK, Tony, you're the boss.
Now, tell me, what's your pleasure?
A la carte? Dinner?
[Barking]
A-ha. OK.
Hey, Joe.
Butch-a, he says
he wants-a two spaghetti special.
Heavy on the meats-a ball.
Tony, dogs don't talk.
- He's a-talkin' to me!
- OK, he's a-talkin' to you.
You the boss.
Mamma mia. [Grumbling in Italian]
Now here you are.
The best spaghetti in town.
[Slurping]
# For this is the night
# It's a beautiful night
# And we call it
# Bella notte
# Look at the skies
# They have stars in their eyes
# On this lovely bella notte
# Side by side
# With your loved one
# You'll find enchantment here
# The night will weave its magic spell
# When the one you love is near
# For
[both] # This is the night
# And the heavens are right
# On this lovely
# Bella notte #
[chorus] # This is the night
# It's a beautiful night
# And we call it
# Bella notte
# Look at the skies
# They have stars in their eyes
# On this lovely
# Bella notte
# Side by side with your loved one
# You'll find enchantment here
# The night will weave its magic spell
# When the one you love is near
# For this is the night
# And the heavens are right
# On this lovely
# Bella notte #
[rooster crowing]
Oh! Oh, dear.
Is something wrong, Pige?
- It's morning.
- Yeah. [Stretches]
So it is.
I should have been home hours ago.
Why? Because you still believe in that,
"in the faithful old dog tray" routine?
Aw, come on, Pige.
Open up your eyes.
Open my eyes?
To what a dog's life can really be.
I'll show you what I mean.
Look down there.
Tell me what you see.
Well, I see nice homes
with yards and fences.
Exactly. Life on a leash.
Look again, Pige.
[Tramp] There's a great
big hunk of world down there
with no fence around it.
Where two dogs can find
adventure and excitement.
And beyond those distant hills,
who knows what wonderful experiences?
And it's all ours for the taking, Pige.
It's all ours.
It sounds wonderful.
But?
But who'd watch over the baby?
You win.
Come on.
I'll take you home.
[Man whistling]
[humming]
# It's a beautiful night
# And they call it...
[chickens clucking]
[Tramp] Not to change
the subject, but...
Ever chased chickens?
I should say not!
Oh, ho! Then you've never lived.
- But we shouldn't.
- I know.
That's what makes it fun.
Aw, come on, kid.
Start building some memories.
But we... We won't hurt the chickens?
Hurt 'em? No!
[Tramp] We'll just stir 'em up a bit.
[Tramp] Just look
at those fat, lazy biddies.
Why, they should've
been up hours ago.
[Barking]
[squawking]
Some fun, eh, kid?
[Man] Hey, what's going on in there?
- [Gunshot]
- What's that?
That's the signal to get going. Come on.
[Gunshots]
- This is living, eh, kid?
- Is it?
Come on, Pige. Follow me.
You know, there's a little bit
of bird dog in all of us, eh, Pige?
Pige? Pige?
Pige? Where are you, Pige?
Pige?
[Echoing] Pigeon?
Oh, Pige!
[Dogs howling and barking]
[howling mournful tune]
[howling continues]
[whimpering]
[dog] Hey.
Hey, Dachsie, how we coming?
Just one more chorus and we're out.
OK. On a downbeat.
- One, two...
- [clanking]
[man] Put her in number four, Bill,
- while I check her license.
- OK.
[Bill] All right, baby, in here.
Well, look yous guys,
Miss Park Avenue herself.
[Chuckles] Blimey.
A regular bloomin' debutante.
Yeah. And pipe the
crown jewel she's wearin'.
Hey, whatcha in for, sweetheart?
Putting fleas on the butler?
All right, you guys. Lay off, will you?
Aw, what's the matter, Peg?
We was only havin'
a bit of sport, we was.
Can't you see the poor kid's
scared enough already?
Pay no attention,
my little ochi chernye.
That's right, dearie.
They don't mean no real harm.
It's like Gorky says
in Lower Depths, quote:
"Miserable being must find
more miserable being.
Then he's happy."
- Unquote.
- Boris is a philosopher.
Besides, little bublichki,
wearing license here,
that is like waving,
you should excuse the expression,
red flag in front of bull.
My license?
But what's wrong with it?
There ain't nothin' wrong
with it, dearie.
Confidential, there's not one dog here
who would not give left hind leg
for such a knick-knack.
That's your passport to freedom, honey.
- Without it...
- [clanking]
Hey. Hey, yous guys, look.
Poor Nutsy is takin' the long walk.
[Lady] Where is he taking him?
[Dog] Through the one-way door, sister.
[Door locking]
You... You mean he's...
Oh, well.
A short life and a merry one.
Yeah, that's what
the Tramp always says.
- The Tramp?
- Now there's a bloke
what never gets caught.
He's given the slip
to every dogcatcher in this burg.
You won't believe this, dearie,
but no matter how tight a jam he's in,
that Tramp always
finds some way out.
I can quite easily believe that.
Ah, but remember, my friends,
even Tramp has his Achilles heel.
Pardon me, amigo.
What is this "chili heel"?
Achilles heel, Pedro.
This is meaning his, uh, weaknesses.
Oh. Oh, the dames. Yeah.
[Chuckles] He has an eye
for a well-turned paw, he has.
Let's see. There's been Lulu.
[Dog] Yeah, and Trixie.
[Dachsie] Und Fifi.
And my sister,
Rosita Chiquita Juanita Chihuahua.
I think.
What a dog.
Yeah. Tell us about it, Peg.
What a dog!
Peg used to be in
the Dog and Pony Follies.
# He's a tramp
# But they love him
# Breaks a new heart every day
# He's a tramp
# They adore him
# And I only hope he'll stay that way
- # He's a tramp
- [howling]
# He's a scoundrel
- # He's a rounder
- [whimpering]
# He's a cad
# He's a tramp
# But I love him
# Yes, even I have got it pretty bad
- [howling]
- # You can never tell
# When he'll show up
# He gives you plenty of trouble
# I guess he's just a no-count pup
# But I wish that he were double
- # He's a tramp
- # Bum-bum-bum-ruff
- # He's a rover
# And there's nothin' more to say
# Bum-bum-bum-ruff
# [Peg] If he's a tramp
# He's a good one
# And I wish that
I could travel his way
# Wish that I could travel his way
# Wish that I could travel his way #
Yeah.
But he never takes them serious.
Ah, but someday
he is meeting someone different.
[Boris] Some delicate, fragile creature
who's giving him a wish
to shelter and protect.
Like Miss Park Avenue
here, eh, matey?
Mm-hmm. Could be.
- But when he does...
- Yeah. I'm way ahead of ya.
Under the spell of true love...
The poor chump grows careless...
The Cossacks are picking him up...
And it's curtains for the Tramp.
[Door opens]
[man] It's the little cocker, Bill.
- In number four.
- [Bill] OK.
All right, baby.
They've come to take you home.
You're too nice a girl
to be in this place.
Courage, man.
Courage!
But, uh...
I've never even considered matrimony.
Nor I.
But no matter which of us she accepts,
we'll always be the best of friends.
Now remember,
not a word about her
unfortunate experience.
- We don't want to hurt her feelings.
- Uh, yeah. Yeah.
Lassie.
Miss Lady, ma'am.
Please, I don't want to see anybody.
Now, now, lassie.
Don't feel that way about it.
Of course not, Miss Lady.
Why, some of the finest people
I ever tracked down
- were jailbirds.
- [Jock] Quiet!
You great loony!
Uh, please, lassie.
We've come with a proposition.
[Jock] For helpin' ya.
Help me? What do you mean?
Well, now...
You see, lassie...
Neither of us
is as young as we used to be.
But we're still in the prime of life.
Aye.
And we've both got
very comfortable homes.
[Trusty] That's right. Where we know
you'll be welcome
and appreciated, Miss Lady.
So... So, to come
directly to the point...
[clears throat]
If you could, uh,
find it possible to, uh...
To, uh...
You're both very kind,
and I do appreciate it.
- But...
- [Tramp] Oh, Pigeon.
Oh, Pi...
[Tramp] Oh! Oh, hi, boys.
Anything new in the kennel club set?
[Chuckling]
A little something
I picked up for you, Pige.
Hmpf.
Looks like I'm the one
that's in the doghouse.
If this person
is annoying you, Miss Lady...
We'll gladly throw the rascal out.
That won't be necessary. Thank you.
Very well, ma'am.
You... You...
...mongrel!
Aw, come on, Pige.
- It wasn't my fault.
- Hmpf.
I thought you were
right behind me. Honest.
When I heard they'd
taken you to the pound...
Don't even mention that horrible place.
[Sobbing] I was so embarrassed and...
- And frightened.
- Oh, now, now.
Who could ever harm
a cute little trick like you?
[Lady] Trick? Trick!
- That reminds me, who is Trixie?
- Trixie?
And Lulu and Fifi
and Rosita Chiquita wh...
- Whatever her name is.
- Chiquita...
Oh! Yes! Well, I-I...
As far as I'm concerned,
you needn't worry about your old heel.
[Stammering] My heel?
I don't need you
to shelter and protect me.
- But...
- If you grow careless, don't blame me.
I don't care if the Cossacks
do pick you up! Goodbye.
- And take this with you.
- [Thunderclap]
[Lady sobbing]
[board banging]
[thunderclap]
[growling]
[barking]
Stop that.
Hush, now, hush.
[Barking continues]
[Sarah] Stop that racket!
[Tramp] What's wrong?
- A rat!
- Where?
Upstairs, in the baby's room!
- How do I get in?
- The little door.
On the porch.
[Thunderclap]
[sniffing]
[growling]
[snarling]
[barking]
[squeaking]
[baby crying]
- [crashing]
- [squeaking]
[crying continues]
[gasping] Merciful heavens!
Oh! Oh, you poor little darling.
No, no, no.
Thank goodness you're not hurt.
You... You vicious brutes. Back!
Get back!
Go on! Get back!
The pound. The pound, that's it.
I'll call the pound.
[Barking]
Come here, you. Come here!
Come on, come on.
Come along.
I'll call them this minute.
[Whimpering]
I won't sleep
with that brute in the house.
[Barking]
[telephone ringing]
[Sarah] Hello? Hello!
[Whimpering]
I don't care if you
are alone there, young man.
I insist you pick him up immediately.
[Bell rings]
[Jim] Darling, look.
[Sarah] If you want my advice
you'll destroy that animal at once.
[Man] Don't worry, ma'am.
We've been after this one for months.
We'll take care of him.
- [Darling] What do you suppose?
- [Jim] What's going on here?
[Man] Just picking up a stray, mister.
Come on, giddup. [Whip cracks]
Caught him attacking a baby.
- [Jim] Heavens.
- My baby.
[Both] Aunt Sarah!
[Darling] Aunt Sarah!
I was certain he was no good
the moment I first laid eyes on him.
Yeah, but, uh...
I never thought
he'd do a thing like that.
[Sarah] I got there in time.
There they were...
[Jim] I'm sure there must be
some mistake. Lady wouldn't...
[barking]
[Sarah] Watch out! That dog's loose.
Keep her away.
[Jim] Nonsense.
She's trying to tell us something.
- [Barking continues]
- What is it, old girl?
What are you try...
Darling, Aunt Sarah, come here.
- [Darling] What is it?
- [Sarah gasps]
[Sarah] Aaah! A rat!
A rat?
We should've known.
I misjudged him.
Badly.
Come on. We got to stop that wagon.
But man, we don't know
which way they've gone.
We'll track 'em down.
And then?
We'll hold 'em.
Hold 'em at bay.
Now what?
The scent. Follow the scent.
Ach. Let's face it, man.
We both know you've
lost your sense of smell.
[Howling]
[howling continues]
[howling]
- [man] Get out of here.
- [Barking]
Go on, get away.
[Barking]
Easy. Go on, get away.
Watch it now. Watch it!
[Horn honking]
[crowd murmuring]
Hi, Pige.
[Whimpering]
[howling]
[Jim] All right,
everybody, watch the birdy.
[Growling]
- [squeaking]
- Steady, now.
[Jim] Hold it.
[Coughing]
I guess I used a little too much.
Uh-oh.
Darling, visitors.
Visitors?
[Darling] Why, it's Jock.
[Jim] And good old Trusty.
Careful now, man.
Careful. It's a wee bit slippery.
[Trusty] Yes, it is.
[Jim] All right, boy. We'll let 'em in.
No, no, not you, young man.
You're going to take a nap.
Well, Merry Christmas.
Come in, come in.
If you'll just step into the parlor
[Jim] I'll see about refreshments.
Oh, darling, where did you
put the dog biscuits?
The box Aunt Sarah sent for Christmas.
[Darling] In the kitchen, Jim dear.
Oh, no doubt about it.
They've got their mother's eyes.
Aye. [Chuckles]
But there's a bit
of their father in them too.
Well, and I see you finally
acquired a collar.
Oh. Yes.
Complete with license.
Oh, yeah, a new collar.
Caught the scent the moment
I came in the house.
[Trusty] Trusty, I says,
Trusty, somebody's wearing a new collar.
'Course, my sense of smell
is very highly developed.
Runs in the family, you know.
There'll be no livin'
with him from now on.
As my grandpappy,
Old Reliable, used to say...
I don't recollect if I've ever
mentioned Old Reliable before.
[All] No, you haven't, Uncle Trusty.
Huh?
I haven't?
Well, um...
As Old Reliable used to say...
He'd say, uh...
He'd say... uh...
Uh...
Hmm.
Doggone.
You know,
I clean forgot what
it was he used to say.
[Chuckling]
[chorus] # Peace, my children
# Of good will
# Peace, my children
# Peace
# Be
# Still #
[# Bella Notte]