(MAN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
OMAR: Hey, look! Over there!
Wow!
LIAN: Their ship is so big.
OMAR:
Wish ours was that fancy.
I'd be so happy
if ours was that fancy.
- 'Cause then...
- MARINER: Why is that?
Because it looks better?
This boat has seen us
through many a storm.
It may not look like much,
but it has something
theirs never will.
What? Wood rot and rats?
(OMAR AND LIAN GIGGLE)
WOMAN: Are the children
learning something, dear?
It is unclear.
All right, (CLAPS HANDS)
sit, children.
I think it's time
that I told you the story...
of Aladdin, the princess,
and the lamp.
What's so special
about a lamp?
Oh, this is a magic lamp.
Maybe if you sing.
It's better when you sing.
No, no. No singing.
It's been a long day.
(SINGING) Oh, imagine a land
It's a faraway place
Where the caravan Camels roam
Where you wander among
Ev'ry culture and tongue
It's chaotic
But hey, it's home
When the wind's
From the east
And the sun's
From the west
And the sand
In the glass is right
Come on down, stop on by
Hop a carpet and fly
To another Arabian night
(MARINER CHUCKLES)
(MIDDLE EASTERN MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
MAN: Hey! Psh!
MARINER: As you wind
Through the streets
And the fabled bazaars
With the cardamom-cluttered
Stalls
You can smell e'vry spice
While you haggle the price
Of the silks
And the satin shawls
Oh, the music that plays
As you move through a maze
In the haze
Of your pure delight
You are caught in a dance
You are lost in the trance
Of another Arabian night
Arabian nights
Like Arabian days
More often than not
Are hotter than hot
In a lot of good ways
Arabian nights
Like Arabian dreams
This mystical land
Of magic and sand
Is more than it seems
There's a road
That may lead you
To good or to greed
Through the power
Your wishing commands
Let the darkness unfold
Or find fortunes untold
Well, your destiny
Lies in your hands
LION'S HEAD:
Only one may enter here.
One whose worth
lies far within.
The diamond in the rough.
MARINER: Arabian nights
Like Arabian days
They seem to excite
Take off and take flight
To shock and amaze
LION'S HEAD: Seek thee out
the diamond in the rough.
MARINER: Arabian nights
'Neath Arabian moons
A fool off his guard
Could fall and fall hard
Out there on the dunes
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
What's your monkey's name?
- Abu.
- (ABU CHITTERING)
He's a lovely monkey.
Hmm. That's a lovely necklace.
So, where does Abu come from?
He, uh...
Oh!
I think this belongs to me.
Good day, ladies.
Okay.
Abu.
(MAN SHOUTING)
(CHITTERING)
(GRUNTS)
How'd we do, Abu?
- Good monkey.
- (CHITTERS)
Stop right there, Aladdin.
Whatever it is you stole
today, I don't want it.
Whoa, whoa.
I didn't steal anything.
It's a family heirloom
that's worth a lot.
I'll give you a bag of dates
for it, nothing more.
Zulla, we both know it's worth
at least three bags.
00:05:55,52