Charles, you have finally lost
your senses.
This venture is impossible.
For some. Gentlemen, the only
way to achieve the impossible...
is to believe it is possible.
That kind of thinking could
ruin you.
I'm willing to take that chance.
Imagine trading posts in Rangoon,
Bangkok, Jakarta...
The nightmare again?
I won't be long.
I'm falling down a dark hole...
then I see strange creatures.
What kind of creatures?
Well, there's a dodo bird...
a rabbit in a waistcoat, a
smiling cat.
I didn't know cats could smile.
Neither did I.
And there's a blue caterpillar.
Blue caterpillar.
Hmm.
Do you think I've gone round
the bend?
I'm afraid so. You're mad,
bonkers, off your head.
But I'll tell you a secret.
All the best people are.
It's only a dream, Alice.
Nothing can harm you there.
But if you get too frightened,
you can always wake up.
Like this.
Ow!
Must we go?
Doubt they'll notice if we
never arrive.
They will notice.
Where's your corset?
And no stockings.
I'm against them.
But you're not properly dressed.
Who's to say what is proper?
What if it was agreed that
"proper" was wearing...
a codfish on your head.
Would you wear it?
Alice.
To me, a corset is like a
codfish.
Please, not today.
Father would have laughed.
I'm sorry. I'm tired.
I didn't sleep well last night.
Did you have bad dreams again?
Only one.
It's always the same, ever
since I can remember.
Do you think that's normal?
Don't most people have
different dreams?
I don't know.
There.
You're beautiful.
Now, can you manage a smile?
At last. We thought you'd
never arrive.
Alice, Hamish is waiting
to dance with you. Go.
You do realize it's well
past 4:00.
Now everything will have to be
rushed through.
I am sorry.
Oh, never mind!
Forgive my wife.
She's been planning this affair
for over twenty years.
If only Charles were here...
My condolences.
I think of your husband often.
He was truly a man of vision.
I hope you don't think I've taken
advantage of your misfortunes.
Of course not. I'm pleased that
you purchased the company.
I was a fool for not investing
in his mad venture...
when I had the chance.
Charles thought so, too.
Hamish, do you ever tire
of quadrille?
On the contrary.
I find it invigorating.
Do I amuse you?
No.
I had a sudden vision of all
the ladies in trousers...
and the men wearing dresses.
I think you'll do best to keep
your visions to yourself.
When in doubt, remain silent.
Pardon us, sir. Miss Kingsleigh
is distracted today.
Where's your head?
I was wondering what it would
be like to fly.
Why would you spend your time...
thinking about such an
impossible thing?
Why wouldn't I?
My father said he sometimes
believed in six impossible things...
before breakfast.
Come along.
Alice, meet me under the gazebo
in precisely ten minutes.
We have a secret to tell you.
If you're telling me, then it's
not much of a secret.
Perhaps we shouldn't.
We decided we should.
If we tell her, she won't be
surprised.
Will you be surprised?
Not if you tell me.
But now you've brought it up,
you have to.
No, we don't.
In fact, we won't.
I wonder if your mother knows...
that you two swim naked in the
Havershims' pond.
You wouldn't.
Oh, but I would.
There's your mother, right now.
Hamish is going to ask for
your hand.
You've ruined the surprise!
I could strangle them!
Everyone went to so much effort
to keep the secret.
Does everyone know?
It's why they've all come.
This is your engagement party.
Hamish will ask you under the
gazebo. When you say yes...
But I don't know if I want to
marry Hamish.
Who, then?
You won't do better than a lord.
You'll soon be twenty, Alice.
That pretty face won't last
forever.
You don't want to end up like
Aunt Imogene.
And you don't want to be a
burden on Mother, do you?
No.
So, you'll marry Hamish...
you will be as happy as I am
with Lowell...
and your life will be perfect.
It's already decided.
Alice, dear.
I'll leave you to it.
Shall we take a leisurely stroll
through the garden...
just you and me?
Do you know what I've always
dreaded?
The decline of the aristocracy?
Ugly grandchildren.
But you're lovely.
You're bound to produce little...
Imbeciles!
The gardeners have planted
white roses...
when I specifically asked
for red.
You could always paint the
roses red.
What an odd thing to say.
You should know that my son has
extremely delicate digestion.
Did you see that?
See what?
It was a rabbit, I think.
Nasty things.
I do enjoy setting the dogs
on them.
If you serve Hamish the wrong
foods, he could get a blockage.
Did you see it that time?
See what?
The rabbit.
Don't shout.
Now, pay attention. Hamish said
you were easily distracted.
What was I saying?
Hamish has a blockage.
I couldn't be more interested,
but you'll have to excuse me.
Aunt Imogene.
I think I'm going mad. I keep
seeing a rabbit in a waistcoat.
I can't be bothered with your
fancy rabbit now.
I'm waiting for my fiance.
You have a fiance?
Hmm.
There!
Did you see it?
He's a prince.
But, alas, he cannot marry me
unless he renounces his throne.
It's tragic, isn't it?
Very.
Lowell?
Alice.
We were just...
Hattie's an old friend.
I can see you're very close.
Look, you won't mention this
to your sister, will you?
I don't know. I'm confused.
I need time to think.
Well, think about Margaret.
She'd never trust me again.
You don't want to ruin her
marriage, do you?
Me?
But I'm not the one who's
sneaking around behind her back.
There you are.
Alice Kingsleigh...
Hamish.
What is it?
You have a caterpillar on
your shoulder.
Ew.
Don't hurt it.
You'll want to wash that finger.
Alice Kingsleigh...
will you be my wife?
Well...
everyone expects me to...
and you're a lord.
My face won't last, and I don't
want to end up like...
But this is happening so
quickly. I...
I think I...
I need a moment.
Hello.
It's only a dream.
You'd think she would remember
all this from the first time.
You've brought the wrong Alice.
No, she's the right one.
I'm certain of it.
She's the wrong Alice.
Give her a chance.
Curiouser and curiouser.
I told you she's the right Alice.
I am not convinced.
How is that for gratitude?
I've been up there for weeks,
trailing one Alice after the next...
and I was almost eaten by other
animals.
Can you imagine?
They go about entirely unclothed,
and they do their shukm in public.
I had to avert my eyes.
Doesn't look anything like herself.
That's because she's the wrong
Alice.
If she was, she might be.
If she isn't, she ain't.
But if she were so, she would be.
But she isn't, nohow.
How can I be the wrong Alice
when this is my dream?
And who are you, if I might ask?
Oh, I'm Tweedledee, he's
Tweedledum.
Contrary-wise, I'm Tweedledum,
he's Tweedledee.
We should consult Absolem.
Exactly! Absolem will know
who she is.
I'll escort you.
Hey, it's not being your turn.
So unfair.
Hey, leave off!
Let go!
Are they always this way?
Family trait.
You can both escort her.
Who is this Absolem?
He's wise. He's absolute.
He's Absolem.
Who are you?
Absolem?
You're not Absolem, I'm Absolem.
The question is...
who are you?
Alice.
We shall see.
What do you mean by that?
I ought to know who I am.
Yes, you ought, stupid girl.
Unroll the Oraculum.
The Oraculum, being a calendrical
compendium of Underland.
It's a calendar.
Compendium.
It tells of each and every day
since the Beginning.
Today is Griblig Day, in the
time of the Red Queen.
Show her the Frabjous Day.
Mmm. Yeah, Frabjous being the
day you slay the Jabberwocky.
Sorry?
Slay a what?
Oh, yeah. That being you, there,
with the Vorpal sword.
No other swords can kill the
Jabberwocky, nohow.
If it ain't Vorpal, it ain't
dead.
That's not me!
I know!
Resolve this for us, Absolem.
Is she the right Alice?
Not hardly.
I told you.
Oh, dear.
I said so.
Contrary-wise, you said she
might be.
No, you said she would be if
she was.
Little impostor. Pretending to
be Alice. She should be ashamed.
I was so certain of you.
I'm sorry. I don't mean to be
the wrong Alice.
Wait, this is my dream.
I'm going to wake up now and
you'll all disappear.
That's odd. Pinching usually
does the trick.
I could stick you, if that
would help.
It might, actually. Thank you.
My pleasure.
Ow!
Bandersnatch!
Wait.
It's only a dream.
Nothing can hurt me.
What's she doing?
Can't hurt me... can't hurt me.
Run, you great lug!
This way, east to Queast.
No, south to Snud.
No. No, no.
This way.
Someone has stolen three of
my tarts!
Did you steal them?
No, Your Majesty.
Did you?
Did you steal them?
No, Your Majesty.
Did you steal my tarts?
Squimberry juice.
I was so hungry!
I didn't mean, to!
Off with his head!
My family!
Oh, please, please don't!
No! I have little ones to
look after!
Go to his house and collect
the little ones.
I love tadpoles on toast, almost
as much as I love caviar.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Drink!
Majesty?
Ilosovic Stayne, you knave,
where have you been lurking?
Majesty, I have found the
Oraculum.
That? Looks so ordinary for
an oracle.
Look here, on the Frabjous Day.
I'd know that tangled mess of
hair, anywhere.
Is it Alice?
I believe it is.
What's she doing with my
darling Jabberwocky?
She appears to be slaying it.
She killed my Jabber-baby-wocky?
Not yet, but it will happen
if we don't stop her.
Find Alice, Stayne.
Find her!
Find the scent of human girl
and earn your freedom.
For my wife and pups, as well?
Everyone will go home.
Dogs will believe anything.
It looks like you ran afoul of
something with wicked claws.
And I'm still dreaming.
What did that to you?
Banner, or Bander...
The Bandersnatch?
Well, I'd better have a look.
What are you doing?
It needs to be purified by someone
with evaporating skills...
or it will fester and putrefy.
I'd rather you didn't. I'll be
fine, as soon as I wake up.
At least let me bind it for you.
What do you call yourself?
Alice.
The Alice?
There's been some debate about
that.
I never get involved in politics.
You'd best be on your way.
What way? All I want to do is
wake up from this dream.
Fine.
Then I'll take you to the Hare
and the Hatter...
but that's the end of it.
Coming?
Watch what you're doing!
Hey, watch it!
Okay, okay.
All right.
It's you.
No, it's not. McTwisp brought
us the wrong Alice.
It's the wrong Alice!
It's absolutely Alice.
You're absolutely Alice.
I'd know you anywhere.
I'd know him anywhere.
Well, as you can see, we're
still having tea.
And it's all because I was
obliged to kill Time...
waiting for your return.
You're terribly late, you know.
Naughty.
Well, anyway, Time became quite
offended, and stopped altogether.
Not a tick ever since.
Cup.
Time can be funny in dreams.
Yes, yes, of course, but now
you're back, you see..
and we need to get on to the
Frabjous Day.
Frabjous Day!
I'm investigating things that
begin with the letter "M."
Have you any idea why a raven
is like a writing desk?
Downal wyth Bluddy Behg Hid!
What?
Down with the Bloody Big Head...
the Bloody Big Head being the
Red Queen.
Come, come. We simply must
commence with the slaying...
and such.
Therefore, it is high time
to forgive and forget...
or forget and forgive, whichever
comes first...
or is, in any case, most
convenient. I'm waiting.
Hey. It's tick-tick... it's
ticking again!
All this talk of blood and
slaying has put me off my tea.
Ah.
The entire world is falling
to ruin...
and poor Chessur's off his tea.
What happened that day was not
my fault.
Oh, dear.
You ran out on them to save
your own skin...
you guddler's scuttish pilgar
lickering...
shukm juggling sluking urpal.
Bar lom muck egg brimni!
Hatter!
Thank you.
Meow.
I'm fine.
What's wrong with you, Tarrant?
You used to be the life of the
party.
You used to do the best Futterwacken
in all of Witzend.
Futter what?
Futterwacken!
It's a dance.
On the Frabjous Day...
when the White Queen once again
wears the crown...
on that day, I shall Futterwacken
vigorously.
Oh, no.
Uh-oh.
The Knave.
Goodbye.
Hide her!
Drink this, quickly.
Quick!
Hide her!
Oh, dear.
Aye.
Mind your head.
Let me out!
Well...
if it's not my favorite trio...
of lunatics.
Would you like to join us?
You're all late for tea!
We're looking for the girl
called Alice.
Speaking of the Queen...
here is a little song we used
to sing in her honor.
Twinkle Twinkle little bat...
how I wonder where you're at.
Up a...
If you're hiding her, you'll
lose your heads.
Already lost them.
All together now!
Up above the world you fly...
like a tea tray in the sky.
Twinkle, twinkle, twinkle,
twinkle...
twinkle, twinkle, twinkle...
Oh!
Downal wyth Bluddy Behg Hid!
Would you like some cream?
A slice of Battenberg?
Follow the bloodhound.
Sugar?
Yes, please.
Oh, that's lovely.
You're all mad.
Thanks very much.
Pass the scones, please.
That one there.
Oh! Pardon.
Yes.
Yep, aye.
One moment.
There.
Yes.
Try this on, for size.
Oh.
I like it.
Good thing the bloodhound is
one of us, or you'd be...
What do they want with me?
Wait a minute, best take her
to the White Queen.
She'll be safe there.
Spoon...
Your carriage, milady.
The hat?
Of course.
Anyone can go by horse or rail,
but the absolute best way to travel
is by hat. Have I made a rhyme?
Oh, I love traveling by hat.
Mally. Just Alice, please.
Fairfarren, all.
What do you mean?
Wait. Gae!
'Twas brillig, and the slithy
toves did gyre...
and gimble in the wabe...
all mimsy were the borogoves,
and the mome raths outgrabe."
Sorry, what was that?
What was what?
"The Jabberwock, with eyes of
flame...
jaws that bite and claws that
catch!
Beware the Jabberwock, my son!
And the frumious Bandersnatch!
He took his Vorpal sword in hand.
The Vorpal blade went snicker-snack!
He left it dead, and with its
head...
he went galumphing back."
It's all about you, you know.
I'm not slaying anything.
I don't slay, so put it out of
your mind.
Mind.
Wait!
You can't leave me here!
You don't slay.
Do you have any idea what the
Red Queen has done?
You don't slay.
I couldn't, if I wanted to.
You're not the same as you
were before.
You were much more muchier.
You've lost your muchness.
My "muchness"?
In there.
Something's missing.
Tell me what Red Queen has done.
It's not a pretty story.
Tell me anyway.
It was here.
I was hatter to the White Queen
at the time.
Hightopp clan have always been
employed at court.
Hatter?
Hatter!
I'm fine.
Are you?
Did you hear that?
I'm certain I heard something.
What?
Oh!
Red Knights.
Go south, to Trotter's Bottom.
The White Queen's castle is
just beyond.
Hold on tightly.
Down with the bloody Red Queen!
You were supposed to lead them
away! The Hatter trusted you!
They have my wife and pups.
What's your name?
Bayard.
Sit!
Would your name be Alice, by
any chance?
Yes, but I'm not the one that
everyone's talking about.
The Hatter would not have given
himself up just for any Alice.
Where did they take him?
To the Red Queen's castle at
Salazen Grum.
We're going to rescue him.
That is not foretold.
I don't care. He wouldn't be
there, if it weren't for me.
The Frabjous Day is almost
upon us.
You must prepare to meet
the Jabberwocky.
From the moment I fell down
that rabbit hole...
I've been told what I must do
and who I must be.
I've been shrunk, stretched...
scratched and stuffed into
a teapot.
I've been accused of being
Alice and of not being Alice...
but this is my dream.
I will decide where it goes
from here.
If you diverge from the path...
I make the path.
Take me to Salazen Grum, Bayard,
and don't forget the hat.
There's only one way across.
Lost my muchness, have I?
Bayard!
The hat!
Your Majesty.
So sorry.
Splendid shot!
Where's my ball?
Page!
Yes, Your Majesty.
I want to help you.
Well, if it isn't the
wrong Alice.
What brings you here?
Mmm?
I've come to rescue the Hatter.
You're not rescuing anyone
being the size of a gerbil.
Well, do you have any more of that
cake that made me grow, before?
Upelkuchen?
Actually, I might have some left.
Not all of it!
Oh, no! Stop! No, no, no, don't.
Don't do that!
Page!
Oh, dear.
And what is this?
It... it's a "who," Majesty.
This is, um...
Um?
From Umbradge.
What happened to your clothes?
I outgrew them. I've been
growing an awful lot, lately.
I tower over everyone in Umbradge.
They laugh at me.
So I've come to you, hoping you
might understand what it's like.
My dear girl...
anyone with a head that large,
is welcome in my court.
Someone find her some clothes!
Use the curtains if you must,
but clothe this, enormous girl.
I need a pig here!
I love a warm pig belly for
my aching feet.
Would you like one, Um?
No, thank you.
Sit!
Go away.
Where are my fat boys?
You must meet them.
Fat boys!
Oh! There they are.
Aren't they adorable?
They have the oddest way of
speaking.
Speak, boys.
Amuse us.
Go on.
No.
Speak!
Is that being...
No, no, it isn't. Not a bit. No.
Contrary-wise, I believe
it's so.
No, it ain't so, nohow!
I love my fat boys.
Now, get out.
He did pinch me.
And who is this lovely creature?
Um, my new favorite.
Well, does she have a name?
Um.
I believe your name has slipped
the Queen's mind.
Her name is Um, idiot!
From Umbradge.
Any luck with the prisoner?
He's stubborn.
You're too soft.
Bring him!
We know Alice has returned
to Underland.
Do you know where she is?
I've been considering things
that begin with the letter "M."
Moron... mutiny...
murder... mmmalice.
We're looking for an "A" word, now.
Where is Alice?
Who, that wee little boy?
I wouldn't know.
What if I take off your head?
Will you know then?
Stop that.
What a regrettably large head
you have.
I should very much like to
hat it.
Hat it?
Yes.
I used to hat the White Queen,
you know.
Wasn't very much to work with,
poor dear.
Her head is so small.
It's tiny.
It's a pimple of a head.
But this...
What I could do with this
monument...
this orb...
Nay, this magnificently heroic
globe.
What could you do?
Unbind him, Stayne.
How can he work if his hands
are bound?
Well, then, shall it be a bonnet,
or a boater?
Or something for the boudoir?
Cloche, dunce hat, death cap...
coif, snood, barboosh, pugree,
yarmulkecockle hat...
porkpie, tam o'shanter, billycock,
bicorne, tricorne, bandeau...
bongrace, fan-tail, night cap,
Garibaldi, fez...
Hatter!
Fez?
Leave us.
The trees seem sad.
Have you been speaking with them?
Yes, Your Majesty.
Perhaps a bit more kindly.
Would you all excuse me for
a moment? Thank you.
What news, Bayard?
Alice has returned to Underland.
Where is she now?
In Salazen Grum.
Forgive me. I allowed her to
divert from her destined path.
No, no, no, no.
But that is exactly where she
will find the Vorpal sword.
We have our champion.
Rest now. You've done well.
Have you seen a hat around here?
You must find Alice, Stayne.
Without the Jabberwocky...
my sister's followers will
surely rise against me.
Ugly little sister. Why do
they adore her, and not me?
I cannot fathom it.
You are far superior, in all
ways.
I know.
But Mirana can make anyone fall
in love with her.
Men, women...
even the furniture.
Even the King?
I had to do it.
He would have left me.
Majesty...
is it not better to be feared,
than loved?
Not certain anymore.
Oh, let her have the rabble.
I don't need them.
I have you.
They're wonderful.
You must let me try one on.
It is good to be working
at my trade again.
It's just a pity you have to
make them for her.
What is the hatter with me?
Hatter?
Hatter.
Have you any idea why a raven
is like a writing desk?
I'm frightened, Alice.
I don't like it in here.
It's terribly crowded.
Have I gone mad?
I'm afraid so.
You're entirely bonkers.
But I'll tell you a secret.
All the best people are.
Here.
That's better.
You look yourself again.
Hat man!
Where are my hats?
I'm not a patient monarch!
I'm told she keeps the Vorpal
sword hidden in the castle.
The rabbit will help you.
Find it, Alice.
Take it to the White Queen.
We'll go to the White Queen
together.
Why is it you're always too
small, or too tall?
Tweedles.
Alice.
How do you do, again?
Where's the rabbit?
How is it you're being so
great big?
She ain't great big,
this is how she normal is.
I'm certain she's smaller
when we met.
No, she drank the pishsalver to
get through the door, recall it?
Oh, yeah.
Where's the rabbit?
Over theres.
What are you doing here?
I'm rescuing the Hatter.
He told me that the Vorpal
sword is hidden in the castle.
Help me find it.
I don't take orders from big,
clumsy, galumphing...
Shoo!
What is it, McTwisp?
I know where the sword is.
The sword's hidden inside.
Be careful, Alice.
I know that smell.
I'm not going in there.
Look what that thing did to
my arm.
Dear, oh, dear.
Why haven't you mentioned this?
It wasn't this bad before.
Hatter?
Where are you?
Mallymkun.
Do you still have the
Bandersnatch eye?
Right here.
I need it.
Come and get it.
Hey!
Give it back!
I like you, Um.
I like largeness.
Get away from me.
I have your eye.
No.
Hmm.
You look stunning in that hat.
Yes.
Next.
Your Majesty has never looked
better.
Hmm.
Another.
Oh!
I don't wish to alarm you...
but it smells as though you might
have dropped something.
Never mind him, he's mad.
Come along.
Stayne!
I suppose this makes us even now.
Um forced herself on me.
I told her my heart belongs to
you...
but she's obsessed with me.
Off with her head!
Stand back, Mallymkun.
How's this for muchness?
No, no! It mustn't be used
for anything...
Arrest that girl for unlawful
seduction!
Hatter!
Take it to the White Queen.
I'm not leaving without you.
Go!
Run, Alice!
Alice?
Run!
Seize her.
Alice.
Of course.
Why didn't I see it?
Well, it has been a long time...
and you were such a little tyke,
then.
Give me the sword.
Stay back.
The Queen will be so pleased.
She will take great pleasure
in taking off your head.
Oh, Alice!
Bayard! To Marmoreal.
Majesty, Alice has escaped...
on the Bandersnatch...
with the Vorpal sword.
How could you let this happen?
I may have underestimated her,
but we have her conspirators...
the Hatter and a dormouse.
Off with their heads!
Welcome to Marmoreal.
I believe this belongs to you.
Mmm.
The Vorpal sword is home again.
The armor is complete.
Now all we need is a champion.
You're a little taller than
I thought you'd be.
Blame it on too much upelkuchen.
Oh.
Come with me.
Is the March Hare here?
You're late for your soup, you
wee besom.
You're late for your soup.
Could use some salt.
Come here, you!
Give me that here.
Choppy, chop, chop, chop.
Leek and potato. Yes.
That would be...
Pishsalver.
Let me think.
A pinch of worm fat...
urine of the horsefly...
buttered fingers.
My sister preferred to study
Dominion Over Living Things.
Tell me, how does she seem
to you?
Perfectly horrid.
And her head?
Bulbous.
I think she may have some kind
of growth, in there...
something pressing on her brain.
Three coins from a dead man's
pocket...
two teaspoons of wishful thinking.
You can't imagine the things
that go on in that place.
Oh, yes, I can.
But when a champion steps forth
to slay the Jabberwocky...
the people will rise against her.
That should do it.
Blow.
Feel better?
Much, thank you.
There's someone here who would
like to speak with you.
Absolem?
Who are you?
I thought we'd settled this.
I'm Alice, but not that one.
How do you know?
You said so yourself.
I said you were not hardly
Alice...
but you're much more her, now.
In fact, you're almost Alice.
Even so,
I couldn't slay the Jabberwocky
if my life depended on it.
It will.
So, I suggest you keep the
Vorpal sword on hand...
when the Frabjous Day arrives.
You seem so real.
Sometimes I forget that this
is all a dream.
Will you stop doing that?
I've always admired that hat.
Hello, Chess.
Since you won't be needing it
anymore...
would you consider bequeathing
it to me?
How dare you?
It is a formal execution.
I would like to look my best,
you know.
It is a pity about all this.
I was looking forward to seeing
you, Futterwacken.
I was rather good at it, was
I not?
I really do love that hat.
I would wear it to all the
finest occasions.
I love a morning execution,
don't you?
Yes, Your Majesty.
I'd like to keep it on.
Suit yourself.
As long as I can get
at your neck.
I'm right behind you.
Off with his head!
I can't watch.
Good morning, everyone.
Chess, you dog.
Madam...
you are being heinously
bamboozled...
by these lickspittle toadies
you surround yourselves with.
What is that?
I'm not the only one, Majesty.
Look!
A counterfeit nose.
You should be ashamed.
Me? What about that big belly
you're so proud of?
Liars!
Cheats!
Falsifiers!
Off with their heads!
The abused and enslaved in
the Red Queen's court...
all of you stand up and fight!
Rise up against the bloody
Red Queen.
Downal wyth Bluddy Behg Hid!
Release the Jubjub Bird!
You're right, Stayne...
it is far better to be feared,
than loved.
Come, boys, quickly, quickly!
Come on!
Hatter!
Come on, Mally, quickly.
Come on, come on.
Prepare the Jabberwocky
for battle.
We're going to visit my little
sister.
I had hoped to have a champion,
by now.
Why don't you slay the
Jabberwocky yourself?
You must have the power.
It is against my vows to harm
any living creature.
We have company.
Have a look, Bayard.
Bielle.
I'm so happy to see you.
I thought they were going to...
So did I.
But they didn't, and now here
I am, still in one piece.
And I'm rather glad about that
now that I'm seeing you again.
I would have regretted not
seeing you again...
especially now that you're you,
and the proper size.
And it's a good size.
It's a great size.
It's a right proper Alice size!
Hatter?
Size... Fez... I'm fine.
Where's your hat?
Mmm.
Cheshire.
How's the arm, love?
All healed.
Goodbye, sweet hat.
Have you any idea why a raven
is like a writing desk?
Let me think about it.
You know what tomorrow is,
don't you?
Frabjous Day.
How could I forget?
Wish I'd wake up.
Still believe this is a dream,
do you?
Of course.
This has all come from my
own mind.
Which would mean that I'm
not real.
Afraid so. You're just a figment
of my imagination.
I would dream up someone who's
half-mad.
Yes, yes. But you would have
to be half-mad to dream me up.
I must be, then.
I'll miss you when I wake up.
Who will step forth to be champion
for the White Queen?
That would be I.
You have very poor evaporating
skills. I should be the one.
I'll do it.
No, me.
No other slayer, nohow.
If it ain't Alice, it ain't dead.
Alice, you cannot live your
life to please others.
The choice must be yours...
because when you step out to
face that creature...
you will step out alone.
Nothing was ever accomplished
with tears.
Absolem?
Why are you upside down?
I've come to the end of this
life.
You're going to die?
Transform.
Don't go. I need your help.
I don't know what to do.
I can't help you, if you don't
even know who you are...
stupid girl.
I'm not stupid!
My name is Alice.
I live in London.
I have a mother named Helen,
and a sister named Margaret.
My father was Charles Kingsleigh.
He had a vision that stretched
halfway around the world...
and nothing ever stopped him.
I'm his daughter.
I'm Alice Kingsleigh.
Alice, at last.
You were just as dim-witted
the first time you were here.
You called it "Wonderland,"
as I recall.
Wonderland.
What do you call yourself?
Alice.
The Alice?
Then I'll take you to the Hare
and the Hatter...
but that's the end of it.
She's the right one.
I'm certain of it.
Ah, Thackery, not at the table,
please.
Have some tea.
You're not Absolem.
I'm Absolem, stupid girl.
What is this?
I'm Tweedledee, he's Tweedledum.
Contrary-wise, I'm Tweedledum,
he's Tweedledee.
You'd think she would remember
all this from the first time.
Curiouser and curiouser.
It wasn't a dream at all, it
was a memory.
This place is real, and so are
you and so is the Hatter.
And the Jabberwocky.
Remember, the Vorpal sword
knows what it wants.
All you have to do is hold
on to it.
Fairfarren, Alice. Perhaps I
will see you in another life.
Hello, Iracebeth.
Hello, Mirana.
On this, the Frabjous Day,
the Queens Red and White...
shall send forth their champions
to do battle on their behalf.
Oh, Racie.
We don't have to fight.
I know what you're doing.
You think you can blink those
pretty little eyes...
and I'll melt, just like Mummy
and Daddy did.
Please.
No! It is my crown!
I am the eldest!
Jabberwocky!
This is impossible.
Only if you believe it is.
Sometimes I believe as many as six
impossible things before breakfast.
That is an excellent practice.
However, just at the moment...
you really might want to focus
on the Jabberwocky.
Where's your champion, Sister?
Here.
Hello, Um.
Six impossible things.
Count them, Alice.
One, there's a potion that can
make you shrink.
Two, and a cake that can make
you grow.
So, my old foe...
we meet on the battlefield,
once again.
We've never met.
Not you, insignificant bearer.
My ancient enemy, the Vorpal one.
That's enough chatter.
Three, animals can talk.
Four, Alice...
cats can disappear.
Five...
there's a place called Wonderland.
Six...
I can slay the Jabberwocky.
The Hatter's interfering!
Off with his head!
Off with your head!
Kill her!
We follow you no more, Bloody
Big Head.
How dare you?
Off with his head!
Iracebeth of Crims, your crimes
against Underland are worthy...
of death.
However, that is against
my vows...
therefore, you are banished
to the Outlands.
No one is to show you any kindness,
or ever speak a word to you.
You will not have a friend in
the world.
Majesty, I hope you bear me
no ill will.
Only this one, Ilosovic Stayne...
you are to join Iracebeth
in banishment...
from this day, until the end
of Underland.
At least we have each other.
Majesty, please! Kill me!
Please!
But I do not owe you a kindness.
Take off my head!
He tried to kill me.
Majesty! Please! Please!
He tried to kill me!
I offer you my head!
Oh, the Frabjous Day!
Callou! Callay!
What is he doing?
Futterwacken.
Blood of the Jabberwocky. You
have our everlasting gratitude.
And for your efforts on our
behalf...
Will this take me home?
If that is what you choose.
You could stay.
What an idea.
A crazy, mad, wonderful idea.
But I can't.
There are questions I have to
answer, things I have to do.
Be back again before you know it.
You won't remember me.
Of course I will.
How could I forget?
Hatter, why is a raven like
a writing desk?
I haven't the slightest idea.
Fairfarren, Alice.
She left me standing there
without an answer.
A case of nerves, no doubt.
Alice.
Good Lord.
Are you all right?
What happened to you?
I fell down a hole and hit
my head.
I'm sorry, Hamish.
I can't marry you.
You're not the right man for me.
And there's that trouble with
your digestion.
I love you, Margaret, but this
is my life.
I'll decide what to do with it.
You're lucky to have my sister
for your wife, Lowell...
and you be good to her.
I'll be watching very closely.
There is no prince, Aunt Imogene.
You need to talk to someone
about these delusions.
I happen to love rabbits,
especially white ones.
Don't worry, Mother...
I'll find something useful to
do with my life.
You two remind me of some
funny boys I met in a dream.
You've left me out.
No, I haven't, sir.
You and I have business to
discuss.
Shall we speak in the study?
Oh.
And one more thing.
My father told me he planned
to expand his trade route...
to Sumatra and Borneo.
But I don't think he was looking
far enough.
Why not go all the way to China?
It's vast, the culture is rich...
and we have a foothold in Hong
Kong.
To be the first to trade with
China, can you imagine it?
You know, if anybody else had
said that to me...
I'd say, "You've lost your
senses".
But I've seen that look, before.
Well, as you're not going to be
my daughter-in-law...
perhaps you'd consider becoming
an apprentice with the company.
Hello, Absolem.