[# Those Dancing Days: "I'll Be Yours"]
[girl] High school.
It happens to everyone.
And for four years,
it has a way of dividing us.
Athletes, overachievers,
drama queens, misfits, jokers...
But then, just before it ends,
when we're almost out the door...
...one night has a way
of bringing us together.
Prom.
[girl] It's the one night
when nobody cares
who wore the varsity jacket
and who got cut from the team.
It's the night when
you might find yourself
singing at the top of your lungs with
people you've never even spoken to.
The night when that cute guy
from your math class
might finally make his move.
Prom's our night,
and each of us wants it
to be unforgettable.
That's why I've been working
all semester to make it perfect.
For me, and for all the seniors
at Brookside High.
[girl 2] Hey, Nova.
[Nova] We were three weeks away
and everything was going as planned.
Well, almost everything.
Has he asked you yet?
[chuckles] It's 8:00 a.m.
He will! [laughs]
You guys are perfect together.
You're in all the same AP
classes, swim team co-captains,
you've both been, like, class
everything since kindergarten.
- Trust me, it's going to happen.
- [sighs]
Has he asked you yet?
[whispers indistinctly]
Well, he will.
He's never once made a move.
- Well, he's Brandon. He's shy.
- Mm-hm.
Or, maybe he's just not interested.
Don't you want him to ask you?
[chuckles] Yes, I want him to ask me.
It's prom!
Here he comes.
[Brandon] Hey, Nova!
- It's happening.
- [girl] Bye.
Wow. Beautiful.
Brandon! Thanks.
[Brandon] Posters look great. Nice job.
Yeah.
I'm gonna do the cafeteria.
Oh.
You know, Rachel, I found that prom
dress you were talking about.
Thanks, Nova. We'll be there.
You know, you could go.
No, thank you.
Prom's like
the Olympics of high school.
You wait four years,
three people have a good time,
and everybody else gets to live
on with shattered dreams.
My stepbrother, folks.
Can you believe he's single?
Come on, Lloyd. Your fear of girls has
gone from cute to clinical.
It's just prom.
Ask somebody. And be creative.
This is your last chance to make anyone
remember you even went here.
Wow. Nova, that looks awesome.
Thanks. Make sure you and Tyler
aren't too late.
We crown prom king and queen
at 9:35. Just saying.
Hey! My queen!
[boy 1] Hey, Tyler.
- [girl] Hi, Tyler.
- [boy 2] What's up, man?
So, I saw the posters,
and I thought about you.
And about a party bus.
[boy 3] Oh, yeah!
Hey, Tyler, can we talk?
OK, so you can only listen
to one artist for the rest of your life,
- and Stick Hippo does not exist. Go.
- Oh, man.
No Stick Hippo, the
greatest band of all time?
Jack White. You get three
epic bands, and counting.
[scoffs] Lucas, you blow my mind
every day.
OK, next one. Grunge rock supergroup,
1990-96, no Dave Grohl. Go.
Oh, good one. OK, how 'bout, uh...
[girls laughing]
Look at them.
I want to go to prom.
Well, Megan Brooks went
when she was a sophomore.
So it can totally happen.
It's like they're in a trance.
Yeah.
- [girl] See you later.
- Bye.
- Lucas, you gotta ask her out.
- Dude, you're crazy.
She doesn't want to go out with me.
I've got nothing to offer.
No car, no cool parties, no prom.
Whoa, check it out.
Prom this year
is gonna be so much fun.
Oh, my gosh. I really want to go
with Dakota. That'd be amazing.
[overlapping chatter continues]
[school bell rings]
Hey, Rhoda,
I turned 18 last week.
You know what that means, right?
They can try you as an adult?
Rhoda! You break my heart.
It means we can
finally run away together.
You, me, the open road.
[scoffs]
So, what are you in for?
Let me guess.
Trouble at the model UN?
Prom poster crisis?
Wait, I know.
You're receiving an award
for most awards.
Actually, I'm in trouble this time.
Really?
They caught me riding around
school on my little moped
- because I think I'm such a rebel.
- It's not a moped.
It's a 1972 Norton Commando.
It's adorable.
Jesse Richter? My office, now.
Nova, I'll have those papers
for you by lunch.
- Richter, Richter, Richter.
- [clears throat]
Let's see.
"Jesse has cut last period
every Monday for four weeks."
- You know what this means?
- I'm consistent?
You do realize you're only
cheating yourself, right?
You know, I had a talk
with myself about that.
- [man] Mm-hm.
- Turns out I'm OK with it.
I don't have time for this.
Today it's cutting class. Last month
it's fighting in the cafeteria?
You don't care about anything.
And you and I both know...
...you're going nowhere.
The good news is,
the really good news,
in a month and a half,
that's not gonna be my problem
'cause I'm going on vacation,
and you are gonna disappear forever.
You wanna do that with
a diploma, that's up to you.
Six weeks, Richter. Six weeks.
Do you think you can handle that?
Yeah. I'll leave this place
in one piece for ya.
Because in September,
you're gonna be right back here.
Get to class.
What is this?
[exhales] An earring?
Very good.
Why was it in your car?
Wait, I know. I drove half the girls'
soccer team to Papa Gino's last week.
You did?
Yes, OK? Now stop acting crazy.
You know you're my girl.
And you're gonna be the prom queen,
up there looking beautiful.
What is it?
You need to ask me.
I know, OK? Don't worry.
I've got plans.
Here. For the soccer team.
[up-tempo music]
- [whistle blows]
- [boy] I got it! I got it!
- [chattering]
- [boy] Pick it up.
[whistle blowing]
[boy 2] Come on, you guys.
[girls chanting]
[Brandon] I got it. I got...
- OK.
- You guys got it?
- Yep. You guys all right?
- Yeah.
[Brandon] Feel like
I'm carrying all the weight.
[boy 3] Me too. I feel like you're
carrying all the weight.
[Brandon] Lower it.
- Careful of the stars.
- [Brandon] Let it down.
[boy 3] Hey, man, relax.
- OK.
- Are we... done?
- What?
- Well...
...that was the last
of our prom decorations.
But we still
have to figure out a floor plan,
come up with a schedule
of who's selling tickets,
get the voting system down
for prom king and queen, and...
But you know what?
I can totally do that stuff later.
So, you guys are... done.
[all cheer] Yay!
In three weeks, "Starry Night"
will be Brookside's best prom ever.
Our theme is "Starry Night"?
[snickers]
Uh... yeah.
Cool.
I can't thank you guys enough
for all your hard work,
but when those couples walk through
the door and see how perfect it is,
it's gonna be so worth it.
Uh, plus, you each get two
free tickets to prom. Ali.
Awesome. Thank you.
- Mei.
- Thank you.
- Rolo.
- Sweet!
- Brandon.
- Thank you.
So, Rolo, who are you
gonna take to prom?
My girlfriend. Athena.
- Athena?
- She's Greek.
Uh-huh. And where does she live?
- Canada.
- [laughs] Oh! So, she's Greek-Canadian?
There's a very vibrant
Greek culture in Canada.
Vibrant.
So, how did Justin take it when
you told him about New York?
I haven't exactly told him yet.
Mei, you have to tell him.
He thinks you're staying here
and going to Michigan with him.
You got into Parsons.
It's a huge deal.
[Mei] I know, but I haven't
decided if I'm going.
It'll be like breaking up
with him. How can I do that?
Hey, hey, hey!
Prom's looking good.
Guess I better find
a hot girl to go with.
Right.
- [Mei] What are you doing here?
- [Justin] Come with me.
Bye, guys.
[# Opus Orange featuring
Lauren Hillman: "Almost There"]
[Justin] Right here.
- What's going on?
- You'll see.
[chuckles]
[Justin] "P." It's for
the paralyzing crush I had
on the new girl in my math
class in the eighth grade.
Her name was Mei,
and she was awesome.
"R."
It's for the really long time it took me
to get up the nerve to ask her out.
"O" is for the only girl
I've ever called my girlfriend,
and the only one I ever want to.
And "M"...is for
University of Michigan, of course.
Because that's our
next chapter together.
But I'm getting ahead of myself,
because before graduation and college
and the rest of our lives together,
there's something that I need to ask.
[laughs] Yes! Yes!
Hey! Hey! Prom?
[girl] Yes! Yes!
[boy] Yes!
- Yes!
- Oh, yeah.
Darrell. Come on.
Get him. Let's go.
Come on. Don't...
Darrell.
Darrell!
[chattering]
Looks like it's just us.
Yeah.
Do you have a minute? I was...
I was hoping to talk to you alone.
Yeah. Sure. What do you
want to talk about?
Uh, it's about prom.
Oh.
We've been working on the prom
committee now for several months,
and, uh, since we're on the committee,
I think it's a good idea for us
to arrive a little early on prom night.
You know, make sure
everything's copacetic.
I suppose that makes sense.
So, driving-wise, we should go together.
You want to...
Carpool.
[girls cheering]
Oh, right.
Well, you know, people
get so carried away
with the whole prom date thing.
I say why not be practical
about it, you know?
Uh... Brandon, I...
Is that a yes?
I'd love to.
Oh. OK, then. Uh...
Here you go.
[stammers] Or do you
want me to hold on to it?
So it's a date.
[young boy] And Ethan got to be line
leader because it was his birthday.
But my birthday's in July,
which is totally unfair.
Totally.
Every summer birthday gets celebrated on
one day at the end of the school year.
And there are like six of us.
And two of them are girls.
And they made Mike S. line leader first
and his birthday
isn't even until August,
so I said... Mom!
- Hey!
- What are you doing home?
Well, the place was dead,
so Lou gave me the afternoon off.
- I actually get to see my kids.
- Cool!
You see what came in the mail?
Wanna try it on?
Nah. Since you're here,
I think I'll call work
and see if I can pick up
some extra hours.
Come on, sweetie.
Let's all take tonight off.
Who keeps opening this door?
There's nothing
but garbage down there.
[sighs]
[Nova] Dad, if Mom got the hang
of this, then you can, too.
- [Dad] Oh...
- [Nova] Here. Watch.
- Just click this, and... There we are.
- [Dad] Uh-huh.
Wow. [laughs]
- [laughs]
- Hold on.
What?
- You just have a little grease.
- Oh.
See? [clears throat]
It's paying off already.
Ah, boy. I don't know about this. Uh...
- It's super easy.
- Mm-hm.
Make sure I'm online. And then
choose me from the contacts menu.
And next fall, we can talk
whenever you want.
OK. How 'bout midnight?
Every night of the week.
[chuckles] I don't know
about that, Dad.
[laughs]
Georgetown on a scholarship, boy.
It's just like we always
talked about, huh?
You heading off
to achieve great things.
It's the heading off part I'm just...
...having a little trouble with.
That's all.
Dad.
[# A Sunny Day In Glasgow:
"100/0 Snowdays Forever"]
You deserve an awesome prom,
so... why wait?
Wow.
Tyler, this is beautiful.
Told you I had plans. And what is prom
without a romantic dinner?
You got Taco King.
Vegetarian burrito, extra guac.
[exhales] So...
...will you go with me?
To prom?
Yes.
[woman vocalizing]
Come on.
[muffled scream]
Thanks, Tyler.
[fire engine sirens]
[song ends]
[chattering]
Whoa.
It's like Apocalypse Prom.
Hey, there.
How you doing, Nova?
Nova, what do we do now?
[Rolo] Yeah. Is prom, like, canceled?
We could always postpone
till after graduation.
No.
I don't wanna tell
the entire senior class
to return their dresses,
cancel their dates.
- If we do that, then...
- The terrorists have won?
[sighs] People are counting on us.
Prom's three weeks away.
So we work before school.
After school.
I would, but I can't.
I'm starting my internship.
And I'm...
I'm in the spring musical.
Yeah, man. I mean, this was already
my hardest class this semester.
I'm tapped out. I got nothing left.
Brandon?
Nova. AP tests are coming.
I'm already behind.
We need to get these kids
back into class, OK?
There has to be
something we can do.
[Mei] Nova?
Mr. Dunnan, the prom decorations
are completely destroyed.
Nova, I know.
The prom committee
worked very, very hard.
Everything was in that shed.
There's no one left to help me.
Mr. Dunnan, what are we
gonna do? What are you...
- Bill.
- Sir.
- Principal Dunnan? Mr. Dunnan?
- [Dunnan] Richter!
Get that pile of junk
off of school grounds.
- You can't ride that back here.
- [Jesse] Oh, right. Sorry.
Wouldn't want any school
property to get damaged.
You think it's funny
when people's hard work gets destroyed?
It's just a bunch
of dumb prom decorations.
- [scoffs]
- Oh, wait. No. Prom's ruined.
The boys and girls of Brookside
have been robbed of their right
to stand around in a gym
and drink punch.
Put the flags at half mast.
I got a better idea. You're
gonna help her rebuild.
- What?
- What?!
Nova, you need help.
Richter, you clearly need
a way to stay out of trouble
for the next couple of weeks.
Him? Mr. Dunnan,
I really don't think he...
Little Miss Sunshine's right.
You should listen to her.
- [sighs]
- Oh, no. You're gonna do it.
Who knows?
You might even learn something
about hard work and dedication.
And if this prom isn't rebuilt to her
specifications, you won't graduate.
You can't do that! You can't
keep me from graduating.
You know what? I had a talk
with myself about that...
...turns out I'm OK with it.
[scoffs]
[# Stick Hippo: "Stick Hippo"]
[chattering]
Hey, guys.
- [Lucas] Hi, you.
- [girl chuckles]
- What's with the helmets?
- Uh, varsity made us wear them.
- It's... humiliating.
- I think it's cute.
Yeah? We could get you one.
Maybe it'll catch on.
[laughs] Well, you could get me pink.
It'd match my outfit.
That'd be pretty. And safe.
[laughs] Well, I need a serious cram
session for the elements test.
[Lucas] Yeah. Any time.
Just think of me as your lab partner.
- You are my lab partner.
- [chuckles]
- Good point.
- I'll see you guys later.
Are you OK?
[chuckles] Yeah. Fine. Helmet.
[laughs]
Your sister's right.
There are tons of girls out there
who'd be thrilled to go
to prom with you.
All you have to do is ask one of them.
Thank you, Oprah,
for that nugget of wisdom.
You can do it.
Just be... Lloyd.
That hasn't exactly worked out
for me, like, ever.
She's right. It's not that hard.
This coming from the guy who hasn't
asked anyone out since middle school.
You guys have been together forever.
Your whole lives are planned out.
Next year...
Dude, I just don't understand how your
sister convinced you to ask someone.
You've been ignoring my advice
for years. Right, Mei?
Lloyd, she's out there.
Now go find her.
[exhales]
[up-tempo music]
[girl 1] So do you think
you're gonna go to prom?
[girl 2] I don't know yet. It depends.
Do you know what? I really wanna go.
Only if he asks me, like...
Alice, you know he's gonna
ask you. So, it'll be OK.
- What is that?
- Oh, my God.
Who did this?
- I don't know.
- [crying] I mean,
what kind of sick twist would put creepy
serial killer letters
on a person's locker?
- It's OK.
- [crying] Oh, God!
- What did I do wrong?
- Oh.
- So?
- I was never here. You never saw me.
Lloyd? [scoffs]
- [chattering]
- [blows whistle]
[man] Come on, guys. Work it.
[grunts] Well, now you
have to ask her out.
- I don't know, dude.
- [scoffs] You're killing me here, man.
[grunts] Ah, there you go, fellas.
We totally had that.
Hey, Lucas.
You're looking good out there, bro.
- Really?
- He is?
You've got real varsity potential.
[chuckles] He does?
[clears throat] I gotta go.
Wow. Thanks, Tyler.
Hey, I'm having a team barbecue
on Thursday. You should swing by.
- Really?
- Yeah. Totally casual.
Bring a friend if you want.
Corey?
[Corey groans]
I was thinking more
like a girl, Lucas.
Oh. Right.
You know some of those,
don't you?
Yeah. Of course. Tons.
[laughs] All right. See you there, bro.
- Here you go.
- [grunts]
[# The Pains Of Being Pure At Heart:
"Heart In Your Heartbreak"]
Just some dumb prom decorations and
you're going to help her rebuild them.
Yeah. Sure he is. If he
ever bothered to show up.
Glad you could make it.
No place I'd rather be.
Great. You know what?
Why don't you move
that stuff from there...
...to over there.
Do you think
you can handle that?
- [Jesse exhales]
- [stumbles]
Ow.
Problem?
No. I was just taking
inventory of this...
...bucket.
- That would be one.
[grunts]
You want some help with that?
[exhales] Yeah. Sure.
Why don't you give it a long,
brooding stare until it carries
itself across the room.
[Nova grunts]
Wait. Nova, hold on a second.
I just wanna say one thing.
Lift from the legs.
He's a menace.
A rude, arrogant menace
who'd rather look down
on everyone else
than make any effort
of his own. And he was late.
I don't know if Dunnan is doing
this to punish him or me.
What's his name again?
- Is that Jesse Richter?
- Yeah.
That that punk that stocks
shelves down at the market?
[groans] I think he works there.
Well. Well, I used to
run with his dad, OK?
Apple doesn't fall
far from the tree.
Is there any chance Jesse
might actually help you?
Kitty, he's a punk, all right?
He's not gonna all of a sudden
turn into an upright citizen.
I didn't say that.
I'm just saying it seems like you could
use some help, Nova.
Three weeks isn't a lot of time.
Yeah, help, sure. But he's a...
- He's a walking misdemeanor.
- [Nova] Thank you, Dad.
[sarcastic] "I'm a tough guy.
I have long hair
and drive a motorcycle.
I can lift heavy things."
- Whoop-iddy-doo.
- [doorbell rings]
Be right back.
You should see this guy, Dad.
It's like he enjoys watching me suffer.
This kid gives you any more trouble,
you just come to me, OK?
- [Kitty] Nova, it's Brandon.
- [Brandon] Hey, Mrs. Prescott.
Brandon. Hey, invite him in.
I'II... I'll set another place.
Yeah.
- Brandon, what are you doing...
- I got into Princeton!
- Wow! Congratulations.
- [whispers] Yeah!
[Brandon] Thank you. That's not all.
I'm a finalist
for the dean's scholarship.
That's amazing.
The interview for the scholarship,
it's the same weekend as prom.
- Oh.
- I hate to leave you hanging.
No. I, uh, I...
I totally get it.
There's still some time for you
to find another date, right?
Yeah. Totally. I'll be fine.
- Fine.
- All right. Cool.
[chuckles] Yeah. Cool.
I just can't believe
he would do this to you.
- I mean, two weeks before.
- Yeah. He's a jerk.
- A loser.
- I hate him.
- I've always hated him.
- He's an idiot.
Guys, it's not that
big of a deal. Honest.
Besides, prom's not even close to being
ready. I still have a ton to do.
[Mei] But who are you gonna go with?
Well, lots of people
go to prom without dates.
No. You don't have
to do all this, Nova.
- Yeah.
- Just because Brandon bailed on me
doesn't mean I'm gonna bail
on the senior class.
- [bell rings]
- I'm fine. Now go.
Go.
[chatter in hallway]
[toilet flushes]
- Hey.
- Uh...
[up-tempo music]
[Lloyd] Oh, wait.
Uh...
Gah!
[pained exhale]
[Lucas] It's a varsity party
and Tyler invited me.
- [Corey] No way.
- No, really.
And he told me to bring a girl.
Wow. Tyler Barso's barbecue.
That's almost a "triumphant
Jimi Hendrix at Woodstock" moment.
- [Lucas] Really?
- Well...
No. That could be your
Hendrix moment.
- Hi.
- Hey, Simone.
But first, fly check.
Pit check. OK.
Now breathe on me.
- Wait, why?
- You wanna ask her out with butt mouth?
- I don't think so. Come on. Hit me.
- [exhales]
[inhales, exhales] I didn't
get anything. Hit me again.
- Dude.
- I just had a cough drop, all right?
My olfactory nerves are compromised.
Come on.
- [exhales]
- [inhales]
What are you guys doing?
- Uh... [stammers] Extra credit!
- Yeah. Yeah.
- I gotta go.
- He's... weird.
Yeah. [laughs]
So, um, I'm glad
you're here today.
I mean, I knew you'd be here.
This is our class.
Not that you never miss class
or anything.
I mean, you don't miss a lot of class.
You have excellent attendance
as far as I can tell.
[scoffs]
I try.
There's a lacrosse team barbecue
on Thursday
and I was wondering
if you wanted to go with me.
I mean, unless you have a lacrosse
issue, which some people do, sometimes.
- That sounds like fun.
- Really?
Yeah. I love barbecues.
[chuckles]
[mouthing] She loves barbecues.
- Oh. Cool.
- [both make guitar noises]
[makes explosion noises]
[clears throat]
[# Moon: "Time Stand"]
We start every day at three.
Dude, relax. It's 3:15.
[scoffs] I'm not a dude,
and I know what time it is. You're late.
All right, dude.
What's this supposed to be?
It's a celestial fountain.
Well, it's gonna leak
all over the "celestial" floor
unless you purge the line
and unclog the intake.
I know that.
- Um, hey, Rolo.
- Hey.
Can I see Athena's profile?
Oh, no. She doesn't have one.
Really? No profile?
Actually, she had to take her page down
'cause she got grounded.
Oh. What's she in for?
She was out clubbin' till late.
So Athena likes to get
up in the club, huh?
Yeah. Big time.
[Rolo] Sweet!
[up-tempo music]
Come on. Come on.
[horn blares]
Oh! No! No, no, no, no, no!
Stop, sir!
Stop, truck!
No, no! Jen.
Jen, you missed it!
There was a sign!
[pop music plays in car]
Ah, no! No!
Gah!
OK. [sighs] Come on, baby.
Stop, stop, stop! Stop!
And... it's leaking.
[sighs] Yes, it is. Happy?
- Amused.
- [Nova sighs]
You act all tough,
but I know you.
You're the guy who cried when the class
hamster died in third grade.
Yeah, well, Heady didn't
make me build a cosmic canopy.
You remember her name?
You just need a hamster
to love, don't you?
[chuckles]
[sighs] This is a disaster.
A hurricane's a disaster.
Smallpox. Locusts.
Those are disasters.
This is just a fountain.
And it's just prom.
Just prom?
Yeah. Lame DJ, balloons,
poofy dresses.
Not something to get
so worked up about.
I forgot. School functions
conflict with your "thinking that I'm
better than everyone" time.
Well, for the rest of us,
prom happens to be fun.
Not for the guys. You gotta buy dinner.
You gotta get the little flower thing.
Don't pretend
you don't know what it's called.
And then there's the tuxedo,
the ultimate symbol of conformity
that a bunch of other guys
have already sweated in.
Whereas you opt
for the long hair and black jacket.
The whole "motorcycle" thing.
The ultimate symbol of nonconformity.
At least I don't wear it posing
in front of some stupid backdrop.
- People keep those pictures forever.
- In a box in their attic.
A lot of people worked
really hard on prom.
And it all burned down.
[scoffs]
Look, I'm sorry.
Prom is obviously really
important to you.
I just don't get it.
All this for one night.
[scoffs] Yeah, you're right.
But... it's the last night,
and it's the last dance.
And for that one night, who we were
for four years of high school...
...it doesn't matter.
It's just all of us together
in this one perfect moment.
And I wanna be a part of that.
[door opens, closes]
[# Stick Hippo: "Stick Hippo"]
- [Lucas] It should be this next block.
- Thanks for driving, Corey.
Oh, yeah, sure thing.
I'm a driver. I can drive.
As long as it's during daylight hours
and with adult supervision.
Now, slow down.
What is that sound? I could swear
it's my mom nagging me, but no,
that's impossible since she promised
to be quiet during this car ride.
- Use your signal.
- [whines] Mom.
- Aren't you coming, Corey?
- Right.
- Only Lucas was invited.
- Silence.
But it's a team barbecue.
Yeah, it is, but it's... varsity.
Everybody's in the back. Go ahead.
- [boy] Hey, Tyler, what's up, man?
- My man, what's up
Oh. That explains it.
You kids have fun... without me.
If you guys need a ride before sundown,
you know,
just give me a call. I'll be here.
Hello, hello. What's up?
Lucas, you made it.
What's up, man? This is Simone.
We've met.
Really?
Doesn't everyone know Tyler Barso?
[chuckles] Hey, you know what?
Come inside.
Let me show you guys around.
[# Neon Trees: "1983"]
- [chattering]
- Come on.
- Hey, my man.
- Hey, what's up?
- Hey, Tyler, what's up?
- Sean!
- Tyler!
- What's up, buddy?
Um, I'll be right back, OK?
Hey, ladies. This is, this
is Lucas, and he's on the team.
Oh, yeah? What position are you?
Seated, usually.
[laughs]
You're funny.
- Hey.
- Don't talk to me.
Come on.
Don't play it like that.
I'm glad you're here. I miss you.
I had no idea this was your party.
Are you sure about that?
There wasn't
a teeny, tiny part of you
that wanted to see me, too?
- [scoffs]
- [exhales]
[# Those Dancing Days:
"Can't Find Entrance"]
[Jesse] How many more twinkly
lights do we really need?
[Nova] A lot.
You collect these things?
[sighs] Kind of.
Whenever I have an event:
college tour, scholarship
dinner, awards banquet,
I always just stick 'em there.
I know, it's kinda dorky.
No. It's impressive.
[# Keili Lefkovitz: "Party"]
- No. Not this song.
- You hate this song, too?
There's like eight words in it
and two of them are "party."
[laughs] If this were my world,
Corey and I would have veto power for
all music released into the airwaves.
[laughs] Really? Just you guys?
Well, you too, if you wanted.
[chuckles] Yeah, thanks.
So, do you just talk the talk
or can you walk the walk?
Um, do I play?
No. I don't.
You wanna learn?
- Um...
- Here.
Put your hand like this.
No. OK.
That's a "C."
C.
[laughs] Yes,
but you have to strum.
Oh.
- [strums guitar]
- OK, wait, wait.
OK, try now.
There you go. You'll be
a rock god in no time.
Do you have a boyfriend?
- Um...
- I'm sorry.
I mean, it's none of my business.
- C, C, C, C.
- [strumming guitar]
No, it's OK.
There was one guy.
But it turns out
he's not exactly available.
Oh. Sorry.
It's fine. I'm over it.
It's perfect! She doesn't
have a boyfriend, she told me.
- And she plays guitar.
- Lucas.
I mean, it's just
like you said, right?
- You never listen to what I say.
- She's into me.
Which is why I'm gonna ask her
to study as soon as I see...
Hey.
- Did you forget what day it is?
- Friday?
Yes, which we've established and
designated as "Stick Hippo T-shirt day."
Where's yours?
I guess I forgot.
All right. Well, I have an extra,
you know, for emergencies...
Oh! Tyler! Great party, bro!
Hey, you the man, Luke! [laughs]
"Luke"?
[exhales]
Mei? You have a very important
decision to make.
What?
And I want you to know that
whatever you decide, I support.
What are you talking about?
The limo. Both Mark
and Izzy want white,
but I said I thought you and I were more
the classic black types.
- Aren't we?
- I guess...
What's wrong?
[scoffs] It's just...
Do I get any say in this?
Yeah, yeah, of course you do.
How many other things
have you figured out?
I mean, who says
I even wanted a limo?
All right. Look, we don't have
to decide this right now.
Forget I said anything.
[up-tempo music]
Go for it!
OK, what do I say?
Just pretend you're a normal person.
OK.
[clicks teeth] Hi, Kristen! It's Lloyd.
I'm in your Civics class.
- Really?
- Uh, you lent me a pencil.
I was like,
"Do you have a pencil?"
And you were like, "Yes."
So, I brought it back...
Uh, here... it is. But wait,
that's not the point.
This might seem out of the
blue, this is out of the blue,
actually, but, prom is coming up, as you
know, and I am looking for a date,
and I was wondering if maybe
you wanted to go with me.
Are you serious?
Well, I know it's
a little last minute,
but I'm really fun, I swear.
- You know, I have references...
- No, it's not that.
I have a boyfriend.
Didn't you know that?
Oh. No, I guess not.
I thought everyone
knew about us.
I'm Kristen, he's Anton.
We're Kranton.
[Lloyd] Uh...
I mean, how could you
not know about us?
- You'd have to live in a cave.
- I don't.
Yeah, I mean, we're always together
and the five minutes I'm talking to you
have been the longest
we've been apart in months.
- Huh.
- Yeah. You're back.
God, I missed you.
Anton.
OK, I'll just... slip it in.
Just slip it in there, oh.
Just... Right in front of me. OK.
Well, talk to ya later then,
"Kranton."
- [bell rings]
- [girl]... and she called him.
- Hey, Simone.
- Hey.
Listen, if you wanna study
for the elements test after school...
I'd love to. I really need it.
Cool. How about
we meet in the library?
Perfect. I'll be there.
Hey, I thought
we were gonna study.
Dude, I'm sealing the deal.
OK, yeah. I'll just study by myself.
That's much more efficient.
Cool.
[water splashing]
You must've worked all night.
It's...
...inspired.
I have a kid brother. He's seven.
And because of my mom's work schedule,
I have to pick him up from school.
Why are you telling me this?
It's why I cut class
and I'm late getting here.
I just want you to know, I'm not blowing
it off 'cause I'm a slacker.
[deep breath] From now on...
...we start at 3:15.
[# Shere: "In Deep"]
Oh! Hi, Simone.
Welcome to the library.
Hey, Simone, you ready to study?
Oh, hey, Simone, didn't see you there.
What am I saying?
Of course I saw her.
Hey.
What do you want?
Can I give you a ride home?
I have plans.
[sighs] Listen, I really
need to talk, Simone.
All right, there aren't a lot
of people I can do that with.
Just a few minutes?
- Why won't you answer my texts?
- You know why.
I mean, you said it was over
between you and Jordan.
I never would've gone out with you.
Please don't ice me out
like this, Simone.
I know it's messed up about Jordan,
but we've been together for a long time.
OK, she's been talking
about prom for years.
- But, Tyler, this isn't...
- You're such a special girl.
If you weren't, I would
never expect you to understand.
Just give me until after prom.
[Tyler] You're missing my...
[indistinct]
[muffled conversation]
Unbelievable.
- [sighs]
- What?
Archfield's prom is this weekend,
and Ali just found out that their theme
- is "Starry, Starry Night."
- They have an extra "Starry."
- So?
- [sighs] It's gonna sound stupid.
I just thought that we were
creating this one-of-a-kind night,
and turns out there's another
one a couple miles away.
Just makes it feel so... ordinary.
Well, maybe we should check out
how starry their night really is.
[# The Naked And Famous:
"Young Blood"]
You can do it, Nova.
Do what?
Trust me.
[Nova] Great.
[sighs] So, how are you
gonna get us in there?
I'm gonna fire my grappling
hook gun, climb onto the roof,
and crash in through the skylight.
Really?
No.
Good thinking.
Oh, man. This is pathetic.
These totally come in a kit.
That's lame.
And a balloon wall, really?
These lights don't even twinkle.
And where's the cosmic canopy?
[chuckles] Complete amateurs.
Why are you doing this?
Well, I hadn't broken in
anywhere in a while, and I thought...
I'm serious.
You don't care about prom.
So... why help me?
It's nice to be around someone
who believes in something so much.
[breathes heavily]
Oh, oh, what are you doing?
What do you mean?
You were gonna kiss me.
- No, I wasn't.
- Well, why not?
What?
Nova. If I'm about to kiss you,
you'll know it.
- [door opens]
- What was that?
- [door closes]
- [man] Hey! Who's there?
We gotta go.
[# Girl in a Coma:
"Come On, Let's Go"]
Nova, this way.
- Black and white?
- Come on!
We did it!
- [police radio, indistinct]
- I have a record now.
A rap sheet. I have "priors".
You don't have "priors".
A stern warning
and a call to your parents
isn't exactly your "first strike".
What if they tell Georgetown?
- Nova, it's fine. They're not...
- [door closes]
- You! Hey, you!
- Dad...
- What'd you do to her?
- It's OK.
- OK? What are you, out of your mind?
- He was doing all this for me.
What? Breaking into a school?
Getting stopped by the cops?
Please listen to me.
I deserve the blame, OK?
Oh, really? Whose idea was it?
- Dad, Archfield had the same exact...
- You're right. It was my idea.
This isn't you, Nova. Let's go.
Kid's a loser.
[door closes, engine starts]
- Hi.
- Oh, hey.
- Tyler.
- Hey, babe.
It's over.
I know about your sophomore.
I'm really sorry I didn't
make it to the library.
Oh! The library! I totally forgot.
Really?
- I gave a girl a ride home.
- This isn't about her. It's about you.
I was out with the team. Tyler wanted to
show me some moves. Varsity stuff.
I'm looking good
for next year, so...
Tyler showed you.
Yeah. We must've lost track of time
and forgot about our plans.
- What are you so upset about?
- I'm not upset. I'm done.
Well, I'm still really sorry.
I would've hated waiting all afternoon
for someone to show up.
Yeah. That would've sucked.
Prom's right around the corner.
What are you gonna do, not go?
Don't worry about me, Tyler.
You just keep worrying about you,
since that's what you're best at.
[boy] Out of the whole collection,
these two are my favorites.
This Harvey Kuenn's worth,
like, 40 bucks,
and this Al Kaline
would go for 80 at least.
You must have some allowance, kid.
My dad left them behind.
Charlie. Why are you
carrying those around?
They stay in the basement.
What are you doing here?
The way my dad talked to you,
you didn't deserve that.
And the way Dunnan treats you...
A lot of people are wrong about you.
And... I was one of 'em.
You came all the way here
to tell me that?
I even ditched last period.
For her, that's a big deal.
[sheepish chuckle]
What are you,
his peer counselor or something?
Hey! Yah! Talking about?
Peer counselor! [grunts]
Can I at least
just see it on you?
[Mei] No! I look like a manatee.
No one will ever
see this dress on me.
Cut is wrong, the color is
wrong, the fabric is wrong.
Everything is wrong!
No, don't! Mei...
Now what are you gonna wear?
I don't know! Nothing.
What is this about?
I know you.
It's not about a dress.
Look, if you don't want to go to
prom, just let me know.
What are you talking about?
Well, first it was the limo.
Now the dress.
You're obviously looking
for excuses not to go.
- I never said that.
- You don't have to.
I know when I'm being blown off.
You don't wanna go? Fine.
Prom's off. Problem solved.
[# East Hundred:
"Slow Burning Crimes"]
Good bye, Tyler.
Hey, Jordan,
I was thinking. Are you?
Whoa.
I like it better that way.
Me, too.
- There you go.
- Thank you.
So, you say you two have been
working together at school?
Something like that.
[laughs]
Can I get a refill
before I barf, please?
[men laughing]
[scoffs] My favorite kind of customers.
[all] Aww!
Oh, waitress!
Uh, cleanup on aisle five.
You gonna clean that up?
- Um, I think we should go.
- Are you gonna clean that up?
- [man 1] Do you hear something?
- Nah, I don't see anything either.
I want you to come with me.
Jesse... You can do it.
- Do what?
- Trust me.
[sighs] Those idiots aren't worth it.
Come on.
They'll get what's coming
to 'em. Stuff balances out.
- Wake up, Nova.
- What does that mean?
It means it's easy
to believe in that stuff
when everything
always goes your way.
You think that
everything goes my way?
That I have no problems
in my life because my dad didn't leave?
You think sometimes I don't
wanna just forget everything,
get on my motorcycle all angry
and misunderstood
and go beat some people up?
I have to work my butt off
just to try to get things to go my way.
Everybody does.
What?
I bet you could
beat some people up.
[scoffs] Yeah, I could.
[exhales] OK. Let's go dress shopping.
What?
[# Oh Darling!: "Prettiest Thing"]
So, how come you don't
have a date?
[Nova] He bailed on me.
Well, there must be somebody
else you could go with.
Like the class president
or something?
I am the class president.
Come on. There must be some honor
student out there who you could go...
Really?
That looks fantastic with
our garnet pendant necklace.
Necklace?
With the price of this dress,
the only necklace I'll be able to
afford'll be made out of candy.
That guy who ditched you
made a big mistake.
[chattering]
[sighs] This is awful.
You've been dissed, trampled,
humiliated, stomped on.
Your heart's just been, like,
torn out and ground up in...
I get it! OK?
What's that?
Hey, Simone. You didn't happen to see
anybody put this in my locker, did you?
Why? What is it?
Tickets.
To see Mechanical Sandwich?
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
They had an interesting single,
but then they changed bass
players on the second album
and totally ended up sucking.
Yeah. Their second album
was pretty lame.
I don't even know why
Stick Hippo's opening for them.
- What?!
Hold on. How do you
know about this? I mean,
I'm a certified Stick Hippo webmaster,
and even I didn't know about this.
Well, it's kind of a secret gig.
I got the last two tickets.
Oh, I like your site, by the way.
You're the one hit.
Dude, she's the one hit!
Wait. That means
my mom's been lying to me.
- I bet they're great live.
- Are you kidding? They're the best!
Where are our seats?
Oh. This is like
a"you guys" thing. OK.
Just get me a T-shirt
or something.
Definitely.
Ugh. Do all assigned books have
to be so torturously boring?
Oh, yeah. This is rough.
Ethan Frome?
The worst! The guy falls in love
with his wife's cousin,
goes sledding with her,
she winds up paralyzed. Snore.
[chuckles] That is an incredibly
accurate plot summary.
- [laughs]
- [bell rings]
Hey, listen. You don't happen
to have a date to prom, do you?
- Me?
- Yeah.
I mean, I know it's
a crazy thing to just ask...
Uh, no. It's sweet. I don't think we've
ever talked before, have we?
Maybe not. I'm Lloyd.
- Betsy.
- Short for Elizabeth?
- That's right.
- Pretty.
Thanks.
So, what do you say, Bets?
Uh, prom?
[Betsy sighs] Well, it could be fun.
You seem nice.
But I have a date already.
I mean, we're just friends, we're going
as friends, but, uh, prom's Saturday.
I can't cancel now.
Yeah, no, I underst... Yeah.
It's too bad. If only we'd
met sooner, you know?
Yeah.
Isn't it funny how you can go to school
with somebody for so long
and not even meet them till now?
Yeah. Funny.
Like sledding
and getting paralyzed.
[# The Weepies:
"Please Speak Well of Me"]
What are you doing?
Can't a guy ask a girl to prom?
I thought you
were taking Jordan.
It's over.
I ended it for real.
Tyler...
I mean, if you want to think
about it,
you can just bring
your answer to school tomorrow.
Oh, and, um...
I got this for you, too.
I'd love to hear
you play sometime.
[door chimes]
Rolo. Wow.
That's a good look for you.
How do I know which one to pick?
Well, do you know
what Athena's wearing?
Yeah. Oh, uh, this.
[laughs] Nice try.
[stammers] What do you mean?
You'd have to be a Victoria's Secret
model to pull this off.
Well, that's what she's wearing.
What magazine did you
rip this out of?
Oh, no, no, no.
She sent it to me.
In the mail, of course.
Because her e-mail privileges,
they were revoked when
- she stayed out clubbing.
- Clubbing.
Exactly.
All right, Rolo.
I guess I'll see you guys at prom.
- Cool.
- [door chimes]
- [# Smith Westerns: "Weekend"]
- Wonder if they'll be too high?
- I don't want to be taller than him.
- Taller than who?
You got a prom date, and this is the
first we're hearing about it?
He hasn't asked me yet, but...
...tomorrow's our last day working
together, and I think he's going to.
Is she talking about Jesse Richter?
Are you talking about Jesse Richter?
Oh, wow! Nova likes bad boys.
- Who knew?
- You rebel!
It's more than that.
I've never felt like this before.
- [both] Ohh!
- [Mei] You and Jesse Richter.
I don't believe it.
- [Ali] Yeah, no one will.
- [Nova scoffs] Why not?
Um, because you're you, and he's...
And he's not exactly Brandon.
He's kind of on the other side
of the planet from Brandon.
Yeah.
Well, maybe that stuff isn't
as important as I thought it was.
Maybe there's more to a person than
being valedictorian or class president.
[Mei and Ali laugh] Aww!
So sweet!
- Hey.
Hey, Jesse.
- I'm here about Nova.
Is she all right?
Yeah, she's fine.
In fact, she's, uh,
she's better than fine.
Top of her class,
full scholarship next year.
Big plans.
I know.
OK. You know.
But maybe you don't know how much work
she's done to get where she is.
She's in the home stretch now.
And that's where you came in.
Right at the end.
You don't even know me.
No, I... I do know you.
Come on. I was just like you.
Struggling to get by,
angry at the world.
You know, no plans for the future.
And you might even figure it out.
But it's not fair to drag
Nova down while you do.
So, if you care about her
as much as I think you do...
...you won't be the thing
that holds her back.
[truck door closes, engine starts]
[school bell rings]
OK, so the President of
the United States comes to you,
says that we need a new national anthem,
any band, any era, right?
Oh, there's, there's Simone.
I'll catch you later.
- Hey, Simone.
- [girl] All right.
Hey, Lucas.
So, on Saturday, what do
you think? Pick you up at six?
Actually, I've been looking for you.
Because Saturday's prom,
and do you remember
that guy I told you about
who wasn't available?
Well, he asked me.
And we're going.
Oh.
I didn't mean to mess up your
plans. It all happened so fast.
No. I'm happy for you.
[boys laughing]
I'm really sorry, Lucas.
- Let's go. I'm starving. Huh?
- Go.
You guys are going for pizza?
You're the man, Luke!
[sighs]
[moped approaching]
Hey.
So, I was thinking we should check
the speed of the disco ball,
make sure it's not too fast or...
OK. Great.
That looks good. Right?
Or is that too slow?
Is it too slow?
Nova, just tell me how you want it.
Oh, well, don't you have an opinion?
My opinion is I wanna set this
thing and be done with it.
Oh. That's fine, then.
I can't wait until
you turn on that fountain
under these lights tomorrow night.
- Me?
- Well, who else?
I won't be here.
You didn't think I was actually gonna go
to this thing, did you?
Um...
Yeah.
I've wasted enough of my time on prom.
I don't think it was
a waste of time... for us.
What "us"?
You expect me to believe that this
hasn't meant anything to you?
That you don't feel any different?
How I feel or how you feel
doesn't mean anything.
What?
Your world may be all disco
balls and celestial fountains,
but that's not where I live.
Where I live, I'm a bad guy
who's going nowhere,
and that's the only reason I'm here.
None of that stuff matters.
As long as you feel
the same way about me as...
...I feel about you.
I don't.
[door opens]
[door closes]
[attempts to start engine]
[engine starts]
OK. So, just to be clear,
that is a "no."
- Yeah.
- OK.
I know the feeling.
What's her name?
Simone.
[exhales] Simone.
I didn't ask her.
What happened?
She's going to prom.
Huh. Shoulda known. Prom.
That soul-crushing mistress.
Yeah, well, she's going and now
she'll never know how I feel.
You gotta tell her.
- You don't even know me.
- Don't I?
Shy, nice guy, always waiting
for the right time to make his move,
and the right time never comes?
Before you know it, you're a senior,
couple weeks from graduating,
and... you saw.
You can't keep waiting
for the right moment to happen.
Make it happen.
What do you have to lose?
[doorbell rings]
- Hey.
I have to tell you something.
I got accepted to Parsons.
For design.
In New York.
New York.
I didn't even know you applied.
I didn't think I'd get in.
And I was wait-listed
and I thought "no way."
And then I got in.
Justin... I'm gonna go.
Say something.
How could you think
I wouldn't be proud of you?
[sobs]
This is why you've been acting
so crazy about prom.
Prom is supposed to
be this "forever" night.
And we're supposed to be
this..."forever" couple.
Yeah.
You know,
nobody knows the future.
But I do know
how I feel about you.
[# M83: "Too Late"]
And what if
that's not enough?
Mei, look at me. It's enough.
- Do you think...
- What?
Anyone would notice if I wore
my homecoming dress?
Who cares?
[laughs] Dude, get off me!
Shut up. Idiot.
Hey. See me now?
[both grunt]
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Get outta here! Stop it!
- Break it up!
- Get off of him!
- [Jesse spits]
- [man] Move it!
Let me see you. You OK?
Are you all right?
Oh, God, look at you.
Look at you.
Come on. Come get inside.
[# Shout Out Louds: "Impossible"]
OK, ready? OK.
Do we really have to do the whole
picture-by-the-fireplace thing?
Aw, come on.
It's gonna be great.
Why?
Because the balloons are right
and the tablecloths match the napkins?
Lots of people go to prom
without dates.
This is about someone
in particular, isn't it?
I know it didn't make sense.
It just...
...it just felt right.
Why can't I have that?
What did I do wrong?
I had a talk with him.
You did what?
I was protecting what we always
talked about for you.
You've worked so hard.
I didn't want him to...
...ruin all the great things
you had ahead of you.
[scoffs]
I know you think you were doing
what's best for me...
...but tonight could've been
one of those great things.
And he's not the one who ruined it.
[sighs]
- [screams]
- [Lucas] Ah!
Sorry.
What are you doing?
I meant to hit the window.
[sighs] Why are you in the tree?
I have to tell you something.
- Lucas, my date's gonna be...
- Don't go to prom.
You're not seriously
asking me that.
I love you...
...as more than a friend.
Love implies more than a friend.
Yes. It does, and I've missed every
chance to tell you until now
because I was stupid and scared.
But now I'm in this tree,
and you're so beautiful.
And if you walk out that door,
I might as well stay up here forever.
Don't go.
[car approaches]
[car door opens]
Tyler? You're going to prom with Tyler?
I didn't know how to tell you.
[doorbell rings]
I'm sorry, Lucas. I have to go.
[chattering]
[# Taio Cruz Featuring Ludacris:
"Break Your Heart Ft Ludacris"]
Yo, Tyler! How's it goin', man?
What's up, baby?
Chillin'. Chillin'.
Lookin' fresh, lookin' fresh.
Hey, let's get together. Let's do this
picture thing real quick. Come on.
- Cheese!
- [group] Whoo!
Nova! Hi.
Brandon!
What are you doing here?
Well, I made it back early.
You did it, Nova Prescott.
Starry Night. I mean, it's all
that you said it would be.
Yeah.
Everything's OK, right?
No. It's not.
[boy] She came by herself.
[boy 2] Jordan?
[boy] Wow. I can't believe it.
You know, the first time I met
him, he'd just been in a fight.
Yeah, like father like son.
- What are you talking about?
- Come on, Mom.
You married a fighter and look where it
got us. Look where it's got me.
I did not marry a fighter.
I married an idiot that got into fights.
There's a difference.
You are a fighter.
You've been through a lot
and you're still here
taking care of this family.
I'd bet on you every time.
Not everybody feels that way.
She does.
You know, your dad never knew
what the hell was important.
What was worth fighting for.
If he did, he'd be here...
...to see how great you turned out.
Even if it fits,
you're still the bigger man.
[doorbell rings]
Hey.
I was a jerk, Corey.
And I'm sorry.
The band... is back together.
Hold on. Mom! Let's go!
- Hippos forever!
- Oh, yeah!
All right. Top five tragic
band breakups of all time. Go.
Ah... Oasis. The Kinks.
[# Katy Perry: "Firework"]
This is awesome!
Go. Have fun.
Really? You sure?
Yes. Go. Enjoy your youth.
Whoo! Come on!
[# Allstar Weekend:
"Not Your Birthday"]
I can't believe
she dumped Tyler and came alone.
I know. It's awesome.
Hey. Where you been?
They're about to announce
king and queen.
You didn't break up with Jordan
to be with me.
She dumped you.
Well, yeah. Technically. But...
You know, Tyler, all you had
to do was tell the truth.
Was that really so difficult...
...to tell the truth
about how you felt?
[sighs] I mean...
Attention, attention!
We're about to crown the king and queen.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we have tallied the votes
and are proud to announce
Brookside's new prom king is...
[drum roll]
- Tyler Barso!
- Whoo!
Yeah! Ha, ha! Whoo!
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
And what's a king without a queen?
In a landslide win...
[drum roll]
Jordan Lundley!
[audience cheers]
Please make room for the king
and queen's official dance.
Oh, no. I'm not
gonna dance with him.
One second. Are you sure?
Um, OK.
At the request of the queen,
she will be sitting this dance out.
So, it'll just be the king's
dance. By order of the queen.
Oh. OK.
Shall we?
Actually, Tyler, there... there's
somewhere else I have to be.
[audience gasps]
[# Neon Trees:
"Your Surrender"]
Oh... my... God.
Hey.
Nice dress.
You brought your sister to prom?
Yeah, uh, it's... I can explain.
I think that rocks.
- Where have you been?
- [chuckles]
Oh-ho! Amazing. I mean,
that version of "War Craving"?
The best!
[# Passion Pit: "Dreams"]
Hendrix. Woodstock.
Come on. Let's dance.
Uh, I think I'm prom'd out.
Nova!
The fountain stopped working.
You guys can figure it out
or just leave it off.
[water splashing]
You're here.
Will you go to prom with me?
Yes.
- [snickers]
- What?
I thought you'd never wear
that sweaty symbol of conformity.
I thought about that,
but then I realized...
...I kinda rock it.
[# Band Of Horses:
"No One's Gonna Love You"]
It's so romantic.
[Nova] Prom, a night when nice
guys might not finish last.
When friends might
completely surprise you.
When the person you were
throughout high school
could change in an instant.
Maybe you find
what you're looking for.
Or maybe you just
find yourself.
It's true, one night can
bring us all together.
But it's more than that,
'cause when it ends...
...it's really just the beginning.
You're about to kiss me.