More than three
thousand years ago,
a man named Job complained to
God about all his troubles.
And the Bible tells
us that God answered.
Do you give the
horse his strength?
Or clothe his neck
with a flowing mane?
Do you make him
leap like a locust,
striking terror with
his proud snorting?
He paws fiercely,
rejoicing in his strength
and charges into the fray.
He laughs at fear,
afraid of nothing.
He does not shy away
from the sword.
The quiver rattles
against his side,
along with the flashing
spear and lance.
In frenzied excitement
he eats up the ground.
He cannot stand still
when the trumpet sounds.
Kate, Sarah, you have to
leave in ten minutes.
Penny, I have three shirts
to pick up at the cleaners,
and two more to go in the
hamper, if you wouldn't mind.
- I'll pick those up.
- Also go by the wine shop,
pick up some Riesling?
I have a client
coming in. That's all he drinks.
Sarah, orange juice, please.
- No nuclear devices on the table.
- Come on, Dad.
Daddy, I need to pick up a gown.
Another gown?
When you earn your own money, you
can buy gowns for every party.
I'm sure we can find something
reasonable. We can go
look this weekend.
Not Gewürztraminer, only Riesling.
Mum, can we have pancakes?
- Working on it.
- Che Guevara or Ho Chi Minh?
What are you doing?
Getting ready for a
Christmas pageant.
- A Christmas pageant? When?
- Spring.
It's experimental. Has to do with
Christmas and lots of things.
Really? That's great.
What's the role?
- The War Protester.
- I was thinking that we could...
- The what?
- The War Protester.
It's a really good role, Mum.
You'll love it. You, too, Dad.
Tweedy residence. This is she.
War protester in a
Christmas pageant?
We'll leave this
afternoon. Thank you.
What are you doing? I don't pay
you to dream, I pay you to work.
Now, let's get to it. Come on.
You do that on your own time.
Thank you.
Oh, Hollis.
Mama's gone.
She's gone. Hi, Jack.
Hollis, I'm so sorry
for your loss.
Your mother was
always so kind to me.
- Miss Chenery, we're sorry.
- Thank you.
Penny...
Penny, darling. Darling.
Girls, you remember Miss
Ham? Granddaddy's secretary?
- Hi, Miss Ham.
- Oh, my, you two have grown.
Thank you so much, Miss
Ham. For everything.
Hollis said you found her.
She had just fallen. The
doctor said she didn't suffer.
She looked... peaceful.
How is Daddy?
He keeps asking, Where is she?
But I'm not sure if he's
asking for your mother or you.
Girls, I'm going to go in and
see your granddaddy now.
I'll bring you in later.
Come on, girls. Let's get
you something to eat.
Don't let them fool you, darling.
It's not whether
they think we won.
It's whether we think we won.
You run your race, Penny.
We'll take 'em.
We just got ourselves
a couple new horses.
Are we going to race them?
No.
They're going to be mommies
and daddies for new horses.
Helen?
Daddy, it's Penny.
Penny.
You got married.
Yes.
But I'm here now.
Because Mama's gone.
Mama's pin?
Yours now.
Daddy.
The Lord shall preserve thy
going out, and thy coming in.
From this time forth...
and even forever more.
And so we return to You your
faithful servant, Helen Chenery.
Loving mother, devoted wife...
who lived each moment
to the fullest,
cherishing the life she had with
her beloved husband, Christopher.
And may the peace that
passeth all understanding
be in your hearts now
and forever more.
- Amen.
Eddie? Eddie, I just wanted to
thank you so much for coming.
Miss Penny, your mama
was a fine woman.
I just feel real bad
for Mr Chenery.
He always thought
the world of you.
He said you could hear the horses'
thoughts through your hands.
Yeah, well, your father's
a good man, Miss Penny.
Thank you.
Mrs Tweedy?
I'm Arthur Hancock.
- Your daddy called me...
- Bull.
Oh, yes, and everyone else
did, too, as I recall.
This is my son, Seth.
- Hi, nice to meet you.
- Thank you for coming.
Your mother was a fine woman. It
was a privilege just knowing her.
Thank you.
I know you're going to
be making some changes,
and if you or your family have any
questions, Miss Ham's
got my number.
Thank you, Bull.
Ma'am...
Your daddy's eyes would always
light up when he talked about you.
How smart you are. How
much you loved the horses.
Doctor says there may
be some brief moments
when he is aware of things,
but we shouldn't expect much.
Practical thing would be to
put him in a nursing home.
This is home to him. And
he knows he's here.
I think as long as
he does, we should
hire nurses and let
him stay at home.
The farm has to go. And
it won't bring much.
It's been losing money hand
over fist for years now.
We have to face facts. To run
a horse breeding operation,
you need a certain touch.
I'm a professor, and
you're a housewife.
I moved up our flight
to first thing
tomorrow. I've got to get back.
Jack, I need a few more days here.
I have to make sure Daddy's all
right, sort through
Mother's things.
The kids could all do with
a little responsibility.
It will just be a few days.
We need to file right away
for his power of attorney?
Miss Ham says he tried to sell
four of his best horses last month
for half of what
they're worth. Mum had
to step in and stop
him, and now...
I suppose someone will have to
clean up for the liquidation.
Hollis, if you need
any help on the
tax issues you call me, anytime.
Thanks, Jack. It will
just be for a few days.
Sarah makes great pancakes.
- Oh, no.
- They're toxic. We won't survive.
That's right, you won't.
Make sure Hollis has that
power of attorney order.
- The estate's vulnerable.
- I will. I'll stay on him.
Mum, give Granddaddy a hug
for us when he wakes up.
- I will. I love you.
- Love you.
- Bye, Mum.
- Be good.
We will.
Miss Ham. Thank you.
Two sugars and cream?
How did you know?
- It's how your daddy likes it.
- Oh.
You doing all right, honey?
Yes.
No. But I'll be all right.
These two are both
pregnant by Bold Ruler.
And great colts come
from great sires.
Miss Ham?
My mother thought
the world of you.
And my father's trust in
you was... is absolute.
I hope you'll stay.
Funny, I was about to
tell you the same thing.
Al. Who the hell told you
to bring this one out?
The sable, put it back. Bring
out the yearling in 18.
- Yes, sir, Mister Jansen.
- Who are you?
Penny Tweedy.
- Penny Chenery.
- Oh, you're the daughter.
- Better get back to work.
- Excuse me, Mr Jansen?
Could I talk with you
a moment? In private?
Oh.
About what?
I wanted to ask you
about that sale
of those broodmares that my
mother stopped a few weeks ago.
I know you and your brother aren't
horse people and you
suffered a loss,
but you don't need to worry
about this right now.
Apparently, I do
since they're my
father's horses, and
the sale would've
been bad business.
It's bad business to come to a
barn, interrupt a trainer's work.
- Not if you want to keep him.
- I understand.
- But about that sale?
- What about it?
They were worth twice what we
were going to sell them for.
I couldn't sleep last night,
so I checked the books
and I made some calls
this morning to be sure.
Like you say, I don't
own the horses.
Your father has to sell them.
But as trainer, you
would know their worth
and that they were
about to be sold.
I'm wondering why it
had to be my mother
who stopped the sale and not you.
The old man, your father? Ask him.
I'm asking you. My father's been
sick for quite a long time now.
You've been paid to look
out for his interests.
And I do. Just because
this place is
going downhill it ain't my fault.
The sale was going to
be to Oakworth Farms?
I learned this morning
that the owners
of Oakworth were already talking
about selling our horses for twice
the price they were
going to pay us.
You train for them,
too, don't you?
I don't have an
exclusive deal here.
I work for them
sometimes. So what?
So if you arranged a deal
that gave them four horses
at half their market value
and they paid you
back, plus an extra
share on everything they made,
that wouldn't just be disloyal.
That would be committing fraud.
Who the hell do you think you
are? Coming here, accusing me?
Someone who knows enough
law to know she's right.
And I'm not Missy anything. Get
your things and get off my farm.
I have a contract,
and I'll sue you.
If I ever even hear
your name again,
I will see that you go to prison.
Where does Bull Hancock eat lunch?
At his club, every day.
But it's gentlemen only.
Miss? Miss, you can't...
I'm sorry, Mr Hancock.
I told her this
was a gentleman's
club, she just...
it's all right, Brenda.
It's all right.
Thank you, Seth. I apologise
for interrupting.
It's fine. I have friends
here, Miss Chenery.
Thank you.
Well, how's it going?
I fired Earl Jansen.
Do tell.
Does that mean you're selling
the horses or keeping them?
The farm's in bad
shape, as is Daddy.
But I'm not willing to sell it
unless I get what it's worth.
Well, horse farm needs a
strong hand on the reins,
but the hand that
threw Earl Jansen out
the door looks
pretty strong to me.
Well, I've got a
family back in Denver.
I need a good trainer just
to get things stabilised.
You need to talk to Lucien
Laurin. He's a French Canadian.
Dresses like Super Fly.
He's trying to retire.
What do you mean, trying?
Mr Laurin?
Excuse me. I'm Penny Chenery,
Chris Chenery's daughter.
And, I need a
trainer. Bull Hancock
suggested that I find you...
Yeah, Bull called
me, but I tell you,
I'm tired of babysitting half-ton
animals who are nearly as stubborn
and stupid as their owners are.
I've lost interest in racing.
Don't even follow it any more.
Well, I'm in a bit
of a tight spot.
I wonder if you might just try it
- for a few months and see how...
- I don't need to try anything,
and trainers don't go anywhere
to work for a few months.
They go where there
is a good horse.
We have plenty of good horses.
No, you don't. You have one or two
that might be worth the time,
but you're a little
short on people
over there who know
what they're doing.
Well, that's why I've come
to see you, Mr Laurin.
Miss, you're not
hearing me. A trainer
makes his living off commissions.
Ten percent off sales,
ten percent off winners.
To get a top trainer,
you need a top horse.
You're going to have
to go back to Bull
and see if he has any other ideas.
Mr Laurin, two of our mares
are pregnant by Bold Ruler
who is the finest stallion
of his generation.
- Fore.
- Hey.
- Watch where you're hitting.
Well, I yelled fore, you
idiot. That's what fore means.
You see how I am, Miss
Chenery, when I put myself
in a position to do
something poorly?
And I'm afraid at your stable, I'd
be yelling fore all day long.
Give my regards to your father.
Fore.
- When are you coming back?
- Soon.
I need to talk to you about
this coin toss thing.
- Coin toss?
- Jack, listen.
Stallions cost more than mares.
No, they're more glamorous.
But Daddy knew that a great horse
comes just as much from
the mare as the stallion.
He invested in mares, which is
the first smart thing he did.
Second smart thing he did was he
made a deal with Ogden Phipps.
Phipps? Richest man in America?
Yes. Instead of paying a stud fee,
Daddy made a deal to breed Phipps'
best stallion with
our two best mares.
When the mares are
close to term, they
toss a coin to see
who gets which foal.
That coin toss is in two weeks.
What's the difference?
I don't have
any idea which horse to choose.
I've been through the stud books,
Jack. Bold Ruler, that's the sire.
He was fast, but he couldn't
last over distances.
Now the two dams are Hasty
Matilda and Something Royal.
Hasty Matilda is eight years
old. She's still young.
Since broodmares tend
to produce their
best offspring while
they're young, that
makes her foal the obvious choice,
since Something Royal's 17.
But her grandsire
was Princequillo.
He had great stamina, Jack.
- Penny? Penny.
- Do you know what that means?
- What?
- Sire and dam and Sam-I-Am?
What is this? Come on.
We need you here, Penny.
Come home.
Right after the coin toss.
- You about ready?
- We're ready.
Excuse me just a minute.
I'll be making the toss. Are
you waiting on anybody else?
- No, I came alone.
- We toss right on the hour.
- Good luck to you.
- Thank you.
Hi. Good to see you, Mr
Hancock. How are you?
Hollis. What are you doing here?
I called Jack about
our tax issues,
and he told me you
fired our trainer.
How do you expect we can fetch
a good price on the farm
if we don't have a training
operation in place.
He was dishonest.
He had to go. You
came down here because
of a trainer?
This coin toss is big. The foal
could be worth a great deal.
I checked with some
of Phipps' people.
They think he wants
Hasty Matilda's foal.
So that's who we'll choose.
No, Hollis, I think that's wrong.
Something Royal's
colt could have an
unusual mix of speed and stamina.
Phipps has the best
horse people in the
world. You know more than they do?
Come on.
Please don't take
offence, Miss Chenery,
but your father almost
never won our coin tosses.
And I do hope you've
inherited his luck.
All right. We're all here now.
Mr Phipps has the call as
the owner of Bold Ruler.
The winner has the choice of the
offspring of Mr Chenery's mares.
Hasty Matilda or Something Royal.
Are we all in agreement here?
All right. Here we go.
- Call.
- Heads.
Heads it is. I'll go
with Hasty Matilda.
Miss Chenery. Please give
my best to your father.
Well, that's that.
But I got what I wanted.
You got what nobody else
wanted. Time to go home.
Can I give you a lift home?
No, thank you, I have
Daddy's truck here.
- All right.
- Bye, Bull.
So, who won the coin toss?
Phipps. He went
with Hasty Matilda.
Of course he did.
Call me when she's ready
to drop her foal.
Pigs. Pigs. They're all such pigs.
We've been putting on this
Protest Pageant for a year.
Now the teacher says it's too
political and we can't put it on.
What do you mean you can't?
They have a rule that theatre
projects can't be political.
When the teacher saw what we were
doing... Dad, can
we, like, sue them?
If you didn't disclose
until today, they
couldn't be held
liable for a breach.
What?
Honey, listen. If this is really
important to you, you won't...
- Tweedy residence.
- Is Miss Chenery there?
Can we talk about this some more?
Yeah. Ok. Fine.
Penny. For Miss Chenery.
- This is Penny.
- This is Eddie.
Something Royal is about
to drop her foal.
- All right. Thank you.
- Bye, Miss Chenery.
Something Royal's
foal is on its way.
Kick hard. Come on. Kick,
Chris. Come on. Good job.
Hey, John. How would
you like to come
with me and see a
horse being born?
- Really?
- Yeah.
Ok.
How many times has she done this?
She did it 13 times.
You've done it four.
Yes.
It's a boy. It's a boy.
- Have you ever seen that?
- No. Not me.
- What?
- A colt stand up that fast.
Hey, Daddy. I brought
you some company.
This is the Bold
Ruler colt, Daddy.
We call him Big Red.
Let him run his race, darling.
Flight 226 to Denver is ready
for boarding. Gate 33-D.
- Almost done.
- I know this is hard for you.
How long do you think you can
keep living two lives at once?
The yearlings are looking
good, especially the red one.
We've cut expenses.
We're breaking even.
I thought the point was to sell
the farm, not to break even.
When I went off to college,
I felt like that colt.
Full of promise.
Full of adventure, like I could...
make something work.
I gave up a career to
have our family, and...
this colt is part
of our family now.
I just want to see him run.
So after two years of
juggling all this...
it isn't ending, it's
just... beginning?
How's he feel, Jimmy?
Just a big kid having
fun out there.
He'll figure it out. Huh, Red?
That's good. That's good.
Now, listen, don't try to
change his natural gait, ok?
Don't force him.
Well, Mr Laurin,
what do you think?
I think he's 1100
pounds of baby fat.
He eats too much and too often.
The only reason he
doesn't eat more
is because he's too busy sleeping.
He only does what he wants to do
exactly when he wants to do it.
He lays against the back
of that starting gate
like he's in a hammock
in the Caribbean.
And when he finally does
get out of the gate,
it takes him forever
to find his stride.
Any other questions?
I have one. How much did
you spend on that hat?
Right now this horse
is all sleep and eat.
But he's got fire inside
him. Ain't that right, Red?
That horse couldn't beat a
fat man encased in cement
being drugged backwards
by a freight train.
Well, you should know, Mr Laurin.
You thought that was
funny. I did, too.
I wish we could just race
him under his name. Red.
The Jockey Club insists
on unique names.
I keep sending them, they
keep rejecting them.
I've tried Something Special,
Royal Line, DEO Volente...
DEO Volente. God willing.
God may have been willing,
but The Jockey Club wasn't.
Well, there is a race up in
Aqueduct in a couple weeks.
I think we should
send him out. It's
time. Not that I'm expecting much.
Let's enter him, then.
DEO Volente.
- Well, that was really good.
- Can we be excused?
Sure.
- Please bring in the dessert.
- Ok, Mum.
It's good you're home.
Your daughters have something
they want to talk to you about.
Oh? What's that?
Kate and I were
thinking of going to
Chile. Just for a
couple of months.
Chile? What for?
Teach English and learn Spanish.
It's part of a cultural mission.
A mission to stir
up trouble and act
cool, you mean? Chile
is socialist now.
- Thank you.
- Go play.
It is not. And that's
not why we're going.
Although if an
opportunity to protest
the war did present itself...
See? This is what you're missing.
Your teenage daughters are
growing up to become rebels.
No, more like hippies.
Free spirits.
Hippies are running from
paying the price of freedom.
If there's a price, how
is it freedom, Dad?
I'll answer that question
when you become an adult.
Would anyone like some pie?
- No, thanks.
- No, thank you.
Well...
When do you have to
give an answer by?
There's a meeting for the
parents on the fifth.
The day after my Protest Pageant.
Your play? You're doing your play?
Yeah. I present it as a civic
arts summer programme, so...
Oh, Kate, after two years,
you're finally going to do it.
Both of you can make it, right?
The new colt runs his
first race on the fourth.
That's in New York. I will
be on the first plane home.
- Ok.
- Oh, by the way, Miss Ham called.
Something about a
name for the horse.
Rounding out the field
in the fourth race.
Secretariat.
Right up through there,
that one's ours.
Let's take off this stupid...
Paul. Where's Paul? Paul.
- Here. Right here.
- Listen.
Quit sneaking around.
Got it? Listen.
Yes.
Watch out for number
six. He's got the speed.
Also, watch out for number
three, who's going to hold back
with five and eight along with
him. And watch out for number one.
That's the best horse in the
field. Watch out for him.
- All right.
- Where do you want this?
Are there any horses he doesn't
need to be watching out for?
Did I say number four?
We're four.
- What?
- We're four.
Oh, yeah. Right. Well, definitely
watch out for number four.
- Jockey's mighty young.
- He is mighty young.
He's good enough. He'll do.
You don't like my hat? Why?
Do you like my hat?
- Your hat?
- Yeah.
I... Well... it's...
I do. I like the hat.
Sorry. I do, I do, I
like the hat. Help me.
Of course I do. I
like it very much.
Sorry.
- Oh.
- What's wrong?
I just realised that's the
first time I've laughed,
I've really laughed, in a...
Since I don't remember when.
She scares me.
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome
to the fourth race at Aqueduct,
maiden trip for
two-year-old, among
them, Secretariat by Bold Ruler.
Secretariat leaning against
the back of the gate.
And they're off.
It wasn't exactly
what I had in mind.
You said he was ready to race.
He was ready to race. He just
wasn't ready to play bumper cars.
Fourth? And he runs like he's
afraid? I expect more than that.
So do I. What were you doing?
He got hit coming out of the gate.
We saw he got hit.
You got him mugged
at the gate, mugged
in the pack, and
mugged on the rail.
- You're off him.
- We need to talk about this.
Don't start with me.
You are off him.
Go on home. Just go on.
And you stay out of this.
It's none of your business.
Excuse me? What are you saying?
The horse should never have lost.
Are you sure that it was
Paul's fault, then?
Say that in English.
No. It was my fault.
He doesn't have enough
experience. This
horse needs a jock
with more experience.
Well, I know this.
If his jockey won't back off, Red
won't back off. From anything.
You want a jockey who won't back
off, then you want
Ronnie Turcotte.
I want to meet with him.
When I'm back in two weeks.
One more thing. I'm
new to this, and you
know a lot more
about it than I do.
But don't ever say this
is none of my business.
Every bit of this is my
business. Do you understand?
Yes, ma'am.
I called to check on your flight.
They cancelled it due to weather.
Oh, no.
- I'm sorry.
- No. Kate's play.
♪ Silent night ♪
War, war, war, war...
♪ Holy night ♪
♪ All is calm ♪
- Mum?
- Honey. Is she on, almost?
Yeah, she's just starting.
Oh.
Let me hear.
♪ Mother and child ♪
War, war, war...
♪ Holy infant so ♪
♪ Tender and mild ♪
- Can you hear?
- Yeah, I hear.
Dad says it's Commie crap.
It's art, honey.
It's art.
♪ Sleep in heavenly peace ♪
War, war, war, war...
♪ Silent night ♪
♪ Holy night ♪
♪ Shepherds quake ♪
♪ At the sight ♪
Thank you.
You got a problem?
- Hey.
- Get out of the street.
I'm trying to get
across the street.
Move out of the way. Use
crutches on the sidewalk.
Idiot.
- Miss Chenery?
- Mr Turcotte. Oh, I'm so sorry.
Well, Lucien and I
were so hoping that
you'd be able to ride
in our next race.
I'll be ready. Why wouldn't I be?
I spoke with some of the
owners you ride for.
They say you're one of the
best. You got a great touch.
You're great with young horses.
They also say that you
can be over-aggressive.
Use bad judgement.
Put a horse into
too much traffic
where he can't run.
Then why did you come to me?
I hear you have the heart of a
champion. I know my horse does.
I read here that
the last horse you
were on ran so hard
his heart burst?
- I'm sorry?
- Lucien told the truth.
- What did Lucien say?
- That you're hard as nails.
Miss Chenery, I risk my life
every time I climb on a horse.
I'm not afraid. Neither are they.
I want to win, just like they do.
It's true. The last horse I rode
ran so hard his heart burst.
But it's who they are.
And it's who I am.
You want somebody else,
get somebody else.
I don't want somebody else.
I want you.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
So which of you ladies
owns Secretary?
His name is Secretariat.
And he's going to make
your horse take dictation.
You don't know which
horses we own.
Doesn't matter. Mine's the big red
one. And he's going
to beat them all.
Big red one.
- I see him.
- Yup.
It's a beautiful day
at Saratoga Park.
- Close them up.
- We're ready for our six-furlong,
single-turn sprint
for two-year-old.
Conditions are perfect. The
track is rated very fast.
And they're off.
The field is spreading out.
Russ Miron out quickly.
Come on, Ronnie, make your move.
He's got nowhere
to move. I thought
you said Turcotte was aggressive.
Ok, Red. Let's go get them.
Secretariat. Secretariat
making a bold move.
Secretariat surging,
knocking Blackthorn
and Fat Frank aside
with brute force.
That's it, Red. We got them.
He's overtaking the field,
passing Joe Iz, Tropic Action,
now approaching Blackthorn.
A spectacular event. Secretariat
is catching up to Russ Miron.
- Fore.
- Russ Miron on the inside.
Secretariat on the outside, now
getting the lead by a head.
Secretariat pulling away.
It's Secretariat.
Secretariat and Russ Miron.
Secretariat taking the lead
as they come to the wire.
It's Secretariat with an
impressive victory by two lengths.
Oh.
Thank you.
- Looks like you finished last.
- I was there long enough.
Oh.
Is it just me, or is
that horse posing?
You and I both know that horse...
Owner hates the attention,
but the horse loves it.
Secretariat wins by three lengths.
Secretariat by five lengths.
Secretariat by eight.
Secretariat wins.
- Secretariat.
Secretariat.
Seven wins in four months.
There's talk he could
be Horse of the Year.
But most of the sons of Bold Ruler
couldn't handle the
distances 3-year-old runs.
And they've all failed as
Triple Crown contenders.
So what can you tell
us about Secretariat?
He loves to run. Loves it.
Likes to come from behind.
Nerve-racking for me,
but his fans love it.
And he's a ham.
He likes to show off, doesn't he?
You really think he
knows what he's doing?
Don't look at me.
Beyer's the one that
said you can't run long distances.
You do acknowledge
the issue, right?
That speed and endurance
don't necessarily go...
Oh.
No way.
Hey, Thelma. Bring more hamburger.
These little guys
eat like elephants.
You are doing a great
job with him, Lucien.
Let me ask you something.
Why did you choose me?
I know Bull recommended me.
But you had to know, you do your
homework, that there were other
more successful trainers
you could've gotten.
The truth? I was hungry.
And so were you.
I heard that you
carried the clippings
from the big races that you lost.
So that's why you didn't try
very hard to convince me.
I knew you couldn't stay retired,
after I saw your golf swing.
Hey. Secretariat.
Horse of the Year.
Fantastic.
Ronnie.
- Arnold Palmers for everyone.
- Oh, big spender.
Congratulations.
- Great riding, Ronnie.
- Good job.
- Look at this.
- Hey, Ronnie.
- Good job, man.
- Thank you, man.
To the greatest horse I ever rode.
And to its owner, who took
on the old boys and won.
But now that you've
gotten their attention,
you're going to have to take
them on in earnest next year.
- The races are longer.
- Much longer.
- The horses are faster.
- Much faster.
And every owner, every trainer,
every jockey out there
is going to be trying
to bring us down.
- I'll be ready.
- Salut.
Horse of the Year. We
have to celebrate.
Is this the article that's going
to be running across the country?
Did you hear?
It's your daddy, honey.
He's had a stroke.
Let's just go.
I don't think there's much
left unsaid between us, Daddy.
I always knew where you stood.
And I'm grateful... so grateful,
for the way you showed me
what it was to stand
up in the world and...
live the way you believe.
The big red colt won Horse
of the Year, Daddy.
I think he can go all the way.
And if he does...
I hope...
I hope you could see it.
Jack, what are you doing here?
How did you get here so fast?
I'm so sorry about your father.
I was already on my way.
Already? Are the
children all right?
They're fine. I left Denver
before I heard the news.
Hollis had asked me to
study the tax issues
that would arise upon
your father's death.
Issues that now find
us totally unprepared.
So you've asked my husband
to become your ally in this?
It's family business.
And, last time I
checked, Jack and your
children were still
part of this family.
Hollis, you're my
brother and I love you,
but if you presume to judge my
fitness as a wife or mother
I will count you a stranger
for the rest of my life.
Penny, Hollis is only
trying to talk sense.
We need to regain
some perspective.
- Regain?
- Penny, it's just...
Let's not talk about
this right now.
No. No, no, no. She
needs to hear this.
She needs to hear what?
At the current value
of his estate,
the inheritance tax will be
at least six million dollars.
And neither of us has a
fraction of that money.
So we sell the mares
and the yearlings.
I had an appraisal done, and that
won't get us half of what we need.
But there is another option.
I'm not selling him.
Due to his outstanding
two-year-old season,
if he were sold today,
Secretariat would
bring a price of seven
million dollars.
But if he were to lose just
one of the Triple Crown races
that value would drop to three
million with no way to recover it.
So we sell Secretariat.
- You try and sell him and...
- We're out of time.
If we don't play this right,
it could amount to nothing.
Our father came from nothing.
And his legacy to me isn't money.
It's the will to win. If you can.
And live with it if you can't.
If I have to challenge you
in court on this, I will.
Miss Ham? Would you come
in here a moment, please?
Thank you, Miss Ham.
Would you tell Jack
and Hollis about
the document that
Daddy left for you.
Five years ago Mr Chenery had me
witness him signing
a provision that,
while both of you
are beneficiaries,
dispersal of the farm
would be left to Hollis.
Decisions regarding the horses
would be left to Penny.
We could argue he
already had dementia.
He was of sound mind
when he signed it.
I'd swear to it... in court.
Thank you, Miss Ham.
Great. I teach
economics at Harvard,
and I don't know a way to
conjure up six million dollars
before you race him again.
What makes you think you can?
I'll find a way. And if I
can't, I'll live with it.
Why? Why do you need
to live with it?
Make me, the whole family, live
with it for a past that is gone.
Our father was a great man,
but we can't bring him back.
This isn't about going back.
This is about life being ahead
of you and you run at it.
Because you never know how far
you can go unless you run.
That's great.
But if you stumble and fall,
you don't just make us
fools, you make us beggars.
When your horse people call the
house, they don't
ask for Mrs Tweedy,
they ask for Miss Chenery.
- Is that who you've become?
- Jack...
Miss Chenery and Mrs Tweedy have
always been the same person.
I'm wondering how it is that Mr
Tweedy could take
sides against me.
Trying to muscle me into
something. Can't do that.
- Good evening, Eddie.
- Hi, ma'am.
How are you, Big Red?
- How's it going?
- Ma'am...
I reckon you heard about
Bull Hancock, ma'am?
No.
Well...
After your daddy's
funeral, they say
he went home and just fell dead.
Oh.
I don't know about the
ways of God, ma'am,
but... I know your daddy and
Mr Bull lifted each other up.
The way you lift me up and
the way you lift up Red.
Everything living
lives from its heart,
and I wish I can give you
something to lift yours up.
Well, thank you,
Eddie. You just did.
What does he see?
When he looks at me, I feel
like he looks right into me.
He sees what matters to him,
ma'am. What's immediate.
The clouds and stuff, they
don't mean nothing to a horse.
Lights, sounds,
flashes... intentions.
That's what a horse notices.
Especially one as smart
as Big Red here.
And they can tell when the horse
next to them or behind them
wants to be first to
the food. Or the mare.
Or the finish line.
That's what matters to them.
Ain't that right?
It's never been done. But that
doesn't mean it won't work.
We offer 32 shareholders
exclusive breeding rights.
We call it a select opportunity.
Father would've loved that
phrase. How much per?
190,000.
A hundred and ninety?
That's more than
anybody's ever paid
for a breeding share. Lot more.
That's what makes
it exciting, Seth.
Horse racing's all
about excitement.
He's been a great colt, but he's
completely untried
as a three-year-old.
And the sons of
Bold Ruler, they're
long on speed, but
short on stamina.
Yeah, and his mother
was old when she
had him and Ogden
Phipps knew all that
when he could have chosen my colt.
But he didn't. And now
I've got Secretariat.
And he's got a horse named
Missed Opportunity.
Daddy used to always say
that rich people are rich
because they're smart
with their money.
And they're going to insist
on a performance clause.
No son of Bold Ruler has ever
won a single Triple Crown race.
That's a mile-and-a-half distance
that Secretariat's never
come close to running.
You're going to lose the farm
and the horse, everything.
This is a big deal. I have never
done anything like this before.
Nobody has.
You mind if I ask
why you called me?
Well...
Your father, he really
helped me and...
and work is good for grief.
I'm in.
Howard Keck on line one,
Bunker Hunt on line two.
Ladies and gentlemen,
start your engines.
- Mr Hunt? Penny Chenery.
- Mr Keck, Seth Hancock.
I was calling about a select
opportunity on Secretariat.
No, sir, he's not for sale.
No, we are moving to syndicate
his breeding rights.
It's a select opportunity.
We have 32 shares...
Yes, sir. It's a
great opportunity.
I will head that way. I'll see you
in a bit. All right, bye-bye.
Look, Seth, I've been a part
of lots of these deals,
but I've never been asked to pay
190 grand for a breeding share.
Nobody has.
Tell Mr Chenery's little girl
that she's priced this colt
like he's already won
the Triple Crown.
I'm calling on behalf
of Penny Chenery.
We will call him back
later. Thank you.
Dr Todd, please.
It's Elizabeth Ham.
No disrespect, sir, but
if he gets any better,
you're going to want
to be in on this.
All due respect,
but I got a pretty
good handle on where I want to be.
You could have her give me a
call me later this afternoon.
Yes, Mr Cleaver,
it's lots of money.
But my father used to tell me
you got to spend money to make it.
I'll put some thought
into it, all righty.
Thank you, sir.
Jock Whitney's a no. And
Mr Mellon's on line two.
Mr Mellon, thank you for
getting back to me.
Of course, I
understand, Mr Mellon.
I'll hold a share for you in
case you reconsider. Thank you.
Have you ever seen that?
No, not me. That boy a whopper.
I don't care how many
times they say no.
I don't care how
many times they tell
us we can't do it. I
am not giving up.
I will not live the rest
of my life in regret.
We are going to see
that horse run and win.
And we are going to live
rejoicing. Every day.
Amen.
Ronnie. Going to have some lunch?
Mrs Tweedy.
Yes, ma'am. Just
getting a bite to eat
before I go to the
ring. What about you?
I'm meeting somebody.
Hello, Mr Phipps,
- Thank you for coming.
- Miss Tweedy. My pleasure.
You know Ronnie
Turcotte, my rider?
Ronnie.
So, they call you Tiny?
- What?
- Mr Phipps...
- Thank you for coming.
- Sure.
Are we ready yet?
We're still thinking about it.
If I smell the air
correctly, Mrs Tweedy,
you're about to ask me
to spend a small fortune
to buy a share in a horse I
could've owned for nothing.
That's true, I am.
Nobody's buying yet, are they?
That's right. They need
someone to lead them.
You know that horse I chose
the day we flipped the coin?
She's the prettiest, best-tempered
horse in my whole stable.
And she couldn't
outrun my accountants.
So now you've got the Horse of
the Year, and I look foolish.
It's not foolish to be
unlucky, Mr Phipps.
Most men, if they had chosen
wrong and lost this horse
wouldn't think of investing in him
again, but you're
bigger than that.
And if you do invest in him
instead of being the man who
lost Secretariat in the past,
you'll be the one
who had the vision
to lead investors in his future.
His future is uncertain.
And I don't buy
shares in untested three-year-old.
But my accountants,
they may be slow afoot, but
they are quick to calculate
and they tell me that
you're in a rough spot.
So I'll buy that horse
of yours right now.
Seven million dollars. All cash.
I can't do that.
If he does what I
think he'll do, his
value will double, if not triple.
You do know what you're saying.
You're guaranteeing
that this horse
is going to win the Triple Crown.
The Derby, the Preakness
and the Belmont.
Three races, three states
in just five weeks.
Hasn't been done in 25 years.
There are a lot of good horsemen
think it can't be done any more.
Just understand, this
is what you're saying.
That is exactly what I'm saying.
Eight million.
No.
You're that stubborn?
I'm that right.
Have we made up our mind yet?
Yes, I think we have.
All this talk about
Secretariat. He
hasn't faced a horse
as good as Sham.
My horse is faster
and stronger. We're
not waiting for the
Derby to prove it.
We're going to the Wood Memorial.
And when Secretariat has to run
as far as my horse did today
he's going to fade
like the sunset.
- I guarantee it.
- He is ridiculous.
Well, Seth, what do
you make of that?
I think that fellow is going to
make Lucien say things in French
my mama would spank him for.
This guy will not shut his face.
Lucien Laurin cannot
train a winning horse.
Ok, so he's saying that I'm
incompetent. He never shuts up.
This guy, he couldn't
train a flea to jump.
He couldn't train a monkey
to pick at his own butt.
- Step out here with me.
- He could not train...
The guy couldn't train
his own bowel movements.
The Wood is in New York. You're
going to need a new dress.
They say, Secretariat's owner
is striking and charismatic.
- Penny Tweedy.
- I saw the paper.
- Yes. Didn't Seth do a great job?
- I'd like to say congratulations,
but I am a lawyer, and I know
what performance guarantees mean.
Jack, I don't know how to earn a
reward without taking a risk.
Is it really true Ogden Phipps
offered you eight million dollars?
It's true. He wouldn't
have made that offer
unless he thought Secretariat
would be worth twice that.
The richest man in the world can
take a risk like that, Penny.
- But I can't.
- You?
I just mean, do what you
want with your money.
But I can't spend my money
on a risk like that.
Don't worry. I understand.
Not a cent of your money.
I didn't mean it like
that. I just meant...
I understood how you
meant it, Jack.
Let's talk later.
There are words of wisdom
that have sustained me
throughout my darkest times.
If you don't mind, I'd like
to share them with you.
I'm all ears, Miss Ham.
Good evening, K-mart shoppers.
Fifteen minutes to
post. Fifteen minutes.
There he is.
Edward, it's big enough
for a Clydesdale.
It ain't big enough for Red. Maybe
he's still hiding fat
from the winter.
Does he look fat to you?
What are you doing?
The same thing I've done with
every belt I ever owned.
Come on, Red.
Miss Penny, look this way, please.
You ok, Miss Ham?
I hate what she's
having to go through,
and there's so little
I can do to help.
Someday I'd like to be
able to do for that horse
half of what you do for its owner.
Lucien, those are the grandest
words anyone's ever said to me.
- Lucien.
- Mr Phipps. How are you?
- Good morning.
- Best to you.
- Good luck today.
- Thank you.
The horses now being loaded in
for the big race of the day,
the match-up between
Secretariat and Sham.
You're going to eat
dirt today, Ronnie.
The final test before the
campaign for the Triple Crown,
the first test of
whether the big horse
from Virginia can
cover the distance.
Time to see who's
got the real horse.
The horses are in the gate.
Secretariat a bit uneasy, but that
seems characteristic for him.
- And they're off.
- Yeah, he goes right to the back.
Horses breaking nicely. Angle
Light moving from the outside.
Secretariat settling in
at the rear of the pack.
- Ok. It's ok.
- Come on, Ronnie.
Heading toward the rail.
Step Nicely in second.
Sham in good position
running in third.
Secretariat seems to be labouring.
- Go, Red.
- He always does this. It's ok.
Angle Light holds
the lead into the
turn. Sham in perfect position.
Sham moves up. Secretariat
pressing forward.
- Come on, Red.
- Go. Go.
Come on, Red. Come on.
Pincay's waiting for
Turcotte to move.
Now, Red, now.
Whoo.
Come on.
Angle Light and Sham
driving for home.
Secretariat starting to challenge.
They straighten away
in the stretch.
Angle Light holding
on to the lead now.
Sham second, far outside
is Secretariat.
Coming on the 16th pole,
Angle Light in front
by a length and a
quarter. Sham is second.
- God.
- What's he doing?
Angle Light in front.
Sham on the outside.
Sham and Angle Light driving to
the wire. Secretariat fading.
- No.
- Go. Go.
It's Angle Light and Sham. Angle
Light and Sham at the wire.
Secretariat a stunning
and distant third.
All right, Sham. Way to go.
You know I speak for
everyone. One loss
can happen. Two is
non-performance.
- I understand.
- I'm sure you do.
Another son of Bold Ruler,
all speed and no distance.
Magnificent. Magnificent.
Next time we'll bury
him even worse.
You cost me ten grand,
Turcotte. Hey, loser.
Who are you calling a loser?
Think you can do any better?
- Eddie.
- Ronnie. Ronnie.
What was that?
He didn't fire. He
didn't sound right.
- What do you mean?
- In his other races
- he sounded like a freight train.
- Come with me. Just go inside.
Sit.
We just lost a race that we
could not afford to lose.
We finished third. Third.
In front of Ogden Phipps.
I've got a slew of other investors
here. What am I
supposed to tell them?
Just tell them the truth.
The horse had a bad day.
The horse? We're
blaming the horse now?
And you? How could
you hold him back
that long? What were you thinking?
I didn't hold him back. I rode
him the same way I always do.
The only reason Sham didn't
beat us worse is because
his jockey couldn't
believe what was
happening. He was waiting for you.
The only reason I
don't fire you both
is we're leaving for
Kentucky tomorrow.
Do what you think is right, ma'am.
It's not Ronnie's fault. He
had him where he should be.
Well, if it's not the
horse and it's not Ronnie
then you had better figure
out what happened today
and you had better fix it.
Because if that is
the best he can do
at this distance, we are finished.
- Has he eaten anything?
- Nothing.
And this a horse that's never
missed a meal in his life.
How much oats you
usually give him?
Sixteen quarts.
- Twenty-five pounds of hay.
- A day?
That's more than a couple of
pregnant mares would put away.
Yeah, well...
ok, now. Easy. I'm not
going to hurt you.
I don't think he the one
going to get hurt, Doc.
Settle down.
Lucien, you want to
give me a hand here?
- No, thanks.
- You scared of him?
This horse has been
waiting two years
for me to put a hand
next to his mouth.
I'm not going to do that.
Ooh.
I think I got your
problem here, Lucien.
He's got an abscess.
Hello?
I'm calling for Kate Tweedy,
please? It's her mother.
Kate. Your mother's on the phone.
Mum.
Oh, I just wanted
to see how you're doing.
Hey, I'm kind of busy right now.
We're getting ready for a march.
Mum? Are you ok with that?
Oh...
Kate...
our political beliefs can change,
but our need to do what
we believe is right...
that doesn't.
I'm proud of you.
Thanks, Mum. Hey, I got
to go. Can we talk later?
Sure.
- Are you all right?
- Sure. Yeah, we'll talk later.
Ok. Bye.
Doc found a big
abscess in Red's lip.
It probably hurt him all
the way around the track.
Ain't nobody seen it
because Red won't
soften up his mouth
for nobody but you.
- Oh... Lucien...
- Forget it.
Let's get him ready for the Derby.
Ronnie.
I am so sorry.
I didn't know what happened
before. Apparently...
In preparation for
the 99th running of
the Kentucky Derby,
please welcome Secretariat.
We love you, Big Red.
Story's over here.
Do you think Secretariat is ready?
We're very excited.
Is Secretariat ready
for this race?
Yes, indeed.
Listen, we'll take
care of the horse,
you take care of the reporters.
I don't know what to say.
You're as big a story
as the horse, ok.
If you want him fit,
you take care of them.
- Welcome to the Derby.
- Thank you.
So that's Pancho over
there with Sham, right?
Sure is.
Can't wait till you win this
Derby, so we can go home.
I keep hearing rumours.
Secretariat's got bone chips,
bad ankles, bad knees.
Sham's burning up the track and
Secretariat has gone missing.
So is his owner.
She'll be at the press conference.
The only thing she
hates worse than
talking about herself
is backing down.
I can't wait much longer.
All right, gentlemen, I guess
we're going to get started.
Let's open it up for questions.
Pancho, is it true you're
predicting Sham's victory?
Lucien, there are rumours your
horse is hurt. Any comment?
Pancho, how are you feeling
about Sham's readiness?
Fantastic. You've all seen his
workouts. He's never
looked better.
Penny, Sham's turning
in awesome workouts.
- When will you work Secretariat?
- Soon.
Any concern Secretariat will run
the same way he did his last race?
Yes.
Pancho, some people
think Secretariat
didn't appear to be himself
- in Wood Memorial.
- Didn't appear to be himself?
Is that journalism-ese for
getting your butt whipped?
Horse racing is unforgiving for
trainers, horses and housewives.
Let me tell you
what you're going to hear
from the Secretariat people.
Excuses, excuses, excuses.
Let me tell you what you're
going to hear from me.
We beat Big Red at the Wood, and
we're going to beat
him here again.
Any comment, Miss Tweedy?
How much pressure are you feeling
from your investors right now?
Well, it's like every
other all-or-nothing,
multimillion-dollar gamble we
housewives make every day.
Miss Tweedy didn't hear me, so
I'm going to make it very clear.
Secretariat is going down.
I guarantee it.
Pancho's starting to
brag like a boxer.
Maybe he plans on
taking up prizefighting
after he finishes horse racing.
Sham has about as much chance
of beating Secretariat
as Pancho has of
beating Muhammad Ali.
I know it hurt, but I
got to do it, Red.
How's it look?
Same. Still ain't ate.
I'm going to have Ronnie
take him out in the morning.
See how it goes.
It's nothing like
Sham's been running.
Nothing like Secretariat's been
running. Penny's not talking.
Eddie?
No, ma'am. He's
still off his feed.
Miss Tweedy? Miss Tweedy?
How's your horse doing?
He'll answer that question
for himself on race day.
- You're Bill... Nack, right?
- Yes, ma'am.
I've read you. You write like
a poet. Why do you do this?
For years they had me
covering politicians.
I wanted to write about the
other end of the horse.
Why do you do this, Miss Penny?
I'm his voice.
Penny, we think the abscess is
gone, but he still hasn't eaten
and Ronnie says his breathing
is still a little shallow.
I don't know. I don't know
if we should run him.
Can I have a moment with him?
All right, then. I'll
see you in the morning.
Ok, Eddie.
Thank you.
Hey, Kentucky.
Big old Red done ate his
breakfast this morning.
And you about to see something
that you ain't never
even seen before.
So get ready.
Get ready.
♪ We will sing one song ♪
♪ For my old Kentucky home ♪
Do you think he'll be ok?
He ate his food this morning.
It's your day, baby.
Excuse me.
Hold it.
- He's posing again.
- This way.
- Good luck today, Miss Penny.
- Thank you.
- Go, Secretariat.
- Yeah.
Easy, Red.
Safe trip, boys.
Bring it home, Red.
Big day, Mrs Tweedy.
Yeah.
There you go, boy.
Ok, get him in.
Get him in there.
Hold it, hold it.
Come on now, Red, come on. Don't
get distracted. Focus. You got it.
Go ahead. Hold up, now.
Steady. All right.
Come on, Big Red.
All right, let's go.
They're at the post. Secretariat
throws his head just a bit.
And they're off in the 99th
running of the Kentucky Derby.
Shecky Greene sprinting to the
front, Royal and
Regal just behind.
Gold Bag quickly
moving into third.
And Secretariat breaks
last from the gate.
Sham moving up to
challenge for the lead.
Royal and Regal now being moved
to the inside, looking for room.
Gold Bag is up on the outside.
Run them down, run them down, Red.
Run them down. Come on. Come on.
Sham and a dozen others moving
into striking position.
Secretariat is at the
back of the pack.
I can't watch this.
You have to stay here
and take this with me.
Sham working into strong position.
Sham now third on the
outside by two lengths.
Fast first quarter in 23.2.
There you go. Come on.
As they're heading into the
back straight Sham moving up,
challenging for the lead.
Navajo, Forego, and
Warbucks beginning
to move up, followed
by My Gallant...
- Come on.
- Run them down, Red.
Sham moving up into third.
Gold Bag just in front of him
as they clear the half mile.
Secretariat still
lagging off the pace.
I'm sick of this dirt.
Let's get rolling.
Sham closing to the
rail. A speedy 1:11.4.
- Gotta move him, Ronnie.
- Let's go.
- Come on, Ronnie, move.
- Sham has taken the lead.
Secretariat well
back of the leaders
and failing to mount a challenge.
Entering the final
turn, Secretariat
surging past Angle Light.
- Come on, Red.
- Final quarter mile.
Come on, Red. Pace yourself.
This yours. This yours.
- Come on, Ronnie.
- Run.
Go.
They're at the head of the
stretch and Sham is the leader.
He leads it by a length.
Secretariat is in the centre
of the racetrack and driving.
It's Sham and Secretariat,
neck and neck.
They're in the stretch.
It's Secretariat
on the outside to take the lead.
Sham holding in second.
Run him, Ronnie.
It's Secretariat at the finish.
He wins it by two lengths.
- Holy.
- Whoo.
I knew he was going to do it.
Whoo. All right.
We won. I knew you
could do it, Mum.
Congratulations.
- I can't believe it.
- You did it.
Penny, it's been 25 years since
horse racing's had a
Triple Crown winner.
Now, is this the horse that
finally breaks that streak?
We still have a lot of work to do.
But at least we've given
ourselves the chance.
Congratulations, Penny
and Secretariat
on the fastest Derby ever.
Here's hoping we
see the same thing
two weeks from now
at the Preakness.
Girls. The race is about to start.
The excitement over this
super-horse has captured
the imaginations of Americans
and brought together people across
great divisions of culture,
politics and passion.
Go, Secretariat, go.
Of course he's the
favourite in this
race as we look at
him in his barn.
He's getting ready now to make the
walk across to the saddling area.
I'm Jack Whitaker, along with
Heywood Hale Broun, Chic Anderson
and Frank Wright.
We welcome you to
the 98th running of the Preakness.
- Hey, there's Mum.
- I can't believe that's Mum.
- Wow. She looks awesome.
- I can't believe she's on TV.
- That's amazing.
- So cool.
With three horses in, I'm going
to give this to Chic Anderson
who will call the race for you.
We're about ready to
go as Ecole Etage...
Secretariat bobs his head.
We're still looking...
And they're off.
For the early lead, that's Deadly
Dream. On the
outside, Ecole Etage.
Settling into second,
Torsion. Sham
has good position,
third on the rail,
and Secretariat is last,
again, as they move...
Red's last.
He's last. Why is he always last?
But here comes
Secretariat. He's moving
fast. And he's going
to the outside...
He's going for the lead, and it
is right now he's looking for it.
- See him right there?
- All right, Red.
- Come on.
- Yes.
Secretariat is right alongside.
Sham now going to the
outside in third.
We're moving down the backstretch.
They're incredible. Look at them.
Secretariat the leader by...
- Dad, you seeing this?
- I see him.
And it looks like Ecole Etage has
had it, dropping back in third.
Here's the race, folks.
Secretariat trying to hold it.
Look at this.
Head of the stretch,
Secretariat at two and a half.
Sham under a strong
left-handed whip.
Secretariat by two lengths.
Sham driving second.
It is Secretariat.
He's coming to the
wire. He wins it
by two and a half,
almost three.
I don't believe this.
And it was a powerhouse race again
by the big, strong Secretariat.
Here is Mrs Tweedy,
who has just won
the second of two very
important races to her.
Secretariat has now
won the Kentucky
Derby and the Preakness Stakes,
and this time he did
it the same way.
What is it, Lucien? What's wrong?
Nothing.
He just won Preakness,
like he won the Derby.
You keep staring into your coffee.
Are you worried about Red?
Since Citation did it in 1948,
seven horses have won the
Derby and then the Preakness.
Every single one of them has
failed to win the Triple Crown.
He just won the first
two in record time.
Yeah, and the Belmont is the
graveyard of speed horses.
It's the longest race
they'll ever run.
What do you suggest?
Normally we rest him, right?
- Yeah. Sure.
- Let him recuperate.
Yeah.
But you don't want to back off.
In all my years of training
I've never had a horse who loves
to run the way this one does.
You take that horse out one day,
he's going to run faster the next.
My instinct?
My instinct is to train him.
Hard. To stoke that fire.
But if I'm wrong,
then they will say
that not only did
we ruin the horse's
chances at the Triple Crown...
they may say we ruined the horse.
Red is not afraid.
And neither am I.
Just remember, if we push
him instead of rest him...
it could be dangerous.
Nobody knows how much he can take.
He does.
He knows.
Mr Martin. Secretariat has
beaten your horse twice.
What makes this race different?
Any good horseman will tell you
that Secretariat
is built for speed
and Sham is built for distance.
But, of course, Miss Tweedy
believes that her horse
has somehow magically
inherited both.
I believe that this
race is going to prove
that her woman's intuition
will only take her so far.
Penny. What about all the
attention Secretariat's getting?
Covers of both Time and Newsweek.
Well...
Let me tell you something about
all this talk about super-horse.
Sham broke the Derby record, too.
He ran the second-fastest
Derby. He ran
the second-fastest
Preakness... ever.
We were right there with the red
horse every step of the way.
And now we're getting
ready to run the
longest of the Triple Crown races.
When we're done, you'll be
calling Sham the super-horse.
Any comment, Penny?
Well, I'd have to say I agree
completely with Mr Martin.
His horse did run the
second-fastest ever.
I'm out of here.
Where are you going? Come on.
That woman, she's so arrogant.
Lucien will do
anything to prove he's
not a loser. That's
where they're weak.
We rest our horse,
they push theirs.
On race day, we push
him even harder.
We push him until he comes apart.
1:12 and a fifth.
Oh, that's good time.
Sure you want to send him
a mile next time out?
I'm just asking.
They think we're
training him too hard.
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome
to the Belmont Ball.
It's not bad.
Your daddy would be so proud.
Where did you find her?
Told her I was taller when
I stood on my wallet.
Miss Chenery.
Mr Laurin. You look
exceptionally handsome tonight.
Well, I wanted to go on record, I
left my hat at home, just for you.
I brought you a little something
from a mutual friend of ours.
I offered to give it
back to Seth, but
he too thought you should have it.
The tails side is very nice.
Lucien, you know
you are absolutely
the best trainer that
I could have ever...
You're the best owner I ever saw.
Turcotte and Edward say he's the
smartest horse they've ever seen.
Maybe. I've trained
horses my whole life.
I still don't have
the slightest idea
what they know and
what they don't know.
Three years ago I
would've said that a
racehorse didn't care
who his owner was.
But then he's not a racehorse.
He's Secretariat.
And I think tomorrow
he'll be wearing wings.
- Mum. I'm sorry I'm late.
- Kate.
Oh.
You're not late. You're
perfectly on time.
Look at you. You're so beautiful.
And you're all grown up.
You look beautiful,
too, Mum. All grown up.
I'm so proud of you.
Thank you.
Oh.
- I love you.
- Mum.
- Come here.
Oh, Sarah.
Oh, look at you.
Missed you.
- You're amazing.
- Look at what I've got.
- Is that the coin?
- The coin?
- The coin.
- Oh.
Here. Go ahead. You can hold it.
You guys keep it safe. Don't
lose it tonight. It's important.
Come on, boys. Let's go.
They are growing up. All of them.
Kate is so beautiful in that
gown. And Sarah in hers.
Yeah. Wish I'd bought
those gowns earlier.
Something I need you to know.
I want you to win.
And win or lose,
you've taught our children
what a real woman is.
What it is to believe
in yourself, and I
never could have
taught those things.
And you've taught
me something, too.
Come here.
I realised something.
I've already won.
I made it here. I didn't quit.
I've run my race.
Now you run yours.
A record crowd is expected today
as Secretariat makes his bid
for horse racing immortality.
The race is scheduled for
5:38 this afternoon.
Forecasters are predicting
temperatures in the mid-90s.
- Easy. Easy, easy.
- Hold him, Eddie. Hold him.
- Easy, Red. Easy.
- Watch yourself.
Calm yourself. Calm yourself.
Let him walk. Walk off his nerves.
Horse seems pretty fired up.
He knows what's going on.
- I saw Big Red.
- Good girl, sweetheart.
- Is that the one?
- Oh yeah, right.
I don't make a lot
of guarantees, but
listen, this one you can bet on.
You're going to eat
dirt today, Ronnie.
I don't think so.
Go hard for the lead. Draw him up
close. If he comes, he's ours. Ok?
Lot of track today,
Red. A lot of track.
Ok, Ronnie, don't
send him out, all
right? But don't
choke him, either.
Remember, we have a
mile and a half to
cover. And one last
thing, don't...
What? Burst his heart?
Just bring him home, Ronnie.
Come on, Big Red.
Go, Big Red.
The eighth race,
the 105th running of
the Belmont Stakes.
- Here we go.
- Oh, here he comes.
- Big Red.
- Go, Big Red.
Oh, I think he's coming. Oh.
Big Red.
Very big day, Mrs Tweedy.
Ok, Big Red.
Come on, Sham.
Hey. Hey.
Ah, look at him.
You got a couple
thousand I can borrow?
Come on, Red.
He looks fantastic.
Oh. I was afraid you
wouldn't show up.
Well... got a tip on a horse.
- Yeah.
- Where is Lucien?
Oh.
Good luck.
The remaining field,
now entering the gate.
Easy there, easy.
That's good.
Only five horses in
the field today,
many of the owners conceding that
this is a match race between
Secretariat and Sham.
The field is at the post.
Chic Anderson with the call.
Horses now loaded in.
And they're off.
Secretariat surging from the gate.
Secretariat away very well, has
good position on the rail.
Secretariat driving
immediately into the lead.
Secretariat and Sham off to
a surprisingly rapid pace.
He's going out too fast.
Sham, on the outside, is
also moving along strongly.
Now it's Sham. Sham and
Secretariat are...
This is no good.
- Why is he going to the lead?
- Because I don't know.
Go. Go.
Sham pushing Secretariat
into an even faster pace.
As they round the first turn...
drawing away down
to the backstretch.
Sham pressing Secretariat
even faster.
Secretariat refusing to
yield. Driving forward.
This is unbelievable. No
horse can take this pace.
Sham pushes forward to
challenge for the rail.
Come on, Ronnie. Come on.
Three quarters, a
blistering 1:09.4.
There you go. There you go.
Secretariat and Sham
locked in a deadly duel.
It's another eight
lengths to Private
Smiles, who is trailing the field.
It's Secretariat and Sham.
- Oh, man. This is a catastrophe.
- It's too fast.
Before the turn, it's Secretariat.
Come on, Big Red.
Let him run, Ronnie. Let him run.
Sham and Secretariat pulling
away at blazing speed.
With a half mile still to run,
Secretariat sprinting away.
Four lengths.
Six.
Nine. Eleven.
Entering the final
turn, Secretariat
is moving like a
tremendous machine.
That's impossible.
He laughs at fear,
afraid of nothing.
He does not shy away
from the sword.
He cannot stand still
when the trumpet sounds.
Oh. Glory.
The lead is now 24 lengths.
- Twenty-six lengths.
- Whoo-hoo.
- Twenty-eight and still surging.
- Ride him, Ronnie. Ride him.
- Go, Red.
- Whoa.
- God.
Ronnie.
Ronnie, don't fall off.
There you go, Red.
Secretariat by 30.
Secretariat wins.
Secretariat wins by 31 lengths.
You have a great horse.