(UPBEAT 1950s MUSIC PLAYING)
(UPBEAT 1950s MUSIC
CONTINUES ON RADIO)
GUS: Bernie, seriously...
this is where they asked us
to meet? (LAUGHING)
BERNIE: Yeah. What do you mean?
GUS: (GASPS)
Oh, I think I see her.
BERNIE: Where?
GUS: Oh, that's gotta be her.
(CONTINUES LAUGHING)
So, what are we gonna do?
Are we gonna grab
a milkshake, Bernie?
Is that why we're here?
BERNIE: Oh, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, I guess.
GUS: All right. You're gonna
owe me big for this.
(CLEARS THROAT)
So...
(WHISTLES)
You think I should have worn
the other shirt?
You look nice. (LAUGHS)
I don't know, Gus. Maybe, she...
What if she don't like
the look of me or something?
Bernie. Come on.
Are you serious? What about her?
Aren't you dying to see
what she looks like?
She could be a dog.
No, she isn't a dog.
(SCOFFS) She could be.
I already know what
she looks like in my head.
- She ain't a dog.
- (SNICKERS)
So, uh...
You been talking to her for
weeks on the phone, right?
- Yeah.
- Right?
Yeah.
(CAR DOOR OPENS)
She likes you
from talking to you, Bernie.
And I don't think
you gotta worry about her...
getting a good look at ya.
That ain't never
been your problem.
Let's go.
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
(KNOCKS ON WINDOW) Come on.
Should have worn
the other shirt.
(GUS EXHALES)
(GUS BLOWING)
I'm the one taking a risk.
Doubling with some girl
I ain't never even spoke to...
let alone seen!
I don't know
why this Miriam girl...
says it's gotta be a double
date, anyway. (LAUGHS)
Maybe she's not
sure about me yet.
How can anybody
not be sure about you, Bernie?
Yeah. Thanks, Gus.
Yeah, hey,
don't tell none of the guys...
down at the station about this.
It's not like you've
never been on a date before.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
- CATHERINE: All set there?
- Uh...
Excuse me.
Are you Miriam?
No. (LAUGHS)
I'm her friend.
She's, uh...
Hi. How you doin'? I'm Gus.
- Catherine.
- It's nice to meet you.
(LAUGHS)
Okay. We'll talk later.
(CHUCKLES) Bye.
Hi.
Wait.
You are Bernie Webber, right?
Uh, yeah.
Yeah, I'm Bernie.
(LAUGHS)
GUS: Hey, you two,
let's go grab a drink.
Yeah.
You wanna go?
Sure.
How you doin'? I'm Gus.
You know, for a minute there...
I thought it was
Smokey the Bear...
makin' a call in that booth.
(STAMMERS)
'Cause of your jacket.
On. (LAUGHS)
CATHERINE: Bernie...
Miriam's never been on a boat.
She's scared of the water.
Has she never?
I told her I don't know how...
she's gonna date a guy
in the Coast Guard.
I'm not scared.
I live on the Cape.
Don't worry, Miriam.
You know, we, uh...
We all get scared out there.
I'm not afraid
of the water, Bernie.
It scares me at night,
that's all.
You can't see what's underneath.
Just more water.
(CHUCKLES)
(UPBEAT 1950s MUSIC PLAYING)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
GUS: You know, I get funnier
as the night goes on.
So, why, uh... Why didn't you
wanna meet me for a date?
Why'd you...
Why'd you wait so long?
I didn't know if you'd be a...
If I'd what?
- You know.
- No.
You're so handsome...
I just didn't know
if you'd be attracted to me.
Oh, God, no, Miriam.
You're exactly
how I pictured you.
Yeah?
Oh, yeah.
Better.
(LAUGHS)
You know... (CLEARS THROAT)
My brother, uh...
He always says that, "When
you know, you just know."
Which one?
Uh, all of it.
I guess, you know, everything.
No. I mean, which brother?
Oh. (SIGHS) AY...
Uh, Paul. My brother, Paul.
He's the one who fought
over in Germany, right?
In Germany, yeah.
He's the oldest.
Father's favorite.
All three of my brothers
went over to the war.
He's your father's what?
(GUS LAUGHING)
GUS: Hey.
We should get Miriam
out on a boat tonight.
What do you say, Bernie, hmm?
We take out the dory.
It'll be fantastic.
You know we can't do that, Gus.
We could get in trouble.
Come on, Bernie. It'll be fun.
Rules are rules.
No. (LAUGHS)
We don't gotta row out far.
Just so this sweet girl
can say...
she's been on a boat, that's it.
A rowboat? No.
(SCOFFS) No.
No, no. Small boats that...
How about one of those bigger
boats? Tied up to the dock?
If Bernie's with me, I'll do it.
GUS: Oh, a fishing boat?
(LAUGHS)
Those fishermen
don't want us around...
unless we're pullin' them in.
They think they own
the goddamn water.
- (CATHERINE LAUGHS)
- They're not very nice.
Come on. Don't be
such a fathead, Miriam.
Yeah.
Let's go out on the dory.
What's there to be afraid of?
(WHISPERS)
What's underneath, right?
Hey there, Mr. Stello.
How's it goin'?
- Hey, Bernie.
- Mr. Ryder.
Hey, so you see that girl
sitting over there?
The one with the coat
looks like a bear, Bernie?
- Yeah.
- Can't miss her.
I said the same thing myself.
Funny you should say that.
Looks like Smokey, right?
Smokey the Bear.
I don't know no Smokey, Bernie.
Oh, it's just a cartoon.
Anyway, Mr. Stello,
she thinks...
she's scared of
going out on a boat.
And I don't think
we should row out on a dory.
I don't want her gettin' sick
on that nice, big coat.
So, I was wondering if...
So, you wanna take her on
the Anna G round the harbor?
Yeah.
CARL: Can't row out on that dory
even if ya wanted,
right, Bernie?
- Carl, stop.
- Year anniversary's coming.
My sister's now
livin' in my house.
How's it going with you, Bernie?
That's enough, Carl.
He did all he could.
I am sorry, Mr. Nickerson.
I didn't mean to upset you.
Just wanted to ask Mr. Stello...
about borrowing a boat.
- GUS: Got you. I got you.
- (CATHERINE LAUGHS)
This is a boat. (LAUGHS)
BERNIE: Give me your hands.
- It's okay.
- (BOTH LAUGHING)
(PLAYING 1950s MUSIC)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
♪ Now the hacienda 's dark ♪
♪ The town is sleeping ♪
♪ Now the time
has come to part ♪
♪ The time for weeping ♪
♪ Vaya con dios, my darling ♪
BERNIE: Just, uh...
- Just follow my arms, okay?
- Mmm-hmm.
- Stay with me.
- (BOTH LAUGHING)
- It's all about the rhythm.
- Mmm-hmm.
Okay? So it's, uh...
So it's, uh...
Here we go.
BOTH: One, two, three.
Right, left, right.
One, two, three.
- One, two, three. One...
- (LAUGHS)
I can't one, two, three to this.
- Let's just sit down, Bernie.
- No, sweetheart.
Look, all you gotta do is you
gotta relax and be patient...
and settle in my hand.
Hey, look, just... Here...
settle in my hand.
You feel that?
Mmm.
Just listen to the music, right?
And... One, two, three.
One, two, three.
Right, left, right.
You're doing great.
♪ Now the dawn
is breaking through ♪
♪ A gray tomorrow ♪
♪ But the memories we share
Are there to borrow ♪
(SIGHS)
♪ Vaya con dios, my darling ♪
Will you marry me?
What?
Uh...
No.
(INHALES SHAKILY)
♪ Vaya con dios, my darling ♪
♪ Vaya con dios... ♪
BERNIE: Miriam, hold on!
(MIRIAM SIGHS)
It's cold, sweetheart.
Don't you wanna go back inside?
The band's not through.
It's cold. Do you feel that?
There's a storm comin'.
Okay.
Okay, what?
Okay, let's get married.
(STAMMERING)
I just... I don't wanna...
Wanna what?
Well, it's only been
a few months...
and it's still winter,
after all.
And, look,
there's a storm comin'.
It's just like this one
that come through last year.
What does that...
I heard it's gonna miss us.
Yeah, but maybe not.
You never know.
Some people, they're
just not cut out for this.
Sometimes you go out
and you don't come back.
Are you talking
about the storm...
or marriage, Bernie?
I think I'm talking about
the storm, right?
You're scared of a storm?
No.
I don't want to
disappoint nobody.
And...
I don't wanna lose you.
I love you.
So...
Yeah, let's get married.
You sure?
Oh, yeah.
When?
You want me to pick a date? No!
When do you wanna get married?
April 16th.
Okay.
Okay. April 16th it is.
But, uh, I gotta ask
permission from Cluff first.
You gotta ask permission?
Yeah, it's from
my commanding officer.
It's Coast Guard regulation.
But I promise
I'll ask him tomorrow.
Okay, Bernie.
Let's get you home.
(MIRIAM LAUGHS)
- Man, you can dance.
- (CHUCKLES)
Ah, look at that. It's already
starting to snow. Hmm?
(WIND HOWLING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(SCREAMS)
(GROANING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
SYBERT: Can you hear me
over this hummin', Captain?
That fracture
they welded last month...
is not gonna hold
in these seas, Cap.
Takes a bad jolt,
she could fracture again.
(MAN SHOUTS INDISTINCTLY)
I don't have to go on deck, Cap.
I can hear it from
right down here.
That weld is really hummin'.
It's hummin', sir.
The weld is, uh... Hummin'.
Uh, I'd like to take it down
to three knots, please.
(SCOFFS) Uh...
If we don't slow her down,
Captain...
we might not have a, uh...
A position to hold.
Uh, no problem, Cap.
Uh, holdin' at seven knots.
Thank you, sir.
(MAN CONTINUES
SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
Hey, POP?
I hear it.
You wanna go up on deck?
Have a look at
those crack arrestors...
holdin' that weld together?
(LAUGHS) Might as well
go be get a hat, Popo.
What did he say?
Uh, he says he would like you...
to consider taking a hat
with you, as well.
(LAUGHS)
Get some sleep.
TINY: J' For the people
all said sit down ♪
♪ Sit down,
you're rockin' the boat ♪
Hey, Pops!
What do you know
about this weather?
It's killin' me and
young Eldon here.
Tiny, sure it's the weather?
Maybe it's your singing.
♪ For the people
all said sit down ♪
♪ Sit down,
you're rockin' the boat ♪
Come on.
♪ The people all said sit down ♪
♪ Sit down,
you're rockin' the boat ♪
Shut up, shut up, shut up.
Ah, it's gonna get worse.
(PANTING)
FRANK: Sybert!
I didn't make it topside.
That weld can't hold
in these seas.
You gotta slow her down.
I'm calling the captain back.
(G ROANS)
(SEAMEN SCREAMING)
(SEAMEN YELPING)
(SEAMEN GROANING)
(GROANS LOUDLY)
SEAMAN 1: It's coming in!
- You okay, Pops?
- Yeah.
(GRUNTS)
SEAMAN 2: Go up!
(SEAMEN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
We've got a hull fracture
in the engine room!
All hands muster mattresses...
blankets, whatever you can
get your hands on!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
Tchuda.
Yeah, boy?
I can't get anyone
on the bridge.
I need you to go up
and tell the captain...
we got an 18-foot fracture
in our hull.
Tell him these pumps
are holding for now...
but we don't put her into
port, we're gonna wreck.
Captain don't
understand me, Bouloo.
I know he can't
understand you...
but he doesn't listen
to anyone, anyway.
- (WIND HOWLING)
- (BREATHING HEAVILY)
(G ROANS)
(GASPING)
Jesus, Mary, and Joseph.
(WIND HOWLING)
(BLOWS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER ON RADIO)
- Cold out there? (CHUCKLES)
- Yeah.
You still tryin' to
fix that darn thing?
Yeah.
Oh, come on.
Fitzy, it's useless.
Let the guy
who fixes it come fix it.
I would if he would show up.
What's this on the radio,
ship breaking up?
That's the Fort Mercer.
Fort Mercer?
She's a big lady.
She's a T2 tanker.
Started radioin'
a couple hours ago.
Apparently she's got
a big crack in her hull.
It's spillin' oil
all over the place.
She's, uh, about 20 miles east
off of Nantucket.
It sounds like Boston
and Nantucket...
are sendin' out
their entire fleet, huh?
We could be next.
They're saying
gale force winds...
50 to 60 miles per hour.
Yeah. Yeah.
ANNOUNCER: (ON RADIO)
waves at 50 feet. Over.
It's gonna be a mess.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER ON RADIO
CONTINUES)
(SIGHS)
Oh, uh, Bernie, Bernie.
Uh, Miriam called for you.
Yeah.
Good luck, pal.
- CLUFF: Yeah.
- Mr. Cluff?
It's me, Bernie, sir.
Webber. Pick yourself a crew.
Go out there,
help them fishermen...
secure their boats to the pier.
Oh. Uh, yes, sir.
Sir, I need to
ask you a question.
Uh...
I need permission about
a girl, you know?
Permission?
Permission... For a girl?
FITZGERALD: Mr. Cluff,
it's working.
Yes, sir.
Not now, Webber.
(STAMMERS) But, sir. It's
not just "some girl," sir...
Not now, Webber.
We're back up.
Cluster here's
the Mercer rescue, right?
And this here other pip,
two miles from here.
We must still be gettin'
phantom echoes.
How we supposed to tell
where anything is out there?
When's that technician
comin', Fitzpatrick?
And where
the hell's Chief Bangs?
Uh...
It's Fitzgerald, sir.
(IN SOUTHERN ACCENT)
Chief Bangs...
is in the mess hall, sir.
You makin' fun of my accent...
'cause I'm not from around here?
No, Mr. Cluff.
Why are you still
standing here, Webber?
Sir, but...
Take Livesey here with you,
go tie up them fishin' boats.
Yes, sir.
You want me to go
with Webber, sir?
Secure fishing boats?
You didn't hear me, Livesey?
Uh, yeah, you with Webber.
Sorry, Richie.
His orders, you know.
(RICHIE SIGHS)
(ALL PRAYING)
That's enough time,
what do you think, huh?
We're takin' on water, we
gotta launch them lifeboats.
Why you gotta be
such a jackass, Brown?
Least we can do, pray for
the captain, Chief Collagen...
Rest of them men. All good men.
Hey, ain't we good men, Quirey?
Ah, don't get me wrong.
Prayin's great,
but it ain't everything.
We need to actually
do somethin'.
FRANK: Sybert.
A word.
That hothead Brown, he wants
to launch the lifeboats.
The lifeboats?
Quirey, he wants to do nothin'.
Now, between them,
the two of them...
are getting the men worked up.
(FRANK GROANS)
Now, I figure that you know
the boat better than anybody.
You're practically
married to it.
So, I think
they'll listen to ya.
Listen to me?
Pop, those men don't like me.
Nobody on the ship likes me
but you and Tchuda.
They might not like you, but
they'll know to listen to ya.
We don't know if the captain
got off an S.O.S.
Radio room's gone.
We can't call nobody!
It's just Garcia over there
with a little shortwave...
tryin' to pick up chatter.
I mean, as far as we know...
nobody even knows
we're out here.
Now I'm saying we launch
them lifeboats now...
and we get off this ship
while we can.
How are you gonna get 'em down
in the water in this storm?
It can't be done,
those boats are too small.
It's suicide, Brown.
BROWN: You can't do this,
you can't do that.
What do you
want us to do, Quirey?
Just sit up here and do nothin'?
That's it, no officers,
no orders.
Every man for himself.
That ain't the way, Brown.
That never did
nothing for nobody.
Now, the ship's split...
at the bulkheads separating
tanks eight and nine.
Mr. Sybert says that the other
tanks aren't fractured...
So the air in the ballast
tanks should keep us afloat.
But Mr. Sybert also says that...
Mr. Sybert says this,
Mr. Sybert says that.
He's a big boy.
Let him say it himself.
He's right here.
Go ahead.
Uh...
We're sinking. (CHUCKLES)
(ALL SIGH)
SYBERT: Yeah,
but the whistle works.
So, we should keep blowing that.
"Maybe somebody“ hear" w.
I don't know,
but we're definitely sinking.
The crack in the engine room
is takin' on too much water.
Pumps can't keep up.
If the water reaches the
air-intake in the engine...
we're going to,
uh, lose all the power.
And if we lose all the power,
we lose the pumps.
When we lose the pumps...
She's gonna drop pretty quick.
How long have we got
before that happens?
Four, maybe five hours.
(SEAMEN MURMURING)
We need to buy
ourselves some time.
So somebody can find us.
If anybody's even lookin'.
QUIREY: Even if they
do know we're here...
those seas are big enough.
I mean, it ripped
this thing in half.
How the hell
are they gonna get out?
That's why I'm sayin' we gotta
launch some lifeboats.
Our luck's runnin' out.
I don't believe in luck, Brown.
Put those lifeboats
out in those seas...
they won't last 12 seconds.
You and Quirey both...
you just wanna sit around
and do nothin'.
You got a better idea, Sybert...
or you just go back,
hide down below?
(SCOFFS)
We're gonna run her aground.
- ALL: Huh?
- (STAMMERS) Do what?
You wanna run her
aground, Sybert?
Even if you could with
half a ship, why would you?
She'd break apart,
dump us all out in that sea.
SYBERT: It's our only choice.
We're gonna find a soft shoal,
and we'll lay her up.
We'll slow the water
that's coming in.
We'll stay in the same spot.
We'll blow the whistle.
We'll give whoever's
coming to look for us...
a chance to find us.
You're gonna steer a ship
without hydraulics?
That's your plan?
How's that gonna work?
I'm gonna build a manual tiller.
BROWN: Hey, Sybert, why should
we even listen to you?
The only thing you ever cared
about was this ship.
Man, I'll tell you what.
You two make a cute couple
at the bottom of the ocean.
Me, I'm gonna get on a lifeboat.
Look.
We'll insert a steel beam
into the steering quadrant.
We'll put pulleys
on the end of it for leverage.
And we'll move her manually.
(SEAMEN MURMURING)
DOMINGO: Excuse me. Excuse me.
I think I got the radio working.
MALE DISPATCHER:
Bearing 83 degrees true...
27 miles from Pollock Rip Light.
About 20 miles east
of Nantucket...
"East of Nantucket"?
That ain't the Pendleton.
Fort Mercer's
emergency condition...
Fort Mercer. That's another T2.
Another tanker split in two
besides us.
But if everyone's gonna
help them, who's gonna...
Who's gonna come for us?
How you feelin'?
- You all right?
- Mmm.
(CHUCKLES)
Did you, uh, ask Cluff, yet?
No.
Why don't you ask him?
- Webber!
- What's wrong with you?
- What?
You ask him yet? You ask Cluff?
I told you not to tell nobody.
I'm sorry, I'm not havin'
a very good day.
BERNIE: I know
you're not feeling well...
You know, Webber...
you don't need permission
to get married.
No, actually, you do, Chief.
- Unless you're underage.
- (RICHIE LAUGHS)
Thanks, Chief,
just following regulations.
Let's go get suited up.
Uh, it's not regulation, Webber.
It's just a formality,
like a courtesy.
And, hey, did I hear right,
that she asked you?
Following orders, right, Webber?
Yeah. Yeah, she asked me, Chief.
WOW. (CLEARS THROAT)
Wow. You, uh, sure you got
your pants on, Webber...
or is she wearin' 'em?
Sounds like
this girl cut off your...
What, Webber? What? Huh?
Don't you got boats to tie up?
She's my fiancée, sir.
Who asked you...
to be married.
(MEN SNICKERING)
Come on, Richie, let's go.
- (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
- One moment.
Uh-huh, sure.
OPERATOR 1: I'm sorry, sir.
Please speak up.
OPERATOR 2:
This line is bad, ma'am.
I'll try and
reconnect it to you.
OPERATOR 3: Please, sir.
The lines are down.
Bernie? How are you? How's work?
Yeah, it's been one
of those days, you know.
But how are you?
Hey, you're not the radar
technician, are you?
Uh, no.
I was ordered to hole up here
till the storm passes.
Catch a ride back out
to my lightship.
Um, you can go wait in
the mess hall, if you want to.
Now is not a good time,
you know.
Um, I gotta get ready to go...
down to the pier,
tie up some boats. So...
MIRIAM: I wish
you were here with me.
I'm hearin'
all sorts of things...
about a ship
breakin' up, and I...
- Oh.
- OPERATOR 43 Hello?
What, you okay?
(CHUCKLES) Yeah,
we just lost our lights.
You better go find 'em, then.
(LAUGHS)
CLUFF: Nantucket's dispatched
their 36-footer to the Mercer.
We got orders to do the same.
You asked Cluff yet?
That's him, right?
Not yet, sweet-... Uh...
I'll explain later.
- I... I gotta go.
- Okay.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Yeah, bye.
(MEN LAUGHING)
DONALD: The best
part of it is...
she had no idea who I was.
(CLEARS THROAT) Bangs?
Pick yourself a crew...
take the 36500
out of Old Harbor.
Proceed to the Fort Mercer...
20 miles east of here
off Nantucket, you hear?
DONALD: Uh, whoa,
I don't believe
we'd get over the bar
in this weather, Mr. Cluff.
We're better off takin'
the 36383 out of Stage Harbor.
That would take longer, right?
Not much.
- (SCOFFS)
- What do you think, Webber?
You're a bosun mate, too.
You know what
it's like out there.
Yeah, look. No one's
gettin' over the bar...
in this weather, Mr. Cluff.
Nobody.
It's a suicide mission.
We should take the 36383
out of Stage Harbor.
It'll take longer, sure.
At least
we'll be able to get out.
(BREATH ES DEEPLY)
Godspeed, Chief.
Webber, take Gouthro and
Livesey down to the fish pier.
Yes, sir.
(WIND HOWLING)
(SHIP HORN BLOWING
IN THE DISTANCE)
(HORN CONTINUES BLOWING)
(SNEEZES)
Don't get me sick, Gus.
You shouldn't even be out here.
Why you always
raggin' on us, Richie?
Don't take it out on us...
'cause you couldn't
go out with Bangs.
At least he'll get out.
Screw you. That were a year ago.
Screw you.
No one could have
got over the bar that day.
Bangs coulda.
Oh, really, Richie.
He's not trying to get
across the bar today.
No, he's taking the 36383...
right out from the nice,
protected bay side.
- Ah.
- (GUS COUGHS)
(SNIFFLES)
Bernie, it doesn't matter
what Richie here thinks...
or Bangs or Carl Nickerson
or nobody.
Nobody could have got out
to save the men on the Landry.
Sometimes, you know...
Sometimes men die, Bernie.
(SIGHS)
(SEAMEN CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY)
SYBERT: All right. Here we go.
(SEAMEN GRUNTING)
All right, hang on.
Easy, now. Easy, fellas.
- I got it.
- SYBERT: Okay, up, up, up!
One...
Two.
All together now.
- Three!
- (ALL GRUNTING)
FRANK: Tie it down, boys.
I got it.
SYBERT: All right.
Now we've got a tiller.
We're gonna
drive her up on the shoal.
Uh-uh. Brown and them others...
they're getting ready
to launch them lifeboats.
They think it's their best hope.
SYBERT: on, Pop.
We need every guy we got.
Well, they're gonna
take them lifeboats.
(SIGHS)
(SEAMEN ARGUING INDISTINCTLY)
(GRUNTS)
What are you
tryin' to do, Sybert?
FRANK: Get Off him!
You come up here
tryin' to kill us?
Are you trying to kill us?
TINY: Back off him.
Get up!
You're out of your mind!
QUIREY: Brown, he just
saved your life, okay?
The boat's in pieces. It's gone!
Enough!
That boat is too small
for these seas.
And this ship
will be sunk by nightfall.
Now, every fella here
wants to live...
and the only way that happens
is if we run her aground!
We gotta set up a watch
and look out for a shoal.
I need four men
working the pulleys...
on the emergency tiller.
I need four men manning
the pumps, aft to steering...
and the rest of you
run a bucket line...
topside down below...
communicate with
the engine room.
And somebody...
keep blowing that whistle.
You heard him, boys!
Now move it! Come on!
Sounds like
you're the man now, Sybert.
I hope you didn't
just kill us all.
(SIGHS)
CARL: I saw a Ship driftin'.
Heard it whistle.
A distress signal.
45 minutes ago, Bernie.
From my house.
Uh...
With the wind blowin' south,
and those currents...
I guess that'd put her
close to here about now...
comin' up over the bar.
Can't be part of
the Mercer, Bernie.
She's off Nantucket,
40 miles southeast of here.
Means she would have
drifted northwest then, right?
I know what I heard.
Know what I saw.
Well, okay, then, uh...
How about we go
back to the station...
see if we can get
to the bottom of it?
Just got off the phone
with Boston.
They diverted a plane
from the Mercer...
and it sighted the stern
of the tanker Pendleton...
five miles east of here.
Oh, my God.
Two tankers broken in half
in one day.
That's gotta be
some kind of record.
Boston and Nantucket
have dispatched...
all their boats to the Mercer.
They can't make it here
in this weather.
(RADAR BEEPING)
Webber.
Pick yourself a crew.
Take that 36500 out
and you go over the bar...
and you find the stern of
the Pendleton. You hear?
Uh... Yes, sir.
Um...
You fellas want to
get warmed up...
get some coffee?
Bernie.
Yeah.
Uh...
What?
What Carl's trying to say...
This isn't about the Landry.
Oh, sure it is.
Richie.
RICHIE: Eight men
died that night.
You and Gus and Masachi
couldn't even get out.
What makes you think
you can do it now?
You know the bar on this
kind of day, right, Bernie?
Yeah.
That man in there
don't know what he's doin'.
He's sending you out to die.
You can't make it over Chatham
bar on a day like this.
Can't stay afloat for long
on half a ship neither.
Mr. Stello, in the Coast Guard
they say, you gotta go out.
But they don't say
you gotta come back in.
That's regulation, you know.
Bernie, better you get lost...
afore you get too far out, then.
Oh, don't worry about me,
Mr. Ryder.
I can't get lost out there.
I know those waters pretty good.
How could I get lost?
No, no, no, no, Bernie.
What Dave's trying to say...
you should just
motor around the harbor...
say you tried to get out
and couldn't.
You know?
Thank you, Mr. Ryder. Thank you.
But, Mr. Stello, I'm gonna do
my best to get out there.
I don't know if I will,
but I'm gonna try.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Okay.
I guess Richie's in.
Who else?
Uh, I don't know, Gus.
You can hardly lift your head.
Who else you gonna take, Bernie?
Fitz is the only other
engineman left.
And he's only third class...
and he don't got the experience.
I'll... I'll go.
(STAMMERS) Yeah,
I can do the job.
I mean, I can do it.
You can't go.
You're sick as a dog, Gus.
He's right, Gus.
One more.
(RICHIE CLEARS THROAT)
Someone has to go out there
and save those guys, right?
That's why I signed up.
Guess now's my chance.
Seaman Ervin Maske,
Stonehorse lightship.
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
(WIND HOWLING)
(PHONE RINGING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(PHONE CONTINUES RINGING)
(HORN BLOWING LOUDLY)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Pumps aren't keepin' up.
Three more feet...
till we lose the engines.
Can you lock
that boiler on full?
You crazy to think
you can steer her broken...
with a couple of ropes
and a hand-made tiller, boy.
You got a better idea?
I'm all ears.
There!
A shoal about a mile distance!
We can make that!
Rudder, 15 degrees to port!
Half-speed
if we want to hit it head on!
Gotta make a turn 80 degrees
on the compass to 310!
(PANTING)
Rudder, 15 degrees port!
Half-speed!
80 degrees to 310 on compass!
15 degrees port! Half-speed!
Rudder, 15 degrees port!
Half-speed!
80 degrees to 310
on the compass!
Rudder, 15 degrees port!
Half-speed!
80 degrees to 310 on compass!
Rudder, 15 degrees port!
Half-speed!
80 degrees to 310 on compass!
Rudder, 15 degrees port!
Half-speed!
80 degrees to 310
on the compass!
Rudder, 15 degrees port!
Half-speed!
80 degrees to 310 on compass!
Rudder, 15 degrees port.
Half-speed.
80 degrees to 310 on compass.
Thank you, Eldon.
(BREATH ES DEEPLY)
(GRUNTS)
All right! You guys! NOW. pull!
- (SEAMEN GRUNTING)
- Pull, pull, pull! Come on!
Please tell me
we're takin' that boat...
to a bigger boat.
You ever been
on a rescue mission before?
No.
Mostly I just chip paint.
Sometimes I cook for the boys.
Great.
(GRUNTING)
BERNIE: All right, you,
uh, take the glory hole.
Maske. Ervin Maske.
Ervin, yeah.
Uh, Richie, drop
the mooring line when you can.
Last known position
of the Pendleton is here.
So, I figure
once we cross the bar...
I reckon with the currents...
she'll have drifted about here.
That's six miles from us.
So, you think Bernie can get
us out past the bar in this?
I've never seen
anything like it.
Yeah, I mean,
he's just gotta be sure...
that he doesn't pitchpole us,
that's all.
Huh?
The power of the waves
on that bar...
they can pick you up...
they can turn you end for end
over and over again.
There's no way to survive that.
That's pitchpoling.
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
Hey, Fitz, are we good?
All right, give it a shot!
(ENGINE STARTING)
Free the lines!
Lines freed!
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Did Bernie go out, Gus?
Miriam, what are you doing here?
Did he?
Yeah, Cluff sent him.
I wanna talk to him.
- Who?
- Cluff.
Your commanding officer.
Where is he?
I wanna find out
where Bernie is.
I'm worried about him.
We're supposed to get married.
Miriam, this isn't what
any of the other girls do.
Or wives.
They don't come in here,
and they don't do this.
So?
If you want,
I guess you can wait in here.
Listen to what's going on.
Sit down.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Tide's risin'.
Gonna work us off that shoal.
We need to hit it hard.
Yeah, there's no other way.
Wave!
(SEAMEN YELPING)
(SEAMEN GROANING)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
SYBERT: You feel that?
She's drifting.
Must have lost the tiller.
We gotta slow her headway...
or we're gonna miss
that shoal for good.
Close the governor valves,
cut the propulsion.
We gotta isolate the boiler.
We gotta conserve everything
she's got left!
I keep tellin' you, Bouloo.
This boat just bad luck.
It's got nothing...
to do... with luck.
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING CONTINUES)
Station Chatham,
this is the CG-36500.
Do you COPY?
CLUFF: (ON RADIO)
This is Station Chatham.
36500, what is your location?
Over.
BERNIE: Station Chatham,
we, uh...
We are now passing
Morris Island.
Heading down the channel
towards Chatham bar. Over.
What's it mean,
going over that bar?
Miriam,
don't do this to yourself.
Why not?
Why not, Gus?
If I'm gonna be with him,
I wanna know.
You're the girl
with the bear coat, right?
Yeah.
Yeah, that's me. (CHUCKLES)
You gonna tell me
what it's like out there?
Shoals on that bar are never
in the same place twice.
Flood currents carryin' them
big ocean swells...
that rise up
when they hit the shallows...
crash up against that bar.
Outgoing tide
crashes up against that bar.
That, uh...
That man shouldn't have sent
them out to cross that bar...
in a storm like this.
Maybe they can turn back.
Maybe they get lost before.
Can't get out.
You know Bernie, right?
You know he won't
get lost out there.
You know he follows the rules.
(SCOFFS)
Yeah, we know.
We all going down
to the pier soon.
See if there's anything
we can do down there.
Welcome to come.
GUS: Miriam. Miriam!
Miriam, please come here.
Miriam!
Excuse me, are you
Commander Cluff?
Who are you?
I'm Miriam Penttinen,
Bernie Webber's girlfriend.
I want you to call
Bernie back in.
That girl he was
asking me about.
You know what
he was gonna ask me?
For your permission to marry me.
(SCOFFS)
Well, that's between you,
him and your God.
Asking me is just a formality.
He can marry you all he wants.
Don't he know that?
But you can't be in here, miss.
It's Bernie.
BERNIE: (ON RADIO)
Chatham bar dead ahead. Over.
36500, Station Chatham.
Proceed as directed
towards Pendleton stern.
I didn't copy that,
Station Chatham.
Conditions hazardous.
Why give us permission if
you're sending him out to die?
What the hell?
Gouthro, get her out of here.
Sir, winds have gone
from 40 to 60...
since the call first come in.
That's gonna be
hurricane strength in an hour.
CLUFF: Gouthro,
he's got his orders.
You get her out of here,
and you get yourself to bed.
You're too sick to be in here.
36500, Station Chatham,
proceed over the bar.
I repeat, proceed.
Once over,
travel directly south.
The radar's intermittent...
but it's showing
a pip 10 or 12 miles...
east of Monomoy Point,
moving south. Over.
Station Chatham,
this is the 500.
Copy that.
(CLUFF SIGHS)
I hear what everyone's saying.
You don't know
what you're doing.
Excuse me?
Maybe... Maybe it's because
you're not from here.
You don't know
what it's like out there...
What the hell would you know...
what it's like out there, miss?
Hmm?
Please, just call them back.
What do you think
it's gonna be like...
being married to
a Coast Guard man?
Please, just call them back.
You gonna come in here scared...
every time he out in the water?
Please call them back.
You don't belong here.
Get out of here!
Get out of my station!
And go home to
where you belong, miss!
Please call them back.
Get out of my station!
(CRYING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(GASPING)
(HORN BLOWING)
Shoal's getting behind us.
Only chance now
is a harder turn...
if the chains hold.
But it could capsize us.
(SEAMEN GRUNTING)
That's good, boy.
(GRUNTING CONTINUES)
You need to stand clear, boys!
If those shackles crack
and these chains snap...
it'll rip right through ya!
Here we go.
(GRUNTS)
- Got her moving!
- Yeah!
- (RUMBLING)
- Hear that?
That's it, that's the bar.
(RUMBLING CONTINUES)
Couple minutes now, boys.
(SIGHS)
♪ When I was a little boy ♪
♪ So my mother told me I
BOTH: ♪ To me! Way, haul away ♪
♪ Haul away ♪
♪ We'll haul away Joe ♪
♪ Now, first I met
a Yankee girl ♪
♪ She was fat and lazy To me! ♪
"ALL". ♪ Way haul away ♪
♪ We'll haul away Joe ♪
♪ And then I met an Irish girl ♪
♪ She damn near drove me crazy
To me! ♪
♪ Way haul away ♪
♪ We'll haul away Joe ♪
♪ Now way, haul away ♪
♪ We're bound
for better weather ♪
♪ To me! ♪
♪ Way haul away ♪
♪ We'll haul away Joe ♪
(RUMBLING CONTINUES)
Hey, hey, boys!
We're not gonna be able
to see much, all right?
So we'll have to listen to
those waves hittin' that bar.
Gotta time it.
So I'm gonna wait for a lull...
and then we go.
We got faith in you, Skip!
Anytime you're ready...
you just go, Bernie, all right?
- (ALL BREATHING HEAVILY)
- (RUMBLING CONTINUES)
(ENGINE REVVING)
(WHIMPERS)
(ENGINE ROARING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
- (MEN GRUNTING)
- (SCREAMS)
(ALL GASPING)
(G ROANS)
(GASPING)
(COUGHS)
The compass is gone!
(YELPING)
(ENGINE STALLING)
Fitzy! The engine died!
Ahh!
(PANTING)
- I got it, I got it!
- No, you don't.
You got about
five seconds, boys!
It's gravity-fed,
it doesn't know...
which way is up and down.
I know!
(WHIMPERING)
Come on, fire it up!
- (ENGINE STARTING)
- Yeah!
(COUGHS)
Maske! Get back here!
Tide's risin'.
It'll get us through.
But let me know what's comin'.
(PANTING)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
(ENGINE REVVING)
(PANTING)
Hey, Fitz!
We made it over the bar.
Back to the spotlight!
Coming out!
We turned too late!
We gotta buy that time back.
Tell Sybert we need 30 degrees
in the next two minutes...
or we'll miss that shoal!
Thirty degrees
in the next two minutes!
in the next two minutes.
Thirty degrees
in the next two minutes!
in the next two minutes.
We're putting her in reverse.
We're gonna let
the ocean push us.
Hold on.
SEAMAN: Okay.
- (GROANING)
- ALL: Whoa!
You may wanna
brace yourself, Eldon.
318!
316!
Close her down
as soon as she hits!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
312!
(PANTING)
Gentlemen, brace yourselves.
Hold on!
(ALL SCREAM)
Now!
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
(HULL SCRAPING)
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
(ALL GROANING)
(SCREAMS)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING CONTINUES)
(SEAMEN WHOOPING)
Well...
You did it.
It bloody well worked,
Mr. Sybert.
We gotta keep the water away...
from the air inlets
for the engine.
If we lose power,
we'll lose our pumps.
And I'm afraid we're taking on
so much water...
the weight will pull us
right back off the shoal.
Feels funny not to be
moving around, huh, Eldon?
All right.
Let's get to it.
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
(SHIVERING)
BEA: We're heading down
to the lodge.
- Everything okay?
- GIRL: Stop it!
- Hi!
- Quiet down now.
My God, give me a break.
Uh, I was on my way home.
My car spun out into a ditch.
I need some help.
Yeah, all right.
We live near here.
We can go back to my house.
I'll call my brother.
He can tow you out. Jump in.
Thank you.
BEA: You don't got a coat?
You can move that.
We're bringing it
down to St. Martin's...
in case there are any survivors.
Oh, uh...
I left my coat
at the Coast Guard station.
You got a man there?
Stop it!
Uh, I...
He's not there right now.
It's, um...
It's Bernie Webber.
Yeah. Bernie, he's a good man.
We can't find them without
a compass, Bernie!
We got no idea where they are!
Hold on!
(WHIMPERING)
(GASPING)
- You okay?
- (SPITS) Yeah.
You Okay?
I'm having
a great time now, Bernie!
Lot of fun!
- Brace yourselves!
- Oh...
Whole lotta...
Whole lot of fun here.
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
Here. Come on, take it. Use it.
SEAMAN: Got it, Pop!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING CONTINUES)
(POWERING DOWN)
We lost the pumps.
The pumps are
tripping the breakers.
I'll go check the connection.
Give me the light.
It's not worth a damn, Bouloo.
Sometimes, I wish
I didn't understand you.
(TCHUDA LAUGHS)
FRANK: Sybert, what's going on?
We're using
every pump we've got.
We jammed the breakers so
the pumps wouldn't trip them.
We've got about
two feet till the water...
hits those air inlets
to the engines...
and then the ship's dead.
Jesus Christ.
BROWN: You hear that?
That's the tide rising,
gonna work us off this shoal.
Look, look, this'll at least
give us some time.
Isn't that right, Mr. Sybert?
That right. Sure does, boy.
Yeah, long as
we got the generators...
keeping the pumps going-
Buy whoever might be coming...
to find us a little bit of time.
You wanted to be
the man, Sybert.
Now you're the man, right?
Except you got no wife,
you got no kids back home.
You're a single man.
Always hiding down below.
What you got to lose?
All right, that's enough, Brown.
I'm scared, too, Brown.
I got a life, the same as you.
Just don't see the point
in sitting around...
talking about it.
BERNIE: Station Chatham, 36500.
Station Chatham, 36500.
Do you COPY?
Station Chatham,
this is Chief Bangs...
CG-36383.
Pollock lightship, CG-36500,
do you copy?
Why can't they hear us, Bernie?
We can hear them!
DONALD: Seas are too high,
zero headway.
Station Chatham, do you copy?
DONALD: Repeat,
we're coming home.
CLUFF: Station Chatham to 36383,
return to Old Harbor.
Pollock lightship, CG-36500,
do you copy?
- We're all alone.
- Bangs, return to Old Harbor.
You heard Bangs on the radio.
It sounds like
he couldn't get out.
Going back in,
the storm is getting worse.
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
We should turn back in, Webber.
FITZGERALD: Look, Bernie,
we already made it out...
further than anybody
thought was possible.
Maybe Richie's right.
Maybe we should just go back.
DONALD: Winds at force
of eight to nine.
Repeat: Winds at force
Heavy snow squalls.
You heard Bangs on the radio!
We got no compass!
We have no way to communicate!
You're...
What? What? I'm What, Richie?
I got us out this far, didn't I?
Not Bangs or Cluff,
or nobody else.
I did it!
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER
CONTINUES)
We did it, Richie.
You wanna turn back around?
No.
No, not now. We came too far.
We're not giving up on them.
(TURNS OFF RADIO)
Not on my watch.
Just do your job.
Hey. Fitz!
Turn off the beam, Fitz.
We'll run her dark.
Better shot at seeing light
from the Pendleton
if we're running dark.
Watch it!
(FITZGERALD SCREAMS)
Get back here!
Fitz!
Get your butts back here!
I lost my hat!
(RUMBLING)
Whoa...
Are you okay?
Yeah, yeah.
I'm just tired.
Come on.
You kids go on and
play in the bedroom.
You can wait with them, miss,
while I call my brother.
Thanks.
Please call me Miriam.
You think your mother would
mind if I turned on the radio?
"MAN". Coast Guard Boston,
this is the Unimak.
We're at the Mercer bow now,
here in support of the Yakutat.
Four Mercer crewmen jumped
from the deck. All were lost.
Repeat, four men lost.
Several crew members
have hypothermia.
We're going to wait
until daybreak...
to attempt another rescue. Over.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Does no good listening
to all that chatter, Miriam.
Better learning
to live not knowing.
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
(TURNS OFF RADIO)
How long you been
married to Bernie for?
We're...
We're not married yet.
I don't know if I can...
Like I said, Bernie,
he's a good man.
Him and some of them others
tried getting out a year ago...
to save my husband Arne
and the crew of the Landry.
They were out fishing Monomoy
near Nantucket Sound...
when the boat started
taking on water.
A night just like this.
Come on.
We gotta get going.
My brother's on his way
to come meet us.
- Thanks.
- I gotta get down the lodge.
Come on, you two.
(DOOR OPENS)
(HORN BLOWING)
♪ For the people
all said sit down ♪
♪ Sit down,
you're rockin' the boat ♪
♪ For the people
all said sit down ♪
♪ Sit down,
you're rockin' the boat ♪
♪ And the devil
may pull you under ♪
♪ By the sharp lapels
Of your checkered coat ♪
♪ Sit down, sit down, sit down ♪
(GENERATOR POWERING DOWN)
(GASPS)
(WIND HOWLING)
You know who she is?
Ain't Bernie's fault, Carl.
Ain't nobody's fault.
Be like her blaming you.
(SCOFFS)
For what?
You're the one that told them...
there's another ship out there.
They're out there
because of you, right?
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
Fitz.
Turn on the search light.
I can't believe we found her.
Look at that.
We're too late.
She's a ghost ship.
- Are you seeing this, sir?
- BERNIE: Yeah.
- You see that guy?
- Yeah, yeah, I see him.
Not sure I believe it.
Where the hell's he going?
(SEAMEN CLAMORING)
SEAMAN: Good to see ya, boys!
(LAUGHS)
(CLAMORING CONTINUES)
How we gonna fit
them all on this boat?
We're only built to hold 12,
includin' us.
That's just regulation,
though, right?
How many can she fit?
20, 22, tops.
Wait!
They're coming down here.
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
- Drop the stanchion!
- Port side!
- (ALL GRUNTING)
- (SEAMAN COUGHING)
- (SEAMEN GRUNTING)
- (SCREAMING)
Come on!
Come on! I got ya!
(YELPING)
We got ya!
(SCREAMING)
FITZGERALD:
Maske, get over here!
Come on!
RICHIE: Grab him!
You know where
you're going now, miss?
I think so.
Thanks for your help,
Mr. Nickerson.
Yeah.
You know...
Bernie ain't out there
because of me.
Yeah, I know.
It's Bernie's job
to go out, right?
How can I blame you for it?
(SEAMEN SHOUTING)
TINY: Nice and slow.
Nice and slow.
You'll be all right.
Pete, you're next.
Take it nice and slow.
Easy, easy.
BERNIE: Come on!
You gotta go,
we're leaving nobody behind!
SEAMAN: Eldon,
get on the ladder!
Come on, we gotta get them down!
She's slipping!
We gotta get off this ship!
SEAMAN: Hurry!
Eldon? How you doing?
I'm scared.
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
Well...
Gonna be a lot scarier up here
without us.
SEAMAN: You gotta listen to me!
Eldon.
You just follow right behind me.
If I can do it, anyone can.
Come on!
(ALL GRUNTING)
- ELDON: Tiny!
- (SCREAMING)
Tiny! Tiny, hold on!
Hey!
(ALL GASPING)
(SIGHS)
Eldon.
Eldon!
Eldon, look at me!
Look at me!
(YELPS)
When I say jump, let go.
You ready?
Jump!
(SCREAMING)
(ALL GRUNTING)
You Okay?
We're riding so heavy,
you can hardly steer.
Sir, they're saying
there's still...
seven or eight
up there on board.
Maybe we take
these guys back in...
and come back out.
We can't leave them
out here alone.
That boat won't last.
We all live, or we all die.
Right?
You, uh...
You did good.
You should be
the last one off, Mr. Sybert.
(SIGHS)
RICHIE: Last man!
Hey. Fitz!
Turn off that
search light, yeah?
We were in radio contact
with the McCullough.
They said they lost four men,
but saved the rest.
The captain of the Pollock Rip
sent word that they...
GUS: Mr. Cluff!
It's the 36500! It's Bernie!
It's right there on the radio.
BERNIE: Station Chatham?
Station Chatham, copy?
CG-36500,
this is Station Chatham.
Webber, is that you?
Yes, sir, it's me. It's Bernie.
We got 32 survivors aboard...
from the tanker Pendleton, sir.
Station Chatham, do you copy?
36500, Station Chatham.
Did you say you have
32 survivors on board?
They rescued them.
They rescued 32 of them!
BERNIE: Yes, sir, 32.
Sir, we've lost our compass,
so we don't know where we are.
But we're gonna try
to make it back home.
Can't get back
without a compass.
MAN 1: Not in this weather.
MAN 2: They're not gonna
make it back.
You lost your compass, Webber.
MALE DISPATCHER:
Negative, 36500,
this is the Pollock lightship.
Do not proceed to shore.
We're five miles northeast...
of the Pendleton's
last known location.
Proceed to our position. Over.
CG-36500, Station Chatham.
Proceed to
the Pollock lightship...
and unload all survivors. Over.
What do they know, right?
(CHUCKLES) Right, Richie?
CLUFF: CG-36500, do you copy?
If they know where they are...
someone tell me where I am...
because I don't know
where the hell we are.
Webber, do you copy?
I'm not heading out to sea.
No.
This is Station Chatham.
Do you copy?
We just got you
all off a boat...
so there's no way we're gonna
get you all back up one.
CG-36500,
this is Station Chatham.
Webber, your orders
are to proceed...
five miles northeast...
and unload all survivors
onto the Pollock...
(TURNS RADIO OFF)
Sounds like he cut off
his radio, Mr. Cluff.
He's going it on his own.
Bernie Webber.
What do ya know?
WOMAN 1: How are they gonna
find their way home?
MAN 1: He must have
shut off his radio.
WOMAN 2: Those poor boys.
MAN 2: I can't believe
that's happening.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Some more stuff in the car.
WOMAN 3: Power's out now.
MAN 3: How they gonna
see their way home?
MAN 4: Power's out.
The whole town. The power's out.
MAN 5: Worse than last year.
WOMAN 4: They'll never make it.
(SIGHS)
- Let's get down to the pier.
- (CHATTER CONTINUES)
How'd you find us
without a compass?
We, uh...
We just jogged along with
the seasonal currents.
- I think we just got lucky.
- (SYBERT CHUCKLES)
Yeah.
Lucky.
So, you know how to get home?
To be honest with ya,
I'm not sure.
Just disobeyed
all my ranking officers...
and they don't know...
so I guess
I'd better then, right?
Had the wind
on my left going out.
Figure if I, uh...
(CLEARS THROAT)
keep her on my right
we ought to be...
heading the right direction.
We just follow
the lights on shore.
Follow all the lights on shore.
Well, we're in
your hands, Captain.
Listen up!
I'll put the sea behind us.
Just let it push us along
till we lay up somewhere.
The storm's easing up, boys...
so we just look for the lights
on the shore to guide us in.
Even if we have to go so far
as Nobska Point, so be it.
We just gotta find land.
Been one heck of a long day,
right, fellas? (CHUCKLES)
Yeah.
Sure has.
But don't you give up
hope on me now.
She's a good boat.
She'll get us through.
We'll get you home, okay?
We're all going home.
We're with you, Skipper!
(ALL AGREEING)
Yeah! (WHISTLING)
(ENGINE REVVING)
(COUGHING)
(EXHALES)
MAN 1: Keep your lights on!
Like she's doing!
WOMAN 1:
Quick, turn your lights on!
MAN 2: Turn your headlights
on! Everyone!
MAN 3: Turn 'em on!
MAN 4: More lights
so they can see us!
I think we made it over the bar.
I think high tide
carried us over.
Richie, you see that?
(BOTH LAUGHING)
BERNIE; Fitz!
Turn on the search light!
(TOWNSFOLK MURMURING)
MAN 1: Look, you see that?
MAN 22 ls it them?
MAN 3: Well done, Bernie!
You did it, Webber!
Way to go, Webber!
MALE DISPATCHER: 36500 is now
docking at the Chatham pier.
There appear to be
32 survivors, sir.
Repeat, they have 32 survivors.
(TOWNSFOLK CHEERING)
That's right.
Throw it, son.
MAN 4: Attaboy, Bernie!
(ENGINE POWERING DOWN)
MAN 5: Give 'em a hand.
MAN 6: Good to see you.
Get on up here.
Nice and easy.
MAN 7: We never thought
we'd see you again.
MAN 8: This guy's freezing.
Give me your coat.
MAN 9: Go on in.
It's warm inside.
(CHEERING CONTINUES)
Let's get you up to the lodge.
Next up. Come on, now.
I got you.
SYBERT: Good job, Captain.
MAN 11: Way to go, Bernie.
Webber.
Bernie.
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
Let's go home.
Are we still good
for April 16th?
- Yeah.
I asked Cluff for ya.
He said it's just a...
Just a formality.
Now I know, right?
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
♪♪
(SEA CHANTEY PLAYING)
♪ When I was a little boy ♪
♪ Or so my mother told me X
♪ Way, haul away ♪
♪ We'll haul away Joe ♪
♪ We rode it far,
homeward bound ♪
♪ Took it free and easy ♪
♪ Setting sail
to newfound lands ♪
♪ The wind was high and breezy ♪
♪ We overcome and rose above ♪
♪ The storm that
we were facing ♪
♪ Finally arriving home ♪
♪ Together, warm and safely ♪
♪ Hey, haul away ♪
♪ Hey, haul away Joe ♪
♪ We sail on away ♪
♪ With the music
playing freely ♪
♪ Our spirits light and gay I
♪ We sail on today ♪
♪ Way, haul away ♪
♪ We'll haul away Joe ♪
♪ Now up aloft ♪
♪ This yard must go ♪
♪ We'll pull her free and easy ♪
♪♪