(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(FESTIVE MUSIC PLAYING)
(CHATTER CONTINUES)
(BIRDS TWITTERING)
MAN: Ho, ho!
(MOUSE SQUEAKING)
(SNIFFING)
CLARA: Shh! Fritz.
Now, be very still.
This is how we'll do it.
With science,
mechanics...
and a bit of luck.
First, we've got energy.
The heat from the candle
will make the balloon rise.
(CLACKING)
With the momentum
from the ball...
- that hits the monkey...
- (DINGS)
...and pivots
onto the bellows.
(AIR HISSING)
FRITZ:
Which blows the longboat.
CLARA: Giving us Newton's
third law of physics...
that says every action
has an equal...
- and opposite...?
- Reaction.
- Yes! (LAUGHING)
- FRITZ: Yes!
- (MOUSE SNIFFING)
- Do they bite?
I suppose they do.
If you're horrid to them.
(MOUSE SQUEAKS)
Oh, there you are.
Up and down I've been
looking for you rascals.
Worn out, I am.
FRITZ: We were
catching a mouse.
Well, if you catch one,
I'm not cooking it.
Too many bones.
Now, come on, be quick.
We have a lot to do
before this evening.
LOUISE: There you are!
I've been looking
all over for you.
Look at the state of you.
We were trying
to catch a mouse...
with toys and momentum
and matches and...
Matches?
- It was Clara's idea.
- (SCOFFS)
LOUISE: Catching mice
on Christmas Eve?
Honestly, Clara.
We nearly had him.
What were you gonna do with
him when you caught him?
FRITZ: Teach him tricks.
He could dance.
Ah. There you are.
What do we think?
It's wonderful, Father.
With a few adjustments,
perhaps.
It's not how Mother did it.
(QUIETLY) Fritz.
Um... Now, children,
I have some presents for you.
But it's not Christmas Day.
They're from your mother.
She asked me to give them
to you on Christmas Eve.
That one's for you.
(CHUCKLES)
- Louise.
- Thank you.
FRITZ: Soldiers! Yay!
BENJAMIN: Clara.
FRITZ: The enemy
has found our location!
(IMITATING GUNFIRE)
We've been ambushed!
They're from both sides!
(GASPS)
It's Mother's favorite.
Yes. Yes, it was.
What is it, Clara?
It's an egg of some sort.
What's inside?
Is it jewelry?
I don't know.
It's locked.
Are you sure it opens?
There's a keyhole. Here.
But there's no key.
Why would Mother give me this
without a key?
It's just a silly egg
that doesn't open.
It's not just
a silly egg, Fritz.
Clara.
Clara!
CLARA: "Everything you need
is inside."
BENJAMIN: Clara.
Is everything all right?
No.
This is a pin tumbler lock.
It's impossible to open
without a key.
I see.
Well, why don't you
get ready for the party,
and then you can
work it out tomorrow.
Clara, Christmas comes...
whether we like it or not.
We must do our best
to enjoy it.
I don't want to enjoy it.
I don't want to enjoy anything
right now.
Well, that may be
the case...
but it's important to maintain
traditions as a family.
It's what's expected of us.
I don't care
what's expected.
- Well, you should.
- LOUISE: Father?
It's almost time to go.
Do I look all right?
Yes.
Yes, indeed.
Please get your sister ready.
LOUISE: You must be gentle
with him, Clara.
I wish Mother was here.
We all do.
I have to open this.
LOUISE:
You'll work it out.
You're an extremely
clever girl, just like Mother.
I don't feel
very clever lately.
Maybe you should spend
a little less time
in the attic...
and a little more time
in the real world.
The real world just doesn't
make sense to me anymore.
You must try, Clara.
If only for Father.
Father is acting
as if nothing has changed.
But everything has changed.
"D." It's Drosselmeyer.
He must have made this.
And maybe he can open it!
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY) Good.
Now, will you let me
finish with your hair?
Yes. But please hurry.
(LOUISE CHUCKLES)
(FESTIVE MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(LAUGHTER)
BENJAMIN:
It is important to be
on your best behavior tonight.
That means remembering our
manners at dinner. Fritz!
I do want one dance
with you, Louise.
And you, Clara.
- Do I have to dance?
- BENJAMIN: Yes, you do.
And no disappearing
tonight either.
Mingle and engage
with the guests.
What about me?
What about you?
Who will dance with me?
(MECHANICAL WHIRRING)
FRITZ:
Yay! Godfather's house.
Last one in
is a nincompoop.
(LIVELY CHATTER)
BUTLER: Master Drosselmeyer
welcomes
Mr. and Mrs. Jeremiah Jones.
Doctor and Mrs. McDonald,
Timothy and Ezekiel McDonald.
FRITZ: Magic!
CLARA: Fritz, come on.
FRITZ: How do we
get them back?
BENJAMIN:
The Stahlbaum family.
Benjamin, Louise,
Fritz, and Clara.
(WALTZ MUSIC PLAYING)
Godfather?
- (OWL SCREECHES)
- (GASPS)
Hello.
(HOOTING SOFTLY)
Have you seen
Godfather anywhere?
DROSSELMEYER:
He sees everything.
Which can be a great help
to an old man.
(CHUCKLING) Godfather.
Hello, Clara.
I need your help.
Ah. But I need
your help first.
Look at this damn thing.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
- (CLANKING)
- Backwards.
It moves...
backwards.
The mechanism
must be reversed.
I know, but I can't,
for the life of me,
figure out why.
May I?
Please.
- (SWITCH CLICKS)
- (MUSIC STOPS)
It looks like the idler wheel
has slipped.
Hmm.
Causing the pinion ring
to engage
the secondary drive gear.
Pliers.
Ah.
There.
- (SWITCH CLICKS)
- (MUSIC RESUMES)
Ah.
Clever girl. (CHUCKLES)
I knew you could do it.
- All right now, Miss Clara...
- (SWITCH CLICKS)
Why are you down here with me
instead of upstairs, dancing?
I need your help
with something.
With this.
Ah.
I haven't seen this
in a very long time.
I made it
for another clever girl...
who came to live with me
after she was orphaned
at a very early age.
- Mother.
- Mmm-hmm.
You know,
when she first arrived...
she wouldn't leave her room.
Spent day and night
locked away...
her head buried
in her books.
So, what did you do?
I left this
outside her door.
And, over time,
she came to trust me...
but most importantly...
herself.
And now
she's given it to you.
But she didn't
leave me the key.
You must miss her terribly.
I know I do.
And I can't imagine
how your father must feel.
All Father cares about
is appearances.
No.
My guess is he feels
every bit the way you do.
Remember, Clara,
some locks are harder
to pick than others.
And I'm afraid this one
is especially tricky.
Pin tumblers.
I know.
- I tried.
- (CHUCKLES)
- (BELL TOLLS)
- Oh.
It's time.
Here, you run along
and I'll be up shortly.
It's Christmas Eve.
It's going to be
a magical night.
(FOOTSTEPS RECEDING)
(OWL CHIRPS)
Yes, I know, my friend.
It won't be easy.
But it was her
mother's dying wish...
so go keep an eye on her.
(INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING)
- (MUSIC ENDS)
- (AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
Ladies and gentlemen...
my favorite part
of Christmas...
of this evening...
I present to you...
your gifts.
(EXCITED CHATTER)
(CHILDREN GIGGLE)
(CHATTER CONTINUES)
"Fritz." (LAUGHS)
BENJAMIN: Clara.
Where have you been?
I've been looking
everywhere for you.
I was in Drosselmeyer's
workshop trying to open...
I told you
not to disappear.
And I was expecting
to dance with you.
Father, I really don't
want to dance.
Why, Clara, must you think
only about yourself?
I could ask the same of you.
GIRL: Come look!
Come over here!
- Come look!
- BOY: I need to go.
- No, this way.
- GIRL 2: Okay.
(CHILDREN CHATTERING)
GIRL 3: I found mine.
(CHATTER CONTINUES)
FRITZ: Look at my present.
- (GROWLS)
- (GASPS)
(CHUCKLES)
A nutcracker soldier?
What do you think of him?
How handsome.
FRITZ: He's your boyfriend.
(FRITZ LAUGHING)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(LEAVES RUSTLING)
What?
Where?
- (OWL SCREECHES)
- (GASPS)
(SOFT TINKLING)
(TINKLING CONTINUES)
Clever, Godfather.
Clever.
- (MOUSE SQUEAKS)
- (GASPS)
(SQUEAKING)
That's mine!
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
My key!
(SQUEAKS)
(CLARA GRUNTS)
Bring back my key!
(SQUEAKING)
(ICE CRACKING)
(SQUEAKS)
Filthy mouse.
A nutcracker soldier.
SOLDIER: Halt!
Who goes there?
- It's just me!
- State your purpose, Just Me.
No, my name is Clara,
and I must cross this bridge.
Impossible.
Nobody crosses the bridge
to the Fourth Realm...
without a direct order
from the regents.
Fourth Realm?
Where am I?
You're in
the Christmas Tree Forest.
But that is
the Fourth Realm...
which is currently at war
with the other three realms.
War?
That is correct,
Miss Clara Just Me.
No. My name isn't
Clara Just Me.
It's Stahlbaum.
- (CLATTERS)
- Clara Stahlbaum.
Stahlbaum?
Are you a relation
to Marie Stahlbaum?
She's my mother.
Forgive me, Your Majesty!
I didn't recognize you,
Princess Clara.
Princess?
Captain Phillip Hoffman.
At your service,
Your Majesty.
(QUIETLY) Maybe I have been
spending too much time
in the attic.
Captain Hoffman,
I'd like to cross the river.
But the Fourth Realm
is a very...
I have to go,
Captain Hoffman.
Is that an order,
Princess Clara?
Yes. I suppose it is.
And you can call me Clara.
Is that an order, too?
Yes.
Very well.
Call me Captain.
- (CLEARS THROAT)
- (CLANKING)
(CREAKING)
PHILLIP: Jingles!
Wake up, you lazy horse.
- Jingles!
- (JINGLES SNORTS)
CLARA: Guess I'm not
in London anymore.
PHILLIP: London?
What's London?
CLARA: It's where I'm from.
PHILLIP: Clara?
What are we looking for?
A gold key.
It must be important,
this key.
- (BIRD SQUAWKING)
- It is. Very.
Are you scared, Captain?
Me? Never.
(JINGLES SNORTS)
CLARA: Are you out here
all by yourself, Captain?
PHILLIP: Of course.
I'm the only nutcracker
in the entire kingdom.
- Don't you get lonely?
- Lonely?
No. I know my place.
That's good enough for me.
You're lucky.
I wish I knew mine.
(MICE SQUEAKING)
PHILLIP: But you're
the daughter of the queen.
Surely you know your place.
CLARA: I'm afraid not.
That's why I have
to find that key.
PHILLIP: Then we shall
do exactly that.
- (MOUSE SQUEAKS)
- Stop!
There he is!
Mouserinks!
Ah! That diabolical
little rodent.
We need to approach
with extreme caution!
(JINGLES NEIGHING)
Coward!
Clara, wait!
(SQUEAKING)
Give me my key back...
you horrid little mouse!
That key belongs to me!
Come on out of there!
Come on!
- (LOUD SQUEAKING)
- (SCREAMING)
Clara!
(SCREAMING)
CLARA: Let me go!
Put me down!
- (SQUEAKING)
- Put me down!
Captain!
Captain, help me!
PHILLIP: Run!
- What is that thing?
- It's the Mouse King.
Don't look back.
Just keep running.
(LOUD SQUEAKING)
(MOUSERINKS SQUEAKING)
I think we've lost him.
- (BRANCH SNAPS)
- Show yourself!
- Oh. Jingles.
- (JINGLES NEIGHS)
Jingles, good boy.
Clara, we need to go.
- Not without my key.
- But...
Who's intruding in my realm?
Okay. Maybe going
is a good idea.
Is that you, Clara Stahlbaum?
(ECHOING)
Why are you here?
I have your key.
It's a trap.
If you go...
you'll never come back.
No one ever does.
Clara!
Come here and get your key!
What was that?
That was Mother Ginger.
And she doesn't like
intruders.
(SWEEPING MUSIC PLAYING)
CAVALIER: Halt.
I need to
get to the palace.
I'm sure you do,
sunshine.
But we have
procedures around here.
Protocols.
I'm Captain Phillip Hoffman
and I demand
you let us through.
- Oh! "Demand," is it now?
- "Demand," oh.
Captain Hoffman of the famous
Hoffmans, is it?
Well, if we'd known
you were coming,
we would have
rolled out the red carpet...
booked the trumpeteers.
Captain Hoffman has arrived.
For goodness' sake,
she's a princess.
HARLEQUIN: Well, they
all say that these days.
Wishing don't make it so,
my love.
Overindulgent fathers,
that's what I put it down to.
Would it help if I told you
that her name
was Clara Stahlbaum?
Daughter of
Marie Stahlbaum?
(STAMMERS)
All right, just a few
questions, Your Highness,
and you'll be on your way.
This is ridiculous.
Have you had any contact
with mice
or mouse-like
entities recently?
- I was in the Fourth Realm.
- Thank you.
Do you have any cheese
or cheese-based products
on or about your person?
- CLARA: i...
- Thank you.
How would you describe
your sympathies
towards rodents in general?
- Well...
- Thank you. Good, right.
Well, that is
the survey complete.
There's no ink
coming out your pen.
You may pass, please.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Attention!
Lower the bridge!
Thank you.
HARLEQUIN:
Lower the drawbridge!
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
WOMAN: Is that
Marie's daughter?
MAN 1: She's so beautiful.
MAN 2: Make way
for the princess.
(TRUMPETS PLAYING FANFARE)
Mother.
Your Excellencies...
may I present
Miss Clara Stahlbaum.
(GASPS AND STAMMERS)
Is it true? It is true.
I'm Hawthorne...
Regent of
the Land of Flowers...
at your most humble service.
I am Shiver...
Regent of the Land
of Snowflakes, ma'am.
An honor.
And the Regent
of the Land of Sweets...
Sugar Plum.
SUGAR PLUM: I never thought
this day would come.
Oh, tell us, we long for news.
How is our queen, dear Marie?
- My mother?
- We miss her so.
You don't know?
My mother, she's...
She died.
(ALL GASP)
Marie, dead?
We are so sorry
for your loss.
To leave life so young...
She was the most beautiful,
wonderful...
She meant everything to us.
Everything.
SHIVER: This is
your mother's throne...
Your Grace.
SUGAR PLUM: Have you come
to save us, Clara?
No.
(SUGAR PLUM GASPS)
I'm sorry.
I didn't even know this place
existed before today.
You see, I was looking for
a Christmas present
from my godfather.
I love Christmas!
What's Christmas?
And then I ran into this
horrible little mouse.
(WHISPERS) Mouse?
And that's when
I met the captain.
We barely escaped
Mother Ginger
and the Mouse King.
(GASPS)
You met Mother Ginger?
Oh, my dear Clara...
you're lucky to be alive.
You must promise
never to go back
to the Land of Amusements,
Clara!
Oh! Hawthorne!
Its title has been
rescinded, Hawthorne!
Oh! (STAMMERS) Of course.
I meant the Fourth Realm.
Apologies.
I'm just so upset.
Forget I ever mentioned
the Land of...
Oh!
Oh.
HAWTHORNE: It's pure fortune
you got out alive.
No one ever escapes
from the Fourth Realm.
SHIVER:
Hawthorne is right.
We can't risk
losing our princess
when she's only
just arrived.
- CLARA: But...
- And talking of arriving...
we need to organize a pageant
to celebrate your coming.
- Oh!
- And a tour of the realms.
Oh, this is so exciting!
I love a pageant!
That sounds lovely...
but I have to get back
to Drosselmeyer's party.
(ALL LAUGHING)
She doesn't know.
Time is very different
in the realms.
Very.
SUGAR PLUM: Come.
I'll show you.
Princess Clara, I'll be
returning to my post now.
You are not leaving me.
That's an order.
Sugar Plum...
who's Mother Ginger?
SUGAR PLUM:
Well, she used to be a regent.
Just like me
and Hawthorne and Shiver.
She was the Regent
of the Land of...
(WHISPERS) Amusements.
(NORMAL VOICE) But now...
she is banished.
Why was she...
banished?
We had no choice, Clara.
She tried to take control
of the other realms...
by force.
But when her evil
intentions became clear...
even her own people
deserted her.
And her realm...
fell to ruin.
That's so tragic.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(GASPS) But things are
looking up
now that you're here,
dear Clara.
Come! It's time
to put your mind at ease.
(MECHANICAL WHIRRING)
See anything familiar?
CLARA: It looks like the clock
in Godfather's ballroom.
But that's impossible.
Is it?
Stand very still.
(TICKING)
I'm back.
Everything seems to be
going so slowly.
How is this possible?
Your world moves much more
slowly than our world.
Fritz and Louise.
There they are.
And look, there's Father.
He looks...
lost.
Everything looks different
from the realms.
(CLOCK CHIMING)
Voila.
For the pageant.
Which one
will you choose?
I'm not very good at dresses
and hair, shoes...
If I may be so bold
as to suggest that I help?
- Would you?
- It's my favorite thing!
(GASPS) Oh, we will not
disappoint them.
You will look magnificent.
Did my mother
ever talk about me?
Oh, yes. All the time.
Sometimes it seemed as if
you were right here with us.
Now, close your eyes.
Close your eyes.
Now, open your eyes.
Do you like it?
I love it.
I look so different.
SUGAR PLUM: You look like
the daughter of a queen.
(PLAYING FANFARE)
Ladies and gentlemen,
on this momentous day...
in the history
of the Four Realms...
We are proud and privileged
to present before you...
Clara Stahlbaum,
daughter of Queen Marie.
(ALL APPLAUDING)
They're all staring at me,
Sugar Plum.
Of course.
You're every inch
your mother's daughter.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
(CLEARS THROAT)
(SIGHS)
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING)
The ballet tells the story
of the Four Realms...
how your mother
discovered our world.
First, the Land of Flowers.
SUGAR PLUM: Now...
the Land of Snowflakes.
And the Land of Sweets.
(INAUDIBLE CONVERSATIONS)
(BELLS JINGLING)
Mice?
SUGAR PLUM: Now we're in
the Fourth Realm.
Watch closely, Clara.
This is where
our troubles began.
With Mother Ginger
and the mice?
Beastly woman.
There's nothing motherly
about her.
(KEYS WHIRRING)
Mother Ginger's the one
who began this war.
I hope you'll be the one
to finish it.
What do you mean?
- (ORCHESTRA STOPS PLAYING)
- (ALL APPLAUDING)
Come, I'll show you.
Dear Queen Marie kept
Mother Ginger in line...
but now that she's gone,
we're utterly defenseless.
I don't understand.
You see, once we were
lifeless toys...
mere playthings for children.
Then your mother arrived
and changed everything.
She gave us life.
How?
With this.
The Engine.
CLARA: This is
my mother's invention?
SUGAR PLUM: Yes.
The Engine made us real.
And now we have feelings
just like you have.
Happiness, sadness,
anger, love.
Fear.
There's plenty of that
going around.
You're right,
sweet captain.
Our spies tell us that
Mother Ginger
is on the warpath...
gathering all her forces.
The Engine
is the only way
that we can build an army
to defend ourselves.
But it doesn't work.
If we can't get it to work
again, then all is lost.
Perhaps I could fix it.
It's not broken.
We're simply
missing the key.
- Key?
- The key.
We've searched hither and
yon throughout the kingdom.
(KEYS CLATTERING)
I fear your dear mother
must have taken it with her.
But she never returned.
A pin tumbler.
Sugar Plum, look.
This was a present
from my mother.
The locks match.
It must be the same key.
This key of which
you speak...
where is it?
That horrible
little mouse took it.
PHILLIP: Mouserinks!
He's diabolical.
But that means that
Mother Ginger has it.
Oh, pooh!
Then we can't
make the army...
and we'll be annihilated.
Unless we can bring
the key back.
Get it back?
I could go
to the Fourth Realm.
Oh, no!
It's too, too dangerous!
I came here
to find that key.
Clara, you're not
going back there.
This must be why my mother
sent me here.
I can't let
Mother Ginger destroy
everything she created.
We were lucky to escape
with our lives the last time.
Mother Ginger's more
dangerous than you know.
I must get that key.
MARIE: You found him.
He's your favorite,
isn't he?
Well, we can't have Christmas
without the nutcracker.
I found him
at Drosselmeyer's.
He reminds me of a land
I discovered
when I was a little girl...
full of sweets and flowers
and the funniest people.
That sounds wonderful.
It was.
Maybe you'll go there too
one day.
Maybe you can
take me there.
Are you all right, Mother?
I'm fine.
I'd love to take you,
my darling.
But there are
some journeys...
you have to go on alone.
Clara, I know
you sometimes wish
you were more like
your sister.
But I love you
because you're so different.
You see the world
in a unique way.
When you realize that's
your greatest strength...
you can change the world,
my girl.
And I'll be watching you.
Now, where are you
going to put him?
It's perfect.
(CLOCK TICKING)
(TAPPING)
(OWL HOOTS)
CLARA: Oh, Mother,
it's so beautiful here.
I don't know
if I can get the key back.
And if I fail...
this whole world
you discovered...
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
I wish you were here.
So you can tell me
that I'm doing
the right thing
like you used to.
(WIND BLOWING)
(TINKLING)
(OWL HOOTS)
Thank you.
Clara! (SPEAKS FRENCH)
Oh, I wish I could
come with you.
You understand.
But you'll have
my tippy-top top-notch
handpicked troops
to protect you.
Good luck, my brave girl.
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
HARLEQUIN: (CLEARS THROAT)
Your most gracious majesty...
Why are you
talking like that?
- Shh!
- Do it properly.
- Your Majesty, we request...
- Look, we're volunteering.
Yep. That.
You?
Don't say it like that. We're
trained killers, we are.
Deadly.
(CLATTERS)
Attention!
CAVALIER: Pick up the dagger!
The dagger!
- By the right...
- Sorry.
...turn!
(CLANKING)
Squad march.
(HORSES SNORTING)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
CAVALIER: (QUIETLY)
Remember your training.
Stay alert.
HARLEQUIN: I'm not alert.
I'm scared.
CLARA: What's going on
up there?
Why have we stopped?
Come on!
It's only a bit of fog!
(HORSE NEIGHS)
(CROW CAWS)
(MOUSE SQUEAKS)
(CROW CAWING)
(THUDS)
- (RUSTLING)
- (GASPS)
CAVALIER: What was that?
(METAL CREAKING)
- (RUMBLING)
- (SOLDIER 1 GRUNTS)
(SOLDIER 2 SCREAMS)
Gather at the carousel!
We can't fight
what we can't see.
(MICE SQUEAKING)
CLARA: It's the mice!
They're under us!
(RUMBLING)
(SOLDIERS GRUNT)
CAVALIER: Move it! Move it!
(SOLDIERS SCREAMING)
Captain!
- (CLARA YELPS)
- (GRUNTS)
(MICE SQUEAKING)
Hang on!
(GRUNTS)
Clara!
Let me go!
Clara! Where are you?
(MICE SQUEAKING)
(GRUNTS)
Well, if it isn't
Clara Stahlbaum.
I've been expecting you.
I'm here to reclaim
what you've taken from me
and from my mother.
My key!
Please, come in.
(DRUMS PLAYING)
- (BELLS JINGLING)
- (GASPS)
- (CIRCUS MUSIC PLAYING)
- (WHOOPING)
(LAUGHS)
Whee!
(WHOOPS)
(GIGGLES)
(WHOOPING)
(VOCALIZING IN
HIGH-PITCHED VOICE)
♪ Clara Stahlbaum
Lovely Clara Stahlbaum ♪
Little Princess Clara.
She looks like a goose!
POLICHINELLE 2:
What a clumsy thing she is.
- (LAUGHS)
- (WHIMPERS)
- POLICHINELLE 4: Look out!
- (YELPS)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(CLARA GRUNTS)
POLICHINELLE 3:
Where are you going?
POLICHINELLE 2:
Leaving so soon?
POLICHINELLE 3:
Step right this way.
(SCATTING)
POLICHINELLE 1:
We have a surprise for you.
(GASPS)
- (CLARA GRUNTS)
- POLICHINELLE 3: Have a seat.
POLICHINELLE 2: Bon voyage!
POLICHINELLE 4: Adios.
(MUSIC STOPS)
MOTHER GINGER:
Hands off, young lady!
You're Mother Ginger.
And you're Queen Marie's
daughter, apparently.
(METALLIC WHIRRING)
Yes.
Now, what business brings you
to the Fourth Realm?
Don't you know
it's dangerous here?
I've come to get
what belongs to me.
That key.
If this key
belongs to anyone...
it belongs to your mother.
No.
She left it to me.
Why would she give it to you?
My mother, she...
she passed away.
Queen Marie is dead?
As if you care!
You're trying to
destroy everything
my mother ever created.
(GRUNTS)
- (BELLS JINGLE)
- (ALL GASP)
- (CIRCUS MUSIC STARTS PLAYING)
- (ALL WHOOPING)
Look what you've done
to your own realm.
You've ruined it.
- Whee!
- (GRUNTS)
Clara!
- (RUMBLING)
- (GRUNTS)
(ALL GRUNTING)
POLICHINELLE 1:
(SPEAKS FRENCH) Look out!
Clara! No!
- (POLICHINELLES LAUGHING)
- PHILLIP: Whoa.
(GRUNTS)
(POLICHINELLES LAUGHING)
MOTHER GINGER: Bring it back!
Captain! I got the key.
MOTHER GINGER: Get back here!
CLARA: She was different.
PHILLIP: Don't be fooled
by that little old lady act.
The woman is deadly.
MOTHER GINGER:
That's a dangerous key!
Foolish girl.
(PANTING)
(MOUSERINKS SQUEAKING)
Our future depends
on that girl, Mouserinks.
- To the palace!
- (SQUEAKS)
Captain...
I need to stop.
I have to open this.
It's important.
All right.
We should be safe here.
(CLICKING)
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
It can't be.
No.
It's just a music box.
But my mother told me...
"Everything you need
is inside."
There's nothing here.
There's music.
- I thought...
- (MUSIC STOPS)
I thought
if I found this key...
then I would find answers...
that everything
would make sense.
I'm just as lost
as when I arrived here.
Here...
take the key.
Bring it to Sugar Plum.
Where are you going?
- Home.
- Home?
But, Clara, we need you here.
No.
Captain, you need my mother.
She was a queen...
and I'm not.
I've never left my post,
you know.
I knew my place.
And I was happy.
But when you told me you were
going into the Fourth Realm...
I knew I'd go with you.
And it wasn't because
you're Marie's daughter...
but because
you have her same look...
of confidence...
and determination.
I don't feel very confident
right now.
You just led a regiment of men
into the Fourth Realm...
and took back this key
from Mother Ginger.
You're not lost,
Clara Stahlbaum.
- Your place is here.
- (OWL SCREECHES)
Thank you...
Captain.
(HORSE NEIGHS)
It's time to save the kingdom.
SUGAR PLUM: Clara!
I have it!
(SQUEALS) You clever girl!
Down, quick!
Quickly!
Finally!
How long I've waited
for this moment!
(CLICKS)
(WHIRRING)
(SQUEALS) Wonderful!
Bring me the tin soldiers.
(RATTLING)
You can't use tin soldiers.
Well, of course I can.
Don't be silly.
You have no idea
how they'll behave.
They're completely hollow.
They'll behave
exactly as I tell them to.
The perfect soldier.
Put them on the platform.
It is time to think big.
Are you sure about this?
She has to protect
the realms.
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
(CLATTERS)
Ready, steady, go!
(GASPS)
(WHIRRING)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(RATTLING)
(METAL CREAKING)
Hello, boys!
They're huge!
I know. Isn't it magnificent?
Soldiers...
attention!
Report!
(CLANGING)
Prepare to march
on the Fourth Realm.
March on the...
I thought this army
was to defend us.
Well, attack is the best
form of defense, my dear.
My mother wouldn't
have wanted this.
I don't care
what your mother wanted.
She's not here.
I...
I order you to stop.
You order me?
Well, well, well.
Finally ready to play queen,
are we?
Too late.
I only needed you
to bring me the key,
and now that I have it...
I have no more use for you.
Seize them!
Take your hands off her!
SUGAR PLUM: Oh,
they won't listen to you.
I gave them life...
so they'll only listen to me.
Traitor!
Why are you doing this?
Your mother abandoned us.
And then...
she just expects us to
carry on and play nice.
Well, I don't want
to play nice!
Mother Ginger didn't do
anything wrong, did she?
You lied to me.
To everyone.
But I have a very special plan
for Mother Ginger...
and the other regents.
Watch.
Oh, Guard...
will you stand
over there, please?
Yes, just right
in the center.
(LEVER CLICKS)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLES)
SUGAR PLUM: You see...
there's a funny little perk...
to your mother's invention.
It works both ways.
You are horrible.
How dare you speak
to your queen that way!
Guards!
Lock them up.
There's no way to escape.
HAWTHORNE: Get your hands
off of me! Don't touch me!
- SHIVER: Hands off!
- HAWTHORNE: How dare you!
SHIVER: I've never been
treated like this...
in all my life.
Get off! Oh, my God!
- (GASPING)
- Alas...
you're here as well,
my dear.
What's happening?
What's Sugar Plum doing?
Why are we
locked up here?
It's all my fault.
I've let you all down.
No. No.
Clara, that's not true.
Sugar Plum lied to us.
But I gave her the key...
and now she's going to use it
to destroy the realms...
and everything
that my mother loved.
- Clara, listen to me.
- No!
I wanted to go home...
but you stopped me...
and now
I've ruined everything.
(CLANGING)
This is more like it.
A proper army.
To create discipline...
order, control.
Boys in uniform with weapons.
Sends a quiver
right through me.
(EXHALES)
(MUSIC PLAYING ON MUSIC BOX)
"Everything you need
is inside."
It's me.
- (MUSIC STOPS)
- Captain.
I'm sorry for blaming you.
This is all my fault,
and I'm going to fix it.
Will you help me?
(SIGHS)
Please?
Of course I will.
Nutcrackers are very loyal.
You are indeed.
Are you ready?
Ready.
Go!
(GRUNTING)
(BOTH GASP)
I'm sorry.
CLARA: A little more.
A bit more.
SHIVER: My dear, that doesn't
look very secure.
HAWTHORNE: You can't.
It's not gonna work.
It's just the laws of physics.
Do those laws always work?
Always.
(QUIETLY) As far as I know.
Ready.
(WHIMPERS)
Go!
- SHIVER: Whoa!
- (GASPS)
Clara.
SUGAR PLUM:
That's more like it.
There she is.
SUGAR PLUM:
Out with the old...
in with the new.
- Gather at the gate.
- (DRUMS BEATING)
Wait for my command.
Jog on, boys.
She's going.
I have to get to the
Engine Room and stop this.
(CLANGING)
We can't get in this way.
(SQUEAKS)
Mouserinks.
- Get out of here!
- Wait!
I think he's trying
to tell us something.
(SQUEAKS)
Quickly.
- (GRUNTS)
- (WATER SPLASHES)
CLARA: Thank you
for your help.
(SQUEAKS)
Can you get us
to the Engine Room?
Are you sure
we can trust him?
(SQUEAKING)
Don't start with me,
mouse!
All right, stop!
We don't have much time.
We need to work together.
(SQUEAKS)
Show us.
Where'd he go?
This way!
We should be able
to ride the wheels
up to the Engine Room.
All right...
- I'll go first.
- No!
You have to warn
Mother Ginger.
Those soldiers will be heading
to the Fourth Realm.
What? I'm not going
to leave you, Clara.
I can handle this.
You have to trust me. Please.
I do.
Can you take the captain
to Mother Ginger?
(SQUEAKS)
Thank you.
Be careful.
That's an order, Captain.
(SQUEAKS)
(CLARA YELPS)
Thank you, Captain.
Please, Clara,
call me Phillip.
Thank you, Phillip.
Let's go, mouse.
Lead the way.
(SQUEAKING)
I don't speak rodent.
(SQUEAKS)
(SIGHS)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
- (CROWS CAWING)
- (GASPS)
Mother Ginger!
POLICHINELLE: Oh.
(BELLS JINGLING)
Wait!
I come as a friend.
Look.
(SQUEAKS)
MOTHER GINGER:
Let him through!
(BELLS JINGLE)
- Where's Clara?
- PHILLIP: In the palace.
But she has a plan.
Please, Mother Ginger.
Sugar Plum has built an army
to conquer all the realms.
They're coming for you.
Sugar Plum thinks
she's divided us all.
But a long time ago we both
took an oath to our queen...
to defend the realms
no matter the cost.
(SQUEAKS)
Are you still willing
to uphold that oath?
No matter the cost,
I'm ready.
Brave nutcracker.
So now...
we must draw
Sugar Plum to us.
(SQUEAKING)
(METALLIC WHIRRING)
(CLANGING)
(WHIRRING)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLES)
(BELLS JINGLING)
(POLICHINELLE SQUEAKING)
(POLICHINELLES WHOOPING,
SQUEALING)
Forget those
ludicrous clowns!
I want Mother Ginger!
(SQUEAKING)
(SWORDS CLANGING)
(CLANKING)
- (TOY MOUSE SQUEAKING)
- (SWORDS CLANGING)
(CLATTERS)
(GASPS)
SUGAR PLUM: Victory is ours!
Come out, Mother Ginger!
(DOOR CLANGS, OPENS)
(COUGHING)
The nutcracker?
Were you expecting
someone else?
Where is she?
(CLANGING)
- (BELLS JINGLING)
- Oh! (GROANS)
Mother Ginger!
At your service,
Your Majesty!
Duck!
Destroy him!
You heard her.
Come and get me.
I can disable the Engine.
Go! I'll take care
of this lot.
(WHIP CRACKING)
(GRUNTS)
(CLANGING)
No matter the cost.
I'm ready.
(MICE SQUEAKING)
Mouserinks.
(SQUEAKING)
Come on, you tin cans.
Let's settle this like men.
(WHIP CRACKING)
MOTHER GINGER:
Clara! Please, hurry!
(PHILLIP GRUNTS)
(MOUSE KING SQUEAKING)
(GRUNTS)
Mother Ginger,
I'm just so pleased...
- you decided to drop in.
- (YELLS)
(GRUNTING)
Mouserinks...
don't let them split us up.
Stay with me.
- (MOUSERINKS SQUEAKING)
- (CLANGING)
(CLANKING)
You just had to interfere
again, didn't you?
I stopped you once before,
remember?
You merely delayed
the inevitable.
(LOCK CLICKS)
The princess...
where is she?
She's gone!
She's fled the realm.
She's safe from you!
Then I'm the queen
of the castle...
and you're a dirty rascal.
This is madness, Sugar Plum!
It has to stop!
Put her on the platform.
MOTHER GINGER: Sugar Plum...
I know you miss Marie.
We all do.
But this isn't gonna
make you feel any better!
SUGAR PLUM: Banishing you
to the Fourth Realm...
made me feel just...
delicious.
But this...
(WHIRRING)
this is going to be...
exquisite.
Adieu.
Farewell.
Goodbye.
Sugar Plum, stop!
Clara, run!
Get out of here!
Seize her!
For the princess,
my friend...
and the realms.
(MOUSE KING SQUEAKING)
Don't do this.
My mother loved you.
You had a special place
in her heart.
You, of all people,
should understand, Clara.
She left you alone, too.
CLARA: No.
She left me everything I need.
I'm not alone.
Sugar Plum,
we are not alone.
You're right.
I have a big, beautiful army
to protect me.
No one will hurt me
ever again.
CLARA: I know you're angry.
But you can still do
the right thing.
MOTHER GINGER:
Sugar Plum, listen to her.
This isn't what
Marie wanted for us.
For us?
A true queen does
what's best for herself.
(WHIRRING)
(EXHALES)
CLARA: No.
A true queen does
what's best for her people.
- (SWORDS CLANG)
- (PHILLIP GRUNTS)
CLARA: And you were right,
Sugar Plum.
I am every inch
my mother's daughter.
(WHIRRING)
Clara, what have you done?
(SCREAMING)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLES)
(CLATTERS)
(GASPS)
(CLANGING)
She did it.
Let me go.
(CLANGING)
(MICE SQUEAKING)
Mouserinks.
Clara did it.
(MICE SQUEAKING CHEERFULLY)
Mother Ginger?
Well done, Clara.
(SWEEPING MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Clara, it's over.
We are saved.
Peace is restored.
The realms are reunited.
And it's all because of you,
my dear.
This all could have
been avoided
if only I listened to you,
Mother Ginger.
MOTHER GINGER:
Oh, it's not your fault.
No one else did either.
Your mother would be very
proud of you, my dear.
Very proud.
Captain Nutcracker,
would you escort Clara
to the Christmas
Tree Forest...
and then return
in your new post
as Captain of the Guard.
What about your bridge?
I'm afraid I'd be lonely.
I suppose I have you
to thank for that.
I suppose you do.
And besides, I have
a new friend now.
(SQUEAKS)
(FANFARE PLAYING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
Your Majesty.
Your Highness. And brave
Captain Nutcracker.
It is an honor to serve
at your post, sir.
Keep up the good work, men.
On three.
One, two, three.
- (BOTH GRUNTING)
- (WOOD CREAKS)
(BOTH EXHALE)
You've really put on weight.
(SNIFFLES)
(SNEEZES)
(JINGLES NEIGHS)
Please come back
to the realms one day.
Oh, of course I will.
Or maybe one day,
you could come to my world.
You can meet my family.
Are they like you?
(CHUCKLES)
Well, they're a bit different.
I'm going to miss you.
I'll miss you too.
But when you miss someone,
you remember them.
Are you sure?
And one day
that'll make you smile.
I promise you.
Goodbye, Clara.
Goodbye.
(JINGLES SNORTS)
Clara?
There you are.
Back so soon?
Thank you.
DROSSELMEYER:
Ah. (CHUCKLES)
Pin tumbler locks.
Devilish things
to get into, aren't they?
I worked it out.
Eventually.
Hmm. I knew you would.
Clara...
your mother was the cleverest
inventor I ever knew.
And there was
never any doubt
when I asked what
her greatest creation was.
It was you.
Clara.
Father, I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry.
This time has been
extremely difficult...
for all of us.
I lost the love of my life,
and you lost your mother.
And I will miss her
every day of my life.
But I don't want to miss
one more minute...
with you, or Louise,
or Fritz.
(SWEEPING MUSIC PLAYING)
Shall we go home?
Don't you owe me
a dance first?
After all, it's what's
expected of us.
I suppose I do.
- (SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
- Ah, you've opened it.
Wasn't so hard after all.
What is it?
This is the very song
that your mother and I
first danced to.
LOUISE: May we join you?
I want to dance.
Please do.
(WALTZ MUSIC PLAYING)
(SLOW INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
PLAYING)
(MELLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
(WHIMSICAL MUSIC PLAYING)