This is it, suse.
We're in Kenya.
It's the cradle of mankind.
The source of the nile.
Ted, I think you've seen
too many pbs specials.
Hey, do you think there
are any lions
around here or anything?
Lions?
Ted, Nairobi's a big city.
Come on.
Well, they've got
to have a zoo, right?
This is not gonna be like
Tarzan, you know?
No swinging from the vines.
Hey, I know that.
Why do you always treat me
like a total idiot?
I'm your older sister, Ted.
It's expected of me.
- How are you?
- Susan, honey, hi.
- It's good to see you.
- You've lost weight.
What have you got in here?
You must start eating
like a normal human being.
How was it with grandma?
Were you terribly lonely,
guys?
It was only a month, mom.
It was no big deal.
But we missed you,
of course.
Well, let's get going.
We got a long,
long drive ahead.
Well, this is the great
rift valley.
And down there
is my tracking station.
How do you concentrate
on work, dad?
Are you kidding?
Not even Africa distracts
your father.
This is great.
I can't wait to get out
in the bush
and explore around here.
No.
We don't want you straying too
far from the house, Ted.
Aww, mom!
Well, you know there
are wild animals out there.
Wild animals in Africa?
You got to be putting me on,
right?
This is mwangi.
Gonna help us with some Swahili
while we're here, okay?
Here we are, kids.
Your home for
the next six months.
Huh... Very primitive.
Oh, you think you want
to rough it?
In a few days, believe me,
you'll be grateful
for the creature comforts.
I'd be grateful if I could see
some more creatures.
So what's our first African
meal gonna be, huh?
Rhino ribs?
Wildebeest surprise?
Guys.
Here it is.
Lamb chops.
And mashed potatoes.
Your favorite.
You know,
when I close my eyes,
I think I'm still in Pasadena.
The same thing happens
when mine are open.
They do mean well,
you know, Ted.
Of course.
They're just sparing us
culture shock.
Yeah and who knows
what else?
It's still Africa out there.
All the modern conveniences
in the world can't change that.
It's still gonna be
an adventure.
Good night, Ted.
Ted, you think you could maybe
do that somewhere else, please?
Listen, kiddo.
This is the prison
exercise yard.
If you don't want
to exercise,
you can go back
to your cell.
Cell?
Prison?
It's not that bad.
Oh, it isn't?
No.
I can do my homework
in L.A.,
but one thing I can't do
is see Kenya.
Now that we're here, we're not
even allowed to explore it.
Don't you want to explore?
Don't you wonder
what's out there?
Yes, I do, Ted.
But you know mom.
She's a worrier.
At least she's letting us
go on that safari in August.
Yeah, safe and controlled.
Ted, you can
understand that--
susie, susie, come here.
Take a look at this.
Come here.
What?
Right there by the water.
Those herdsmen,
are they Maasai?
One way to find out.
I'm going for a closer look.
Well, Ted, mom said--
- Wait.
- What?
Is he coming towards us?
What, the little guy?
Yeah, come on.
Back here. Come back here.
Oh!
Ah, whoa!
Ah!
Jambo.
Hi.
Uh, I'm Ted and this
is my sister, Susan.
I'm morogo.
You not English?
No.
No, we're American.
We live around here.
How about you?
Well, I guess
we're neighbors then.
Good.
Come see the neighborhood.
- That'd be great.
- Really?
Whoa, morogo!
Check out those zebras.
No.
No, morogo.
They look pretty much
like zebra to me.
Ted.
They're gorgeous.
Sometimes food tastes best
in mouth of friends.
What does that mean?
It means, uh...
It means I'm happy like
"pumdamlia."
Ah!
This is my home.
You want come see it?
Um, what time's mom
get off work?
Well, the clinic closes
at 5:00.
We have to be back before
our mother.
Are you gonna
be free tomorrow?
Can we see you again?
Meet at the same place
when the sun is up there.
Noon. Noon?
Excellent.
Kwaheri.
Clinic.
It's just wonderful.
So what'd you kids do today?
Um... Homework.
You? Homework?
Um, well,
i shot some hoops
and, um, listened
to some music.
I did my calculus.
Finished Silas marner
finally.
You do better next time.
Wait a minute.
You just won?
I thought I was doing
all right.
Trouble does not
ring a bell.
You know a lot of those
sayings, don't you?
None of 'em make any sense.
Okay, morogo,
coast is clear.
Okay, keep away from 'em,
morogo.
Okay, just keep
getting the dots.
That's good.
Come on.
You almost got it. Come on.
You can do it.
Keep going.
Oh, no.
Hello?
Anybody home?
Mom, what are you
doing here?
I happen to live here. Now--
but it's only 4:00.
We're doing inventory,
so we closed the clinic early.
Mom, say hello to morogo.
Jambo. Samahani.
And how'd you all meet,
hanging out at the galleria?
But morogo has lived here
all his life,
so he can certainly
keep us out of danger.
That is the reason
for the rule, isn't it?
The way I see it,
if morogo shows us around,
we won't be in any danger.
Makes good sense, dad.
You really know which buttons
to push with me, don't you?
Oh, well.
We'll just get it later.
Morogo.
Morogo, we can always
get another soccer ball.
Morogo, it's not
that important.
Morogo?
What does he think
he's doing?
That was great, morogo.
Ted, don't you dare.
I don't expect you
to understand,
but sometimes a man's got to do
what a man's got to do.
What a load of macho baloney.
Ted, get back here.
Shh.
Morogo!
Oh.
Oh!
"What a man's got to do,"
huh, Ted?
Come on.
Let's go.
You said something
to it, right, a spell?
No, I did not speak
to rhino.
A charm, then?
Some special tribal magic?
Yes.
Special magic is to go where
rhino cannot smell.
You mean you were downwind?
Well, couldn't it see you?
Rhino sees with his nose.
Well, that was your problem,
Ted.
You should have taken
a shower first.
There's something down there.
I think that's a baby cat.
But where's its mother?
Well, let's go
check it out.
No.
If mother come back,
very bad for us.
And if the mother
doesn't come back,
what happens to the baby?
Ted, it's over here.
Oh, yeah.
Whoa.
Oh, she is adorable.
Look at her.
She's so cute.
What are we gonna call her?
How about fido?
That is so typical.
Hey, what are these?
Oh.
Ted?
I found the mother.
She is dead.
- Dead?
- Yes.
Skinned by a poacher.
You better go before
the hyenas come.
Right.
A poacher.
Then this may be a clue.
Check this out.
These weird tire tracks
and they don't go anywhere.
Not tire tracks.
Show marks.
Shoes made from old tire.
The mother's dead,
isn't she?
Yeah.
We're taking her home.
What?
Taking this little
duma home? Why?
Because if we don't take this
duma home, she's a goner.
I know you guys want
to keep her
and I'm sure you'd do a good job
taking care of her.
But we will.
We will and it'll
teach us responsibility.
Right, dad?
Ted, what happens
when it's time
for us to go back home?
Have you two thought
about that?
You do realize we can't bring
a cheetah back to L.A.
Unless you want a cheetah
more than a mother.
Mom, if we don't keep her,
she's gonna die.
This house is not
a game preserve.
You know, you never let us
have a pet back home either.
Now don't you try that
sentimental stuff
on me, young man.
It won't work.
I don't know.
It's worked before.
I can't believe you kids
talked us into keeping her.
Come on, admit it,
mom.
Duma is one cute little cat.
She's not going to be
so little six months from now.
Ted, kick.
Okay.
What's duma doing?
Duma, what are you doing?
Duma!
Park at an angle, dad.
You guys can get duma okay?
Yeah.
Morning, Mr. Patel.
Morning, professor.
Morning, Mrs. Johnson.
Morning.
Good morning.
Morning, morning.
I don't suppose
that fabric we ordered
has come in yet?
Perhaps it will come
in the afternoon delivery.
Yes.
Duma.
Well, Mr. Patel,
looks like we just
bought ourselves some cookies.
An unusual snack
for a most unusual pet
and a most beautiful one.
Do you have any laundry
detergent today, Mr. Patel?
Yes, sir.
50 shillings.
There was plenty last week.
Oh, look.
Your cheetah, she's escaped.
She's gone.
Uh-oh.
Red alert. Red alert.
Ted, skip the theatrics.
Come here.
A trained cheetah?
Marvelous.
You call and she comes.
Yeah, that's
our good little girl.
All right.
There it goes. It's up.
Ooh, no, wait.
Morogo, no.
Come back over here.
Okay, look, you have
to stay on this side, all right?
And why don't you
serve it over to Ted?
David, there you are.
You look fabulous.
Hi, Jean.
Mmm.
I'm afraid Ted's grades
are as sloppy as his room.
Yeah, we don't want them
to get too far behind.
So the kids will go home
early for the start of school?
Right.
I've got these last six weeks
to finish up,
and then the station's
all yours.
You're really gonna
love it here, Dave.
We all have.
But I'm sure the kids are ready
to get back to the states.
But we just got here!
Ted, you've been here
almost six months.
I know, but it doesn't
feel like it.
Time has a way
of tricking you.
Even more so as you get older.
Well, can't we extend
our stay a little bit?
Uh-uh.
School starts in a few weeks.
Everything's arranged.
That means we're gonna have
to say goodbye to morogo...
Probably for good.
Yeah, and duma.
That's right, sweetie.
It's time to find out
what to do with duma.
What's best for her.
Now, duma, you know you're not
supposed to be back there.
Silly cat.
What's best for her
is to release her
back into the wild.
That's exactly
what we figured.
But it's good to hear it
from a game warden.
I recommend cheetah valley.
The ecology's perfect there.
It'll be easy for her
to find a mate.
Cheetah valley?
See, dad, this isn't
gonna be that hard.
Ted, it's not gonna
be that simple either.
When one domesticates
these cats,
their hunting skills
are stunted.
You mean she may not know
how to be a cheetah?
Precisely.
And unless she learns,
she'll be in serious danger.
She trusts people,
but people won't trust her.
If she should wander
into a house, for example--
excuse my intrusion,
please.
Distinguished professor
and family
have been most generous.
Perhaps I may reciprocate by
relieving them of this animal.
Thank you.
No.
If I offer £50 Sterling
as additional inducement?
Come on, Larry.
Let's go back to our place.
Good idea.
I'll pick up a rope kit
and we'll
put duma through her paces.
Why is fate dangling
such hopes
and then snatching them away?
That cat could make me rich.
Rich, patel?
How so?
I have an uncle in India.
He's racing cheetah
against greyhounds.
It is bringing him a fortune.
A cheetah racing
against greyhounds?
Yes, and this cheetah,
she's already tamed.
Most difficult part of training
is accomplished.
I could begin negotiations
with racetrack today,
if only I possess cat.
She'll smell the gazelle right
through the sack.
Rather interesting test
of instinct, really.
She knows it's food,
but will she chase it?
Okay.
Ready, Earl?
All set.
We'll see how it goes, Larry.
Okay.
When you get up to speed,
I'll let her out.
Okay.
Chase the bag, duma.
Yeah, you can do it.
Come on, girl. Faster.
Come on, girl.
You can do it.
Come on.
Oh, duma.
Way to go, killer.
Looks like you kids have
your work cut out for you.
How's she ever gonna
learn how to hunt
if all she wants to do
is go for a Sunday drive?
Well, mom was saving this
roast for a special occasion.
Here we go.
All right.
Come on.
All right, we got it.
Come on, guys.
Chase it, girl.
Come on, duma.
There you go. Come on.
Get it away from her, Ted.
Come on, girl.
Come on.
Now duma is getting me too.
Throw it up.
Go and get it.
Come on. Chase, chase.
There you go, duma.
Oh, wow!
She caught it.
Okay, here we go.
All right,
we got some gazelle.
A whole herd of the suckers.
Do you think she's
gonna know what to do?
Well, we have a saying.
When rain falls
on a leopard,
spots do not wash away.
But, morogo,
duma's a cheetah.
It's also sunny,
but that's not the point.
Okay, enough
with the sayings.
Come on. Come on.
Okay.
Why don't you go grab yourself
a gazelle burger
and we'll go find
some ringside seats.
I see her.
Where?
Oh, there she is.
I can't believe it.
Duma's going for it
on her very first try.
Oh, whoa,
look at that, guys!
Go, duma!
She's nearly got it.
She pounces!
Ladies and gentlemen,
it's not pretty,
but that's nature
in the raw--
ah! What the--
that was not our duma.
Ted.
What are you laughing at?
Duma?
Duma!
She's always come back before.
That's a good sign.
Tonight, she's exploring
and even hunting.
Isn't that what you've been
training her for?
Yeah, but, um, what if
something happened to her?
I mean, she could be hurt
or something.
You know what I think's
really worrying you?
That she might leave before
you can say goodbye.
Well, we've raised her since
she was a baby, mom.
It would be awful
if she just left.
When you love something,
loss can be
a part of the bargain, Ted.
Come on.
Let's go inside.
Susie, she's back.
I wonder if she caught anything
for dinner last night.
I'm glad you're back,
sweetie.
But I wish you'd learn
to hunt for yourself.
As I was saying, abdallah,
every schoolchild knows
the cheetah is the world's
fastest runner.
But not so many
people know
that cheetah has no endurance.
She tires quickly.
So we are planning
to make the race too long
for cheetah and
then bet against her.
Yes, quite neat, really.
Nobody will ever guess
that the owners
are betting against
their own cheetah.
When she runs out of steam,
it's the owners
who collect the money.
In addition to your share
of the purse, abdallah,
as a bonus, after the race
you can keep her.
Good.
That skin will
bring me much money.
No long faces now.
You're saying goodbye to a
wonderful time in your lives,
but there's lots of excitement
to look forward to.
Oh, more exciting than going
exploring with morogo?
Or having a cheetah
for a pet?
No, Ted, there are different
kinds of excitement.
How about a toast
to everything
you've had a chance
to experience this year
and to David's family
who are next in line.
Hear, hear.
And to morogo.
Couldn't be here
because he had
a previous engagement
with some goats.
All right, patel,
where's this cheetah of yours?
You said it would be here.
I said I thought
it would be here.
The cat is tame.
It is ordinarily sleeping
in the yard.
Oh, not tonight.
The boy.
The boy calls the cat
with a whistle.
If one of us could get
that whistle--
so beautiful.
Superior cake.
Oh, thank you.
16 degrees above the equator.
Very good.
Mom, that was very symbolic,
i think.
Cutting us right out,
aren't you?
How about we all go
in the living room?
Good idea.
Listen, honey, this is
a pretty special occasion.
You think the kids are
old enough to try champagne?
I most certainly do not.
What about the grown-ups?
Ted, how about
a little more music, huh?
Sure. I haven't packed
all my records yet.
If you don't mind something
a little more African, dad.
It is our last night.
Well, you've got
to take your kids on safari
like we did, David.
Ted and Susan just loved it.
What's the matter, Ted?
I thought I heard something.
Must have been my imagination.
She is ours.
Duma!
I don't like the looks
of this.
Well, let's not lose
our heads.
She stayed out a couple
of nights ago.
Yeah, but she was back
by morning.
Well, maybe she's
making progress.
Maybe.
Except my whistle's missing.
This is for you.
When the river divides,
its waters are not so sweet.
I knew you'd have a saying
for today, morogo.
This one even you know
what it means.
And this means
though we are far apart,
our spirits share
the same earth
and the same sky.
We're never gonna
forget you, morogo.
The way duma left
was too sudden.
I know it.
Ted, you're looking
for a human end
to the relationship.
Now that's just not
a reasonable expectation.
Duma loved us,
but as a cheetah.
She depended on us and then left
home when the time was right.
Exactly.
You two did what
you had to do.
Come on now.
You should be proud
of yourselves.
If we take this road,
we should be at my camp
by nightfall.
It's not a bad road.
There's a little stretch here
with a few potholes.
Mr. Patel?
Oh, good morning, professor.
Good morning.
Could we get some petrol,
please?
Certainly, professor.
Certainly.
Petrol.
Petrol for you.
Kids, get yourselves whatever
you want for the plane.
The young missus finding it
a sad day
leaving this splendid country,
losing her pet?
What did you say?
I recall you intended
to release her
in cheetah valley.
Therefore I'm assuming--
but you said "lose."
Perhaps I did not choose
the most precise word,
but does it not do justice
to how the miss feels?
The tread marks
were the same!
It's the guy who killed
duma's mother.
And what about that
"losing your pet" business?
Oh, Ted,
Mr. Patel is a foreigner.
He made a slip of the tongue.
He's got a better vocabulary
than we do.
Besides, what makes him
think Susan
was crying because of duma?
Patel knows that duma's
one of the family.
Right!
When he tried to buy her
and that demonstrates
motivation.
Ted, now let this thing go.
You're trying to build a case
that just isn't there.
And it doesn't take
a Freud to figure out
that you're looking for
a reason to stay in Kenya.
Now let's just try
and be mature about this.
Ah, Ted.
We'll be joining you
in a month.
I know you guys will be fine.
Grandma will be waiting
at the airport.
You'll be okay.
Dad!
Will the two of you try
and cheer up, please?
I'll bet you anything duma
will be waiting there for us
as soon as your mom
and I get home.
Yeah, we'll take charge
of releasing her.
I know it's not
what you hoped for,
but at least we'll have done
right by her, huh?
Smile and a kiss?
Come here, honey.
I love you, honey.
I love you, daddy.
I'm right, you know?
You heard dad, Ted.
Let it go.
Just listen to the facts.
One, we know patel wanted duma.
Two, she suddenly disappears.
Three, patel mentions
that she's lost
when there's no way he could
have known about that!
Shh!
Four, the guy
at patel's store
was wearing shoes
with the same tread
as what we found when duma's
mother was killed.
Five, did you see the look
on the shoe guy's face
when patel made the slip
about losing our pet?
- No, I didn't.
- Trust me.
Where was I?
Six, my missing whistle.
Ted, the way you pack,
it's a miracle
you can find anything.
No, I put it
in my desk drawer.
How can you be so sure?
Darn it, Susan.
I made a point of putting it
there last night.
I planned to give it to morogo
as a goodbye present.
Really?
Yes!
Okay, I believe you.
What?
Patel took duma.
What can we do about it?
May I have your tickets,
please?
Um... Well, actually,
me and my sister--
"my sister and I."
We're a little confused.
Um, this is the flight
to Beijing, isn't it?
That was great, Ted.
These tickets cost dad
a lot of money.
Refundable.
What about our luggage?
On the plane.
When we get to L.A.,
our underwear
will be there to greet us.
What about grandma?
Isn't she supposed
to meet us at lax?
Well, I think that was a
wonderful experience for them.
I just wish they hadn't taken
duma's leaving so hard.
Now, honey, it's all part
of growing up.
Oh, Earl,
i think I see them!
- Where?
- Isn't that Susan waving?
- Oh, yeah.
- See right there?
- See? Bye!
- Bye!
- Bye, kids!
- "Dear mom--"
- no, skip "dear."
Deal with telegrams
is keep 'em short.
Seems awfully chilly.
All right.
"Plans changed.
Kids arrived later."
No, dad would say,
"kids departure delayed."
Oh, okay.
"Kids departure delayed."
That's better. "Delayed.
- Will advise."
- Nice touch.
Thanks.
"Advise."
That's it. "Love, dad."
Sheer genius, Ted.
He writes to his mother
and signs it "dad"?
Force of habit.
Sign it "Earl."
Done.
Wow, how much have you got?
About 50 shillings.
It's not gonna
get us very far.
We're loaded
with traveler's checks.
Amazing our mom trusts us
to let us buy
our own back-to-school
clothes.
Ted, I hope we haven't
done all this
for some stupid
wild goose chase.
Don't worry.
As soon as we find duma,
it'll all be worth it.
Besides, what's the worst thing
that mom and dad can do to us?
Put us up for adoption.
Well, never thought
I'd see this place again.
Good afternoon.
How may I help?
Is Mr. Patel here?
Uh, no.
My cousin left abruptly.
I bet. Fact number seven.
We need to speak
to Mr. Patel.
Can you tell us how
to reach him, please?
Regretfully not.
He's on retreat and does not
wish to be disturbed.
Well, it's kind of important.
You see, we, um--
we have some money
for Mr. Patel.
Our parents asked us
to deliver it.
Uh, you may entrust it
to my care.
I am happy to send it
to him.
Well, thank you,
but we need to sign them
and give them to him personally.
This is indeed a conundrum.
I'm sure he'd want you
to tell us,
especially since
we're leaving Africa.
There won't be another chance
to give him his money.
He is in a camp near
thomson's falls.
I am to write to him
care of general delivery...
Jamhuri.
Jamhuri?
Thank you.
Not bad.
I sweated it out of him.
How much progress
have we really made here?
Do you have any idea how
to get to the jamhuri?
Look, if we're out
on the road hitching,
you just know mom and dad are
gonna be the first to stop.
This is indeed a conundrum.
We need some help, suse.
Sure.
Well, cheetah...
You've got some more work
to do today.
Are you going to be
a naughty girl?
All right, he's in there.
The only problem is so
is everybody else.
Does it matter?
You bet it does.
Look, this is strictly
a need-to-know operation.
Hey, the beeper,
African style.
Morogo.
Psst!
Over there. Come on.
Jamhuri?
I know where it is.
Maybe a two-day walk.
But you could do it?
You know how?
No way, José.
Morogo, to save duma's life?
My father would
be most angry
with such mzungu foolishness.
I cannot go.
Look, our parents
are gonna
be really mad at us,
but we can handle that.
Can you tell us
how to do it?
Whoa, whoa, Ted, Ted.
You are not
seriously suggesting
that we go ahead on our own,
are you?
If it's the only way, yes.
Okay, you remember
the blue dukkha?
Okay, go to the blue dukkha,
follow the sun.
You see a big pile of rocks
just at the top
of devil's gate.
Devil's gate.
Devil's gate?
Ted, this is nuts.
This is absolutely
looney tunes.
Look,
we are two kids from L.A.
About to spend
two days walking
through
the uncharted wilderness
where animals eat kids
from L.A.
Your heart is
in the right place and all,
but we are not going
to survive.
That's not gonna help duma
or us.
- I think if we just--
- look!
Suse, that's that big pile
of rocks
that morogo was
telling us about.
This is devil's gate.
We're doing okay.
Duma.
The first lesson
she must learn
is that there is no escape.
Then we will train her
to race.
But we need to know
exactly how far
she can run before tiring.
Yes, yes.
We have an odometer.
She may resist.
She must learn
that she's powerless
and we are powerful.
Let's begin now.
Well, you didn't get
very far.
You're a lazy pussycat.
We've only been
at this for three hours
and it's gonna be dark soon.
Yeah, and sunset is feeding
time in Africa.
Okay.
Okay, we need a place
to crash for the night.
Now what would morogo do
in a situation like this?
Morogo had the good sense
not to get in
a situation like this.
Think the kids are okay?
They were so upset
about leaving.
Oh, sure.
Seeing old friends again.
Getting ready for school.
They're having a great time.
Ted!
Ted, this is totally insane.
We are entirely
without resources.
We don't know what
we're doing.
Now wait a minute.
Do you have any idea
what we're gonna
eat or drink today?
Well, I thought about that.
Do you really think that
morogo's instructions
are gonna get us to jamhuri?
Now that you mention it,
they were a little vague.
If one of us gets bitten
by a snake,
do you know lethal
from non-lethal?
No, not exactly.
Look, I don't like it either,
but it's time to admit we
are out of our depth here.
I think we should go back and
tell mom and dad everything.
Absolutely not.
It's not going
to be pleasant,
but it beats dying
of exposure
or getting eaten by something.
Right, right.
You're absolutely right.
Thank you.
The only problem
is there's something
moving around down there.
Morogo!
- Jambo, dudes.
- Morogo!
Oh, morogo,
you don't know how glad
we are to see you,
little buddy.
I worried about my friends.
Maybe you need some help,
so I brought everything we need.
You all right?
Yeah.
Here.
Weren't your mom and dad
upset about you coming?
They don't know yet.
We're in the same boat.
Boat? No.
Now got much walking to do.
Walking.
Boat.
I knew that.
Yet to say "boat--"
I'm so thirsty.
Do you think we can drink that?
I don't think you'd want to.
How'd you manage to find us
way out here, morogo?
Every animal in the bush
knows where you are.
I don't suppose we're getting
close to jamhuri?
Good joke, Susan.
Now we begin.
Begin?
Oh, this is awful.
Lighten up, Susan.
You went on a safari
with your parents.
What's the big deal this time?
Because on that safari,
we slept in tents.
We had bug spray, lanterns,
a Coleman stove.
We had stuff to eat.
And our guide didn't make us
climb any mountains either.
My mom likes thing safe
and controlled.
I'm beginning to realize
that she has a point.
But you call that a safari?
Sounds like you took
your whole house with you.
Exactly.
Aah!
Come on, Susan.
No time for sightseeing.
She cannot eat through
the cage, abdallah.
That's the point.
If she's angry
and she's hungry,
then she chases
the rabbit better.
Like some food, cat?
Too bad.
You've got to earn it.
A root.
Now it's your turn.
Does it taste
as bad as it smells?
It's wet.
That's all I care about.
Oh, excuse me.
Come.
Many hours to go.
Couldn't we just rest
a little while longer?
My feet are killing me.
No.
Think of poor duma.
Come here, cat.
Come on, duma.
Back in the box.
Now we cross for jamhuri.
Morogo, those hippos,
are they dangerous?
Only when they are hungry.
Yeah, but what
do they eat, morogo?
Whatever they find
in the river.
I just hope they're
vegetarians.
All right, come on.
Come on, guys.
Keep moving.
Smooth moves, mzungus.
Guys, look,
i got to stop.
I'm hungry, I'm soaked,
and I'm dead on my feet,
which happen to feel
like lead weights.
Well, I'm beyond hungry.
I'm starving.
Good.
Starving is good.
Now we can make a fire
and talk about food.
You sorry we're doing this?
No.
Just not sure
we're right to do it.
So what do you got
for us, huh?
Roots and berries?
No. Termites.
Termites?
You expect us to eat termites?
I think we can count
two no votes on that
they give strength.
I don't care.
Termites are insects.
Eww.
How can you do that?
Mzungu eat fish.
Put fish in mouth,
can put anything in mouth.
They're really not too bad?
Mmm.
Very not too bad.
Suse, they're not
even dead yet.
Duma's depending on us.
We need the protein.
How are they really?
Remember that time
grandma made us
steak and kidney pie?
This is worse.
You know, Dave,
if we adjust the telemetry
of the whole burg,
we'd probably get that downlink
on that one
eccentric transponder.
Sounds like the same scenario
we had in Australia last year.
Yeah.
- Uh, Earl?
- Uh-huh?
We seem to have a visitor.
Oh?
He's got a spear, Earl.
Oh.
Jambo.
Earl Johnson.
Yes, I know.
What can I do for you?
No. It's what we can do
for each other, Earl Johnson.
I know your wife must
have made a mistake.
I put the kids on the plane
myself and I saw it take off.
Mom. Hi, it's Earl.
Yes, mom, I know
it's a good connection.
Mom, this is gonna sound
like a silly question, but--
telegram?
What telegram?
Wow.
This is not good.
Wind brings our smell
to elephant.
That big one
is magnificent.
He's also angry.
Angry at us?
You want to ask him?
I do not.
Uh, guys,
he's coming towards us.
Um, hey, what's our best move?
Morogo!
What's he gonna do
if he catches us?
Go this way.
Come on, Ted.
Come on!
Ted!
Faster! It's coming!
I'm coming!
Which way should we go?
- Turn this way.
- Oh!
Whoa, morogo.
Watch your spear.
Look out!
I think he really liked
you guys.
That was stupendous!
I don't know
where patel is
and that guy in there wouldn't
give me the time of day.
Hello, again.
I've brought my friend.
We're both very eager
to locate Mr. Patel.
Very eager.
Isn't that so, kipoin?
Ha!
Jamhuri.
Excuse me?
Jamhuri. Jamhuri.
And now please
to leave store.
I am closing.
I want to lock the door.
I am closing
until further notice.
Please leave.
Morogo, I'm almost
afraid to ask, but--
yes, Susan. Jamhuri.
We made it?
We really made it?
All right!
That's it?
That's jamhuri?
That's not even worth putting
on a map.
We have come to jamhuri,
but where is duma?
Well, that guy
in the store that patel
was staying near...
Thomson's falls.
That's right.
Do you have any idea
where that is?
Hakuna matata.
No problem.
Right. Yes.
So you'll call us as soon
as you get any information?
Okay, the police
are on the case.
And so are we, Earl.
They're our kids.
I'm not gonna sit
around here
hoping someone else finds them.
Now there's only
one road to jamhuri.
I suppose we could probably
overtake them on the way.
We go now.
Looks like both our wives
are insisting, kipoin.
Not exactly guarded
like fort Knox.
If poachers live here,
we must be very careful.
We open the gate,
we make big noise.
Wait, morogo,
what are you talking about?
What do you know?
Homemade security system.
Come on.
There he is.
Look, abdallah,
it holds up.
It's all ready.
You see that?
That's patel.
I was right.
Come on.
All right, how many
of the enemy can there be?
Patel and the shoe guy,
right?
That's two of them
and there's three of us.
What are you thinking,
Ted?
We're gonna go in there
and take them out?
Let's wait for night,
then we'll go in
and look for duma.
What if that truck
comes back?
Susan, I'll stay here and
watch for the bad guys.
You go in and look for duma.
Okay, but be careful.
You too.
"Pete patel presents
the ultimate race.
Cheetah versus greyhound."
What a creep!
This is why patel wanted duma.
That's her.
That's duma.
Oh!
Sweetheart.
Oh.
What have they done to you?
Hey.
How we gonna
get her out of here?
It's a combination lock.
We'll have to break
the lock somehow.
I'll go get something.
Duma, hi.
Find something, suse?
Oh, the thought of our kids
out here alone at night.
Honey, they're to alone.
Morogo is with them.
But our son has
never been out
at night like this before.
Well, what do we do now?
The authorities
have long wanted me.
These children know too much.
If i-- if I'm understanding
you correctly,
I cannot countenance this.
There's no time
to argue about it now.
Let's wait till
after the race.
What do we do
with them meanwhile?
A cage, of course.
Yes. Good.
Then we leave
for Nairobi immediately.
Let's get a move on,
abdallah.
I must get my tools.
Bit of bad luck,
those children turning up.
Yes, for them.
Ha!
Good work, mzungus.
Morogo!
We need some help, morogo.
Do you know what
a wire cutter is?
No, wait. Here.
38 right, 24 left, 30 right.
Huh?
When they opened the cage,
all I did was pay attention.
We've got to find
a way to get to Nairobi now.
Jamhuri must have
a police station.
Why don't go file a report?
No, because by the time
it takes the police
to get out to that guy's camp
and confirm our story,
file forms in triplicate,
duma's gonna become
a wall hanging
just like her mother.
Ted's right.
We go to Nairobi right away.
Fine, but how are we
supposed to get there?
Well, we can hitchhike.
I know it may take a while,
but--
Two Americans and one tribal boy
near jamhuri.
We told your father
it wouldn't take long.
You can contact them
at the police station.
Want anything?
Yeah.
I need a bathroom.
Ah, the police station
is only 20 minutes away.
I can't wait that long.
Oh, me either.
I'll be waiting.
This truck better
be going to Nairobi.
Duma's race starts soon.
I'm really very sorry.
But now at least we know
they are all right.
Yeah, but where were
they headed?
What are they up to?
I think I know.
Take a look at this.
A cheetah race?
Against greyhounds.
But this race starts
in two hours.
I don't think you
can make it in time.
But perhaps we can
radio ahead,
set up a roadblock--
you do whatever
you have to do.
We're going to Nairobi downs.
- Come on.
- But--
and your parents and
the police are on your tail?
Look, I know it sounds
incredible, mister,
but it's true.
The police had us in custody
just a couple of minutes ago.
Oh, in a sense, I'm
harboring fugitives right now.
Isn't that right?
Not to fret.
Got into some scrapes myself
as a lad.
And keeping your cheetah out
of a poacher's hands
is a worthy cause.
I'll get you to Nairobi downs!
This Sunday will be ladies'
day at Nairobi downs.
Thanks.
Sorry to drop you here.
Good luck with your cheetah!
Where we gonna
get a taxi?
I think this goes through
the market street.
We can probably
get a cab there.
Okay.
You've broken all
of my Spears.
You are going to pay for all--
thank you. Sorry.
Come--
Stop him!
Stop him! Stop him!
Back in here.
Hey, stop him!
Stop that young man!
Hey, stop him! Hey!
Stop him! Stop him!
Morogo, over here!
Morogo!
We're over here!
Over here!
Morogo, it's okay.
Downwind of the cars.
Morogo, are you all right?
Okay, come on.
Wait.
Eric's boy is sixth,
sunny James loaf behind
in seventh place,
Malakai bringing up the rear.
No problem with this animal,
gentleman.
As you can see,
she's quite tame.
She has no taste
for greyhound fricassee.
Win, lose, or draw,
it's all harmless fun.
There's a taxi.
Come on.
Nairobi downs, please.
Oh, you're going
to the cheetah race.
Ladies and gentlemen,
before our fourth race,
we would like to offer
for your entertainment,
a special event.
A race between
the fastest dogs in Kenya
and the fastest animal
on the planet.
This is an exhibition only,
ladies and gentlemen.
No betting permitted.
Seven to one.
Getting much action,
old boy?
Everybody thinks
the cheetah will win.
When I remind them
there is
no official betting,
they all offered
to wager privately.
They eat out of my hands.
We are rich, Nigel.
We are rich.
Good show.
The results of the third race
are now official.
The stewards have disqualified
Nairobi downs racing association
wishes to thank
patel enterprises for putting
on this exhibition.
Is this seat taken,
old boy?
Not a better picture.
The officials have signaled
that the greyhounds
and cheetah are
in their chutes.
We're about to begin.
And they're off.
Oh, and the cheetah jumps out
to a remarkable lead.
What a display of lightning
speed, ladies and gentlemen.
And as they approach
the first bend,
it's the cheetah
by six lengths.
The cheetah is running away
with this race.
Hold on.
The cheetah's lead is down
to only three lengths.
Can she be tiring already?
Royal flush is gaining on her.
And royal flush takes
the lead from the cheetah.
Excuse me.
There she is.
Oh, too bad,
but that cheetah
has run out of steam early.
She's already out of the race.
Royal flush and Sully
continue
to battle it out
for the lead,
with jolly o...
What are you doing?
Hey!
Ted, it worked.
She's coming this way.
This is remarkable,
ladies and gentlemen.
The cheetah has found
a second wind.
We counted her out
prematurely.
Something's gone wrong.
The cheetah has caught up
with jolly o.
She shows no signs of letting
up, ladies and gentlemen.
She is right back
in this race.
Wait.
She's going right past us.
I can't believe it.
I think she's trying to win.
Look at her fly.
Go, duma!
Come on, girl!
You can do it!
I know you can do it!
Good grief!
That cheetah's gonna
catch bunny.
The cheetah's natural
hunting instincts
have helped her to win it
by five lengths!
How can we possibly
find them in this crowd?
Do you see them?
There.
Susan!
Mom!
Morogo.
Ted, are you all right?
I'm okay.
Are you sure?
Punish us later,
but we got to save duma first.
What are you talking about?
It's the guy who
skinned duma's mother.
Come on. Let's go.
Duma?
Come here, duma.
Come on.
Good girl.
That's right.
Uh-huh.
Abdallah.
We have been after you
a long time.
Bad day for poachers,
eh, abdallah?
I can't believe
you two did this!
You were reckless!
You were irresponsible!
You were disrespectful
of your parents
and of your grandmother.
Cheetah valley.
It's weird, isn't it?
After everything we went
through to get her back,
we're gonna turn around
and give her up.
At least we get
to say goodbye to her.
And to each other.
You know they've risked
so much for duma's sake.
Why don't we all stay in Africa
this next month
and keep duma with us
until we go?
I mean, we've had such
a wonderful time.
Why should we end it
before we have to?
Because it wouldn't
be fair...
To duma or to us.
- But, Ted--
- no.
She's come so far,
and she's ready to hunt.
That's right.
Look, if we keep her now
and pretend
everything's the way it was,
what we went through
won't mean anything.
If we really love her,
we have to let her go.
Ted's right.
We started the job.
Now we have to finish it.
Come on, duma.
Come on.
Hey.
Bye, duma.
How are you supposed
to say goodbye to a cheetah?
I think you already have,
suse.
Look!
Another duma!
Go on.
Go make friends.
This isn't gonna be easy.
Go away, duma.
You have to leave now.
Go, duma.
You don't belong
with us anymore.
Go away!
Though we are far apart...
Our spirits share
the same earth...
And the same sky.