(man) I just jumped at
the opportunity to go,
without even thinking about it, really,
because it opened the way to an old
and very naive childhood fantasy of mine.
To go off into the wilderness
and test myself against
all the dangerous things lurking there.
And to find that basic animal I secretly
hoped was hidden somewhere in myself.
I imagined that at that point
I'd become a new man,
with a strength and courage
that I'd never known before.
As I traveled north,
it was on about the third day
that the reality of what I was about to try
to do began to seep into my bones
and gather in a knot
in the pit of my stomach.
Then I finally reached
the end of the line, Nootsack.
The sheer bulk of the supplies
the department sent along set me back,
as I had to get not only myself
but all this stuff
another 300 miles into the wilderness.
So, you think north of here?
The place is crawling with 'em,
But you wouldn't wanna go up there, son,
Got nothing to eat up there now,
There's nothing but ice
and snow and trees and,,,
You would be
the only fresh meat around there,
They'll come after you, son,
Just for the ugly fun of tearing you apart,
I'd heard some of the tales
about the Arctic,
The mad trappers, Diamond Tooth Gertie,
the ice-worm cocktail and all that,
so I was prepared
for things to be a little weird.
You found the bayonets,
I knew you would,
- Charlie,
- (# bassoon playing)
That's much better, much better, Francis,
Keep practicing,
The only plane in Nootsack
belonged to a part-time bush pilot,
gambler and real-estate tycoon
named Rosie Little.
While negotiating our deal, he introduced
me to this drink that he'd invented.
Known locally as Moose Juice,
it consisted of equal parts
Moose Brand beer and ethyl alcohol.
Before I knew it,
my old fear of flying evaporated,
and I spent all the money I had left
on 24 cases of beer.
T oo much weight, Tyler,
Hang on!
Whoa,,, Nelly!
Come on, Something else out of there now,
The big, heavy ones, Tyler,
I really had no way of knowing
exactly what of the department's gear
we donated to the people of Nootsack.
That big wooden box there,
Get rid of it, Go on, You don't need that,
But by our third attempt at takeoff,
it was a lot of what I might really need.
I tried not to think about it.
In fact, I tried not to think at all.
This one is it, I can feel it,
With my eyes still shut,
I realized that I was still alive.
But this was only the beginning.
It's funny how I keep thinking back
to that going-away party.
All the toasts by Dr Spivey
and Dr Showwalter,
and everybody singing
old Johnny Horton songs.
And the cake with all the coconut frosting,
with the plastic snowshoes on top.
But, then, why me?
Maybe this whole thing was a mistake.
Maybe my name just somehow
got onto the wrong page.
It might have been a typo, or maybe
somebody spilled a cup of coffee,
shuffled a couple of pages,
and there I was.
I can 't go on with this. This is suicide.
But I can 't turn around now.
I'd be a laughing stock.
Still, I wouldn 't last six hours down there,
let alone six months.
Uh ,,,
How do you,,,?
Don't worry about a thing,
I feel my way through these mountains
blindfolded all the time,
Tell me, Tyler,,,
what's in the Valley of the Blackstone?
What is it? Manganese?
Can't be oil,
Is it gold?
It's kind of hard to say,
You're a smart man, Tyler,
Keep your own counsel,
We're all of us prospectors
up here, eh, Tyler?
Scratching for that one crack in the ground
so we'll never have to scratch again,
I'll let you in on a little secret, Tyler,
The gold's not in the ground,
The gold's not anywhere up here,
The real gold is south of 60,
Sittin' in living rooms,
stuck facing the boob tube, bored to death,
Bored to death, Tyler!
(clunking)
Ah.
(engine splutters)
- (screeching)
- What was that?
(rapid bleeping)
Oh, Lord!
Darn!
- What's wrong?
- Take the stick,
Arrrrgh!
What's wrong?
Boredom, Tyler,
Boredom, that's what's wrong,
And how do you beat boredom, Tyler?
Adventure.
Adventure, Tyler.
Where are you going? Rosie!
Rosie, what are you doing?
I can't fly this thing, What do I do?
Catch the updraft there, Tyler, That's it,
Right in the middle, Good,
- Oh!
- Ah!
Tyler, easy, easy, easy!
- Back the other way! Turn it the other way!
- What?
Tyler, back, Tyler! Tyler!
Easy! Tyler!
The other way, That's it,
That's it, Good, Tyler,
That's it, You learn fast,
(engine starts)
(Rosie) Whoo!
Rosie, it's freezing,
Keep moving, Tyler, Gotta keep moving,
(smashing)
- You'll be fine,
- Gotta take it easy with some of this stuff,
Oh, uh,,,
Mind your toes!
Speed, Speed is of the essence, Tyler,
Especially when you don't know
how much fuel you got,
(smashing)
You got any last messages for the world,
Tyler, you better let me have 'em now,
That's sneaky, Tyler, Very sneaky,
Wait, Rosie! Rosie!
- Rosie,
- What?
Hey?
Remember my position, will you?
Sure, I'll stop by
for a drink sometime, huh?
Rosie! Rosie!
What?
- What is my position?
- It beats the hell out of me, Tyler,
I just hope I can find my way home,
Good luck, Tyler,
Yeah,
Well, interesting.
Now, what are the possibilities here?
The possibilities...
are many.
Gotta stay rational, be objective and. . .
plan out all the proper procedures
before doing anything else.
Make a list of priorities, remembering,
of course, to take into account variables,
and the fact that, inevitably,
some problems could arise that. . .
. . . inevitably, some problems could arise
that are completely unexpected.
Get a grip on yourself.
Section 3C of my instructions
reads as follows:
''You will proceed immediately, by means
of canoe and utilizing local waterways,
to establish a base camp. ''
Section 4: ''You will note
that you have been provided
with the following material requirements. ''
''Food supplies, sufficient
until local sources can be utilized. ''
''Various appropriate requisition forms,
documents and vouchers. ''
''And all technical equipment
pertinent to the completion of the study. ''
(distorted radio reception)
(foreign announcer)
Ooh! Eeh!
(lively accordion music)
Hey!
March 23. 5am.
First report from Project Lupine.
Spent the night in a crate.
At daylight I'll try to get off the ice.
But I'd like to go on record as stating
that those who planned this expedition
made significant misc. . .
(howling)
. . . made significant miscalculations,
staggeringly incompetent. . .
(howling)
(howling continues)
Oh!
(panting)
(low growling)
(footsteps approaching)
(frenzy of howling and whining)
(howling stops)
(footsteps approaching)
(low grunt)
Hello,
Uh,,,
Excuse me, You sort of,,,
Could you give me a hand
with some of this equipment, I wonder?
Ya!
I have a lot of equipment here,
I really can't leave it, If you could,,,
Hello?
Ootek,
Ootek?
There are problems recording the events
of the past day or days.
The man has disappeared, although
his face remains vivid in my mind.
I've decided to stay here
until I get my bearings
and I've sorted out what constitutes reality.
(squealing)
April 1.
Temperatures soaring
to 4 1 degrees Fahrenheit.
For the first time in three days
I emerge from my sleeping bag
and begin trying to do my job.
So far I've collected
the following specimens:
five baby mice, one millipede
and something that looks
suspiciously like fleas.
My instructions are to track down
a specimen of Canis lupus,
dispatch it with a rifle
and examine the contents of its stomach.
(strange boom)
(creaking)
(coughing and spluttering)
April 1 6.
Warm days bring
a kind of peace and stillness.
If there are any remaining fears,
they stem only from the recognition
of my own staggering insignificance.
(distant howling)
(howling continues)
May 3. In pursuit of phantoms.
I hear them every night, have seen
their tracks and collected their scat.
So they must be real.
Agh!
(rock falls)
Canis lupus arcticus.
The largest and rarest of the wolf species.
And its den.
The rules of the game are to choose
an observation post downwind,
out of the animal's field of vision,
gain your position and maintain it
without ever revealing your presence.
Outmaneuvered on all counts,
I opt to change the rules.
(pans clanking)
Reasoning that we're suspicious
of what we don't understand,
I decide to reveal
as much as possible about myself,
make a display.
(wolf grunts)
I haven't seen the wolf in two days.
I know I was violating the distance
principle, moving so far into his territory.
But since he hadn't seemed afraid of me,
I hoped that I could. . .
(snuffling)
(growling)
(panting)
(urinating)
I didn't take it personally.
This was a matter of principle,
a territorial dispute.
And he had fired the first shot.
# What never?
No, never
# Hardly ever
# Hardly ever, ever sick at sea
# So give five cheers and one cheer,,,
Oh!
(hums)
# I am the very model
of a modern major general
# I've information vegetable,
animal, and mineral
# I know the kings of England
and I quote the fights historical
# From Marathon to Waterloo
in order categorical
# I'm very well acquainted too
with matters mathematical
# I understand equations
both the simple and quadratical
# About binomial theorem
I'm teeming with a lot of news
# With many cheerful facts
about the square of the hypotenuse
(humming)
27 cups of tea later, I completed
a two-acre circle around my tent,
including a 100-yard section
of the wolf's path.
What had taken me six hours
and 27 cups of tea,
he accomplished in just a few minutes.
At each of the places that I'd marked,
he made his mark on the opposite side,
indicating that my boundary
was acceptable to him.
And thus he granted me the space
for Lupus Base One.
I'm supposed to watch his behavior,
but all he does is stay
in front of his den and watch mine.
I can't remember ever being the object
of so much constant attention.
I now arise at 1 0: 00 in the evening,
as everything becomes more active
during the long polar twilight.
In my notebook,
the wolf has become George.
The two are identical in color,
with the same contrasting
shoulder marking and long-legged gait.
But I've detected a difference,
and I've named her Angeline.
As George has become a family of five,
the reason for his long staring match
with me has lost its mystery.
It's well-known that wolves mate for life,
but knowing that has hardly prepared me
for their constant and varied
displays of affection.
Every evening George goes off
on his nightly rounds.
What he does on these excursions
remains a mystery to me.
Angeline always remains
behind with the cubs,
though I can see that she longs to follow.
(howls)
(distant howl)
- (howls)
- (distant howl)
(howling continues)
It's perplexing.
The overall reason behind the study
is that the government wants final proof
that wolves are responsible
for the disastrous decline in caribou.
So far I haven 't seen a single caribou,
or observed the wolves eating anything.
My own food supplies
are nearing exhaustion,
and the local environment
offers scant pickings.
Yet the wolves seem perfectly healthy.
I've done numerous scatological studies
and only turned up a smattering
of small mammal bones.
The whole question of sustenance
around Lupus Base One
has me completely mystified.
(scratching)
(squeals)
(squeaks)
(scuttling)
Angeline has given me the first clue.
In less than an hour
she's caught and consumed 23 mice.
My rough calculation:
one mouse every ten square feet.
Over 40,000 square feet in an acre.
That's 4,000 mice per acre.
The idea that a large animal
could live entirely on mice
will be greeted with skepticism,
unless I can perform an experiment.
(squealing)
(Tyler yells)
(Tyler continues to yell)
(yells)
(crunching)
(squeaks)
(chuckles)
Arrr!
(growls)
(squealing)
(snarling)
Five wolves appeared today.
I expected one of the pack battles
I'd read so much about.
It was Angie who was
right in the middle of things,
asserting her position
as the dominant female.
The challenges and assertions
were mostly symbolic.
There was no real fighting.
But Angeline got her point across.
George was never challenged.
He just stood there
with his air of masterful certainty,
the alpha wolf of the pack.
Usually, only the dominant pair
mate and have offspring,
going to seek their own privacy
for that purpose.
Apparently, the time had arrived
to rejoin the pack.
There's a young brown wolf who seems
to be a particular favorite of the cubs.
I've named him Uncle Albert.