Are they wild horses, Dad?
No, they're not brumbies.
Someone's gone to a lot of
trouble to put that mob together
You won't find better anywhere.
Ump... it's the man himself. Jim Craig.
- From Snowy River?
- That's Him.
A long way from home.
BOY: I'll look after him.
JIM: Thanks, son.
You're cracking on the pace,
Jim. You going back for good?
- Yep. I've been away long enough.
- Yeah. I suppose so.
But still, you'll be missed in these parts, Jim.
Thanks, mate.
Well... I've got my stake together now.
Not a bad one, either.
They're the best I've seen.
For thousands of miles.
- You going to breed them?
- Mmm. Eventually.
See...
before I left home, I let that old wild
stallion and his mob loose again.
And now I'm going to let
him cover these mares.
Big plans.
Spare me that, mate.
Was it Denny that ran down
that stallion, Mr Craig?
Jim.
Yep. That's him, alright.
About due for a rest, I reckon.
Remember old, um... Harrison?
He had a daughter, didn't he?
- Jessica.
- Right. Right.
Well, I suppose that's as good a reason
as any for going home in a hurry.
JIM: What are you after, Seb?
Rabbits? Or something bigger?
Depends.
I thought I'd come up and
see if the place was alright.
Thanks.
Why the rifle?
Insurance.
A few funny things have been
happening up here lately.
- Like what?
- Cattle and horses spooked.
They must reckon we've been poddy-dodging.
Stealing cattle? Surely not.
- Well, no more than usual.
- Only as much as you can eat, anyway.
- That's right.
- It's traditional.
No, it's more likely some big nobs down below
have finally woken up to this droughtproof
grazing up here and want to grab a bit.
- They've been serving us with papers.
- What, legal papers?
Oh, I don't know.
Found a good use for them, though.
Someone took a shot at
your old stallion last week.
- What?
- He's alright. Back with his mob.
- Who was it?
- We don't know.
It could've been anyone who's blamed him
for every horse gone missing
over the past 20 years.
That's just about everybody.
Yeah, well, he's not exactly
house-trained, is he?
- Anyway, now you're back for a while...
- Back for good, Seb.
Just one more thing to do.
Hope things go the way you
want them to down there, mate.
Mmm.
Well, let's get a fire going.
It's good to have you home!
Jessica!
Mr Simmons tells me you've
been riding that colt again.
- Now, I employ a jockey to do that.
- I know.
But... I get the faster times.
Is that true?
Where is this great jockey you
begged me to hire, Simmons?
He's off trying to lose some weight,
- Mr Harrison.
- Oh, I see... he gets fat off my beef,
then I have to pay him while he
tries to lighten his carcass.
Now, listen to me, Simmons.
I want that colt flying by this weekend.
Do you understand? Flying!
These are my home grounds.
I intend to win that race!
That's all.
Get that jockey into condition.
Lousy weather.
Old and cold, Jess.
Old and cold.
I want you to change into something
more feminine before lunch.
- We have guests.
- Oh? Who?
Patton.
Oh, Mr Patton. I should have
guessed that. I mean...
percentages and balance sheets and interest
rates make such fascinating conversation.
Oh, his son will be there too.
Well, good. Alistair should
liven things up a bit.
And when you're running this place,
you'll be damn glad I made you sit in
on all these business meetings, lady.
- Me?
- Mmm.
Run the place?
I thought all I had to do was...
...show a little bit of petticoat and snare
somebody eligible so he could run it.
- Or think he does.
- Yeah, like I think I do, right?
Now, listen, Jess. Wear plenty of frills.
If we're going to keep this place
growing, we're going to need Mr Patton.
And his loans.
Good day, Denny.
You have a rest, old mate.
Time to teach one of these
youngsters a thing or two, eh?
Well, this is a first-class turnout,
Harrison. Does you credit.
Thanks... Patton.
I was talking to some of
the other families just now.
We're all impressed. We must see more of you.
Well, I'll drink to that.
- I'll get it.
- I can get my own godda...
See to Mr Patton's glass...
You know, once the bank
has decided to back you...
and I'm sure my directors will
see that is a mere formality...
great things are possible.
Well, I'm looking forward to it.
Mind you, if our ties
extended beyond... mortgages,
I would say the sky's the limit.
Well, it's an interesting proposition, Patton.
But of course, that's up to Jessica.
Of course.
Oh, excuse me...
Uh, Colonel Hawker?
Someone I'd like you to meet.
Harrison, Colonel Hawker, Indian Army.
- Well, I'm pleased to meet you, Colonel.
- How do you do?
Colonel Hawker comes
down from India every year
and faithfully buys up the best
cavalry horses in the country.
He means his own, of course.
Well, anyway, you'll be
pleased with this year's draft.
Despite the poor season,
I could still give you 500.
- Good.
- New lines coming through strongly.
Excuse me.
Here, you. Look after the gentlemen.
Interesting man.
- Has he been here long?
- 20 years, more or less.
Don't know a lot about him.
Yankee originally. Made a bit
of money on gold diggings.
Not exactly a first-class background!
Not like us, eh?
No, indeed.
I believe your family came from
the Percys on the Scottish border.
They most certainly did.
- Mine were the Monmouths.
- Really?
Yes. My lot used to hang your lot.
As cattle thieves.
This, Mr Simmons, is the problem.
HARRISON: Jessica.
You want the horse to win or not?
Let the jockey handle it! Mr Simmons?
Where is our fat jockey this morning?
Uh... he took some medicine,
so he had to go to the, um...
- But he'll be back in a minute.
- Oh, he should stay there,
- for all the bloody good he'll do.
- Ah. Miss Harrison.
Mr Patton! Hello.
Excuse me.
Charming girl.
Oh, she has a mind of her own.
The best sort, Harrison.
It's the high-stepping fillies
that make the best mares, eh?
Harrison.
Father.
Come on, Harrison. This is
going to be worth watching.
MAN: Ladies and gentlemen.
The regimental trophy
holder, Lieutenant Patton,
will now demonstrate the skill-at-arms course.
Yah!
- I'm awfully sorry.
- It's alright. You missed.
- I... take it you're looking for the stables?
- No.
For Jessica Harrison. Have you seen her?
- Er... well, yes, but...
- Who would be asking for her?
Oh, that was good riding out there.
My name's Jim Craig.
Oh, the one we've heard so much about.
Could be.
You were a bit lucky that day, Craig.
Mainly old stagers there, I hear.
Everyone was invited.
You're out of your class here, Craig.
HAWKER: Afternoon, Mr Patton.
Sir.
- Mr Collins.
- Good afternoon, sir.
Harry Hawker.
Jim Craig.
Uh, could you spare me a minute, Jim?
I noticed your horse. I was
coming over for a closer look.
He's a good type. Learning quickly.
Just the one?
No, I've got about 100 of them.
Really?
Uh, will you excuse me, Harry?
It was good to meet you.
And you.
Where the devil is Summer Cloud?
Oh, already out there.
Bit overanxious, eh?
Not a good sign. Anyway,
I wouldn't fuss about that.
My Highland Laddie's obviously
got the edge on your fellow.
It's easy to say, Patton.
- I've got £100 to back that up, Harrison.
- £500.
Done.
Come on!
Damn it! What the hell's
that bloody jockey doing?!
- He's moving! What is that jockey doing?
- Come on! Come on!
Come on!
You lost.
Thank you.
Good horse, that.
Yeah, I know. I broke him in.
What the devil do you think you're doing
out there with professional jockeys?
- You might've been killed!
- The jockey was missing.
- What was th...
- Oh, and you just happened to be available?
Simmons!
- Simmons, where is that bloody jock...?
- He's here, Mr Harrison.
Som...somebody locked me in the outhouse!
Simmons...
You're sacked. You're both sacked.
SIMMONS: Suits me.
Working for you two's like
being caught in a meat grinder!
Now, I want you to go in
the house and change.
Right now.
Jess?
Congratulations.
Thanks.
Hello, Jess.
Well, Craig. Been a long time.
G'day, Mr Harrison.
I don't recall having invited you today.
No, I came to see Jessica.
Perhaps I could come back tomorrow.
Well, you're not welcome here, Craig.
Today, tomorrow...
...any time.
Oh.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Tell me, do you still speak for Jessica too?
I don't argue with drifters.
Father... please.
Come with me, Jess.
Jess, I...
...I know it's been a long time,
but I've got a start for us.
Have you been thinking of me, then?
- That's good.
- HARRISON: Jess!
Jessica!
I know you hicks are slow
on the uptake, Craig,
but you're setting a record.
I don't know who you think you are,
but you're not part of this,
so keep your mouth shut.
You've been away too long, Craig.
You don't know who's part of what.
Change your clothes, Jess.
Get off this property.
Now.
There are better ways to make your point, Jim.
Ya!
Get up!
I think you'd call that a live prisoner.
It was more than just a loutish display.
It was open contempt for the values
on which this community is based.
Perhaps now you'll understand why we
must get rid of that riffraff up there
and acquire the mountain grazing
areas for the benefit of the valley.
- It's easier said than done.
- Don't be too sure.
I aim to have a bill before
the House this session.
And in view of our undertakings,
I'm sure I can count on your support?
What you're saying is I support you
or I have problems with the bank.
Is that right, Patton?
Well... a fraction bold, old man,
I see you get the general drift.
Oh, blimey! You're enough
to make a saint swear.
There's no saints around here, Father.
Otherwise, you could do the loaves
and fishes thing with pound notes
and give me something decent to work with!
You miserable sinners.
When this is finished and any
of you come to confession,
you'll be laughing on the
other side of your faces.
When that's finished, we'll
be too old to commit sins.
Now, I'll give you all a fair choice.
Either get on about your business
or contribute to God's work
with your labour or your cash.
Oh. You must be new around here.
Been away for a while.
But there used to be only a small mine here.
Yes.
Yes, an old fellow named Spur
grubbed most of his life away here.
And after he died, they
found it... 50ft from his shaft.
- Found what?
- The mother lode. 1,000ft down.
Pity they don't dig as deep into their pockets.
- Jim!
- G'day, Seb.
Where the hell have you been?
I've been looking for you. Come have a beer.
SEB: G'day, Mrs Darcy.
Hello, Sebastian.
This is Jim Craig.
- Hello, Jim.
- Hello.
So it didn't go too well down there?
I didn't think they'd put out the red carpet.
With old Harrison, it was
more like a red rag to a bull.
Well, we all know they'd like to run us
- right out of the High Country.
- Mmm.
What are the boys doing about that?
Nothing.
They reckon if you don't stir
the possum, it won't bite you.
What Can we do?
I'm glad to hear you're playing the piano again.
It's been too long.
Do you think, maybe, you
could play some other tune?
It's not a tune. It's a sonata.
Well, whatever the hell it is!
You're pining away over that drifter
Craig. You're just wasting your time.
- Jim isn't a drifter.
- What else would you call him?
The man disappears into the
mountains for months at a time.
No-one ever sees him or hears from him.
Whatever he is, he won't be back here, Jess.
Now, I thought you accepted that.
You haven't been outside this house in days.
- Everyone's been asking for you.
- Oh!
I thought this is where you wanted me.
Looking decorative, waiting
for the suitors to call.
One has called.
Alistair Patton.
Called every other day, and I'm
running out of excuses for him.
And then don't make excuses.
- Tell him I won't see him.
- Well, that's fine with me, Jess. Either way.
How you both treated Jim was disgraceful.
The subject is closed!
Now, I am sick to death...
- of hearing about Jim Craig.
- Well, I am not
Craig doesn't belong here, Jess.
He could never belong here. You do.
Oh. And so does Alistair Patton, I suppose?
Affections are all related
to houses and property,
- are they not?
- God, you can be most aggravating woman!
Obviously a chip off the old block!
Because I don't care a hoot in hell
about the Pattons, junior or senior!
- And you know it!
- Well, neither do I!
Then what the hell are we arguing about?!
MRS DARCY: Jim?
- JIM: Morning.
- Are you leaving today?
No. Not Yet.
I want to check into the
affairs of an old friend.
Spur?
You know, I bet he's still
smiling away to himself up there.
How's that?
He willed this place to all
the battlers and fossickers
that have ever grubbed around these hills.
That's not playing the game by the rules.
Gets worse.
You see, none of these people work for bosses.
And that's something the
landed gentry can't digest.
Well... long live Eureka Creek.
Excuse me.
I came to talk to you.
Couldn't believe it when I saw you again.
It was like an illusion.
I want to know why you
were away for so long, Jim.
I told you. To get a start for us.
Why is accumulating things
so damned important?
Because I've seen the lack of it.
And I don't want that for you.
Things change.
Is there someone else?
They've all made plans for
me... with Alistair Patton.
I'm not going through with it.
But I can't come up here with you.
Why not?
My father.
He needs me now more
than he ever did before.
And... the Pattons are the most
powerful family in the district.
If we were together, they would break him.
And then they'd come after
you and everybody up here.
Your own people would turn against
you and I would be the cause.
You're taking too much on yourself, Jess.
No. I've given this a lot of thought.
It'd drive us apart, Jim.
JESSICA'S VOICE: "Dear Father,
I have to go and see Jim.
"Please don't be angry with
me. I must do this my own way."
Are you just going to
stand there and let her go?
Would you mind if I ask why?
For a lot of reasons.
- Oh, really?
- MAN: It's better all round this way, Jim.
Better for whom, Jake?
Why not just say it straight out?
Better for your own interests.
Oh, and better for Harrison's own selfish
interests too, no doubt you've been told.
Oh, yes, Jim. He was always very
good at looking after number one.
Just leave things as they are.
Broaden your minds. Have
another beer. Have two!
Yah! Hah! Hah!
Jess, I'm not going to let you go like this.
We're not going to mess up our lives
doing what other people think is right.
Listen to me.
You've thought of me, your
father, almost everyone else.
Alright.
But what about you?
What do you want?
I want you.
Alright. You two can head on back.
Let's go home, Jess.
The time's passed for that,
Harrison. Let's talk straight.
Jessica, are you coming with me or not?
Father, please, don't do this.
Now, you can't have it both
ways. Not this time, Jess.
Either come with me now...
...or stay here with him.
Can't you understand I love you both?
It's me or him, Jess.
It doesn't have to be a choice.
Jess?
I want to be with Jim.
Alright.
Alright, stay with him, then.
You're just like your mother.
Right, Jack.
Having a good time, love?
Well, look who's here!
MAN: Where's the bloody silver spoon?
Well, what did Daddy give you
for Christmas this year, mate?
A healthy dislike for dimwits.
I'll shout for the bar.
What do you want?
- What have you got?
- Everything.
Well, we'll start with a rum.
See where we go from there.
I've missed you.
- Where have you been?
- Don't worry about it.
Just concentrate on what you know best.
Haven't seen you around for a while.
Looks like I'd better buy a drink.
I might have something for you
that could triple that roll.
I think we could count on bringing
down about 60 foals from those Walers.
And there are eight good yearling
fillies in the brumby mobs.
Harry.
HAWKER: They're good. Very
good. Are they for sale?
- 30 or 40 of them.
- We want to keep most for breeding.
Look, my job is to supply large
numbers of remounts every year,
regardless of conditions.
That's why I deal with people like the Pattons.
They're big suppliers. They
have guaranteed numbers.
So you're not interested in small lots, then?
Well, to put it bluntly, it's not worth my while.
As good as these are.
Wait a minute.
What if we're not talking about small lots?
How about a guaranteed 100 a year?
Every family up here can turn off half
dozen horses as good as these in a year.
That'll bring the numbers up.
Yes, but I'm looking for quality.
I want better than stock horses.
Well, the mountain horse is
bred for quality has to be.
You won't find better doing horses anywhere.
Well, you'll need a lot of cooperation. The
people up here tend to go their own way.
You needn't worry about that.
Jim's very good at getting
people to see things his way.
Alright.
I'll be back in a week.
If you can show me the
numbers, we'll talk contracts.
Right.
Here! Hey! Giddy-up, now. Whoa!
- JIM: Let's block them up here.
- MAN: Hold them.
Righto!
- That brown horse, Charlie.
- Yeah?
And, uh... the tall bay mare there should do.
You certainly go for the best.
- That's what I promised him.
- Hmm.
Well, you drop them off at the new yards
and I'll see you next week with a cheque.
Righto.
- Altogether, that's 74.
- Great.
We'll go over to Bryce's now.
Come on, darling. If you fall
asleep there, I'll never move you.
I never believed I could feel so tired
and so happy at the same time.
You should take it a bit easier.
You know, all my life I've
been judged by who I am.
Up here, it's just what I am that matters.
You've always had that.
You know how good it feels.
You've earned it.
I'll keep earning it.
Did you know that Craig is trying
to undercut us... with hawker?
Not afraid of a little competition, are we?
He's a slimy bastard.
He's got them all eating
out of his hand up there.
That's the first time I've heard
you pay him a compliment.
If you call it that, Collins.
Who'd want to be the leader
of the hairy unwashed?
- It's time we paid him a visit.
- Why?
Let him know we're serious.
People like that should not be allowed
to stand in the way of progress.
Have you spoken to your father about this?
I don't have to.
A nod's as good as a wink.
We're all looking for action, hmm? Right?
- MAN: Yes.
- This is stupid and it's wrong.
Worse, it'll bounce back on you.
Ask him about his real motive.
- Like Jessica Harrison.
- MAN: Shut up, Collins.
Yellow streak, Collins.
Gutless.
If that's the way you want it, I'm waiting.
I'll save my energies for Craig.
I'll see you at the Debutante's Ball.
Whoa!
MAN: What is it?
I heard something.
Settle them down!
There's nothing here.
Arrgh!
Very funny.
Well, come on, let's go!
Come on! You've already
lost two hours of light.
- Did you hear about last night?
- No.
Alistair Patton and a mob of his
mates ran into that stallion of yours.
Oh, yeah?
Young McKay was killed.
We'll talk to you alone, Jim.
We'll both hear what you have to say.
- You were warned this might happen.
- What?
Bringing her up here.
McKay's death is a consequence.
- How do you figure that?
- It was bound to happen.
Now those rich bastards will use it
as another stick to beat us with.
You put it all on Jessica?
That's not right, Jake, and you know it.
We're being mindful of our families.
She should go back to where she belongs.
We're staying here.
Well, it's your problem...
and you fix it on your own.
And you shoot that stallion...
...or I will.
I liked Jamie McKay.
- And such a happy...
- Don't, Jess.
Now he's dead.
You mustn't blame yourself.
Can't you see? It's turned out
exactly as I said it would.
No.
It's got nothing to do with us.
They made their own decisions.
Will you stop trying to tell me
that we are not responsible
for our own decisions?!
If you hadn't trying to stop me going home,
- now this wouldn't have happened!
- Jessica.
I'll be back in a while, alright?
- Do you want to earn some money?
- Depends.
100 horses.
Yours...
...when they're over the border.
Worth a fortune.
Settling a score, are we?
Does it matter?
Yeah, I prefer straight-out business.
If we start immediately, we can't fail.
I'll need a token to convince the boys.
Bullshit. You could buy them for a beer.
But... to show you...
Done!
- How far?
- About 10 minutes.
Jess...
She's not here, mate.
- Where is she?
- I don't know.
When I got here, the place was empty.
- Where are you off to?
- To find her.
Where?
Back down, I think.
Hey, in case I'm wrong and she comes
back, will you stay here for a bit?
Sure.
Thanks. See you.
- You've got to help me with this, Harrison.
- Why don't you go to the police, Patton?
- That's what they're for.
- I don't want the police mixed up with this.
Uh, you know the country up there.
I want you to lead a party
and bring Alistair back.
You mean you want me to stop
him from doing something stupid.
Bring Alistair back
and I'll make sure that your
loan goes straight through.
How is it every conversation with
you sooner or later turns to money?
None of this would've happened
if you'd been capable of
controlling your daughter!
Oh, it's not Jessica who's rampaging
around like some spoiled child.
Your daughter is responsible
for Alistair's state of mind!
She lied to him. Led him on.
Played the coquette with him.
You know, you're a very lucky man, Patton.
In another place and not so very
long ago, you'd be dead right now.
I'm going to make allowances because
of the worry your son has caused you.
My daughter's been the only honest
person in this whole affair.
We're the ones who tried to
twist every advantage out of it.
And now, I've been patient
enough with you, Mr Patton.
Here's your loan application...
...and there's the door.
Don't finished with the bank.
That's a different story altogether.
I must love you.
Couldn't get any further than Eureka Creek.
Ya!
MAN: Someone get a doctor!
Seb. Are you alright?
Nothing that a bit of horsehair
and green gum sapling won't fix.
What happened?
They were driving away your horses, mate.
- What?
- They ran straight over the top of me.
- Who?
- I recognised Alistair Patton.
- There was a fair mob of them.
- Get him inside.
MAN: One, two, three.
Now do we start to fight them?
The scores are even. One
of theirs for one of ours.
That's your own son!
I'm talking about all our
sons. All our women and kids.
Oh, no!
You can't let him go alone.
Whoa!
Come on, Den.
I need you for this one.
Right. Come on, Den.
Get up!
Tell them to ease up a bit.
Nobody's going to be troubling us out here.
Ha!
Hess! Come on!
Get up!
Come on, Den. That's it.
Whoa, lad.
MAN: That's Craig.
ALISTAIR: He's outsmarted himself up there.
- There's no way down.
- Hmm. Don't forget who he is.
Haaaa!
Ha!
You killed him.
Maybe.
I want to make sure.
No bloody fear! Let's get out of it!
Oh, no.
Not you.
What have I done?
What have I...?
I'm so sorry.
My poor old friend.
Get back! Go on!
Get back!
Whoa, big man.
Whoa.
Yeah, you know me, don't you?
Now... I need your help.
That's it.
I'm not going to hurt you.
Just stand.
That's it.
I'm going to touch you now.
Come on, you wild old thing.
Good.
Good man.
Whoa.
Look at this.
Have a look at it.
Just have a look at it. Come on.
It's alright.
Good boy. Good.
Whoa!
Steady. Steady, now.
Steady, now. Steady, now.
Just stand.
Alright.
Oh!
Get back here, you...
Easy, boy. Easy.
- Well, let's go!
- Alright!
ALL: Ah!
MAN: That's it!
Right.
Come on, hurry up.
Yeah, yeah.
MAN: They're onto us.
There's hundreds of the bastards.
- Ya! Get out of here.
- MAN: Come on! Come on!
Come on. Come on.
Downriver!
Wait! Split up!
We'll get round in front of them.
Let's get out of here!
Get around them!
MAN: Get in there!
MAN: Look out!
Ya!
Ha!
Arggh!
Ya!
Get up!
Ooh!
It's alright. Alright.
You're the best, old man.
You should be free.
Off you go.
It's alright now, Jess.
Oh, thank God.
You know, I really missed you, Jess.
I missed you too.
I was wrong.
And I was stupid.
I'm sorry.
Never heard you say that before.
But you're here.
You're both here. Nothing else matters.