- Hey!
- All right, Mr. Benchley.
Thank you, Coslough.
- Noah Dugan?
- Yeah, what do you guys want?
Well, you owe a lot of money, Mr. Dugan,
and Mr. Parker wants it. Now.
You've got a hell of a nerve
barging in here like this.
Where have you guys been, anyway?
Parker owes me.
That red-hot parlay l've been driving
paid off in the ninth last night
when Attaboy Star got his nose
under the wire in front.
50,000 smackers. Fat city!
Fat nothing, Mr. Dugan.
Attaboy Star was disqualified in that race.
Set back to third.
Apparently he interfered in the stretch.
You got 24 hours to come up with 5,000.
Mr. Parker's willing to wait a week
for the rest.
Coslough.
- That's just a reminder, Mr. Dugan.
- (Dugan groans)
Mr. Dugan, 24 hours.
How many jobs did you have
in the last two years?
- Six.
- And on the last one?
- Well, there was a little turbulence.
- l'm sorry.
The word's out. Wherever you go,
there goes trouble. And l can't afford that.
Come on, Slabotsky, l broke both arms
flying stunts for you. l need a job.
l would if l could.
Hey, why don't you try Tallmantz?
They're supplying all the pilots
for a war movie over at 20th.
You can fly those crates
standing on your head.
Yeah, l saw 'em.
The picture's been cancelled.
War movies are out. Rocket ships are in.
l don't qualify.
All the pilots are made out of tin.
But l got that flight gassed up, ready to go.
Not with me. No. Uh-uh.
You couldn't pay me triple to take it up.
Dugan!
Oh, what a surprise.
Here l was just thinking about you
and you pop up out of nowhere.
Stow it, Stoney.
l need a job or l wouldn't be here.
l thought you'd never ask.
Come, l'll show you.
This is your lucky day.
This is the easiest money you ever made.
A straight hop to that Pacific island.
The flight plans have been cleared.
One passenger, a bit of cargo.
You drop them there. Refuel.
- What kind of plane is it?
- Back via Hawaii. Pick up another cargo.
While you're there, take yourself a few
days' vacation. Have yourself a time.
What kind of a plane is it?
The word is out, Dugan.
You're in big trouble.
You've been playing the horses
and without very much success.
Open the door.
No job, no family, no friends
with enough dinero to bail you out.
With one exception.
Your old buddy, Stoney.
Open the door. Will you open the door?
l know. l know you're a proud man, Dugan.
A man who hates to hang his head
like a whipped dog.
Therefore, l don't want you to feel that
you have to be excessively grateful to me
for giving you this rare opportunity.
- Open the door!
- You got it.
(animal noises. children's voices)
(woman) Children!
Close the door, Stoney.
- Did l just see what l think l saw?
- What do you think you saw?
Kids and animals and a moldy B-29.
The kids aren't going. They're here
to wave goodbye to the animals.
They were all brought up
at the orphanage.
- No, Stoney.
- No?
Animals and planes do not mix. You never
know what they'll do when you're in the air.
lt's a hazard. lt's dangerous.
And it ain't worth it.
- Wait! Those are religious animals.
- What?
They were brought up at the orphanage.
The lady in charge is a missionary.
She said prayers over them.
Oh...
There she is now.
Come here, my dear.
Come, my dear, my angel.
l'd like you to say hello to your pilot,
Captain Noah Dugan.
Hello, Captain Dugan.
May l present Miss Bernadette Lafleur?
- And Miss...?
- Charlotte Braithwaite.
Charlotte Braithwaite. Who isn't going.
l'm so happy to meet you, Captain.
l've been looking forward to this day
for such a long time.
l've been telling the Captain about
the wonderful work you've been doing
with those wonderful natives
on that wonderful island.
- What was the name of the island?
- Makuarana.
Makuarana.
But l haven't done anything yet.
This is my first mission.
- How soon can we leave, Captain?
- With me? Never.
l don't understand.
l'm not flying you and the Bronx Zoo
anywhere.
- But l've already paid.
- Well, get your money back. Fast.
lt's gone.
Well, you know, expense and...
Mr. Stoney, l hope
this doesn't mean you've cheated me.
Because if that's the case,
there will be retribution.
l'm a missionary but l am not a pushover.
l'll go to the police.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute, please.
Dugan...
- Dugan, l could go to jail.
- Maybe they'll give you your old cell back.
What are you trying to do to me? Please,
l'll make it worth your while. l swear it.
- How much?
- Two Gs upon your return.
- l need 5,000 now.
- 5,000? l haven't got it, l swear.
OK, l want a certified check for $3,000
waiting for me in Honolulu
on my way back.
Or l don't ship your return cargo.
3,000? You got it. lt's a deal.
OK, let me see the plane.
- (child) Brutus is very nice.
- Gangway, kids. Gangway.
Watch it, kid. Those things are dangerous.
Brutus isn't dangerous. He's a friend.
Does he know that?
Lady, you are past your prime.
- What?
- Huh?
Dugan, how about it?
- (child) Petey, come back.
- Stoney, l never saw anything...
- Petey, come back here.
- Bobby and Julie, what are you doing?
Petey went into this tunnel
and he'll hurt himself.
- Oh, her duck.
- (quacking)
lt's started already
and we're not even in the air.
Excuse me, lady. Come here, duck.
Here, duck, duck.
- Don't worry, children.
- Here, duck, duck.
- Be careful, Mr. Dugan.
- Don't worry, l know what l'm doing.
You stupid duck. Come here. Yes.
Come here. Come here, ducky.
Come here. l got you.
l got you, you spatulated pigeon.
Try that again
and it'll be candied yams and apple sauce.
- Oh!
- (bangs head)
Coslough.
You don't suppose our friend Dugan
is trying to give us the slip here, do you?
Uh...
Yeah, that's what l thought.
Let's get over there.
Stoney, do yourself a favor
and set a fire to this bucket of bolts
and collect the insurance.
And while you're at it,
get yourself another pilot.
Mr. Stoney, if he goes, l go to the police.
Dugan, you can't walk out now.
That woman has the Lord's work to do.
She needs you.
You're right, Stoney, l'll do it,
but we gotta leave now.
Now?
See that car? Two guys in there want to
talk to me and l do not want to talk to them.
l don't care what you do.
l'll fly your plane, just get rid of them.
OK, let's get the rest
of the animals loaded.
- But, Mr. Dugan...
- Move it, lady. We'll talk later.
Dugan?
Oh... Yeah. l...
l... l think he's in my office.
Follow me.
This way.
All right, Mr. Dugan, will you take Agnes?
- All right. She won't hurt you.
- (pig squeals)
OK.
Yeah, he must've stepped out for a minute.
But he should be back shortly.
Oh, come in, come in,
let's sit down and wait for him here.
Yes, make yourselves comfortable,
gentlemen. Sit down. Sit down.
Come on, you mule-headed,
slab-sided tub of meat.
Get up here before l leave you behind.
- Hollering won't do any good.
- Yeah, who says?
My dad. He knew all about animals. He
said you gotta talk slow and easy to them.
- Let them know you wanna be their friend.
- Kid, l don't wanna be their friend.
l hate animals.
They stink, they're dirty and they're dumb
and they're dynamite
when they get scared.
Brutus isn't dirty and he isn't dumb.
Watch out, l'll do it.
- Oh, yeah, you're gonna do it, huh?
- Yeah.
Watch.
Here, Brutus, come on, boy.
Come on.
(lows)
See?
Well, you can put another bug
in his ear, kid.
Tell him if he raises any kind of a ruckus
while we're in the air,
he'll end up on a barbecue.
You're the one that belongs on a barbecue,
hollering at helpless creatures.
- Helpless?
- Come on, Brutus, this is no place for you.
Come here, kid, just watch yourself.
The ramp's going up.
He'll be back. He'll be right back.
- Jimmy...
- OK, kids, we're closing shop.
Everybody off.
Miss... uh... Come on, let's get
the little darlings off, we're closing shop.
Be careful.
Follow me, children.
- So long, Petey, l won't ever forget you.
- You really are my best buddy.
l'm gonna miss you a lot.
And you be careful
and you be a good boy, now.
Yeah.
Well...
Looks like the big day has finally arrived.
- We're gonna miss you something fierce.
- l'm gonna miss you too.
Why can't someone else go to that
old island? Why does it have to be you?
Because l'm a farm girl.
l can teach them what they ought to know.
l gotta go.
Come on, miss, we gotta pull out.
Bye-bye. Bye-bye.
Up you go. There you are.
That captain guy doesn't like animals.
He said they're dirty and they're dumb.
And he'll barbecue Brutus.
She wouldn't let him.
She might need help.
- Are we ready to start?
- Just about.
- Julie, l'm going with them.
- They won't let you.
They'll never see me.
l'll crawl through that hole like the man did.
- But he's started the engines.
- l gotta hurry.
- Bye, Julie.
- Wait for me.
- Hurry, Julie.
- l'm up.
Hurry, Julie.
Julie, l can't make it.
Hurry!
- (he yells)
- Bobby! Bobby! Bobby!
Bobby! Bobby! Bobby!
Here goes nothing.
(inaudible)
- Who's in that plane?
- What plane?
- That plane!
- Oh... Uh...
lt's Dugan.
Coslough.
Come on, the car.
(laughs)
Look.
They're waving us goodbye.
(inaudible)
They aren't the only ones.
Hold onto your bloomers, honey.
Come on, Coslough. Step on it.
The car!
- Coslough, do something.
- All right, Mr. Benchley.
That'll fix him.
(Benchley yells)
(Dugan laughs)
- Yeah!
- Who was in the car?
Bill collectors.
- You owe them money?
- Not any more.
Must you pollute the entire cockpit,
Mr. Dugan?
Oh, l always smoke cigars
for takeoffs and landings.
That's the tough part.
You'll get used to them, Bernie.
- lt's Bernadette, Mr. Dugan.
- Oh, have it your own way, Reverend.
(Bernadette) Reverend!
lf l were a star
A tiny star
You'd be my starlight
Half of me is me
The other half of me is you
lf l were a bird
A tiny bird
You'd be my wings
For only half of me is me
The other half of me is you
Reaching out
And touching hands
ls a way of sharing
Having faith and caring
Will always see us through
lf l were a tree
You'd be my roots
We'd grow together
Half of me is me
The other half is you
(classical music plays)
Do we have to listen to that junk?
- Junk, Mr. Dugan?
- lt's boring, Bernie.
Bach was one of the greatest composers
who ever lived.
Don't you appreciate good music?
Tell you what, Bernie, l'll make you a deal.
You turn off that noise
and l won't smoke any more.
Agreed.
(music stops)
(she coughs)
Well, we're on course.
So...
l don't believe it.
- Thanks a load, Stoney. Thanks a lot.
- Are we on fire?
Like everything else in this scrap heap,
the automatic pilot is kaput. Finito, finish
Oh, that's all?
Mr. Dugan, don't worry. lf you're tired
and you want a little nap, l can manage.
- You?
- Yes.
- You can fly?
Well, l've had a few hours' instruction
on the Mission's Cessna.
This is a little bit bigger but with some help
from you, l'm sure l could cope.
- Cessna?
- Cessna.
Lady, you couldn't fly this crate with
a couple of hundred hours of instructions.
l wouldn't be so sure, Mr. Dugan. Anyhow,
do what you want. l was just offering.
All right, Amelia Earhart, be my guest.
Just keep your compass at 250 degrees.
That's very good, Bernie, l'm impressed.
You know, it's amazing what a couple
of hours of flight instructions can do.
- Aren't you gonna help me?
- You said you knew how to fly.
- Mr. Dugan.
- Pull up. Up, up!
- l'm pulling.
- Up, up, up, up!
Up, up, up, up, up, up!
(quacking)
What the hell is this duck doing in here?
Just leave him alone. l'll get him.
Bobby! Julie!
- What are you doing?
- Give me him.
We came here to make sure
the animals made the trip safely.
- How'd you get on board?
- Through the Bombay doors.
- What? You might've been killed.
- (lowing)
- lt's Melinda. She seems awfully upset.
- She probably heard about the barbecue.
- Melinda? There's more kids back there?
- No, no, no, Melinda's the cow.
- Brutus's girlfriend. She's getting sick.
- Oh, great, that's all we need.
- What the hell did l get into?
- You shouldn't curse in front of ladies.
- Look, kid, don't you tell me how to talk.
- l better go.
You stay there. l'll handle it.
Keep your hands steady on the wheel
and follow the compass.
- You can do that, can't you?
- Aye-aye, sir.
(whispers comfortingly)
(angry lowing)
Ah, shut up.
All we need is another one like you.
Mr. Dugan? Mr. Dugan, wake up!
Mr. Dugan, Brutus didn't mean it. lt's just
you shouldn't have yelled at him like that.
- (snorts)
- Mr. Dugan?
(classical music)
- Miss Lafleur! Miss Lafleur!
- What? What?
- There's been a little accident.
- l'm scared, Miss Lafleur.
- What?
- Brutus. Brutus knocked Mr. Dugan out.
Oh, no.
OK, OK, OK, children.
l'm sure he'll come out of it.
Just loosen his collar. Julie, perhaps you
can wet a cloth and put it on his forehead.
Let me know when he's OK.
And don't worry. God is my copilot.
l hope he flies better than you.
- Peace offering.
- Thank you.
You're not angry any more?
Ah, what the hell, Bernie. lt's a new day.
ln about a minute, you are gonna see the
most beautiful sunrise you've ever seen.
Keep your eye back there. Back there,
as far as you can toward the tail.
Keep watching. lt happens very fast,
like an explosion, all red and orange.
You've never really seen one
until you've seen one from up here.
- What is it doing over there?
- l don't know, l can't believe it.
lt's not supposed to come in off the wing.
lt's supposed to come off the tail.
Excuse me.
We're still on course.
- We've been flying the wrong course.
- What do you mean, the wrong course?
l mean the battery from this cassette player
has been interfering with the magnetic field
of the compass.
lt's been giving me a false reading.
How long was that hanging there?
l don't know, a long time.
Oh, great. We have a certain amount
of fuel to get us to your island.
We burnt that up flying in the wrong
direction for God knows how long.
- So what are you gonna do?
- What am l gonna do?
l'm gonna squeeze as much mileage
out of whatever fuel we have left.
- Turn back?
- No, we've gone too far.
(Dugan) Mayday. Mayday. Boeing B-29.
Zero November Niner. One Three
Two Niner. Mayday. Mayday.
Boeing B-29. Zero November Niner.
One Three Two Niner.
Do you read me? Can anyone read me?
Hello? Hello?
That's great. Even if l knew where we were
l couldn't tell anyone. Did you hear me?
Do you really think that'll do any good?
Do you think it can do any harm,
Mr. Dugan?
- Did you find any life jackets?
- Just one and that fell to pieces.
l'll kill Stoney.
(engines sloww)
- What's that? What's happening?
- We're running out of gas.
- Are we gonna crash, Mr. Dugan?
- Don't worry, Julie, we'll make it.
Why don't we just land?
Just where would you suggest
l land, Mr. Know-lt-All?
Over there on that island.
Kid, you got the eyes of an eagle.
We're gonna do it, Bernie.
We're dropping.
That happens when you've only got two
engines holding up a four-engine plane.
- Can we make it?
- lt gets a lot more difficult with no engine.
So you better start praying again, baby.
Kids, get into that engineer's seat.
Strap yourselves in and hold on.
OK.
Thanks, Bernie.
Get behind that wheel.
l may need some help.
- Oh, Mr. Dugan.
- Don't worry, kid.
(engines sloww)
There they go.
l'm gonna try and pancake her
into the beach from the water.
(Dugan) Hold on!
(animal noises)
Come on,
let's go see how the animals are.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Thank you, Mr. Dugan. You must be
the best pilot in the whole world.
Ah, out of the mouths of babes.
Well, l'm sorry l badmouthed you, old girl.
You did real good. Real good.
Hello.
(in Japanese) l don't believe it.
l just don't believe it.
You just sit here quietly, all right?
l'll get some bandages and a splint. You
might've sprained it. Gonna be all right.
l don't think it's serious.
Well, Mr. Dugan...
What does the situation look like?
Lonely.
l mean, what do you suggest we do?
l don't know.
But after that l'm gonna take a swim.
Oh, really, Mr. Dugan, God has given us
minds and we must use them.
Positive thinking is the key.
We have been spared
and we will be rescued, l'm sure of it.
But God helps those who help themselves.
We must search
for any inhabitants of this place.
We must look for food and water.
But first we must
prepare ourselves for the night.
The corral must be built,
the animals taken out and placed there,
the plane interior must be cleaned so that
we can use it for sleeping quarters.
Oh, and some partition
must be put up for privacy.
- Oh, of course.
- Well, let's get on with it.
A little honest work never hurt anyone.
There's an axe in the plane. We'll use
that to cut palms to make fences.
Wanna bet she's also an Eagle Scout?
- Not bad, huh?
- (groans)
- What'd you do?
- l'm afraid l've gotten some blisters.
Oh, well, a little honest work
never hurt anybody.
- Bobby, come on, bring 'em in.
- All right.
Well, here we go again.
Come on. Come on, you stubborn thing.
Now the pigs.
- (laughter)
- l don't know how to grab one.
Come here, you. Come on, get back here.
(Julie) l got one!
(speaks Japanese)
- We'll be back.
- Well, can' t we come?
Absolutely not. There's no telling
what's in that jungle. You stay put here.
(children) Aw...
Come on, Julie, let's go to the corral.
Come on, Brutus. Come on.
l wonder if there are people here.
Ah, there's probably a Hilton hotel
just around the corner. Don't worry.
- l hope they're friendly.
- Bernie, l'm surprised at you.
Your religion dictates positive thinking,
remember?
Brutus! Brutus!
- Brutus!
- Brutus, come back here.
Brutus!
- Brutus!
- Stop!
Brutus, come back.
Brutus!
Brutus, you're a naughty boy, now.
Come along before l get mad at you.
- That isn't the way.
- Sure it is.
- Brutus knows.
- l wish l had Petey with me.
Ducks know their ways better than bulls.
This is not the way, either.
- Yes, it is.
- No, it isn't.
You'll see.
Tell me something.
What made you become a missionary?
l didn't think people did that any more.
- Mr. Dugan, do you really want to know?
- Of course l do.
Well...
l come from a big family.
My mother died.
l was the oldest so l pretty much
raised my brothers and sister.
When they were ready to leave home,
l was out of a job.
The only thing l knew was helping people.
l tried nursing for a while
but that wasn't quite what l wanted,
so then l thought of missionary work.
Why didn't you just get married
and start your own family?
Oh, well...
l believe that wasn't the way for me.
Anyway, the welfare of others matters
more to me than my personal desires.
- Some guy let you down, huh?
- Mr. Dugan, you have no right...
l got as much right as you,
walking around with your nose in the air
like you know more than anybody else.
l guess when you spend
your life bossing kids around,
you think you can do it with
grown-ups too.
Who do you think you are, talking to me
like that, you insensitive...?
Uh-uh-uh! Don't say it, Bernie.
Listen, stop calling me Bernie.
Whatever you say, Miss Lafleur.
Come on, boy. Come on.
Whoa, boy. Whoa, boy. Whoa.
Look.
Come on, let's go tell Mr. Dugan
what we've found.
(Dugan) Must've been
a military outpost during the war.
(Bernadette) These men are behaving
as if the war's still going on.
lt may be they don't know it's over.
l read where the news
never reached some of them.
What war?
Well, we'll just go right down there
and disabuse them of that notion.
Are you outta your mind? They'd cut
you down before you opened your mouth.
- We don't even know how many there are.
- We've got to do something.
Yeah, beat a hasty retreat back to the plane
where there's a little armor
between them and us.
Come on.
Watch it, Bobby.
Are we supposed to hide in here forever,
Mr. Dugan?
What's the matter with you people?
This is no joke.
They're out there waiting for us.
They have real guns with real bullets.
l'll help you, Mr. Dugan.
Thanks, but that doesn't
make me feel a whole lot better.
- What would?
- A machine gun.
Well, it seems to me
you might have a better plan.
lf l had a plan, lady, l would've
kept going the first time l saw you.
- My dad could've figured out a strategy.
- Hey, how about playing General Custer?
We could send Brutus out there
on a cavalry charge.
- He might get shot.
- Yeah.
Hey, the war is over. Now, why can't
we go out there and explain it to them?
l'm sure we could resolve this amicably.
Amicably? We just crashed on their
island in an air force bomber.
What makes you think they'd believe you?
- l never lie, Mr. Dugan.
- Can you say that in Japanese?
Hey, l don't care what you say.
l have a job to do and l'm going to do it.
Look!
(they speak Japanese)
You come out! Surrender!
Be prisoner of war or die!
Friends, huh? Those aren't
exactly peashooters they're holding.
(speaks Japanese)
l don't believe it.
Last chance. l count to five.
One.
Four.
Three.
Five.
(yells)
Petey!
Petey, get away from there! Petey!
- Petey!
- Julie, stay calm. The grenade's a dud too.
Just stay where you are. Here goes.
Geronimo!
(yells)
- Get out of here.
- (they shout in Japanese)
And don't ever come back.
Do you hear me?
l guess we showed 'em, huh?
You were terrific. Wasn't he, Bobby?
- He was OK.
- Well, thanks a lot, kid.
- Those poor men. They were humiliated.
- Humiliated?
l guess you'd have liked it
if they'd shot me.
- l did not say that, Mr. Dugan.
- Well, then stop feeling sorry for them.
l still think we should make friends
with them. Your way isn't the answer.
l don't believe you, lady.
We nearly get killed and you wanna
open a Sunday school for the enemy.
You listen and you listen good. l'm in
command here and l say that nobody,
but nobody's, gonna open peace
negotiations with those guys until l say so.
Understand?
Now, we'll have to stand watch
throughout the night.
You take the kids back to the plane.
l'll take the first half.
Move it!
Let's go.
(Julie) Good night.
Good night.
Mr. Dugan was very brave today,
Bobby.
l still don't like him.
l thought you only smoked
on takeoffs and landings.
Yeah, but tonight's special.
l figure if l'm gonna go,
l wanna be doing something l like.
- l wanna talk to you.
- What about?
Well, if l have been less than considerate
to your feelings,
l'd like to apologize.
- What's the catch?
- There's no catch.
l just think that l may have said some
things to you that l shouldn't have.
l guess that goes for me too, Bernie.
l think we share a common problem.
We both seem to have a certain difficulty
with relationships.
l just want to say
that l'd like to try and get along better.
All right?
OK.
lt's my turn on guard.
Yeah...
Well, if you hear anything, holler.
Be careful of that.
lt would be the Christian thing to do to
make friends with them if they come back.
Wouldn't it?
Don't forget to holler.
Hey, kids, did you see Bernie?
No, why?
- Where are you going?
- To find Bernie.
She's probably started
World War lll by now.
He really is a pain.
Come on, let's go swimming.
l'm gonna beat you.
Hello, in there.
l come in peace.
Anybody home?
Don't be afraid. l'm a friend.
Hello?
(men speaking in Japanese)
(yelling in Japanese)
No, wait!
Please.
l come in peace. ln the name
of the Universe Society of Quebec.
We're a friendly mission.
We wish you no harm.
- Go on.
- Non.
l must speak with you. lt's very important.
lt's about the war with America.
The war is over.
Bernie?
(insects buzz. he groans)
Bulls and ducks, a cow, kids.
What'd l ever do to deserve this?
Bernie?
Mmm!
- Mmm?
- Hmm-hmm!
- Dozo.
- No, thank you, l can't eat another thing.
- Thank you.
- You like?
l like. Too much.
You lucky. Today me cook.
Tomorrow Commander Hiro.
Hiro! Hiro!
Him not so good.
(they laugh)
(distant Japanese)
- (soldier) Take that.
- (Bernadette) No, please, no more.
- l've had enough.
- (the men laugh)
(Hiro yells)
Stop!
Hiro, Cleveland, stop.
Mr. Dugan's a friend.
(Cleveland speaks Japanese)
- What's going on?
- Look what you've done.
- You've ruined everything.
- l ruined...?
You mean they weren't torturing you?
l'm perfectly fine. Can't you see that?
The war is over, Mr. Dugan.
And now l would like to introduce,
from the lmperial Japanese Navy,
Commander Hiro.
Hiro.
- And Lieutenant...
- Kurishima.
Known as Cleveland.
- Captain Dugan.
- (Cleveland speaks Japanese)
- Cleveland?
- Mm. My mother visit America in 1 924.
Her favorite city, Cleveland.
Name me for that.
Teach me first-class Eng-rish.
Yes...
They have been here for 35 years with
no contact with the world, not even a radio.
But they know now we are going to be
very good friends. Aren't we?
(speaks Japanese)
(Cleveland) Yes. Friends.
Now, everyone clasp hands.
(Cleveland speaks Japanese)
(Bernadette) Mr. Dugan.
Friends.
(Japanese)
That's when they lost their comrades,
the radio.
They spent years transporting
what they had left up to the hill.
l mean, what courage.
What perseverance.
- You're very quiet, Mr. Dugan.
- l told you not to leave.
That's it. Your pride's hurt.
l was dictated by a higher authority.
Huh? Oh...
Yeah, well, l was worried about you
and l thought you might need my help.
l can take care of myself
just fine, thank you.
You don't give an inch, do you?
What if they'd hurt you?
- But they didn't.
- How was l to know?
So you came charging in
like a bull in a china shop.
Well, Mr. Dugan,
you, like the rest of the world,
must learn that violence
is not the only solution to problems.
Well, enough of that.
Let's get the food ready.
You get it ready. l'm not hungry.
l'm sorry.
l said l was sorry.
- You'll wake the children.
- Well, we can go outside.
- Julie, come on.
- OK, l'm coming.
- l don't want to fight any more.
- Neither do l.
Look, l may do things differently than
what you like but l was trying to save you.
- l know that now, Mr. Dugan.
- Would you please stop with this Mr. stuff?
You only make me feel like my old man.
Dugan. Just Dugan. That's enough.
Right, Dugan.
Look, Bernie, l must've walked five miles
tonight trying to figure out what l'm feeling.
What hit me is... l care about you.
- l'm sorry.
- Shh.
- Good night.
- (Bobby) Look out.
- 'Night, kids.
- How can she like him?
- Well, he's kinda cute.
Cute?
Well, you know, Bobby, he's really funny.
He reminds me of Petey
when l first got him,
always squawking and trying to peck
people, but he didn't mean it.
l'm right about him. You'll see.
Pull!
- We won't make it, Dugan.
- We'll make it.
These extra fuel tanks
are made out of rubber.
We can make a raft out of them
and we can float off this mud pile.
- lt'll never work.
- Why not?
All you did as a pilot was get us
crashed on a desert island.
So how come you think
you can be a sea pilot?
Robert, the fact that we were off course
was not Mr. Dugan's fault.
Kid, when your muscles are as big
as your mouth you'll be a real help,
so shut up and pull.
Come on, pull.
- (they speak Japanese)
- Pull!
Make raft.
Sail away.
Go home. Be happy.
(they speak Japanese)
Raft idea, no good.
On ocean, you die quick.
Well, if you've got a better idea, let's hear it.
(he speaks Japanese)
(they speak Japanese)
Commander, number one officer.
Him idea, number one.
No make raft. Make boat.
- Make a boat out of what?
- Out of prane.
- Prane?
- l have problem with Rs.
You'll have a lot more trouble
making a boat out of that plane.
But prane already is boat.
Just wrong side up.
- What?
- (they speak Japanese)
You see, turn prane over. What you got?
- An upside-down plane.
- No!
You got boat.
Look see. Look see.
Tail become a rudder.
Rudder, huh?
And wings inside empty. Float good.
- Better than raft.
- Better than raft, huh?
Make big sail. Have good power.
You'll still have
one wing bigger than the other.
That's gonna put you off balance.
Then the engines are gonna pull you down
in the water. No, l don't think so.
Oh, easy fix. No problem.
You like idea?
- l guess you think it's a great idea, huh?
- Yeah, l like it.
Well, l don't. l'm not so sure
l want anyone chopping up my plane.
Oh, believe me, it no fly again.
You want stay here
until someone find you?
- Well, a couple of days, a few weeks.
- How about... 35 years?
That's great. l'm proud of you.
- (Hiro laughs)
- l'm really proud. That's pretty great.
Why didn't l think of this?
Huh?
(Cleveland) Pull! Pull! Everybody pull!
OK!
(they yell)
lt's going.
Hey, those guys really know
what they're doing.
(they argue in Japanese)
We're ready now. Turn over.
(motor)
OK?
(speaks Japanese)
(they speak Japanese)
Oh...
l need a very large piece
to put in the center.
(speaks Japanese)
Our flag strong. Make good sail. You use.
Thank you. Very much.
l'll put it at the top of the sail.
A place of honor.
(speaks Japanese)
- What you doing?
- Getting the animals on board.
The animals can't come.
What?
Well, it's dangerous enough without them.
We gotta save ourselves.
You mean
you're just gonna leave them here?
Well, they're only animals.
They'll be fine.
- Look, l know you like them.
- l love them.
They trust us to take care of them.
- Yeah, l understand...
- (Bobby) You don't understand.
You don't know about loving them
because you don't even like them.
Julie told me you were just teasing
about Brutus but you really meant it.
- This proves it.
- Now, wait a minute.
You be quiet. You got stuck with all of us
and now you want to get rid of us.
Julie told me you were really nice
underneath and you just talk grouchy,
and she said she was
gonna still love you anyway.
Well...
- Look, Julie, you have to understand...
- You still think he's so great, after all?
He's gonna leave the animals here to die.
Do you?
Julie...
lf we're gonna take the animals with us,
we'd better make them
comfortable beds to sleep in. OK?
OK.
l love you, Mr. Dugan.
Bobby! Bobby!
Bobby, the animals
can come on the plane with us.
Bobby?
What's this?
- Do you like it?
- Well, l hate the name Noah.
Oh...
l'm sorry. l didn't know.
No, wait a second. lt could be worse.
- l guess we could leave it.
- Yes?
Yeah.
(inaudible)
Bernie! Bernie!
Any sign of them?
- Have you seen them? Where are they?
- l don't know.
lt's almost high tide. lf they don't get her
soon, we've blown a whole day.
- Are the supplies loaded?
- All loaded.
Well, we gotta go now.
Bobby, are the animals secure?
They're OK.
lf that plane sinks because of those
animals, l'm gonna cut my throat.
- Get ready.
- We can't leave without them.
lt's OK, they'll swim out after us.
(shouted Japanese)
Yes, wait for us!
- You wait! Wait! Wait!
- Come on.
- OK, we're coming, we're coming. Wait.
- Come on!
(Cleveland) OK, wait!
- What kept you guys?
- We take care of business. Hurry.
But l thought you told me
high tide was at 1 1 .00.
Yes, 1 1 . Hurry, hurry.
Of course. 1 1 .
Please, you hurry, hurry. Get plane to sea.
Well, OK, OK, but you're the one...
(explosion)
- l don't believe it.
- Orders.
Leave island, leave nothing.
Well, what if we're not ready? lf the plane
breaks up, if we gotta go back for repairs?
All of your equipment, nothing left?
- Commander Hiro very efficient.
- Hiro.
Nothing.
Well, everybody, you know what
you have to do. Take up your positions.
lf l were a star
A tiny star
You'd be my starlight
Half of me is me
The other half of me is you
lf l were a bird
A tiny bird
You'd be my wings
For only half of me is me
The other half of me is you...
Good work, you guys.
Well, Bernie, next stop, Hawaii.
God willing.
lf l were a tree
You'd be my roots
We'd grow together
Half of me is me
The other half is you
- Dugan.
- What is it?
l'm sorry, l had to wake you. lt's important.
l was reading the Bible and l got
an idea about sending a message.
Oh, is there a chapter on radio repair?
Genesis 8:8.
And Noah sent forth a dove from him
to see if the waters were abated
off the face of the ground.
Only one thing, Bernie.
We don't have a dove.
We're counting on you
to deliver this message, Petey.
So keep heading that way
until you get there. Got it?
(shouted Japanese)
Be careful, Petey.
- ls he gonna make it?
- lf he does, he'd better speak Chinese.
Hawaii's the other way.
Maybe lucky tomorrow. Catch fish.
Oh, yeah, we could use some.
Julie.
Dear Lord,
thank you for what we are about to eat
and let us be truly thankful.
And if you have an extra minute,
give Petey a little push towards Hawaii.
Please.
Good girl, Melinda, you're doing just fine.
Here, Brutus. Here. Here.
Brutus, you have to try and eat something
or you'll starve.
Good thing you're not seasick, Melinda.
Any eggs in the chicken coops, Bobby?
l'm going to check now.
Still no luck, huh?
Yes, no fish.
Well, maybe you're using
the wrong kind of bait.
(speaks Japanese)
(Hiro speaks Japanese)
Commander Hiro say,
something wrong, not our fault.
- l got five, Julie.
- (sighs) Well, that's better than four.
l'll take them to the kitchen.
Hey, Brutus, try this.
lt's real good for you.
- Hey, what do you think you're doing?
- l'm trying to make Brutus better.
Not any more you're not.
That's our food supply
and l won't have you throwing it away.
- lt's only a little bit.
- Look, kid.
Our rations aren't gonna last forever
so let's get one thing straight.
Animals get animal food, not people food.
You dish that out. l'll take care of this.
Oh...
Share this with Hiro and Cleveland.
- OK. Thank you.
- OK?
- For you, sir.
- ls this mine?
- Yes.
- l can do whatever l want with it, right?
- Oh, yes.
- Then l'm gonna give it to Brutus.
Now l know why he likes animals.
He's as stubborn as a mule.
Mules aren't stubborn.
lt's just that some people are too dumb
to get 'em to do
what they want 'em to do.
- He doesn't mean to be rude.
- Don't give me any of that orphan boy flak.
He'll make out OK. l did.
l'm sorry, Miss Lafleur. We checked
every coop. There aren't any eggs.
All right, Bobby. Thank you.
Well, if our friends
don't come up with some fish soon,
we're down to emergency rations.
The hens aren't laying any more.
Melinda, she doesn't want
to give any more milk.
Yeah, l know. And l'm sick of rice.
Well,
if the chickens aren't laying any more.
- Yes, that's what l had on my mind.
- No.
Bobby, l know how you feel
but l'm afraid we're gonna have to.
We wouldn't have to if Hiro and Cleveland
knew how to catch fish.
The Japanese invented fishing, kid.
lf they can't catch them, nobody can.
- l bet l can.
- Sure...
Sure. What are you gonna do,
talk them into taking the bait?
Now, you look. Me and Frankie used to
catch a lot of fish back at the orphanage.
l'm not in the mood
for a kid story right now.
l may be a kid
but that doesn't mean l'm stupid.
Bobby, that's enough.
Captain Dugan just can't...
Bernie, he's right.
Let's hear him out.
Well, you see, there was a stream
where we used to catch catfish.
You see, what we'd do is hang a lantern
over the side of our rowboat at night.
And then, you see, the fish would swim up
to the lantern to see what it was.
So, why couldn't we
fix up some kind of light here?
Bobby, you're a genius.
We've got the biggest lanterns you could
want. Come on, kid, let's go fishing.
(motor)
OK!
- OK!
- OK.
- Right.
Not bad, eh?
Very nice, nice.
- Look, Miss Lafleur.
- l know. lt's like our private aquarium.
Come. Let's tell the others to start fishing.
There's a lot.
- Can't l stay and watch?
- You can watch later. Come on.
- The more lines out, the better.
- All right.
(she hums Frre Jacques)
(stops humming)
(she screams)
Julie?
Julie!
Take it easy, Julie. What's the matter?
Out there. l saw a shark.
- Why, Julie, it's all right.
- He came at me.
Yes, yes, but it's all right now. OK, OK.
Commander say, shark reason no fish.
Then we gotta get rid of the shark.
- Ah, dangerous at night.
- Well, it's now or no more fish.
- Are you with me?
- l'm with you.
(speaks Japanese)
OK.
OK, we catch.
(speaks Japanese)
That's all we have left.
Well, we can't help it, Bernie.
We gotta use it.
Cast thy bread upon the waters
for thou shalt find it after many days.
- Dugan.
- Ecclesiastes.
Stick around, Bernadette,
l'm full of surprises.
Tell the kids to stay below,
it could get rough.
- All right.
- (speaks Japanese)
- Put it in.
Shark! Shark!
Come on! Come on! Get the rope!
(they speak Japanese)
(Dugan) Hold on. Tie it down.
Hold on. Hold on.
Be careful. Just hold on. Keep holding.
(Dugan) Hold on.
Just keep holding on with all your might.
Keep pulling on it. Pull!
- What happened? l thought you had him.
- Hey, you, get off of there, just get off!
Bobby!
- Mr. Dugan!
- No, Dugan! No, no! No, Dugan!
- (Cleveland) No, don't jump.
- (Bobby) Mr. Dugan!
(Cleveland) Come back, Dugan!
- (splutters)
- Don't worry. Come on. Let's get out.
Please, God, help him.
The shark! The shark, Dugan!
Dugan, come back! Hurry! Hurry!
Come on, Dugan! Hurry! Hurry!
Hurry! Come on, come on, Dugan! Hurry!
(Julie) Bobby! Bobby!
You OK?
l... l was wrong about you, Mr. Dugan.
- l'm sorry.
- You're sorry, huh?
When the hell are you gonna get it through
that skull of yours to do what you're told?
You nearly got yourself killed.
You nearly got me killed.
Cleveland, take him downstairs
and get him changed.
Right, OK. Here we go.
That was a very good shot.
Drink, drink.
ls hot.
ls good for you.
Julie. Cleveland.
Could you leave us alone
just for a minute, please?
(speaks Japanese)
Well, how are you feeling?
l'm OK.
l'm sorry
l had to come down on you so hard.
But you were right.
lt was a dumb thing to do.
l won't ever do anything like it again.
Well, everybody does a dumb thing
every once in a while.
Friends?
Friends.
Well, we're on our way again.
What's the matter?
Come on, what's up?
lt's funny. We're floating around
in the middle of nowhere
and this morning it hit me, it's all my faul
- Oh, Bernie!
- lt's my fault.
l dream up this idea
of making farmers out of Makuaranas.
l bet they're quite happy as they are.
l force my society into letting me go.
l convince you and Stoney
to fly me in a plane
that no sensible person should get into.
l put a spell on the compass. lf it weren't
for me, those children wouldn't be here.
What have l been doing?
Listen, Bernie, you kept those kids going
when they had no reason to.
You kept me going, too.
- Are we gonna make it?
- You bet we are.
Petey's out there right now, flying his little
heart out. lf he hasn't already reached land.
And l'm sure they sent word
when we didn't get to your island.
Planes are probably
looking for us right now.
And we're not far from shipping lanes.
A freighter could come.
l love you.
l love you too.
Big wind.
- We'd better take the sail in.
- Mm-hm.
(speaks Japanese)
Will it be a bad storm, Miss Lafleur?
l'm afraid it will be, Julie.
(speaks Japanese)
(clunking)
(Brutus snorts)
(speaks Japanese)
(crack)
Hurry up. Come on, Hiro.
Come on. Whoa.
lt's over!
We made it.
For somebody past her prime, you are
just amazing, old lady, just amazing.
lt'd take more than a storm to sink you.
Dugan! Dugan!
Oh, you come quickly.
He fall down. Very bad.
l think he dying.
Easy, Brutus...
(Brutus groans)
He... He is gonna be OK.
lsn't he, Miss Lafleur?
Bobby, he isn't.
He is gonna be OK. You'll see.
Mr. Dugan?
He is gonna be OK. Please.
No!
lt has to be done, Bobby. You don't wanna
see Brutus go on suffering like this?
No, stay back. Stay away from him.
What would your dad want you to do now,
Bobby?
l never knew my dad. He left me at
the orphanage and then he went away.
They didn't care.
Well, that was then and this is now and
there are people here who do care, Bobby.
- Like who?
- All of us care. We care about Brutus too.
Stay back! Stay away from him!
No!
(speaks Japanese)
Goodbye, Brutus.
(ship's horn)
Dugan...
- (cheering)
- Now hear this. Now hear this.
All hands fore and aft.
l don't believe it.
Believe, Dugan. Believe.
(man) Do you. Noah. take this woman
to be your lawfully wedded wife.
to have and to hold... ?