Antarctica.
An inhospitable wasteland.
But even here,
on the earth's frozen bottom...
we find life.
And not just any life.
Penguins!
Joyous, frolicking, waddling,
cute and cuddly life.
Look at them...
tumbling onto their chubby bum-bums.
Who could take these
frisky little snow clowns...
Seriously?
Does anyone even know
where we're marching to?
- Who cares?
- I question nothing.
- Me, too.
- Me, too!
Well, fine!
We'll just fly to the front of the line
and see for ourselves.
Kowalski! Rico!
Engage aerial surveillance.
Here we go! Doing it! Come on!
Skipper, we appear to be flightless.
Well, what's the point of these?
I like it! Hey, this could be our thing!
What are we gonna call it?
Let's call it the "high one."
Hey, did anybody see that?
That's an egg!
Is someone gonna go get it?
We can't do that.
Why not?
Well, it's a dangerous world out there,
and we're just penguins.
You know, nothing but cute and cuddly.
Yeah! Why do you think there are always
documentary crews filming us?
Well, sorry, kid.
We lose a few eggs every year.
It's just nature.
Oh, right. Nature.
I guess that makes sense...
but something deep down in my gut
tells me that it makes no sense at all.
You know what? I reject nature!
Who's with me?
The old ship.
No one's ever returned from there alive.
Relax, Kowalski.
There's a bird down there now.
Look, he's fine.
Leopard seals. Nature's snakes.
Aren't snakes "nature's snakes"?
How should I know?
I live on the flipping frozen tundra!
They're going for the egg!
Give me a way down there, ASAP!
All one would have to do
is collect 300 feet of kelp...
Tiny and helpless,
the baby penguins are frozen with fear.
They know if they fall from this cliff,
they will surely die.
Gunter, give them a shove.
...harnessing the jellyfish we've trained
to obey simple voice commands.
Now, that's more like it!
That-a-boy, Rico!
Don't let them have it!
Okay! I guess that works.
Get to high ground!
BOOyah!
Success!
I'd recommend firing it now!
Nope. Hold on.
We really should fire it!
Not till we see the white of its eyes.
They're mostly pupil.
Very little white! Almost none!
They got to have a little bit of white,
right?
None whatsoever!
What if they look really far
to the left?
Fire in the hole!
Kowalski, analysis?
We are really awesome at this!
Boys, we did it! Mission accomplished.
Hey, we could do our thing!
High one!
Yes!
My bad!
Look, it's the miracle of birth!
A moment of extraordinary beauty.
That's disgusting!
I think I have amniotic sac in my mouth!
Hello! Are you my family?
You don't have a family,
and we're all going to die. Sorry.
What?
What? I thought that was what
we were all nodding about.
No one's gonna die!
Know what you've got, kid?
You've got us.
We've got each other.
If that ain't a family,
I don't know what is.
So adorable.
Kowalski, what's our trajectory?
95% certain we're still doomed.
And the other 5%?
Adventure and glory
like no penguins have ever seen before.
I'll take that action.
But where are we going?
The future, boys.
The glorious future.
That song!
I swear, it's gonna make me
lose my salmon.
Singing getting louder, Skipper.
Then move faster!
And somebody get that wig off Private!
Kowalski, status report!
I am really getting tired of this song.
Well, the best part
of owning a circus...
ls you can transport a cannon
over state lines.
Ten years ago, on this very day,
a tiny egg hatched...
and our world got a little bit cuter.
So, tonight, Private,
we celebrate your birthday...
by infiltrating
the United States gold depository...
at Fort Knox!
Splendid!
- What?
- There she is, boys!
The object of our unholy desire...
the butter on our biscuit...
-the royal flush...
- Skipper?
Private, what's our rule
about interrupting analogies?
Sorry. Please continue.
The moment's gone. Private ruined it.
Sir, we're approaching our target.
But, Skipper, I really don't--
Are you questioning
my leadership, Private?
- No, sir.
- Too bad.
Because I respect a soldier
with some moxie.
Really? Then I really think we should--
Whoa, whoa!
Dial back the moxie, sass-mouth!
Look at you. Still so adorable.
Fire in the hole!
Eight o'clock. Night-night time!
What?
Private, come on!
Please enter passcode.
Kowalski, you're up.
Rico, sonic incursion device.
Oh, come on. You're kidding, right?
Kentucky, Skipper.
They do love their Flatt and Scruggs.
Y'all come in now, you hear?
Have yourself an ice tea.
Private, if you could have anything
you wanted in the whole wide world...
what would it be?
Well, gee, Skipper.
I think to be a meaningful
and valued member of this team.
Oh, well, we got you something else.
A vending machine?
Not just any vending machine, Private.
The last remaining home
in America's nanny state...
for those succulent, but chemically
hazardous bits of puffed heaven called--
Cheezy Dibbles!
Happy ding-dong birthday,
you little scamp.
Thank you!
You mess with the bull,
you're gonna get the horns, Private.
Now hit that machine
and get your present.
We just broke into the most secure facility
in North America.
You know what that means?
We're wanted criminals who'll be on the I am
the rest of our lives...
always feeling the hot breath
of Johnny Law on our necks?
No! It means, as elite units go,
we're the elitist of the elite.
Top shelf in the bureau.
The penultimate, plus one.
Where'd Private go?
There he is. D-3.
Oh, Private. How much is he?
He's $3.50, sir.
That's outrageous. Even for Private.
Sir, the machine is alive!
I don't think I like your attitude,
vending machine.
Or your prices!
Release them!
What the--?
Kowalski, analysis!
All evidence indicates...
late too many Cheezy Dibbles.
We're behind enemy lines
and incredibly thirsty.
Rico, bust us out
of this delicious prison.
Nice work, Rico!
You are a meaningful
and valued member of this team.
Private, quit lollygagging.
And regular gagging.
Dark and ominous.
Two of my least favorite traits
in a room.
Look! A button.
Private, don't!
Now, what have I told you about--
Sorry, what?
It looks like some sort of giant laser
sent to kill us all, sir.
Another one!
No!
What the--?
Naughty, naughty!
Pretty birds belong in their cages.
Now, that's just hurtful.
And I was so happy to see you again.
Skipper, Kowalski, Rico...
and sweet little Private.
Who are you?
The humans know me
as Doctor Octavius Brine...
renowned geneticist,
cheese enthusiast...
and frequent donor to NPR pledge drives.
But you know me by a different,
much older name.
A name perhaps you'd hoped
you'd never hear again.
A phantom!
A shadow of a former life.
I...
am...
Dave!
Kowalski?
Sorry, sir. No clue.
Dave!
- Dave!
- Dave?
Dave!
Dave.
Sorry.
Wait, wait. I live this way.
Go ahead, Dan. Continue.
You seriously don't remember me?
Dave! Dave! Right! Oh, yeah, long time!
How's the wife?
I've never been married!
You may not remember me
but I could never forget you.
Let's shake up some old memories.
New York City.
The Central Park Zoo. Life was good.
Roomy tank...
great location...
monkey-house views.
And, of course...
my adoring legion of fans!
Cool!
Dave!
The octopus of a thousand tricks.
Awesome!
I was the total package.
Wow!
Hey. kids!
You got to see this! Get up here, quick!
And then, you arrived.
They're so adorable!
Just smile and wave, boys.
Smile and wave.
And took everything from me.
- They are so adorable.
- Have you ever seen anything cuter?
Four adorable baby penguins.
With you around...
no one wanted an old octopus anymore.
"Out you go, Dave!"
And so it went, over and over...
at zoo after aquarium.
I can't see the penguins, man!
Adorable penguins stole the show.
While I was shunned.
Forgotten.
Unwanted.
Alone.
That sounds awful!
Oh, it was.
I came to realize, some creatures
are born to get all the love.
The rest of us get nothing.
The only thing that has kept me going
all these years...
is my burning thirst for revenge!
And my precious
souvenir snow globe collection.
What is wrong with you?
Daryl, Daryl, Daryl, you can't blame us
for what happened to you.
Can!
That's how this whole revenge thing works!
And with this,
I finally have the power to destroy you!
Crikey!
Nicolas, cage them.
I've got some bad news for you, Dennis.
You messed with the wrong birds.
Because we are an elite unit,
the best of the best.
The cream of the corn on a platinum cob!
And we're gonna take your deadly green
goop and sashay right out the exit hatch.
And just how are you going to do that?
Deploy secret weapon!
The cheese, it burns!
Roll out!
After them!
All right, boys, it's just like Cuba!
Taxi!
How about some music? Something chase-y!
Here they come!
Let's move!
Stroke! Stroke! Stroke again!
Stroke some more!
Stroke! Stroke! Stroke!
Sorry!
We've got baddies, six o'clock!
Kowalski, battle formation!
So, you squeegees
wanna do the gondola mambo?
Let's dance!
Mother of pearl, that stings!
I've lost visual!
Kowalski, be my eyes!
Left!
Right, right! Up!
Duck!
I think I got them.
They are down, sir.
Excelente!
Skipper!
They're back up,
and we are running out of canal!
Parker Pusey! Go all-terrain.
Will you marry-- What?
We've lost Engine One!
And Two and Three!
Four!
Switch to emergency power!
AVE-Bye, Skipper!
We've got melons! Dead ahead!
I can see! Rico, the glowy thing!
Venetian blinded again!
We've been boarded!
Initiate self-destruct sequence!
Nice!
Frankly, I'm surprised
we had a self-destruct sequence.
All right, boys, battle stance!
We're in battle stance, sir.
Okay, good. Now, we spring our trap.
I'm not sure they're the ones
that are trapped, sir.
Kowalski, remember our little talk about
true, but unhelpful, comments?
Yes, sir.
Sometimes we just have to wing it!
Wow.
Sorry for underestimating
the plan, Skipper.
It's okay, Kowalski.
Just don't ever doubt me again.
Now what the heck is going on?
Remain calm, penguins.
You are now under the protection
of the North Wind.
You're welcome.
Oh. my gosh!
You guys are so cute!
You're just so cute!
And cuddly!
Hey. get away! No more hugs!
It's like being licked
by a basket full of puppy dogs.
Corporal!
Corporal! Chart a course
back to North Wind headquarters.
Eva, inform them
that we're bringing in witnesses.
Private, Dibble me.
We're not going anywhere with you.
We don't even know who the heck you are!
The North Wind is
an elite undercover interspe--
The North Wind is an elite un--
An elite undercover interspecies“
...task f--
...force. Dedicated to he--
Helping"
Dedicated to helping--
Dedicated to helping animals who can't
help themselves.
Like penguins.
Really? And you are?
My name is classified.
"Classified," eh? What is that, Dutch?
Can't really hear the accent.
- Excuse me?
- There's the accent!
My name isn't "Classified."
My name is classified,
because I am the leader of this strike team.
The seal is Short Fuse,
weapons and explosives.
The bear is Corporal, he's our muscle.
And the owl is Eva,
intelligence and analysis.
Well, Agent Classified,
we happen to be an elite unit, too.
Self-destruct sequence activated.
You know,
you should really label these things.
In three... two... one--
The name's Skipper. I run this outfit.
Back there is Kowalski.
He's the brains of our operation.
Say something smart, Kowalski.
See?
He's working on a whole other level.
And Rico.
He's our demolition expert.
He destroyed that chair
for the sheer fun of it.
No reason at all.
And then there's Private.
He's sort of our, you know...
secretary/mascot.
- Cute.
- And cuddly.
Oh, sorry.
Well, let's see how well
"cute and cuddly" handles this next bit.
Nice doggy door.
Wow!
Look at this!
Well, well, well.
Not a bad place
you got here, Classified.
Thank you. That's not my name.
Arrival, Pad 17.
All right, tiny penguins.
The best way for the North Wind
to protect helpless animals like yourselves...
is to bring Dr. Brine to justice.
Now, you were inside his sub...
so I need to know everything you know.
Hey!
Just tell me everything you know.
All right.
Numero uno.
Never trust a Dutchman in a tulip fight.
"Tulip fight."
Canada is secretly training
an army of sasquatch.
"Sasquatch."
Hot dogs are, in fact,
only 17% actual dog.
Not "everything" everything!
Just everything regarding your abduction
by Dr. Octavius Brine.
- Why didn't you say so?
- What?
My team has uncovered
that Dr. Octavius Brine...
is actually an individual
known as Derek!
-"Dave".
- As Dave, the octopus.
An octopus?
No, Dr. Brine is not an octopus.
He is--
An octopus. Precisely.
That's exactly what our intel indicated.
Release the sheep.
What you, of course,
could not know...
is that Dr. Brine's laboratory in Venice
is secretly developing a doomsday weapon...
called the "Medusa Serum."
But what you don't know...
-is that Dirk...
-"Dave."
...Dave won't be using his
Bazooka Serum...
-"Medusa Serum."
-...Medusa Serum on anybody.
That part is accurate.
Show him, Rico!
You stole the Medusa Serum?
Well, "Stole the serum,"
"Saved the day," "Did your job for you."
Call it what you will.
Debbie!
-"Dave."
- Dave!
He hacked into our system.
Where's the sound?
Dave!
- Your microphone, it's not on.
- I can't hear anything.
Click on the button
with the picture of the microphone.
Every time a villain calls in,
this happens.
Hello? Hello?
Now we can hear you,
but we cannot see you.
Every time!
It's like talking to my parents.
How about now?
Yes, we've got you.
Excellent. Now where was I?
Dave!
Greetings, North Wind.
I see you've met my old zoo-mates.
We were never "mates."
There was no mating.
Turn yourself in, David.
You're powerless now that I've stolen
your precious Medusa Serum.
You? You didn't steal that!
It's over.
It's over?
Then why did I call you?
Weird.
Oh! Maybe it was to show you this!
That is a lot of serum
for four penguins.
Oh, you thought
this was just about you four?
No! No, no, no.
We're just getting started.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
[have to go do some shopping...
for revenge!
Wait. How do you...7
What do I push?
Is it the red, or...
I thought it was the... It's not this--
Incoming alert!
Put it on the screen.
The Berlin Zoo. 15 penguins missing.
Dave is kidnapping other penguins!
No doubt cute and cuddly!
We have to move!
What?
- Time for our A-game!
- Everybody, huddle up!
Corporal, ready the jet.
I'm initiating
North Wind Protocol "Zeta
Twelve more penguins
taken from London Zoo.
Okay, boys, this is it.
The mission we've been preparing for
our entire lives.
We're gonna take down Dave,
or die trying!
- Kowalski, cancel our lmprov class!
- Yes, sir.
Rico, equip"?!
Private, do that little thing I like.
It's still funny.
Skipper! Good news!
I got them to credit our class!
Sir, the jet is ready.
Oh, yeah, baby!
Just like Super Bowl XIX!
They're stealing my stuff!
No! This mission has no place
for a pathetic waddle of useless penguins.
Who are you calling "pathetic"?
Enough!
See, Rico?
That's why you can't have nice things.
You know,
I'm pretty good with computers myself.
Put on your jammies, penguin.
They are even cute when they're asleep.
Not to me!
I want these butterballs out of my way,
and out of my mission.
Ship them to one of our safe-houses.
The most remote place on the planet.
Where the heck are we?
Oxygen content is low.
I suggest we limit our breathing.
Private!
Sorry! I get gassy when I fly.
Toot sweet! He does!
We must be on a plane!
What did North Wind do to us?
They gave us badges!
Not badges, tranquilizer darts!
Classified!
That low-down dirty dog
is trying to kick us off the mission!
He thinks we can't save the penguins,
because we're just "penguins."
Well, penguins are our flesh and feathers!
They're us!
And if anyone's gonna save us...
it's us.
But, Skipper,
we've got to be five miles up.
That pretty much limits our options.
I make my own options.
Brilliant move, Skipper.
But now we seem to be outside the plane.
I kind of got caught up in the moment!
Well, hindsight's 20/20.
Okay, Kowalski,
your turn to pick up the slack.
Oh! Why don't we catch that plane?
Bird strike, log it.
We've got another target, at 12 o'clock.
Good, it's only 11:30.
Follow me, boys, we're going in hot!
Hot, hot!
No one likes a showoff, Private.
Aim for first class!
I'm okay!
Kowalski, where does this aircraft go?
From the odd shape of this bagel,
I'd say we're headed for Paris.
France? Forget .
Not with their tax laws!
Then I would suggest a mid-air transfer.
Affirmative!
Peanuts! Peanuts! Peanuts!
We're out of peanuts, Skipper!
Try pretzels, Private.
Bingo!
There's our ride, boys.
Can't stay, doll.
Danger is my mistress.
Rico, more height!
Pretzels, pretzels, pretzels!
We're out of pretzels!
Then we're leaving just in time,
because these folks are gonna freak!
Deploy "BPS!
Stay on target!
We're gonna catch it!
Crikey! We're not gonna catch it!
Wait a minute. Where's Skipper?
Time to get creative.
Start grabbing boxes, boys!
Going long!
Private, stop playing
with those backpacks.
Find something useful!
Now we're talking! Let's get to work.
400 meters.
300 meters.
Speak American, Kowalski!
Sorry, sir. 218 yards.
109 yards.
Okay, then.
It's clear what we need to do next.
That feels right!
Impressive bouncing, boys.
Now, then, back to civilization.
If we're gonna take Dexter down...
we need to know
where he's gonna strike next.
Goal!
Elijah, would you please take them away?
Penguin footprints, still warm.
We just missed Dave.
Blast it! He's gone!
So many penguins!
Boss! He's stress-eating again!
Corporal!
There, there.
Rub the angry out of the tummy.
Corporal!
Focus!
We are going to save
those helpless penguins...
because we are the North Wind...
and no one...
no one breaks the Wind.
No one breaks the Wind.
There's a good Corporal.
Now, we rescued those four penguins
already, didn't we?
Shipped them off, all cozy and snug,
to a Madagascar safe--
How come there's beeping?
Sir, those penguins...
they never made it to Madagascar.
What? Well, where the dickens are they?
Kowalski, what are our coordinates?
From my calculations, we've arrived
in the center of Dublin, Ireland.
All right, soldiers, we got to blend in.
Riverdance!
But no time
to kiss the Blarney Stone, boys.
We need to find intel
on Dave's location.
Pronto!
All right, you! Where's Dave?
Give us the goods!
Spit it out!
Don't make me use me shillelagh!
Sir, that's a baby squid.
Sorry, laddie.
Stranded on the Emerald Isle
without a single clue.
Well, so much for the luck o' the Irish.
Skipper, look!
Begorrah!
Does anyone speak Gaelic?
No, but it looks like Dave's been busy.
He's stolen penguins from Guadalajara!
- Madrid!
- Paris!
Athens!
Bangalore!
Dusseldorf!
Osaka!
Rio de Janeiro!
- Nairobi!
Amsterdam!
Baton Rouge!
Dave's snow-globe collection!
It's every zoo and aquarium
he got kicked out of!
Don't tell me where he has been.
Tell me where
he will have has been next.
Wait, what is it, Rico?
It's a book! It's a film! It's a play!
First word.
Two syllables. Sounds like...
Sounds like...
What starts with...?
Shanghai.
Dave hasn't been there yet, Skipper.
If we hurry, we can still stop him.
Nice work, Rico!
Pack your bagpipes, boys.
It's time to blow this potato stand!
So, this is it.
Shanghai's famous
Little Dublin district.
Skipper, look!
I see you, Private.
Who's the big boy
standing on his tippy-toes?
- No, I mean--
- I just wanna eat you up!
Skipper, look! Above Private!
Dave's next target.
Shanghai's famous Mermaid Penguins.
Good eye, Kowalski!
And once again...
you've proved that you are a meaningful
and valued member of this team.
Ladies and gentlemen...
Shanghai Marine World
is pleased to present...
our world famous Mermaid Penguins!
Tonight, our mermaids
dedicate their performance...
to all of the missing penguins
around the world.
Stay safe, little guys,
wherever you are.
And we hope you come home real soon.
Now, keep those eyes roving, boys.
Dave is a master of disguise.
He could be a small child,
a house plant.
Maybe even you, or me!
Is it you, Kowalski?
Hey, hold on.
Wait a minute.
Bingg!
Nice try, Dave.
Operation "Flash, Splash, and Crash"
is a go.
Splendid!
Take positions.
Penguin feeding time
will begin in two minutes.
Target, 30 yards and closing.
In position, Skipper.
Rico, report.
In position.
And for you, Private.
YES. Skipper!
- Here's your mermaid costume.
- What?
We need a diversion.
And, frankly, you're the only one
who can pull off that look.
But I can do more, Skipper.
I want to help the team.
Really help the team!
If you think I'm ready, which I am!
Assuming you agree, and perhaps even...
if you don't.
I like the moxie, soldier...
but right now, I need a tail on that tush
and the cutest smile you've got.
You trust me, soldier?
AVE-Bye, Skipper.
Hey, it's feeding time!
Target, 10 yards from flashpoint.
Private, you're up.
You just mermaid my day!
"Flash" is a go!
Look! They let one of the mermaids
out of the tank!
Oh, she's so cute!
It's the cutest thing I've ever seen!
Shields up!
Target is stunned.
Rico, bring the "Splash."
Yeah, yeah!
What are you doing out here, cutie?
Come on, back in your tank.
Secure the mermaids, and find me--
David, the octopus.
A little late, North Wind.
Mission accomplished.
High one!
Corporal, take our prisoner...
the one that belongs to us,
into custody.
What?
You melted him? You birds are sick!
He's going in through the pipes!
Skipper!
Private? Private!
You got to get out of there!
No, no, no! No, no, no!
Private!
Skipper!
'Help!
"No!
Here we go!
Move, move, move!
He's got Private!
He's getting away! He's getting away!
Skipper! The North Wind's plane!
Sweet chariot of the gods!
But can you fly it, man?
There's only way to find out.
No...
I still can't read.
Then we're going off book.
No! No, no, no!
Too much, too much, too much!
I'm getting the hang of this, Skipper.
Good! We're coming for you, Private!
Those ludicrous butterballs
are letting David escape!
Eva, secure transport.
Short Fuse, Corporal, hitch us a ride!
Fire!
Go, fetch!
Hold her steady!
Sir, Dave is pulling ahead.
We are too heavy.
Curse our heavily cheese-dibbled diet!
Rico, give me a West Helsinki fire sale!
- Yeah, yeah!
- Everything must go!
Huh? What the--?
That's everything, sir.
Have you purged the chemical toilet?
But Rico was in there for 15 minutes!
Just do it!
Self-destruct sequence, in five...
Private!
- Stay strong, soldier!
-...four...
...three... two...
...one.
Skipper's log.
Private has been kidnapped by Dave...
while we have been cast adrift
for what seems like days.
No rations, fresh water...
or land in sight.
Kowalski's sick as a dog...
and Rico...
keeps trying to eat him.
Just, please, just cut it out!
Not sure how long we can hold on.
This may be my final entry.
Ow!
7.004, Grand Cm.
Hints oi pear , white peaches.
This salmon is delicious.
I've never been
more hydrated in my life!
Let me cut you a piece of the salmon.
No, thank you.
It's the most delicious thing
on the boat.
I have to loosen my utility belt.
No, I'm full. Just dump it in the ocean.
You know,
we're all in the same boat, here.
Actually, we're not.
And perhaps you could express
a little more concern...
over the fact that you stole
and destroyed...
a $19 million vehicle!
Bill me!
Corporal?
Corporal!
We're picking up a signal, sir.
It's five klicks southwest...
but it stopped at that remote island.
Land?
Good on you!
You've tracked down some land.
No, silly willy.
We've been tracking
your little secretary/mascot.
What? You put a homing device
on Private?
All of you, actually...
when I "darted" you.
You low-down...
dirty, mangy, filthy...
flea-bitten, bum-sniffing
toilet-drinker!
But...
Good!
See? I told you.
You should've left this
to the professionals.
892... 893...
894...
Ahoy, there!
Penguins!
I bet you're all just dying to know
why I brought you here.
He's gonna kill us all!
What? No.
My Medusa Serum doesn't kill anyone.
Where's the fun in that?
So, what does it do?
Something much, much worse.
Right! But, like, what specifically?
Well, that's exactly
what I came up here to show you.
All I need is a test subject.
Hello, little buggy-boo!
Is this about the chirping?
Because I could--
Behold, as I unleash the full power
of the Medusa Serum!
Fire!
Yes! It works!
I made a monster! I made a monster!
And all you adorable penguins are next!
Crikey!
Who said that?
No.
Yes!
Gentlemen, you remember Private.
Hey, Private.
You'll never get away with this, Dave.
My brothers are coming.
And, together, we'll take a wrecking ball
to your whole rotten operation.
Call off the hunt, everyone.
Turns out the elite unit
will be coming to us.
Eva.
What do you see?
My count is 30 hostiles.
31.
Those two are very close... together.
I mean, "intertwined."
Physically.
But not in a...
lx-nay on the irt-flay, Kowalski.
Poor Private.
Alone! Helpless in the belly
of that beast.
We've faced some long odds
before, Skipper.
But these look like the longest.
And oddest.
If we're going to pull this off,
we'll need a diversion.
Deactivating jungle camouflage.
Will you be quiet?
Listen, Classified...
Short Fuse, you were supposed
to handcuff them to the raft!
Don't you hologram me!
I tried, but they don't have hands.
They just have flippers, boss.
And I have flippers,
so it's flipping useless!
All right, pooch.
If you won't work with us...
you better work for us.
Our plan requires a diversion.
I give the orders around here.
As much as it pains me,
I need you to act as our diversion...
for our operation. Understood?
No! This is our plan, and it
requires you to cause a diversion.
-"Dye"-version.
-"Di"-version.
-"Dye.
-"Di."
“Dye! Dye! Dye!"
-"Di! Di! Di!"
Gentlemen, there is only one way
to resolve this.
- We should kiss.
- Plan-off.
Yup, "plan-off."
That's what I was gonna say.
"Plan-off."
Here's Dave's sub.
And this young, helpless,
vulnerable rock...
is Private.
And here's Dave.
While you four blowhards
divert the octopi...
we strike fast, and strike hard!
Get on in here, boys!
Slap him silly, Rico! Come on!
Kowalski, free the hostages!
Now, that's what I'm talking about,
big fella!
With Private freshly liberated,
we celebrate with a well-earned high one...
and feast off Dave's sweet remains.
Any questions?
Whoa! Hey, now!
Wow. I mean, truly impressive.
Especially the bit
where you slap the fruit.
Corporal, dim the lights.
Short Fuse, glasses.
My apologies. I had to rush a bit.
The schematic is a little crude.
Where is that music coming from?
All right.
At 21:50, Skipper, Kowalski and...
Richard, was it?
...divert the octopi
away from their posts.
At 22:00,
Short Fuse breaches the hull...
with a swarm of self-guided,
underwater nano-charges.
I call them "wet kabooms.
- Please, don't.
- Okay, sorry.
- At 22:02, knock-knock.
- Who's there?
- The North Wind.
-"The North Wind" who?
The North Wind who doesn't have time
for knock-knock jokes...
because we're too busy taking down Dave!
Personal hover tank? Check.
Auto-targeting wing mounts? Why not?
At 22:09...
.mission accomplished.
See that? I don't even look back.
There's a huge explosion,
and I just keep walking.
Way to go, boss!
That's North Wind, sucker!
Nicely done.
Blah-di-blah-blah-blah.
A good plan is about more than
effect-y stuff...
and vocabulary words.
And you certainly know a good plan.
Your operation in Shanghai
allowed Dave to escape...
with your boy.
I've never lost a member of my team.
It must feel...
awful!
God, imagine the guilt. The regret.
The feeling that, I don't know...
that it should have been you.
All for penguin plan.
All for North Wind plan.
His...
His is better.
What?
I'm sorry, boys.
But I can't lead you this time.
But...
we're a team.
And you're our skipper, Skipper.
We don't need these guys.
No, Kowalski, but Private does.
I think...
this time,
we leave it to the professionals.
- But, sir...
- It's settled.
We take our orders
from Agent Classified now.
That's an order, Rico!
All right, Classified...
what's the diversion?
We take this shame to our graves.
Agreed.
Hey!
- Time?
-22:00 hours.
Time to take down Dave.
David, the octopus...
show me your tentacles.
All of them.
We lost them, Skipper.
Not a moment too soon.
These hosen are ridin' up my bundesliga.
All right, boys, grab your coconuts
and hold them tight.
Classified should be walking away
from a huge explosion...
with Private on his shoulder
in three, two...
Give him a welcome home, Rico!
Yes! In your face, Dave!
The Private is back!
Welcome home, Private!
Yeah, all right!
Here we go. All right.
Sir, the sub didn't explode...
and I fear the fireworks...
may have been a tactical mistake.
Stay calm!
Do not panic!
We will still win!
Be full of love! Don't hate!
Follow your dreams.
Love yourself. Love other people.
Pick and choose your battles in life!
Don't let anyone tell you what to do.
Ignore the haters.
Love the one you're with.
Eva !
I know!
Welcome, Skipper, Kowalski,
and rootin'-tootin' Rico!
The gang's all here!
The mood is electric!
Is this really, finally everybody?
All right, Dave,
just what have you done with...
Private!
Guys!
You're in for it now, Dave!
Really?
Anyway, great catching up.
Now, who's ready to move on
to live penguin testing?
You point that death ray
away from Private, right now!
It's not a death ray, Skipper.
He's gonna turn us into monsters!
Yepper-doo!
And what comes next, Dave?
Invasion!
Horrible mutant penguins,
unleashed on the streets of New York City!
You're the monster!
Yes!
I'm the monster.
Everyone made that clear to me
every day of my entire life.
But let's see how much everyone loves you
when you're the monster!
Skipper!
You can't take away Private's cuteness!
He's the cute one. That's his thing!
What?
It's all the little guy's got!
You are super cute.
We better crank this up.
Drew, Barry, more power.
- Ready?
- Negotiations have broken down!
Rico, the paperclip!
Bust us out of here!
We need that paperclip!
Chop-chop, soldier!
Where's the paperclip?
Private!
No!
- Private.
- Oh, no.
I disintegrated him.
That wasn't supposed to happen.
You maniac!
You blew him up!
No.
Oh, well!
This is why we test things, people!
I'll have to lower the power
for the others.
Full speed ahead, gentlemen.
The monsters are due in Manhattan.
Sorry!
Crikey!
All right, all right, octopus.
Whatever Dave's paying you,
I'll double it.
Is that a yes?
Does anyone speak octopus?
- Sorry.
- Not a clue.
Blast it!
You free us...
we give you...
many fishes!
What is that?
Oh, great.
Oh, no! This is it!
I don't want to die all squishy!
We're dead. Dead!
Dead. Dead!
Oh, no, we're dead!
Dead!
I pushed a button!
Super. Well done, Private!
Good work, malinki.
Yes. Yes.
Excellent button-pushing.
Compliment, praise, etcetera.
All right, agents...
we are back In business.
Wait! Skipper, Kowalski, Rico...
all those penguins...
They're this way!
So is a massive army of octopi
And as soon as we return
to the North Wind Headquarters...
grab fresh equipment...
and work up a smashing new plan...
we'll come speeding back,
and take down Dave.
But the penguins are in danger!
We have to go now!
Again, "Huge army of octopi."
So, because you failed once,
you're just running away?
We did not fail.
And we are not running away.
We're just very sensibly regrouping.
Skipper wouldn't care!
Plan or no, fancy equipment or no...
he'd never leave a man behind!
Well, I suppose we can't all be penguins,
can we?
No.
But maybe you should be.
Come on.
Showtime, everyone!
Big smiles for the Big Apple!
Listen up, Doris!
You turn us into freaks, and then what?
You think that's gonna
make everybody love you?
No, but they'll despise you.
And I'm sure going to love that!
Breaking news!
The missing penguins have been found!
Okay. According to my notes...
genetic researcher, Dr. Octavius Brine
has found the penguins...
and is bringing them here
to New York's Battery Park.
The penguins are coming back!
Oh, my gosh! Look!
Penguin lovers of the world!
Guess who I found.
Penguins! Penguins!
It wasn't easy...
but seeing the penguins
get what they deserve...
will make it all worthwhile.
What a weird thing to say.
I'm so excited!
Do it.
Skipper! Skipper! Skipper!
Rico! Kowalski!
It's like I can still hear
his little voice calling to us!
You have to get out of there! Move!
"You have a great otter, there. Moo."
Why would he moo?
What are you asking me for?
I'm not Private's little ghost.
Uh-oh.
No!
Are you ready?
Yeah!
Yaw.!
Your new...
and improved...
Penguins!
Penguins! Penguins!
Penguins! Penguins! Penguins!
The people love you.
Just go give them a hug!
Don't let them touch you!
Oh, no. What's happening?
Nobody likes you anymore?
Well, the fun and games
are just beginning.
Watch this, penguins!
Somebody call...
the exterminators!
And when the exterminators
take you away...
you never come back!
Oh, dear.
Oh, no! Oh, no! Oh, no!
What do I do? What do I do?
Crikey!
Come on, then, you wanna go?
You want some argy-bargy?
Uh-oh, missed one!
What a wonderful day in the park!
Skipper!
Wait!
Hold on! What are you doing?
Skipper!
Don't eat that!
Skipper, listen! It's me, Private.
I've got a plan, but I need your help.
I need my Skipper.
Private?
Yes! That's it!
Private, you're alive!
Oh, God!
Kowalski! You've got to get a grip!
Kowalski! Eva is worried about you!
She is?
What did she say?
Did she say my name, specifically?
I mean, were there tears?
Details! Come on, tell me!
Private! You're alive! Come here.
This feels a little awkward...
but I'm happy-
Rico! You need to listen to us.
I guess you're kind of the same
either way.
Heads up!
Looks like we're back in business, boys.
And our business is saving penguin-kind.
Who's with me?
Count me in.
Let's do this!
Let's create and feel momentum!
Sir, how long do we stand here
like this?
Until we've reached maximum coolness.
There it is.
Now all we need is a plan.
I've got one!
You stole Dave's ray?
Well, I figured if we could
reverse the ray...
we could turn everyone back to normal.
Reverse the ray?
That's brilliant!
But it's impossible.
In order to reverse the ray, we would need
to replace the Medusa Serum...
with a power source
of almost immeasurable cuteness.
"Immeasurable cuteness
Where the heck
are we supposed to get that?
No, wait, Private! No!
We don't know what that will do to you!
All right!
The ray! It works!
It works!
Private! Are you okay?
Yes!
Whoa! Butt-hand!
There's a hand attached to his butt.
That was not there before.
Get out of there! That's an order!
Permission to defy order.
Permission denied!
Then I deny your denial.
It's too risky, Private!
It already made you sprout a butt-hand!
I know it has to be me this time.
And I think you know it, too.
I'm the secret weapon!
I'm happy! And Vet--
now that I have my revenge,
I feel empty.
As if what I needed all along was...
more revenge!
In fact, Robin, write this down.
Tomorrow, we move on to kittens!
Then, puppies! Bunnies! Pandas!
Charlize, they're on the ray!
Helen, hunt them down!
William, hurt them.
Halle, bury them!
Hugh, Jack, man the battle stations!
Kevin, bake on!
We're still gonna need
that victory cake!
We're only gonna get
one shot at this, boys.
How we doing on those snow globes?
Beam-splitter ready!
Fire at will!
Do it, Skipper!
Dead batteries?
Game over, Skipper.
No!
Rico, batteries!
Skipper, Kowalski,
hold off those octopi!
We're doing this now!
You heard Private! Deploy!
Get back, you aquatic savages!
Behind you! Beside you!
Six o'clock! Twelve o'clock!
They're coming from every direction!
There's just too many of them!
Whoa!
You came back!
Oh! That's why you look back
at the explosion.
Fallback positions!
Stay away from Private!
Suck it up, Kowalski!
No!
It's over, Skipper.
Over? That's weird.
Then why is Rico
throwing me a fresh pair of double-As?
No!
The remote!
Rico! Dibble me!
It worked!
Private!
Excuse me! Emergency! Coming through.
Make a hole! Make a hole!
Oh, no!
Don't worry!
A chrysalis is just forming around you.
That's perfectly normal.
Private.
Private?
Oh, look at that. Majestic!
Hello!
- Oh! Hey!
- What's wrong?
Have I got something...?
Cover your eyes. Don't turn your head!
So...
How do I look?
You're hideously disfigured...
and will probably be hunted for sport.
What?
If there's anything we've learned
from this delightful adventure, Kowalski...
it's that looks don't matter.
It's what you do that counts.
And look at what you did.
Yes, sir.
You are the most meaningful
and valued member of this team.
Way to go, Private!
Atta boy!
Nicely done.
Way to go, Private. You did it!
We're so proud of you!
You saved us!
We love you, Private!
Yeah, we love you!
You the penguin!
Ramirez!
-"Dave."
- Dave!
What? Are you kidding me?
Dave! Oh, look at you.
You think this is over?
I'm just getting started!
What do we do with him now?
Open this right now!
Here you go, kid.
Cool!
I hope you find happiness, Dave.
It's snowing!
It's snowing! It's snowing!
Right. Now, then...
This is difficult for me to say--
Is it "osteoporosis"?
You just got to lean into the vowel.
Os-tee-oh-...
No, no.
I want to say, you four are
the bravest agents I have ever known.
The point is...
I was wrong about you.
And I hope there is some way
I can make it right.
- Give us jetpacks?
- We should kiss.
Did you just say...?
Well, that feels right!
I think I'd actually
prefer a jetpack, please.
I think we should go with
Private's idea.
Kowalski, what's our trajectory?
95% certain this will end in massive,
flaming disaster.
And the other 5%?
Irrelevant, sir. Jetpacks are awesome!
Agreed.
Who says penguins can't fly?
Booyah!
Skipper, we are going to turn me
back to normal, right?
Absolutely. First thing, Monday.
I'm in a rocket ship!
I want to push the button.
Give me that.
Stealer!
Let's do this! I'm ready!
Okay, on three. One, three, go!
I'm just going to do
a little practice push.
Okay, I'm not going to press it--
Why are you smacking my hand?
Hey, look over there!
I'm a laser show!
Julien!
Hey!
That's the Private we know and love.
High one!
Immeasurable cuteness, right there.
Good to be back.
I feel like a french fry.
I'm okay!
And with cuteness to spare.
Come on!
Frosty mugs of herring juice, all around.
- Private's buying.
- What?
You know, if I'm being honest,
I expected a little more...
Dizzazz!
Yes! Now, that's pizzazz!