My name is Flint Lockwood.
My whole life I always wanted to be
a great inventor.
Just like my hero.
The Scientifically Wonderful
World of Science.
With your host, Chester V.
Welcome back, science friends.
You know, I have devoted my life
to inventing the future.
But every dream has a beginning.
I still remember my first invention:
The humble Food Bar.
It was like Chester V
was speaking directly to me...
...using the language of science.
Now look at us.
Our new Food Bar XL
with flavor crystals.
Still making people happy
after all these years.
Now, kids, you'll almost certainly
never be me.
But, remember, there's no such thing
as small science.
Only small scientists!
We love you, Chester V!
Speaking of small scientists,
say goodbye, Barb.
Goodbye, Barb.
Can your ideas...
...change the world?
Yes.
Just like Chester V...
...my dream was to make the world...
...a better place.
Spray-On Shoes!
How you gonna
get them off, nerd?
Unfortunately, a lot of people...
...didn't believe in me.
But I never gave up.
And eventually...
...I invented this:
A machine that could turn water...
...into food.
Cheeseburger.
It's called the Flint Lockwood
Diatonic Super Mutating...
...Dynamic Food Replicator.
Or, for short...
...the FLDSMDFR.
Because of my invention's
food weather...
...I finally made the world...
...a better place.
Yeah!
I love it!
Or so I thought.
When the weather evolved
into a disaster...
...of epic portions...
...and the machine started creating...
...dangerous living food...
...I had to face the truth:
It was time to...
...put an end...
...to my FLDSMDFR.
Chee... Chee... Chee... Chee...
Cheese...
By destroying
my greatest invention...
...I made something even better:
Friends!
You made me very proud, son.
- Thank you, Dad.
- Sorry.
Sam Sparks, in the eight minutes
since we saved the world...
...I've had time to reflect.
And I think you and I
should have a place together.
A Place?
A place where we work.
You think we work together?
I do.
Awesome! Yes!
- We could build a lab.
- With cool weather...
...forecasting devices!
We can invent fantastic machines
like the FLDSMDFR.
Yeah!
- But not that one.
- No.
- Not ever.
- Never, ever, ever!
What shall we call our lab?
How about Sparkswood?
Sparkswood.
Sparkswood is gonna need
some security.
And I can be your mascot!
And I can be your dad.
There are many ways
in which I can help.
Can't forget you, lab partner.
Steve!
Where'd he get the brown crayon?
This...
- ...could be our future.
- Oh, yeah!
Greetings, friends.
And namaste.
Is that...?
Chester V?
Mustache.
Please have some humanitarian aid...
...as a gesture of our goodwill.
Chester V!
Your lab vest looks even cooler
in person!
Thank you. The lack of sleeves
frees up my arms to do this.
Hand, what did you do?
There's nothing wrong with your hand,
young Lockwood.
You see, I am merely a hologram
of the real Chester V.
The United Nations has asked
me and my Thinkquanauts...
...to assist in the cleanup
and containment...
...of the leftovers all over the world.
Including your Swallow Falls.
We'll get started on the cleanup...
...right away.
As soon as you all leave.
What? You need us to leave?
Listen up, ghost man...
...you expect us to skedaddle from our
homes because of some nasty leftovers?
Yes. Yes, I do.
Son, you can't argue
with yellow police tape.
Everybody back up!
Listen to ghost man.
But do not fret.
All of you will be
temporarily relocated...
...to sunny San Franjose...
...California!
- The home of Live Corp!
On my word as a hologram...
...you shall all return home
before you know it.
Except for you, Flint Lockwood.
Me? Why?
You are going...
Wait, wait, wait. No, no, no.
Where am I going?
Oh, please tell me!
Just give it a second. He's buffering.
You are going to join me
at Live Corp...
...and help us make the world
a better place.
Sir, that's all I've ever wanted.
But I can't.
On account of making a promise
two minutes ago...
...to build a lab with my friends, sir.
I understand, Lockwood.
But if you become
a Thinkquanaut like me...
...then all your dreams will come true.
You have to do this!
What about our dream?
Flint, this is a once-in-a-lifetime
opportunity.
We're all behind you.
Are you guys sure?
Sure.
This is the best day ever!
Sir, I've taken care of everything.
The locals have been evacuated.
Splendid. And the inventor?
- Oh, he took the job.
- Outstanding!
Now we can keep an eye on him.
He has no idea of our real plan.
Contact me as soon as Operation
Capture the Invention succeeds.
Live Corp.
Cheeseburger.
Oh, big day, big day!
Big day, big day...
...big day! Yes!
Wake up, Steve!
Steve.
Do I look like a future Thinkquanaut?
Morning there, skipper.
You want a sardine scramble?
No, thanks! Can't be late!
Flint! Ask that Chester V when
he thinks we can go home again.
Morning, Sam!
Morning, Flint! Are you ready
for your first day?
Yeah! Are you?
Sam?
Well, this is me. Good luck
with your new jobs, guys.
- Good luck, Flint!
- Break a leg, Flint!
Bye!
Good morning, Flint Lockwood
and lab partner.
I'm Barb.
I know, I'm a huge fan.
Monkey.
Excuse me...
...I'm an ape. One of Chester V's
most brilliant innovations.
An orangutan with a human brain...
...within my ape brain.
Like a turducken.
I'll be your welcome ambassador.
Soy latte?
Okay.
Coffee and milk?
Are you ready to...
- ...live?
- Oh, am I!
Monkey.
Ape. Follow me, boys.
Welcome to Live Corp.
There are caffeine stations...
...every 10 feet.
- Soy-free soy latte?
- Thanks!
- Hot.
- Not too bad yourself, monkey.
Caffeine patches
are available 24 hours.
And our mocha-yoga classes
are offered in beginner or grande.
Over here, indoor sports.
Those are encouraged.
Oh, cool! I've never played volleyball.
Well, neither have they.
You'll fit right in!
Can your ideas change the world?
- Behold, the motivation pod.
- Can your ideas...?
I know, right?
- Quinoa latte?
- Absolutely!
Can your ideas...
...change the world?
Yes, Chester V poster, they can!
- Mine too!
- So can mine!
- I have great ideas.
- Absolutely! I've got my idea pants on.
Thinkquanauts! Awesome!
Hey! Excuse me...
...I'm so looking forward
to working with you guy...
That's where we belong, Steve.
Anxious!
That's not even a possibility
until our next vesting ceremony.
- What's that?
- That's where Chester V...
...handpicks a great inventor
and makes him into a Thinkquanaut.
When? When?
Next one's in six months,
so submit your ideas...
...and who knows?
He might choose you.
Really?
Hot chocolate with
double-whipped whipped cream?
- Thanks.
- Happy inventing!
We're gonna have to get used to
that landing.
Okay, Steve, we have six months
until the vesting ceremony.
Let's do this thing.
Can.
That's the spirit, Steve!
Say goodbye...
...to ice cubes
with the Re-Freeze-a-Fan!
Can your ideas change the world?
The Forkenknifenspooninator!
Can your ideas...
...change the world?
The Grocery Deliverator!
Can your ideas change the world?
Invisible coffee table!
Flint.
Can your ideas...
...change the world?
Flint!
The Celebrationator!
A party in a box for any occasion.
Okay, Steve, time to celebrate!
Celebrate!
Flint!
Happy birthday, Tim Lockwood!
Here you go, Dad. Hope you like it.
Steve picked it out.
Steve!
Yeah. Yeah!
Okay, like we practiced.
When I'm up on stage getting my vest...
...you hit the red button
when I say "celebrate."
Celebrate!
Careful, Steve!
- This is a loaded party-in-a-box.
- Hello, Team Live Corp!
It's a pleasure to welcome you...
...to our annual Thinkquanaut
vesting ceremony!
Chester V!
I have built the coolest, hippest
company in the world.
As you all know, the Food Bar
is the lifeblood of this company.
And this year, I've challenged myself
to reinvent taste.
So in two short weeks...
...we shall release the new
Live Corp Food Bar!
Version 8.0!
- Yes!
- And now, without...
...further ado, who will be this year's...
...newest Live Corp Thinkquanaut?
Yeah!
We have received thousands
of invention submissions...
...and today, one of them
will be deemed...
...Thinkquanaut-worthy.
Thank you, Barb.
This person comes from an island.
He's got a memorable mop
of unruly hair.
Hair. Hair!
That's me!
Our newest Live Corp
Thinkquanaut is:
Flint...
Yeah!
- ...ly McCallahan!
- No.
Crikey blikey! Yes!
For inventing...
...a zero-emission car
that runs on cute.
This is the greatest day of my life!
Didgeridoo! I'm finally a real inventor!
Sorry, Steve. No reason to celebrate.
- Celebrate!
- Wait, Steve, no, no, no. No!
Hi, Sam, it's Flint.
I see you're live on TV
with a tornado.
Probably why you're not
answering the phone.
Thinkquanaut? I think not.
Please call me back.
Okay. Bye!
Bad news! Sir, we lost contact...
...with Search Teams X and Y.
- What?
- Yeah!
The situation is...
...grim, sir. Still no sign
of the FLDSMDFR.
Should I send in Team Z?
Are you mad, Barb?
We'll be all out of alphabet.
Look, we're running low
on Thinkquanauts. We need...
...someone expendable.
Someone who knows the island
inside and out.
Someone who's smart, but still naive.
Someone who idolizes me...
...has recently hit rock bottom...
...and will now do
just about anything I ask.
Where are we gonna find
someone so desperate?
I think we already have.
Sprinkles!
Fire!
Flint, who's number one?
Ta-da!
Hey, Flint, I got your message.
Oh, no, what happened to you?
Flint, everyone gets humiliated
on national television.
It's not that big a deal.
Yeah, but not everyone
gets humiliated...
...in front of their childhood hero.
I'll never be a real inventor...
...in Chester's eyes.
Mom gave me this lab coat because...
...she always dreamed
I'd do great things.
Now I guess I won't.
Now that's a big bucket of churn.
Flint, you don't need
Chester's approval.
You can still make...
...the world a better place
without an orange vest.
I don't get vests.
Is it winter on your torso
and summer on your arms?
For what it's worth, the people
who really care about you...
...think you look great in your lab coat.
Good night, Mr. Lockwood.
Good night, my dear.
Hey, look, son.
This Chester V guy.
He promised us we'd be home
before we know it. Well...
...we darn sure know it
and we're not home.
So I say you, me and your friends...
...we take the boat.
We can go fishing every day.
And if there's still a mess on the island,
we can go clean it up ourselves.
Dad, please. I'm not into fishing.
And cleanup? You're way too old
to be doing that kind of work.
I'm only 49.
Flint Lockwood, please.
Oh, Flint.
There's... Could you
come to the door, please?
I think it's that monkey
in your poster.
What? No!
Barb?
Good day.
I'm afraid I have something
very important to discuss...
...with you.
Live Corp.
Chester V wants to see me?
Follow me.
Young Lockwood.
Chester V. Sir.
I can explain everything.
I thought I was gonna meet
the real Chester V.
You are.
- Oh, not me.
- Him.
Yes, it's me.
Sorry about that.
My holograms and I were having
an urgent brainstorming session.
Mr. V! You're real!
I'm so excited to get this opportunity
to show you my inventions.
Hold on. Hold on. That's not
why I brought you here tonight.
Our cleanup operation
back on Swallow Falls...
...has met with
unexpected complications.
This is a photograph...
...before we began our cleanup.
And this was three days ago.
It gets worse, Flint.
There's only two of us left.
We need help.
What is that thing?
Cheesy.
It appears to be
a living cheeseburger...
...with french fry legs
and sesame seed eyes.
Living food?
Oh, no. This could only mean
one thing.
The FLDSMDFR
survived the explosion...
...and it's still operating.
This is what worries me most.
They're trying to learn to swim.
If they succeed and...
...get to the mainland...
...they will destroy monuments
all around the world...
...including the one monument...
...your food storm didn't destroy.
Not Lady Liberty! I've gotta destroy
the FLDSMDFR. But how?
Well, my Thinkquanauts
have invented...
...this.
The BS-USB.
Or BSUSB.
A Bifurcating Systematic
Universal Stop Button!
Precisely. It would destroy
the machine...
...and everything it created.
But we cannot find your FLDSMDFR.
We've searched everywhere...
...and failed.
Chester, I'll find the machine.
I invented it. I can fix this!
Brilliant!
But are you sure you want to
take this on alone?
Yes! Wait, did you say "alone"?
Alone it is, then.
If you succeed, you'll be more
than just a Thinkquanaut.
You'll be my hero.
Your hero?
Yes, my hero.
Your mission must be kept a secret.
We don't wanna create
a worldwide panic.
You mustn't tell anyone, not even
your closest friends and family.
Sir, I won't tell a soul.
Sam! Sam, Sam, Sam!
I gotta tell you a secret! Sam!
Big news. I'm going to Swallow Falls
to destroy the FLDSMDFR...
...which is creating
deadly food monsters...
...which are trying to learn to swim
so they can attack Lady Liberty!
Sam?
Wait, you're doing this alone?
Yeah. Please don't tell Dad. If he finds
out I'm going back to Swallow Falls...
...he's gonna wanna come too.
Well, I'm coming.
What? No! I promised Chester V
I would go alone.
There's no talking you out of this?
- Nope.
- Wait.
Sam, it's gonna be deadly dangerous
with a good chance of death.
And that's why we'll need help.
Triple decaf mochaccino-boba-latte...
...with skim soy and nutmeg sprinkle?
I'd like to order something strong.
Wait your turn, fancy pants.
Flint Lockwood...
...and Sam Sparks!
And Steve too!
- Juicy!
- Earl, we need your help.
Swallow Falls is overrun
with deadly food monsters.
Hey...
- ...where's my coffee?
- Coffee? I'm not a barista...
...I'm a polista!
Let's ride!
Can I come too, Dad?
Son, you are my beautiful,
precious little angel.
But I cannot let you come with me.
Not until you get
your first chest hair.
I have chest hair.
It's just like mine.
Wait a minute.
That's not a chest hair.
That's cupcake frosting.
Tell your mom
I'm getting our home back.
What's up?
Sponge.
Forceps.
A swab.
Manny. We need your help.
I can drop everything.
Camera.
Chick 'n' sushi
Get it while it's cold
Yo, Chicken Brent!
In the flesh.
Swallow Falls is in trouble.
Will you help us?
You bet I will. I just need someone
to cover my shift.
Thanks, tree.
Okay, gang.
We'll be traveling to the island
using my Grocery Deliverator!
All right, who wants to go first?
Hungry.
Yes, Steve, hungry for adventure.
See you on the island,
my brave lab partner.
Afraid!
It worked!
Banana! Banana! Banana! Steve!
I guess it only works on food.
I gotta fix that.
Ahoy there, skipper, my boy.
- Dad.
- Mr. Lockwood?
Dad, no. How did you know
we were here?
I could see you from the apartment.
Flint, if you're going home, so am I.
The island's gonna be
very dangerous...
I was born on the island, and I wanna
die on that island, just like your mom.
Besides, I know that place like
the inside of a tackle box. I wanna help.
- No!
- Flint, let him help.
The man does have a boat.
Which is twice as many boats
as we have.
Fine. But we'll get there faster...
...if we use the Grocery Deliverator.
Steve!
Okay, okay, we'll take the boat!
Shoving off!
Ninety-nine buckets of chum on a boat
Ninety-nine buckets
Of chum
Nineteen buckets of chum on a boat
Nineteen buckets of chum
You hold your nose
And out one goes
There's 18 buckets of chum on a boat
We'll be there in two flaps
of a sardine's fluke!
Thanks, Dad!
Okay, when we land at Swallow Falls...
...our first objective is to get to my lab.
I can use my old computer to pinpoint
the FLDSMDFR's location.
Once we find it, we can shut it down...
...with the utterly irreplaceable BS-USB.
What if you don't find it?
I have to. It's my machine.
If the world gets destroyed
by these, it's my fault.
I can't let that happen.
Land ho!
If we work together,
this should be easy as...
Pie.
Oh, no! We're...
Toast!
French toast!
This is totally...
Bananas!
I was gonna say "nuts,"
but now I'm afraid to.
- Home!
- No! Steve, wait!
The jungle's no place for a monkey.
Home, home, home!
Manny, are you getting this?
- I certainly am.
- Flint.
Look! The climate
has shifted dramatically...
...to allow this much vegetation
to grow!
Sam! Ratbirds!
Okay, then. All ashore
that's going ashore.
Dad, this place is really dangerous.
I'd feel better if you stayed here
on the boat where it's safe.
Safe? I wanna help.
I'd never forgive myself if you
got eaten by a cheespider.
He's right, Tim Lockwood.
Don't worry, we'll get your home back.
Well, fine.
Thanks, Dad. We'll try to be back
before suppertime, okay?
Sure.
Look what's happened to our town.
Look.
There's my angel son...
...Cal's old preschool.
My old van.
Look! An old thing
that I've never seen before!
That's where...
...the Thinkquanauts were
attacked by a cheespider.
It's like a cheesy spider web,
made of...
...cheese. Let's get out of here!
No, wait. What if there's
a survivor in there?
Stand back, everybody.
I'm gonna cut the cheese.
That was the cheese.
Hello? Anybody in here?
Sorry.
That is the biggest strawberry
I've ever seen in my life.
- Is it heavy?
- Yeah. But other than that...
...it looks like a perfectly normal,
fresh, delicious strawberry.
N-woo?
It's moving!
Oh, that was a close one.
You got a little someone
stuck to your pants.
Get it off! Get it off me! Sam! Sam!
Hey, wait, wait. Stop!
Sam, don't touch it! Put it down!
Put it down!
Look at him.
Seriously?
I think I'll name him Barry!
Okay, Sam, could you please
put "Barry" down?
Look, we have to get to the FLDSMDFR
so we can shut it down...
...with this utterly irreplaceable
BS-USB.
Hey! That's not for you!
I need that. Please?
That BS-USB is really important.
N-woo?
- N-woo. Yes.
- N-woo?
Hi, N-woo. Hey, you wanna
hand it to me, buddy?
I beg you.
Please?
N-woo.
N-woo, N-woo. Yes. Yes. There you go.
No!
Don't let him get away!
Stop!
Gotcha.
- N-woo?
- Here, you take it, you take it.
You're gonna have to carry him
until he passes the BS-USB.
And by "pass," you mean...
Yes. Look, we better get a move on...
...before we run into any more
of these creatures.
It's so beautiful.
It's enough to make a grown man cry.
But not this man.
Get back in there, tear.
Wow, I can't believe
the FLDSMDFR created...
...all of this.
Where's Barry?
Just a little bit closer.
I can get him.
Come on, Earl, faster.
- Look at the mangos.
- You mean flamingos.
Flamangos!
There's a bunch of shrimp!
They look like chimpanzees.
- Shrimpanzees!
Those are some
tasty-looking jellyfish!
What's that one over there?
That's just a tomato.
Barry!
Come on!
Chester gave me that BS-USB.
It's really important.
- Shrimpanzee.
- Steve.
- Shove.
Steve.
There's a leek in the boat!
Hold on, everyone.
This ain't gonna be no picnic.
Stop! Get back here!
Keep it steady, Earl.
Watermelophants!
Barry, grab my hand!
Barry!
Freeze, berry man.
Thanks, Earl.
Okay, come here.
You have caused enough trouble
for one day.
Susheep!
Cantalopes.
I can't believe your machine...
...reprogrammed itself to create...
...this entire ecosystem of living food.
How is that even possible?
I have no idea.
Best we don't think about it.
The world should know about this.
Manny, is your camera still working?
Of course. I've been rolling...
- ...since we landed.
- So much for...
...keeping this a secret.
We can't let these friends
tell the world anything.
What we need to do is go there...
...and separate Flint from his friends
so we can manage...
...the situation.
- Champion!
- Brilliant idea.
- Way to go, Chester.
- Thank you.
- Barb, you take care of that weather girl.
- But, sir...
...I'm a scientist.
That's why I need you.
I want the same brilliant mind
that solved the unified field theory...
...to help me help Live Corp.
Consider it done, sir.
Good monkey.
To the Helpicopter.
Oh, Earl.
Pull over there.
- Duck!
- Duck? I love...
Yeah!
You guys, that wasn't so bad.
Yeah, well, be thankful
we didn't run into a...
Cheespider!
Run!
Cheesy. Cheesy. Cheesy.
Manny!
Wait for me!
I'm glad you still wearing
that diaper.
I wish I brought a fresh one!
Hey, guys! Down this alley!
Oh, no! Dead end.
Ghost man?
Greetings, and namaste.
- Chester V! You're here!
- That's right...
...young Lockwood.
And by the looks of things...
...just in time.
One minute later, and we
would have been food for that food.
Flint, I thought you said you were
going to complete this mission alone.
Can I say something?
Apparently you can.
This is Barb, my number two.
Why are you carrying...
...a strawberry in
your backpack, miss?
Stand back, everyone!
Hey, hey, hey, stop.
You're scaring him.
Scaring him?
Oh, please, it's probably
got a mouth full of fangs.
Now you're scaring me.
I've been carrying him
and he hasn't hurt anyone.
I'm sorry. Are you a scientist?
- Matter of fact, I am.
- She's a meteorologist.
Meteorology. Oh, I love it.
The science of smiling and having
pretty hair while you point at a map.
- It's a very important job...
- Meteorology is...
- ...a comprehensive analysis...
- Ladies, ladies. Please.
I'm sure we can all agree
that one of you is a scientist.
Young Lockwood...
...why was your lady friend carrying this
rabid little strawberry in her backpack?
Why is the strawberry guy in
the backpack? Well, that's funny.
It's... You know what he did?
He... He ate the BS-USB.
Not the BSUSB.
I'm on it.
She's got a knife!
If you touch a leaf on his head...
Step away from the berry, madam.
That orange hairy lady
scared the jam out of him!
N-woo?
Oh, no, it's jammed.
- Lick. Lick. Lick.
- Oh, thanks, Steve.
Young Lockwood.
The world could've been destroyed...
...because of the actions
of one sinister strawberry.
We cannot allow any more mistakes
like this.
It won't...
...be long before
those malicious melons...
...pernicious pickles...
...and belligerent burgers
learn to swim...
...and make their way...
...to the mainland.
What is...
...your plan?
I need to get back to my lab so I can...
...make contact with the FLDSMDFR.
- Brilliant!
- I'll lead the way.
No, we'll lead the way.
Safe, safe, safe.
I believe my Sentinels of Safety...
...are better equipped to lead us
in their robe-suits.
N-woo?
"I'll be back...
...before supper."
What a bunch of baloney.
Just leave me on the boat
without any food.
I know a place where
I can get something to eat.
There she is.
Home sweet home.
What?
There's no sardines?
Had to be looters.
Vintage Baby Brent.
Oh, chum.
No, no!
Yeah.
I like them too. I do. I love them.
Mine. No, no. Mine.
Off. Off. Mine.
No, no, mine. Mine. Off.
Hey, hey, hey. Easy, you guys.
Come on, you could lose an eye.
Look, I tell you what. You want more
sardines? I can get you more sardines.
Hey, thanks for loaning me
these skinny jeans, Flint.
- Those aren't skinny jeans.
- Nope.
My feet are turning purple.
Is that bad?
Bananostrich!
Go, go, go! Come on, Brent!
Banana! Banana! Banana!
That bunch of bananostriches
nearly split us.
Are you okay?
Oh, my gosh.
My house!
Home, home, home!
Oh, my gosh.
Your lab!
Oh, crap balls.
We can't go up there, Flint Lockwood.
That dangly, upsy-downsy lab's
not to code.
I've got to, if I'm gonna find
the FLDSMDFR.
We can do it. Those...
...load-bearing vines will be able
to support a small team.
Onwards and upwards!
Right, sir. To the lab!
Sentinels, keep the locals safe.
I'll keep them safe.
Hey, guys! Where you going?
Guys! Hey...
...wait for me!
A little help?
Spooky.
Spooky is right, Steve.
I say...
...this laboratory of yours
is a wonder of engineering.
Really?
Thank you, sir.
Initiating backup power.
Welcome, Flint.
Whoa, my computer's dead.
The fate of the world is depending
on us. Think, Lockwood.
Well, if I could pull...
...the hard drive, there's enough
equipment in this...
...lab that I could build
a tracking device.
Flint!
I say, young Lockwood,
what extraordinary...
...underpants.
Thank you, sir. They're
my Wedgie-proof underwear.
I invented them when I was 6.
I had no idea we were so alike.
Except I invented mine...
...when I was 3.
You guys have been wearing the same
underwear since you were kids?
- Yes!
Excuse me.
How do you expect us
to get the hard drive...
...with all that electrified water?
We dangle!
Come, Lockwood, give the monkey
your underpants.
What?
Lay on...
...young Lockwood.
Yes!
You know, hanging from
my underpants in this space...
...brings back so many memories.
I too built my lab up high...
...to keep the bullies out!
You were...
You were bullied too?
Absolutely.
People like us...
...are always bullied.
Sometimes I wish I'd kept
my bullies around.
Really?
So I could crush them
with my success.
Just like you did with that man-baby.
You mean Brent?
Sure, he used to be a bully,
but he's my friend now.
Friend?
A bully can never be your friend.
- Never?
- Remember...
...the ancient Chinese proverb:
"Stew offered by a bully
is poisoned broth."
Wow, stew.
I have so much to learn.
Mission accomplished!
Indeed, young Lockwood. Indeed.
Help!
Help! Come on, guys. Get me ou...!
You okay, Earl?
My chest hairs
have been tingling all day.
Don't worry. Live Corp Sentinels...
...have danger-sensing fibers
built into their chest plates.
Bravo, Lockwood.
With luck, we'll survive the night.
Sounds like midnight snacks.
Dr. Manny! This is delicious!
I call it Manny's Gorilla Stew.
So how do you make a gorilla stew?
You keep it waiting for two hours.
Hey, guys. Oh, that smells good.
Hey, Flint! Wanna try some of this
special stew? I saved you a bowl.
It's killer.
Killer stew.
No!
Thank you...
...Brent.
Ever since that ghost man
showed up...
- ...Flint Lockwood's been acting...
- Jerky.
He rejected my stew.
No one has ever rejected my stew.
I'm gonna go talk to him.
- Flint, wait up.
- Yeah, Sam?
Is something wrong?
Yeah, we blew a fuse.
You blew a fuse.
Why are you being so weird
to your friends?
What? I haven't been weird.
You karate-chopped...
...Manny's stew out of Brent's hands.
You hurt their feelings.
Sam, you wouldn't understand.
I do understand,
but you're forgetting that:
"A bully turned friend
will be friend to the end."
Listen, Brent came here to help you.
We all did.
And you're acting like
we're just in your way.
Remember, we work together.
That weather girl is ruining our plan.
I just need more time, sir.
We don't have more time.
If we don't get the FLDSMDFR
in the next 48 hours...
...we'll miss our deadline
to release Food Bar 8.0.
I'll be a laughingstock!
Sir, let me handle this.
Never send a monkey
to do Chester work.
I'll take care of it.
Okay, guys, we're here.
Hey, hey, hey!
That is not for you.
All right, let's get to it.
Okay.
You got this, right?
Okay. Then you wanna put
one of these on there, like that.
No, no, no.
No, don't eat that. That's bad.
You'll hurt yourself.
Hey, hey, easy! Stop picking
on your brother, will you?
How would you like it
if he was shoving you?
Okay, now watch.
Are you watching?
One and two and three!
Catch the big one!
Yeah, good, huh?
It's called fishing.
Out on my boat
With a pickle that likes dill
The frowny one's sour
He's a real bitter pill
She's so sweet
With her onion pet Pearl
Teaching pickles to fish
That's my crazy world
I tell you, if only Flint liked fishing
as much as you guys.
Why am I talking to a pickle?
Dangerous food creatures detected.
Stay put. We'll find and destroy them.
Barry!
You can't be here.
You better hide him.
Okay, gang! Today's the day...
...We find the FLDSMDFR.
Sam, I was thinking about
what you said last night...
N-woo?
What?
Me too.
Right. Listen, I have...
...been acting weird, but it's only because
I'm under a lot of pressure.
- N-woo?
- What?
So true!
But I'm also doing this for us.
You see...
...I still want Sparkswood
to happen, but it can't.
Not until I become a great inventor
like Chester V.
Flint, you don't have to
prove anything...
Lockwood! How goes the inventing?
Very good, sir. I was up all night
making this.
I call it the Flint Lockwood
Food Jungle...
...Topographical Pointing Machine.
- Or...
- The FLFJTPM! Brilliant!
Oh, thank you, sir. Follow the beam,
find the machine.
All I have to do now...
...is cut the leg holes.
Well...
...maybe it's better...
...here.
Great idea, Sam.
And, guys, you can help me by...
Excuse us. Your friends are
distracting you from our mission.
Distracting?
My chest hairs just
don't trust that Chester.
We should be hunting
the FLDSMDFR, not chitchatting.
But, sir, I...
You're heading into the deepest,
darkest part of the jungle.
You need to focus on
saving the world.
Be a hero.
Okay. You're right, sir.
Excellent! Let's go!
Okay, Barry, time to go home now.
Okay. Okay.
Okay, one more hug, Barry.
Barry?
Right! Barry.
You Barry.
Barry.
And I'm Sam Sparks.
- Saspa.
- Right! Sam...
- Come on, Sam!
- Coming!
Okay, Barry, time to go home now.
Now go.
Now you go on home.
Bye.
Saspa?
Hot dog. Hot dog.
Tacodile! Supreme!
Holy guacamole!
I got this, bro!
I'm okay!
Up there! Hurry, Sam!
Barb!
You Okay?
Freeze!
Come on, let's go!
Let's get out of here!
Bravo, young Lockwood, bravo!
A mother?
Sam!
Saspa!
Butter.
Parkay.
Almost there.
The FLDSMDFR
should be just across...
...this syrup bog.
- This is syrup?
Syrup is my favorite.
Darn mosquitoasts!
Don't worry, man-baby.
They, like all the other
abominable food monsters...
...will soon be no more.
Wait, Flint!
What if we're making a big mistake?
Mistake?
About shutting off the FLDSMDFR.
Some of these creatures,
they're incredible.
Incredibly...
...dangerous. We were just
attacked by a giant tacodile.
He's right, Sam. I mean, we were
almost eaten by a cheespider.
It doesn't mean we have to
destroy all of them.
Some of the food's
actually been friendly.
It is true. The dessert creatures
are especially sweet.
Okay. Maybe we...
Mosquitoast!
Was gonna bite you.
See? Even the tiniest creatures
are attacking us.
The only reason they're...
...biting is because of the drop
in barometric pressure.
Bugs do that before a storm. And by
the look of those nimbostratus clouds...
Miss Sparks, we are...
...not talking about the weather.
We are talking about food here.
Dangerous food that does not
have human emotion.
Food that is not friendly.
- Food that cannot love!
- Flint...
...we should be studying
the food animals, not killing them.
What if he's wrong?
The choice is yours, son.
Live up to your full potential...
...or walk away
and let the food monsters...
...destroy Lady Liberty.
Sam, finding that FLDSMDFR...
...and saving the world...
...that's what matters.
Really? Our opinion doesn't matter?
Of course it does!
Yes! Yes, it matters.
But just not right now.
- Wrong answer.
- Toast.
Yeah? Well, I guess
this doesn't matter either...
...young Lockwood.
I'll just...
...see you back on the boat.
Wait! Sam!
Wait, please!
No! No. Sam! Come back!
Come back, Sam, no!
No, Sam!
Sam! Sam!
Sam!
Hey, Earl, would you talk to her?
You bet I will.
Hey, Sam! Wait for me!
Goodbye, Senor Lockwood.
Bye, Flint.
Steve!
Et tu, Steve?
What just happened?
You've made...
...the right choice, son.
Sentinels! Keep them safe.
Butter.
Young Lockwood...
...we're getting close.
I feel it in my beard!
Water goes in the top...
...and food comes out the bottom.
It's gotta be inside that
big rock candy mountain!
This is exactly why I wanted you
on this mission.
Sally forth, Lockwood.
I can't believe Flint
is still listening to that guy!
Flint is naive. It appears
he is being manipulated...
...for some nefarious purpose.
Of course he is!
Sam! Freeze!
What?
Stay calm and walk toward me...
...slowly.
Very slowly.
Oh, come on.
Now you're acting weird.
I'm in no mood for this.
Stop right there, cheese monster!
Nobody eats my friends...
...on my watch!
No, wait! Chester's been lying to us...
...about these creatures,
and I am going to prove it.
Sam, don't do it!
It's foodicide!
Danger! Danger! Danger!
Nice cheespider.
- Yellow.
- Dude!
You got special-sauced!
It's okay, guys. See?
She's not mean. She's just...
...a little beefy.
What's it doing?
I think she wants you
to scratch her buns.
I like that too.
Who's a good cheespider?
She's cute!
But why did she attack us before?
Because we were dressed...
...like them.
She doesn't like backpacks?
No. It appears she...
...doesn't like Live Corp.
The food creatures know something...
...we do not.
Gasp!
Who's Evel?
Not "Evel." Evil.
I knew it! Chester's
up to something terrible.
We have to warn Flint!
Let's ride!
Run!
You're not warning...
...anyone about anything.
Oh, crap balls.
Magnificent.
The FLDSMDFR...
...must be up there.
A very unpleasant fall.
Finish the job, Lockwood.
Yes, sir.
Made it!
FLDSMDFR.
Look, I'm sorry I have to
do this to you...
...again.
But I can't let your swimming
cheespiders destroy Lady Liberty...
...or the world.
Marshmallow.
They're like...
...a family.
Sam was right.
This is a mistake.
Oh, dear!
- Sir! Sir?
- There it is.
- Wait.
- In all its glory.
Chester, look, I can't do this.
Oh, okay. I will.
What? Wait.
Chester, wait. We can't destroy it.
Let go of me, Lockwood.
No, sir, I can't let you do this.
No! No! No!
Live Corp.
The BS-USB...
...reprogrammed it?
It was never gonna
turn off the machine.
A BS-USB? Hello.
Your machine is what I wanted
all along.
You lied to me.
Of course I lied to you.
I knew you'd eventually fall
for these pathetic creatures.
But you were my idol.
My whole life, I looked up to you.
I wanted to be you!
Oh, Lockwood. I was just using you...
...to get your invention.
We're ready.
Launch Operation Slice and Dice.
And now that I've got what I want,
I no longer need you.
I'm afraid we're going to have to
let you go.
Wait, wait, wait. No, no, please.
That's not natural.
No, no, no.
Easy, easy, you guys. Don't cry.
Okay, Steve. If me and you put
our two brilliant minds together...
...we will get out of here.
- Steve?
- Brent, do you ever get...
...the feeling that maybe Steve Lockwood
is just a monkey?
Why would you say that
about him, Earl?
Why would you ever say that?
Of course he's just a monkey.
How stupid are you people?
No one should ever put
any trust in a monkey.
Chester thinks you're a monkey.
Well, I'm an ape. Chester knows that.
But he calls you a monkey.
It is true, he does.
He's just joking around.
Chester's my best friend.
If Chester was really your friend...
...would he still call you a monkey?
N-woo! N-woo!
Flint.
Dad.
What's happening, son?
You look terrible.
- What's with all of them?
- They saved my life.
I let Chester steal the machine and now
he's starting Operation Slice and Dice.
Come on, son. You're really
not making any sense.
Look, Chester's gonna wipe out
all the foodimals.
My friends tried to...
...tell me they were good,
but I didn't listen.
Everything I touch just gets ruined.
- N-woo!
- Barry?
N-woo!
Barry. I'm so sorry I misjudged you.
I should have listened to Sam.
- Saspa. Sam.
- What is it? What are you trying to say?
Saspa, Saspa.
Saspa!
Saspa.
- Sassy pants.
- Dad.
Saspa, Saspa!
Sam and the gang?
It looks like a Sentinel of Safety.
Sassy pants.
Sassy pants? No, Dad. He's saying
Sentinels captured Sam and the gang.
- And they're being held in the factory?
- We gotta get them out of there.
But how? There's just two of us.
N-woo!
- N-woo!
- N-woo! N-woo!
N-woo!
Hey, what's with all the "N-woos"?
Why do they have my TV?
Water goes in the top
and food comes out the bottom.
N-woo! N-woo!
What's it, broken or something?
What's it doing?
N-woo!
Here, you take it, you take it.
N-woo.
- It's saying that I'm N-woo.
- N-woo.
N-woo. N-woo.
- Look, Flint, they came here to help.
We all did. It's time to let us.
Okay, I don't know
if you can understand me.
- I know you think I'm N-woo.
But the truth is I'm no N-woo...
...I'm just a man.
A man who's made a lot of mistakes
in the last couple of days.
And now my friends are in
a lot of trouble, thanks to me.
Someone once told me
that I didn't need friends.
That I could accomplish more
by myself.
I know now more than ever...
...that he was wrong.
We need all the friends we can get.
And I need your help.
All of you. Fruits...
...vegetables and meat!
I need you to help me
to get into that...
...factory, save our friends...
...and get our home back!
Okay, now I just gotta figure out...
...how to get in there.
With the right rod and tackle,
I could cast you up...
...into that unfinished part
of the factory.
Should be a piece of cake.
Dad, let's go fishing.
Wildebeets!
Meatballrus! Go, go, go!
Watermelophant, do your thing!
Spray-On Shoes.
Hair Un-Balder.
Grocery Deliverator.
Helmet.
Got it.
Ready when you are, Dad!
Ready, skipper, my boy.
It's too heavy!
Here comes the cavalry.
No way! Subs!
- Subwhales!
Prepare to release lure.
Hit it, Sweet.
Catch the big one, buddy.
Yes!
We have a problem.
N-woo, in here.
What's going on?
Sam's backpack.
They were here!
Good cheespider.
Saspa?
Got it, Barry.
Thanks, cheespider.
N-woo!
Barry, use the Grocery Deliverator
to save your friends.
I'll go save mine.
There's a leek in my boat.
Flint!
Go, go, go!
Hey...
...freeze!
Food fight!
Crab cakes!
Run!
I'm all cheesed up.
Retreat!
Head scan complete.
Lockwood?
You're still alive?
That's right. Hands up.
Give me back my friends.
Of course! I have them right here.
Hey, Flint.
Sam! Guys!
Chester, let them go!
Don't worry, Lockwood,
I'll let them go.
Right into my super-sized
Food Bar machine.
Food Bars?
Food Bars? You're going to
turn them into Food Bars?
Yes, Food Bars.
The lifeblood of my company.
I learned your FLDSMDFR food
is far more delicious than "food" food.
So using your foodimals
as ingredients...
...would make my products
super-delicious!
I had to have your invention.
Unfortunately, I couldn't find it.
Until you helped me.
FLDSMDFR!
Watermelon!
You're a monster!
Those are living creatures.
Yes, that's the problem.
Food with legs
is much harder to catch.
They hide, they fight back,
they want to live.
But now that I control
your FLDSMDFR...
...I can pave your island
and work in complete secrecy.
Live Corp will remain...
...the coolest, hippest company
in the world...
...with a new Food Bar version...
...8.0!
I never should have believed in you.
Yes, that was quite foolish.
Now if you want your friends back,
I suggest you drop your cans.
Don't do it, Flint! Save the island!
But you are my island.
Okay, first, shut up.
Then drop the cans
or I drop your friends.
Okay, okay. There.
Oh, no, Flint. This is embarrassing.
I changed my mind.
Please understand
I can't leave any witnesses.
Barb, grind them.
- But, sir, I didn't think we were going to...
- This is why I work alone.
Monkey!
You are dismissed.
And now, without...
...further ado...
Flint, hurry!
Why won't this go faster?
- Give me that controller!
- Sure, come and get it.
But which one of us has it?
Is it me?
Or me?
Earl...
...can't you break us out of here?
Yellow police tape!
The one thing I can't break.
Forkenknifenspooninator!
Sam, guys, listen.
Invisible coffee table!
I'm sorry I was such an idiot.
Flint, that's true...
...but now may not be the time!
Please let me finish.
I took you all for granted.
I should have listened to you.
Okay, go on. But hurry!
The truth is I need each
and every one of you guys.
You're more than my friends.
You're my family.
How sweet. Note to self:
put that on their tombstones.
Good one, Chester!
Don't you see, young Lockwood?
These friends are the reason
you keep losing.
Well, it's better than ending up
alone like you.
I'm not alone!
I've got holograms!
Flint! Why don't you throw him
a party?
We love parties.
Party?
Party!
Party's over, Lockwood.
No!
Not yet.
I think it's time to celebrate!
No!
Celebrate!
Yes!
- Thanks, lab partner.
- Helping!
Guys, I'm...
...so sorry for being such a...
- Chester!
- Okay, I guess I deserve that.
No, Flint! Chester!
I've got what I want.
Enjoy your friends, Lockwood.
No! No!
Don't do this!
Food!
Anybody gonna be keeping
folks safe in this town, it's me.
Tacodile supreme.
It's over, Chester.
- Mustache!
- Now hand over the FLDSMDFR.
No! Never!
Chester...
...there's nowhere to go.
That's what you think.
Save me, monkey!
Rm an ape!
Bad monkey! Give that back!
Bad monk...!
My holograms! Save me!
We're here for you.
- You're going to be fine.
- We'll save you.
You see, Flint?
With my holograms...
Oh, fudge.
I saved myself.
That will leave a bad taste
in your mouth.
I believe this belongs to you.
Here you go, pal.
Gosh, I hope this works.
Pickle.
Cheeseburger.
Leek. Strawberry. Lemon.
- Yes!
- Banana.
It's enough to make a grown man cry.
And that's okay.
You go right ahead, tear.
Guys...
...do you think we could still
work together?
I think we will work great together.
Come on, bring it on in, Barb.
This is nice.
Ape!
Monkey.
I'm proud of you, son.
Thanks, Dad.
But there's one last thing
I need to do.
Okay, now, son.
Now, once you put it on like that...
...all you have to do is cast it.
So like this?
No, no, no.
Here, let me show you how.
See, it's all in the wrist. Like this.
Catch the big one, boy.
- Am I fishing?
- Yup.
I'm fishing!
You've got a live one.
Now reel him in, Flint.
That's it. Steady, steady.
He's a fighter!
I got one!
- I got one, Dad!
- Okay.
Can we do this again?
Like all the time?
You betcha, skipper.
Sam, guys, I caught my first fish!
Way to go, Flint!
Flint Lockwood, you are a fisherman.
Happy.
Hey, look, rainbows!
Strawberry.
Hi, Steve.
Hello, Steven. I'm Barb.
So do you wanna
go get coffee sometime?
Dinner!
Even better!