[EXPLOSION]
[MAN] Micky, can you hear me?
Can you hear me?
[GIRL] Micky!
Try not to move.
Blink for "yes"
if you understand me.
I am Dr Muller.
I operated on you.
Do you remember
what happened to you?
Nothing at all?
Micky, that's your name.
Do you remember?
Are you in pain?
[SCREAMS]
Shh. It's OK.
[SOBS]
[MICKY] When can I see myself?
[WOMAN] You suffered
severe cranial fractures.
You required major reconstruction
to your face and jaw.
But you were lucky.
The tissue damage
could have been far more severe.
OK?
Oh, my God.
Who am I?
[WOMAN] Your name is?
My name is Michelle Deane, Micky.
How old are you?
I'm 20 years old.
- Where do you live?
- London.
You make me say the same
stupid things over and over every day.
I can't stand it.
I want to get out of here.
You lost your parents aged nine.
In a car accident. You were unharmed.
Your Aunt Elinor
took care of you after that.
You spent your holidays
in the south of France.
Remember her?
- Where is she now?
- She passed away just before the fire.
So I'm alone.
No, you have many friends.
This is Julia, your aunt's PA.
She's known you
since you were a child.
Do you recognise her?
And these are some of your friends.
Do you remember them?
No.
[MICKY] Am I going away?
Who's taking me?
[WOMAN] Julia, your guardian.
Micky.
Let me look at you.
Do you remember me?
No.
But I want to.
I've come to take you home.
[HORNS BLARE]
[PNEUMATIC DRILL]
[POLICE SIREN]
When your parents died, your Aunt
Elinor asked me to look after you.
Whenever you weren't at school,
you stayed with me.
[JULIA] Do you remember
anything at all?
[MICKY] Just flashes.
- Like what?
- People, places.
I don't know who they are.
Sometimes I just see fire.
One of your aunt's many houses.
How bad was I when you found me?
The injuries on your face were so bad,
I thought you were dead.
[PHONE RINGING]
Hello? It's Jake.
I hear she's back.
[JULIA SIGHS]
- She's really not ready yet.
- Well, is she there?
I'll tell her you called.
Goodbye, Jake.
[JULIA HANGS UP]
I don't know
if I'm remembering or imagining.
Was he my boyfriend?
Jake? One of them.
- There was more than one?
- Of course!
- You were irresistible.
- Not any more.
- Who's this girl?
- Domenica, Do.
- Who is she?
- A friend.
Her mother was
your aunt's housekeeper.
- Can we call her?
- I don't think that's a good idea.
What about my other friends?
Your real friends will understand
that you need time.
What do you mean?
When you're 21,
you will inherit Elinor's entire estate.
- You should have told me.
- I'm sorry. I thought you knew.
I know nothing.
When are you going to realise?
- I don't even know who you are!
- I'm your friend.
I'm sorry.
Are you all right?
Yeah.
Yeah. Come on.
6 Fitzroy Square, please.
Micky!
I wasn't expecting to see you.
Why didn't you call?
Well, this is a surprise.
Please, sit down.
Tell me how you're doing.
Who are you?
I'm James Chance.
I was your aunt's lawyer.
I handle all Elinor's business.
Yes, this must be confusing for you.
I got sent a letter from this address.
This is from Jake.
He works here.
Micky, does Julia know you're here?
Please, let me call her.
You shouldn't be out
on your own so soon.
I'm all right. Thank you.
Jake.
It is Jake?
Micky.
It's great to see you.
What are you doing here?
Looking for you.
- I tried to get in touch.
- I know.
It's nice to meet you.
- I heard about everything and...
- Yeah.
My memory.
What are you doing now, Micky?
Do you want to go somewhere
and talk, get a drink?
Er...
What about my place?
OK.
Last time I saw you, you said
you never wanted to see me again.
I'm glad you changed your mind.
Yeah, well,
I only have your word for it.
So, I hear we were lovers.
On and off.
I used to have some keys to your flat.
- You should have them.
- Let me see.
- Where is it?
- Narpin Road.
Hoxton.
You can stay here if you want.
You look like a stranger to me.
I have nothing to go on.
Just how I feel.
[WINCES]
[JULIA] Do you remember
anything at all?
[MICKY] Just flashes.
People, places.
- My name is Michelle Deane, Micky.
- [WOMAN] How old are you?
I'm 21 years old.
- Where do you live?
- London. You make me say
the same stupid things
over and over every day.
Do you remember anything else?
I remember what you've told me.
[MICKY CRIES OUT IN PAIN]
- What is it?
- Oh, it still... It still hurts.
- Don't stop, it's OK.
- OK. Don't make me laugh.
[MICKY LAUGHS]
Was I unfaithful?
Probably.
That was crap of me. I'm sorry.
I know...
But I suppose you're worth it.
You should have told me to fuck off.
Tell me about Do.
She always got in the way.
Ah, you were jealous.
I was, yes.
What do you mean, "was"?
What changed?
Sorry?
You said you were jealous.
Why not now?
Julia didn't tell you?
What?
Micky, I'm sorry.
Do died in the fire.
Micky, what did they tell you?
I'd like some water.
Micky!
Wait!
Micky! Micky!
Dear Do
It's nice to talk to you
after, well, too many years.
It's a deep regret of mine
that I lost touch with you.
Elinor.
[DO] May 6th.
Today my life began again.
Excuse me.
Micky!
It's Do,
from our holidays in France.
Do!
Oh, my God!
I can't believe it.
I'm so pleased to see you.
- Have you been in London long?
- A year. I work in a bank.
I'm so pleased to see you too.
Listen, what are you doing now?
Do you want to get a coffee or a drink?
I can't. I've got to get back.
OK, um...
- Well, tonight, are you free?
- Yeah.
Yeah? OK.
Look, I'll give you my number.
Will you promise me you'll call me?
- Yeah.
- OK.
- Tonight, then.
- Tonight.
- It's so good to see you.
- You too.
Hey, this is Micky.
Please leave a message.
Micky.
I thought you'd forgotten.
Where?
No, no, I don't know it.
But I can find it.
Yeah, OK. OK.
Yeah, bye. Bye.
[♪ JAMES BLAKE: "LINDISFARNE II"]
[BUZZER]
Hey. Come in. Come in.
I'm sorry. I lost track of time.
- Cheers. Did you find it OK?
- Yeah.
- Yeah? Oh, hang on.
- [PHONE RINGS]
Hello?
Yeah.
No. No, now's not good.
I know.
I know, but something came up.
Yeah.
I'm sorry. I was taking photographs.
I have a deadline.
I have to finish them tonight.
I'll call you soon, OK?
- I shouldn't drink when I'm working.
- Do you want me to leave?
No, you can sleep here if you like.
[♪ THE CHEMICAL BROTHERS: "SWOON"]
You came!
You look gorgeous.
Look at you.
- Do you want to come for a dance?
- Um... yeah.
OK, one, two, three...
Cheers.
- Hey.
- This is Jake. He's my lawyer.
- Oh, really?
I thought I was
the song-and-dance man.
Hi.
I'm Domenica, Do.
So you're the long-lost friend?
I hate my hair. I want to cut it all off.
Do you remember that game?
If there was one thing
you could change about yourself...
- Most guys want to be better endowed.
- Go and get drinks.
All right?
Come here.
So, what would you change, Do?
- Gosh, I don't know where to start.
- I think I'd change my nose.
I'd like one like yours.
God, it's been so long.
We were really close.
- Do you remember?
- Yeah. I kept all the photos.
- Really?
- They're at my flat.
No way.
I could go get them, if you like.
- What, now?
- Yeah. Why not?
- That's crazy.
- You'll still be here, right?
Clapham, please.
You can't get rid of me that easily.
[♪ CAT'S EYES:
"THE BEST PERSON I KNOW"]
[DO] Anywhere here is fine, thanks.
- [DO] Wait here.
- [MICKY] No, I want to come with you.
[DO] No, no, no, no.
It's a terrible place, really. Wait.
[MICKY] I'm coming up.
[MICKY] Ah!
What happened to you after?
We moved back to England.
My mother got a job
in the West Country,
miles from anywhere.
And I came up to London
after she died.
I'm sorry you had to go away.
Are you still in touch with your dad?
He killed himself.
I'm so...
I'm sorry. I've...
I've been rubbish.
I should have tried harder
to stay in touch.
It's all right.
Look at that.
Micky, stop! I can't swim!
I can't swim!
Do! Let go!
Let go. I can't breathe.
- Micky, it's too deep!
- Don't!
Let go!
Let go! I can't breathe!
[MICKY] I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
Micky, what have you done?
- Do!
- [MICKY] I'm sorry! I'm sorry.
- I didn't mean it!
- [DO] It's all right. I'm fine.
Micky! Micky!
Micky!
- Please! Why can't I stay?
- Do!
Micky!
- Micky!
Do! Don't leave me!
- Where are you going?
- Oh, I have to go to work.
- Don't go.
- But I've got to pay my rent.
Yeah? You can move in with me.
OK, yeah, but I told you
I can't talk right now, so...
Yeah, OK, listen...
No, I'll give you a call back later.
But I have to go now. OK.
Bye.
My aunt. She doesn't even pretend
to like me any more.
She always calls at the wrong time.
And I'm going to be late again.
Have you seen my bag? OK.
- I'll see you tonight.
- Bye.
[PHONE RINGS]
- Hello?
- Hello? Micky?
No, it...
Elinor.
Hi. It's Do,
Domenica Law.
Do? Oh, my goodness!
How long have you been
in touch with Micky?
Um... Oh, just a few days.
I see.
- Elinor?
- Yes, I'm here.
Listen, I'll get Micky to call you.
It's so good
to speak to you again.
Good evening, Do.
What do you mean?
It's all right. Don't worry.
- I need to go.
- No, please, Do.
You're Micky now.
Please, let me go.
[JULIA] It's our secret.
Do? Do?
[DO] Today my life began again.
[JULIA] It's our secret.
[DO] Monday, May...
We sat in her apartment together
for the rest of the afternoon.
Nobody understands what we share.
Saturday June 2nd.
She doesn't need him.
She only needs me.
Nobody understands me like she does.
I'd love to be like her.
She only needs me.
Nobody understands what we share.
Can't sleep here, love.
Upstairs, through the double doors,
first on the left.
Please vacate your room by 12,
Miss Law.
- What did you call me?
- Miss Law.
Isn't it?
[DO] Today was another glorious day.
[♪ CRYSTAL FIGHTERS: "AT HOME"]
I can't believe she wants
to spend so much time with me.
It looks OK.
Nobody understands me like she does.
Nobody knows what we share.
Bye. Don't hate me.
Sorry I'm late, babe.
I'll call you, Do, OK?
See you.
[MOANING]
Hi.
[MICKY] Ohh!
Thanks.
[MOANING]
Nobody knows what we share.
Yeah, fine.
[ELINOR] Dear Do.
A small something.
I hope it helps.
Elinor.
[DO] Dear Elinor.
It was so wonderful to talk to you
after all this time
and I was so delighted
to receive your letter.
I felt so stupid after your call
because I wanted to say so much,
but I just didn't know
where to start.
And I can give you news of Micky.
She's so busy
she doesn't have the opportunity
to write as much as she'd like to.
How's that for you?
[ELINOR] My dearest Do,
thank you for your kind
and considerate letter.
It was such a pleasant surprise
to hear your voice
after so many years.
You look good.
[♪ JOKER: "THE VISION"]
Lighten up.
- Oh, are you guys going?
- Bye, see you later.
I'm sorry, madam.
Have you got another card?
I'll do it.
- Don't be stupid, you're broke.
- Oh, is that why he never pays?
- Am I hearing this?
- It's just something I've picked up on.
You're the fucking parasite.
- How can you say that?
- Well, why do you put up with it?
You don't give a shit about money
but your friends are obsessed with it.
What's wrong with you?
Do you know what?
I need to go.
Jake!
Next time it would be nice
to see you without her around.
Get off.
[♪ CRYSTAL FIGHTERS: "FOLLOW"]
- Are you happy now?
- I'm sorry.
- You always say you're sorry.
You say it too much.
I love you.
Do you?
Do you really?
Is this what you want?
- Get off me.
- Is that what you want, Do?
Get off.
Happy now?
Get out!
Dear Elinor, I told you
I'd write with news of Micky.
She certainly lives her life to the full,
maybe too much sometimes.
She and her crowd stay out all night
most of the time.
I can't pretend
I don't worry about her sometimes.
Hopefully I'll get to meet you soon
and I'll be able to thank you in person
for all those precious summers.
With warmest best wishes, Do.'
What happened?
The diary entries just stop.
If I'm Do, then why did you tell me
I was Micky?
I arrived the morning
after one of your fights.
I could see it in your face.
It was clear you'd crossed a line.
There was no going back.
You just didn't realise it.
Elinor's health has taken a turn
for the worse since you last saw her.
She's very ill in hospital.
I'm sorry, but they give her
no more than a few weeks.
She wants you to visit her
in France right away.
Both of you.
Do, please pack a bag.
- No, don't listen to her, Do.
- She wants to see Do too.
- You can't just order her around.
- Pack your bag, please.
I'm not going. She hates me.
- You bitch!
- Micky!
Micky, stop it!
Micky!
I'm just going to go to the bathroom.
I don't believe you.
Because your mind is blocking it out.
I'm not Do.
I don't feel like her.
Do died in the accident.
[DO] Thank you for inviting me.
So... what do you want
to talk to me about?
I thought you needed cheering up.
No, I'm fine.
What, living under Micky's shadow?
- Well, I wouldn't say that.
- Sorry.
I was just reminded
of how it was for me.
I don't know
how I put up with it for so long.
- First Elinor and then Micky.
- You two don't get on, do you?
No. Micky is irresistible.
But she's destroying herself.
Be careful you don't end up getting hurt.
I'm her friend.
So she won't hurt me.
No, you're probably right.
Just a little warning.
I've read your letters to Elinor.
- You've read my letters?
- Sorry. It's part of my job.
- How dare you?
- Do...
I know why you returned
the cheque to Elinor.
You mustn't feel ashamed.
I really don't think
this was such a good idea.
I just think it is so unfair.
Why do we not get
the life we deserve?
When I was 18, I was working
in one of Elinor's factories
and she saw something in me.
She offered me everything.
Then along came Micky.
Deep down you're just like me.
You know you should have a better life.
[JULIA] Persuade Micky
to come to the south of France.
It will be the best for both of you.
I've...
I've moved back to my own flat.
Now, when you both get there,
give me a call.
I can help you.
[DOORBELL]
- Pack your bags.
- What?
You need your swimsuit
and your passport.
Passport?
I thought maybe we could go
to the south of France.
I need a break
and we could see Elinor.
- Yeah, but I thought you...
- Yeah, I changed my mind.
Look, she'd love you to come
and we can fly to Paris, hire a car,
take the scenic route.
Come on.
I'll help you pack.
[♪ PAULINE CROZE: "T'ES BEAU"]
I just hate myself when I'm with her,
the way she makes me act.
Why do you put up with it, then?
Oh...
It's complicated.
Julia brought me up as much as anyone.
At a certain point,
Elinor just gave up on me.
Change the music, DJ.
So, what did Jake say
about us coming away?
- Haven't spoken to him.
- Are you going to stay with him?
If he wants me enough.
[♪ METRONOMY: "THE BAY"]
[DO] You must be shattered.
Pull in here.
- Will this do?
- [DO LAUGHS]
WOW!
Christ, if you'd driven a few more feet,
we would have...
Shit!
WOW!
Come on.
- She's ready.
- Thank you.
Hello, Elinor.
Hi, Elinor.
It's Do, Elinor.
I'm not Micky.
I'm Micky. I'm here.
Bonjour.
You must be Do.
- Bonjour.
- Ca va?
She's sleeping.
- Micky! Ca va?
- Yvette! Comment ca va?
- Ca va bien?
- Ca va bien.
I'm pleased to see you.
Do, come on.
Let's just dump our stuff here
and go straight to the beach.
Kick your feet.
Arms out.
[PHONE RINGS]
Hello.
I'm not going to call again
so please listen.
I just want you to be honest with
yourself about what you want.
I want her.
She's ruined your life once already.
Micky told your mother
about your father's affair with Elinor.
Surely that must have something
to do with why he committed suicide.
Micky!
Don't leave me!
[CRYING]
She'll never love you
in the way you want her to.
It's not in her nature.
Now, listen carefully to me.
This is what you have to do.
You were gone ages yesterday.
I went to the beach.
Was there any action in the village?
Party central.
Right, it's empty.
- My turn.
- No, no, no.
Shit.
- Is everything OK?
- Yes, thank you.
I'll do it.
[MICKY] Do?
What took you so long?
I gave up on you. Anything wrong?
No. It's just the sun.
It's knocked me out.
[SCREAMS]
[SOBS]
[♪ NOUVELLE VAGUE: "LOVE WILL TEAR US APART"]
I wish the sun
would just stop right there,
not move any more.
[SIGHS] Then I'd just lay
like this forever.
What about you, Do?
Do you think about the future?
Gosh, it's too hot
to think about anything.
I don't want to think about it either.
Do you want to go out tonight?
There's a party on some guy's boat.
- What guy? A friend?
- I don't know. It's just some guy.
You should learn to swim.
[FRENCH BOY] Come on.
Let's go to the boat! Come on!
- We go to the boat. You come?
- Yeah. Are you coming?
[DO] Er, I thought you had a big boat.
- Well, that's his boat.
- Oh.
We don't need to bring her, do we?
[CHEERING AND LAUGHING]
[BOAT ENGINE REVVING]
[CHATTER AND LAUGHTER]
[♪ CRYSTAL CASTLES: "CELESTICA"]
- What are you doing here?
- Micky, I'm sorry.
I've got some bad news
about your aunt.
She passed away yesterday.
C'est fini. Come on.
She's quiet now.
Tell me what to do.
Not here.
On 4th July, your birthday,
you'll go out for dinner,
have a little celebration.
That will seem natural afterwards.
That's the night it will happen.
Your plan will never work.
The fire will cause so much damage
they'll assume it was the boiler.
They'll never discover
the disconnected gas pipe.
If I die, I'll deserve it.
You have to start the fire at 1:00am.
We need to agree a time
so that I can be the first to arrive.
We'll never get away with this.
What about Yvette?
She'll recognise me.
That will be impossible.
We'll go to Switzerland.
They're very discreet.
They have the best surgical facilities.
What are you saying?
You will be Micky.
Do you want me to change my face?
I know.
But it will be worth it.
Sometimes you get a chance,
and if you seize it in that moment,
you can change your life forever.
If you let it slip... it will be gone.
[♪ PETER SARSTEDT:
"WHERE DO YOU GO TO MY LOVELY?"]
Come with me.
[LAUGHING]
- Look.
- Christ, we'll be out of it.
- I've got to drive.
- Just leave the car. Come on.
- All right, just one.
- OK.
Ready?
Right, let's go.
[♪ CASSIUS: "TOOP TOOP"]
No, don't make me...
- Can we leave now?
- It's just getting started.
Really? It's the third time
he's started to tell that story
and it's not getting any funnier.
OK, five minutes.
Please.
OK.
A la tienne!
Come on, get into bed.
[HISSING]
[EXPLOSION]
It worked, better than expected.
Your poor face,
it was unrecognisable after the fall.
But even that worked to our advantage.
- And the amnesia...
- Oh, my God.
What have I done?
How could I have gone through with it?
- Do, calm yourself.
- I'm going to the police.
Why? You've got everything
you ever wanted.
I didn't want this.
- I don't want this.
- The old Micky is gone.
You're Micky now.
And if the lawyer believes you,
as he does,
then everyone will.
We'll go back to Elinor's
in the south of France.
We'll wait for the reading of the will.
Here. You're safe now.
Who are you?
1963 E-Type.
It's a beauty, isn't it?
I'd buy it off you
if I had a spare 100,000 euros.
But, then, you don't need the money.
- Let's get in.
- What do you want?
To tell you a story.
This is a private beach.
I'm going for a swim.
Actually, I'm not here for the sun.
I know what you're here for.
Your friend stopped
at the café.
I got interested
when she wanted to call England.
Excuse me.
I'd like to make a call to London.
- Lost your phone?
- How did you guess?
I listened in.
[JULIA] She's ruined your life
once already.'
[MICKY] What does this have
to do with me?
They've got some sort of a plan.
Against you.
She wrote something on a pad.
[JULIA] Remember.
The upstairs bathroom.
Clarissa.
It's blank.
She presses too hard
when she writes.
It says...
"Clarissa upstairs bathroom."
How much?
A thousand?
Meet me at the tabac,
tomorrow at 11:00.
You were gone for ages yesterday.
I went to the beach.
- Was there any action in the village?
- Party central.
Right, it's empty.
- My turn.
- No, no, no. I'll go.
Do?
What took you so long?
I gave up on you. Anything wrong?
No. It's just the sun.
It's knocked me out.
There's 500.
Where is the rest?
If what you have to say is interesting,
you'll get the rest.
All they have to do is loosen the joint
and in a closed room
with a naked flame...
Where is the rest of my money?
That was the rest.
You're lucky to have a taste of me.
I'm worth much more than that.
I don't need you any more.
You owe me.
You should learn to swim.
- [MICKY] Why should I believe you?
- We had a deal, but you killed her.
So the deal is different
and now I want more money.
Let me go. Please.
You're not in a position to bargain.
How much do you want?
100,000.
100,000?
OK.
Just remember,
one phone call will finish you.
[DR MULLER] Do you remember
what happened to you?'
Micky, that's your name.
Do you remember?
[RECEPTIONIST] Miss Law.
Isn't it?
[DR MULLER] Micky, that's your name.
[JULIA] Good evening, Do.
[MICKY] Who am I?
[JULIA] Domenica... Micky... Do.
We've been found out.
The boy from the cafe,
says he's heard it all.
- How could he?
- I don't know.
Yvette's seen him
snooping around.
What did you tell him?
- Well, I didn't tell him the truth.
- The truth?
I didn't tell him that
you plotted with Do to kill Micky.
Just as well.
Tomorrow is Micky's 21st birthday.
I'm meeting Chance in London
and at last we'll read the will.
[CHANCE] I'm sorry
not to have seen Micky.
The rest is doing her good.
I was surprised that
you were not made an executor,
or a beneficiary, indeed.
Perhaps she'd already made
provision for you.
There's been an arrangement
in place for some time.
A modest pension.
- I didn't tell him the truth.'
- The truth?'
I didn't tell him that
you plotted with Do to kill Micky.
Just...
There had been no change to the will
drafted five years ago,
just this, the last detail,
to be opened on Micky's birthday.
Happy birthday to Micky,
by the way.
- Where's my money?
- You'll get your money.
Let's go for a drive.
It's yours
if you can keep your mouth shut.
You said it's worth 100,000.
You could sell it if you want.
Julia?
Hello? Julia?
Are you there?
Julia?
Is anyone here?
Hello?
The old lady had the last word.
I would never have guessed.
What do you mean?
She left everything to you.
- To me?
- To you.
She left everything to
Domenica Law.
All this for nothing.
- And Micky dead.
- Micky knew, Julia.
No.
No, she knew nothing.
Do, you wouldn't be here
if she'd known.
She...
She would have stopped you.
You can't...
- You can't be Micky!
- It's over.
I recorded you admitting to murder.
I sent the tape to Chance.
Let go! I can't breathe!
I'm so sorry.
Run!
Come with me.
- Come with me!
- No! No!
No!
[SCREAMS]
Run, Micky!
Run!
Do, come with me!
Run! Run!
I'm Micky! I'm Micky!
[SOBBING]
[♪ CRYSTAL FIGHTERS: "AT HOME"]
♪ Remember how I said
I'd come some day, baby
♪ How I said I'd come around
to see you one day
♪ I said I'd try to find a way to run away,
I'd get away some day
♪ Gonna come some day, baby
♪ Gonna fly around the world
to hear you say
♪ I'm gonna fly around the world
to try to find you again and say
♪ I never thought I'd see you again
♪ I never thought
I'd get to be with my best friend
♪ Never thought I'd have
to tell you again
♪ Never thought I'd have to tell you
how I lost my mind again
♪ I left alone
♪ I left the world, I was running
♪ To be by your side
♪ I was dying
♪ Alone by your side
♪ I was flying
♪ I came alone
♪ I've come a long way to get here
♪ The leaves that fall to my feet
♪ At home
♪ They mean nothing to me... ♪