Don't think I don't see you, little one.
I think there's enough
for both of us, though.
Mary.
Fear not,
for you have been favored by God
to conceive and bear a son.
A son?
But how?
The Holy Spirit will overshadow you,
and the child will be called the Son of God.
For nothing is impossible with God.
Thank you.
Do I say thank you? I mean, yes.
Let it be done, just as you say.
Guys! Guys!
You're not gonna believe this!
Okay. You are not gonna believe this,
but I think a new star
just appeared in the sky...
No, no, no.
What have I said
about looking through that thing?
Come on. Wait.
This doesn't happen every day.
There's nothing out there for you, kid.
Things are changing.
That star means something.
And I'm not gonna be here forever.
I love the smell of freshly
ground grain in the morning.
Kid, your unemployed bird friend's here.
Dave!
- Hey, pal.
- What's new out there today?
You know, not a whole lot.
I mean, it's Nazareth.
That rooster on Fifth Street overslept again.
And, that horse...
What is his name? Jeremiah? Hezekiah?
There's an "iah" in there. I know that.
He lost a shoe.
And then, well...
I mean, it's barely worth mentioning,
but the royal caravan is rolling
through town today.
What? The royal caravan?
- Are you kidding?
- No, buddy! For real!
I spotted them outside of town
and had to come straight here to tell you.
Today's the day we've been waiting for.
Nazareth can kiss my gleaming
white tail feathers good-bye.
See? I told you that star was a sign.
We're meant for something greater than this.
This is our job, and once you accept that,
you'll be a glowing picture of happiness.
Like me.
We're talking about the royal caravan here.
It's the ultimate job.
You get to go from town to town,
see the world, visit important people,
and you get to march
with the biggest, strongest,
greatest horses in the world.
Dave! Dave! Dave! Dave!
All the animals in every town
watching us go by.
Dave! Dave! Dave!
And we'll finally be doing
something important.
A miniature donkey in the royal caravan?
- That'll be the day.
- Don't listen to him.
And what's a dove gonna do,
carry one grape at a time?
At least he's not
locked up in a mill like us.
I'm telling you,
folks in this town just don't get it.
And, I could carry two grapes,
one in each talon, thank you very much.
Bells.
Wait. Bells.
That's them.
It's time to activate Operation Prison Break.
Okay.
All I have to do is kick
this sharp metal killer stick
towards my head and duck.
It'll cut your harness...
And I'll finally be free.
I love Operation Prison Break.
- Such a good idea.
- Here we go.
Okay, that's not good.
Oh, boy.
See? I knew that would work.
Just like we planned.
With a momentary near-death hiccup.
Well, old-timer, it's been real.
- Good luck to you.
- Wait, Dave.
We can't just leave him.
Buddy, I get where you're coming from,
but it's the royal caravan,
not the retirement caravan.
Look at him. He's like 300 years old.
All right. What's going on in...
Now, this ought to keep you where you belong.
You're nothing but a great big, rotten...
Oh, boy.
...good-for-nothing bully!
Yeah, you better walk away.
Who needs the royal caravan?
There's plenty of excitement
here in Nazareth.
I'm gonna be honest.
I'm very upset right now.
I'm gonna go find someone to poop on.
If that miller thinks
this yoke is gonna stop me...
Boy, do I have a surprise for him.
I'll be riding with kings any day now.
You'll see.
Still no Mary.
Okay. Just a little late.
It's normal to be late
to your wedding feast. Totally normal.
Just like it's normal to talk to yourself.
There he is!
- Hey.
- Hi, Joseph.
Looking good!
Mary. You made it.
You look beautiful.
So do you.
Well, handsome.
I've missed you.
You're a little late, you know.
I was starting to worry.
Sorry.
That's our fault. We're always late.
"We" who? You were driving.
She was such a big help to us
these past several months.
- Wasn't she, John?
- Sorry, big guy.
I know how great she is,
but I'm taking her back.
Joseph?
There's something
I want to talk to you about.
Of course.
And, just warning you,
it might be a lot to take in.
Mary, it's our wedding feast.
Of course. You can tell me anything.
She's here!
Sorry, what did you want to talk about?
It can wait.
Let's enjoy the party.
So, any new escape plans, kid?
What's the point?
I'm always gonna be stuck on the
same old wheel with the same old view.
What's wrong with the view?
I know it feels like
we're just going in circles.
- We are.
- Look, kid.
We're mill donkeys.
We grind grain. We don't carry kings.
Yeah.
Should've listened to you
and given up a long time ago.
What is happening?
Kid, it's my leg. Go get help.
These good-for-nothing animals.
What is it now?
Just what I needed.
- Are the gates open?
- What?
- Yeah.
- You!
What are you doing...
Kid, get out of here.
Wait, but I thought you said...
- What about you?
- I'll be fine.
I just hope you find what you're looking for.
I don't know what to say.
You're welcome, kid.
Now, get going.
No, you don't!
You're free, kid. Make it count.
What?
Where do you think you're going?
Get back here!
Look, I'm not gonna be here long.
Runaway donkey! Somebody grab him!
Sorry, hon. Looks like I'm leaving
sooner than I thought.
Never forget me!
You broke out! Yes, the dream is back on.
See, not free yet.
The miller! The miller's on my tail!
Yeah, and he does not look happy.
I am not happy!
Follow me.
- This way. Up here.
- No, no, not up.
No, donkey don't like up!
Sorry. Sorry.
I'm a really nice guy.
Get out of the way.
Get out of the way. Get out of the way!
- What now?
- Jump.
Jump? What, are you crazy?
Just jump!
A flying donkey!
Well, greetings, ladies.
Wait a second. Are they eating chicken?
Ladies, run!
Other way. Other way!
No, no. Where'd you go?
Dave? Dave? Where are you?
I got you now.
No.
- No, no, no.
- There's no way out of this.
Here we go!
Okay. Here goes.
He's a good man. He'll understand.
Thanks.
Zechariah! Party's over.
Let's go.
Great party, guys.
- Bye, now.
- Joseph,
you must be the happiest man in the world.
Or second happiest.
Clearly, I'm the happiest.
You know, I think I liked you better
when you couldn't talk.
Our place is a mess.
"Our place."
I like the sound of that.
Me, too.
Well, this place isn't gonna clean itself.
I'm starting with the dishes.
Okay. And I'll start down here.
Where I figure out how to tell him about you.
It's all good news. Promise.
All good news.
Yep.
I'm caught again.
There's gotta be a better hiding place.
Okay, maybe not here.
Nope, not that one, either.
Why couldn't I be smaller?
The one time I wish I was smaller.
No.
You poor thing.
You're hurt.
What is she doing?
That can't be good.
If I'm going to help you,
you're gonna have to let me, okay?
Okay.
Better?
Good. Nice to meet you.
I'm Mary.
Hey. You gonna bring me up any more dishes?
You didn't tell me you had a donkey.
I don't.
No, he must be a stray.
Go on, boy. Shoo!
You're scrappy. Scrappy little donkey.
Come on.
All right, that's how it's gonna be?
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, yeah. I'm fine. It's just a...
Well, I'm glad to see
that the donkey survived.
Poor little guy is hurt.
- Give him a break.
- Hello!
Has anyone lost a donkey?
- Because, if you have, he's here!
- What should we call you?
And I do not want him!
How about...
- Wait, what are you doing?
- Boaz.
You're naming it?
What do you think, Bo?
Bo? No way.
Bo's a good name for you. Isn't it?
- Isn't it?
- Yeah, Bo's great. Love it.
Mary, no.
No, if you name him, you're gonna start
feeling affectionate toward him.
And once you feel affectionate,
you're gonna want to keep him.
And if there is one thing
we are definitely not going to do...
Do you think he'll be warm enough down here?
That's my workshop.
Let's just let him stay here
till he's all better.
Don't you think we should at least...
Mary?
Come on. Let's go talk upstairs.
Okay...
Finally. They are gone, and I am out of here.
There you are.
I am so glad you're okay.
Do you know how much flying around
I have done looking for you?
I thought that maybe the miller
caught you and was gonna eat you.
Eat me? Yeah, I don't think
he was gonna do that.
You don't know! He had crazy in his eyes.
So keep it down.
He's still out there someplace.
- Do you think he heard?
- Nah. I think we're good.
This is the last place he'd check.
Nothing special ever happens
in an old shack like this.
The Messiah?
You're saying that baby
is the actual Messiah?
Like from the prophets?
I do need to sit down, actually.
I know. I know how it sounds, but yes.
And God wants you and me to raise him.
Me? Are you sure...
I mean, did the angel mention me?
Well, no, but it's...
Look, I can't raise the Son of God.
He's a king. I'm just a carpenter.
He needs someone with a little
more experience being...
I don't know, king-ish?
I mean, who am I?
You're my husband.
I am so sorry.
This is just so much to take in right now.
Can I have a little time?
Okay. We got it this time.
We're making progress, though, right?
Hate to say it, but even if we got you out,
you're never gonna make it
to the royal caravan on that leg.
Dave, look, I don't want to hold you back.
You fly ahead without me.
I'll catch up once my leg heals.
No. We're in this together,
and I'm not gonna leave you here.
- Friends don't do that.
- Are you sure?
Yeah, and besides,
you'd never make it without me.
I am a bird of the world.
I know how things work out there.
You are a donkey of a barn.
A very small, ill-smelling barn.
- You need me.
- Okay.
So, now what?
Hide out here until your leg heals,
and then just get yourself kicked out.
And we'll be back on track, pal.
Bo, actually.
My name is Bo now. Mary named me.
"Bo."
That's got a nice ring to... Wait.
That lady person named you?
I said hide here,
not settle in and get a name.
- Have I taught you nothing?
- No one is settling in, okay?
Once my leg is healed,
it's time for Operation Kick Me Out.
Good. Now, I'm an expert
at this type of thing, so listen up.
Things I found that tend to tick people off.
Jumping out and scaring them.
Singing really loudly early in the morning.
Staring at them while they eat.
At the risk of stating the obvious,
a well-placed number two.
Breaking things.
Setting things on fire.
Licking things that don't want to be licked.
What child is this
Who laid to rest
On Mary's lap
ls sleeping
Whom angels greet
With anthems sweet
While shepherds watch
Joseph.
Are keeping?
This, this is Christ the King
Whom shepherds guard and angels sing
Haste, haste
To bring him laud
The babe, the Son of Mary.
Wait a minute! Wait a minute!
We three kings
Of Orient are
Bearing gifts
We traverse afar
Field and fountain
Moor and mountain
Hang on!
- Following yonder star
- Cyrus! Deborah!
Come on, guys! Wait up!
I expected a left turn two deserts ago.
I'm dying back here!
I can't believe we passed that last oasis.
- I'm getting thirsty.
- Lost!
These wise guys are lost.
Wise men don't get lost, Felix.
So you're saying they know
where this birthday party is?
And what makes you so certain
it's a birthday party?
Here we go.
Have you seen the presents
these guys are bringing?
Gold, myrrh, frankincense.
Could be a baby shower.
- You bring gifts to a baby shower.
- Baby shower?
What is a baby gonna do
with frankincense, silly camel?
It's a birthday party.
Baby shower.
- Birthday party.
- Baby shower.
Birthday party.
- Birthday party!
What if it's not a party at all?
What if we're on our way
to do something important like,
I don't know, meeting the Son of God?
Deborah's crazier than a box of rocks.
I believe the expression is,
"Dumb as a box of rocks."
You ever shake a box of rocks?
They sound crazy.
You're westward leading
Still you're proceeding
Guide us to the light
So floridly written.
It makes one wonder how the emperor
has so much time for counting his subjects.
But if Caesar decrees a census,
then a census he will get.
Send the royal guard to round up
every man and woman.
- Sire.
- Let the counting of the sheep begin.
Your Majesty, three magi
bearing gifts for the king.
Hold it right there, camels.
I bet they can play that game we made up.
That was fun. What was it called again?
"How High."
On three. One, two...
Three!
- How high?
- Camel high.
Your gifts are unexpected,
though not unwelcome.
Your Majesty, these gifts are not for you.
Yes, they're for the new king.
- What new king?
- The one foretold by the star.
I knew it.
It's a birthday party for the new king.
No, no. I'm pretty certain
it's a baby shower.
Or maybe they're referring
to the coming Messiah.
The Son of God.
Okay, now I'm starting to worry about her.
Deborah, are you okay?
How many hooves am I holding up?
Now bring in my scribes.
There is a prophecy.
What are they saying?
I can't make it out, but it's something
about the king of the... Shoes?
King of the shoes? That's what this is about?
- That can't be right.
- Look!
Look! Dude has gold slippers.
King of the shoes, no doubt.
That, Felix, is money and no taste.
Can we move past the shoes?
- I think...
- Look at that guy.
- You see him?
- He's just the royal dog walker.
Trust me. Felix, I know these things.
What? Dog walker?
He's like a nightmare wearing a helmet.
We must find this king at once.
I will set my scribes to the task.
In the meantime, I invite you to stay
in the palace as my royal guests.
No, no, that's not necessary, sire.
But, I insist.
Okay. That was sinister.
Yep. We're leaving.
We're not gonna do any slumber parties
with any evil shoe kings.
No, thank you.
Too late.
This new king is a problem.
Get rid of the problem.
The room was filled with magical light.
And then the angel said
that the child would be the new king.
New king?
And I thought, "I'm not ready to be a mom."
But then I realized
the angel was talking to the lady.
Wait, wait. I'm not done.
That's usually everyone's favorite part.
Nice story, rat. Here's how it ends.
The end.
Rufus, spit it out.
We need that rat to talk.
I am not a rat.
- I'm a pygmy jerboa.
- What's a jerboa?
It is in the rodent family
but an entirely different species.
Rufus, enough. Spit it out.
I was just starting to
get a little bit of the flavor.
You've been telling this story
to every critter in Galilee.
Now it's our turn to hear it.
From the beginning.
From the beginning?
Okay. Well...
I was born in a sack of barley
somewhere in Capernaum.
Skip to the end! Who's the woman?
Her name is Mary. She lives in Nazareth.
But, please, don't hurt her.
- She's really nice.
- Don't worry.
We're harmless.
That's mine!
No.
Mary!
Looks like you're healed up.
Feeling better?
All I'm saying is it's unfair, you know,
to make all these people
drop everything for the census.
And for us to travel to Bethlehem,
especially in your condition.
Joseph, I'm not dying.
It's just a little road trip. We'll be fine.
This feels right.
You know, Mary, most donkeys have to work.
You are spoiling him.
She is spoiling you.
Hey, look at you.
- Your leg's all better.
- Hey, Dave.
All right, time to activate
Operation Kick Me Out.
What's your plan of attack?
First, I thought I'd let her finish
this belly rub.
Snap out of it!
A little bird named Methuselah
told me the royal caravan will be
passing through not too far from here.
We can catch them if we leave soon.
All right, let's get kicked out of here.
All packed up. Is the donkey ready?
Yes, his leg looks good as new.
Finally. Time for him to earn his keep.
All right, Bo, let's get you
hitched up to this cart
so you can take us to Bethlehem.
- Bethlehem?
Not good, not good.
The royal caravan is nowhere near Bethlehem.
Don't worry. He's gotta catch me first.
- Joseph, maybe if you just...
- Don't worry, Mary. I've got this.
Well, looks like you got me.
Come here!
- That looked like it hurt.
- It did.
- How was that?
- Bo, look out!
Come on. See?
Under control.
Joseph!
No, no, I'm okay.
You know what? We can walk to Bethlehem.
- No problem.
- Useless donkey.
- Nicely done.
- I thought so.
Did you see how I laid him out on the ground?
Those caravan horses have nothing on you.
- Okay, so now what?
- Easy.
All we have to do is slip through the gate
when they're on their way out.
No, no, no, don't close the gate!
Don't worry. We'll be back soon.
I guess that was good-bye?
You're not gonna cry, are you?
Come on, we gotta figure out a way
to open this thing.
This is what I get
for having a friend who can't fly.
You know what? Gates were never
a problem before I met you.
There's gotta be something we can use here.
There's that table, that lumber, those tools.
A giant knife.
Hide!
Okay, Bo. What haven't you told me?
- You been making some new friends?
- No.
I bet the miller sent them
to bring me back to the mill.
- They left the gate open.
- I'll make a run for it.
Dave, you jump out and create a distraction.
What? No. Terrible plan.
Why don't you make the distraction
and I run for it?
Because I'm the one trapped in here,
and you can fly,
- as you like to keep telling me.
- All valid points.
I got a scent.
I smell a dog!
Thaddeus, there's definitely a dog here.
Yeah!
- I smell me.
- Hey! Scary dogs!
You guys here for the show?
- What show?
- What...
"What show," the silly dog asks.
You're adorable.
"The Dance of the Royal Dove," of course.
Played in Rome six years.
Great reviews.
Caesar saw it twice. Made him cry.
He won't admit that because,
you know, he's Caesar and all.
But he definitely cried like a baby.
- But I digress.
- We don't have time for this.
No! Wait! The show is about to start.
Okay. You can...
What are you doing? Don't watch me.
Yeah. This bird can dance.
No, guys. Guys, guys, guys, no,
this is the best part.
Okay, there you go. They're gone.
- Where's your owner?
- Yeah! Where's your owner?
Who, the miller? I don't know a miller.
My owner's a nice pregnant lady.
You would love her.
- That's her.
- Where is she?
Wait, you're looking for Mary?
Did I say "pregnant lady?"
I meant "miller."
I'm just a mill donkey on vacation.
- Who's Mary?
- Keep talking.
Okay, that was pathetic.
Let me handle this, Bo.
- Guys, donkeys are stubborn.
- Yeah.
- He's not gonna tell you anything.
- Sorry, guys.
You would have to torture it out of him.
Wait, what?
- He didn't bandage himself.
- That's her scent.
Now we just gotta figure out
which way she went.
We'll tell her you said hello.
They left the gate open.
Okay. The royal caravan is right this way.
We'll catch it in no time.
Wait. Where you going? Dream is that way.
- Right, but Mary is this way.
- No.
Royal caravan cannot wait
for a rescue mission.
Especially when that guy is after her.
He is major bad news.
I'm not gonna just let her get hurt, Dave.
- She was nice to me.
- Come on, Bo.
- We've been waiting for this.
- It'll just take a second.
Once Mary's safe, we'll turn right around
and join the royal caravan.
- Deal?
- Fine! Deal.
So we turn right around.
Okay, leave this to me. I know a shortcut.
He'll lead us right to her.
- And then what?
- Then we find the baby.
That baby messed with the wrong dogs.
Nothing scares us.
Not even a baby. Right, partner?
Just stop.
Thaddeus, do you think I'm bad at being bad?
I got it.
Okay, Dave, be honest.
- Are we lost?
- No.
'Cause this doesn't exactly
look like the beaten path.
It's a shortcut. Trust me.
Bo? Bo, right here. Look at me, buddy.
Just breathe. Breathe.
Breathe.
Nope. That's it.
No more of your terrible shortcuts. We are...
Look. It's Mary. That's them.
Guess we'll have to take
my terrible shortcut.
You're welcome.
Wait. No, no, no, no. Okay.
Come on. Really?
- Which way am I supposed to go?
- It's a cliff.
You go down.
- Hi.
- Could you help me get down, please?
Just let go.
- Here, let me.
- Wait, no, no, no.
- I'm Ruth.
- Hi, Ruth. I'm Bo.
Ruth? You're a little close.
- You know, personal space?
- Sorry.
Flocking. It's a sheep thing.
So, what are you doing
all alone on a cliff like this?
Well, actually,
I'm here with my friend, Dave.
I'm meeting him at the bottom.
We're on the road to Bethlehem
so we can catch up with
my friend Mary and save her.
And once we do,
we will be joining the royal caravan.
Sounds exciting.
Well, I guess I'll get back
to following the star.
The star? You mean the...
- You mean that super bright one?
- Yeah, that one.
Have you noticed
how it's been getting brighter?
Totally. And the weird way
it kind of pulsates.
Yes! It's like it's...
- Like it means something.
- Exactly.
Okay, come on. We're almost down.
One more chasm.
This is really easy for you, isn't it?
You got it, Bo. Just don't look down.
Okay, great. Now, just...
Just try to get your hooves in...
Okay, yeah, yeah, yeah. Spread-eagle.
We're going for a wedge thing here.
That's it. You got it. You're a wedge.
- How does that feel?
- Fantastic.
Great. Okay. Next, just lift that hoof
and take a step down.
- No, no, no.
- You can do it. Just one hoof at a time.
That's it.
What is taking him so long?
Well, didn't exactly stick the landing,
but that was good.
You're a fast learner.
- Dave? Dave?
- I'm under you and in a lot of pain.
- Dave?
- Yeah. Right here. On your butt.
Come on. Let's get moving.
You must be Dave.
I've heard great things about you.
- I'm Ruth.
- Pleasure.
Well, we've got places to be,
people to save, caravans to join.
- See you around.
- Thanks, Ruth.
Have you ever been to Bethlehem before?
- We've never been anywhere before.
- Well, you're in for a treat.
The Samaritan Mountains
are beautiful this time of year.
Deadly steep, but great views.
- You've been to Bethlehem?
- Are you kidding?
I grew up around there.
I know all the ins and outs,
how to avoid predators
and treacherous high cliffs.
The treacherous cliffs.
You're not really considering this, are you?
Come on, Ruth. Lead the way.
Sheep are usually better at following,
but I will do my best.
- Let's go, flock.
- Yippee.
- Felix, come on.
- Shouldn't we be sneaking out?
Why are we sneaking in?
King Herod is up to something.
And we are gonna find out what.
With the help of a little
well-placed distraction.
Come on, fellas. Hurry.
Still no report from my hunter?
- Has he found the child?
- No, sire.
But your scribes are ready
to present their findings.
Well, finally, someone's doing their job.
So tell me where he is.
According to the prophecy, Your Majesty,
the new king is to be born in Bethlehem.
And? That's all? To what family?
Who are they? I am the king.
I am the king of Judea.
If you people can't find this one child,
then I'll just have to kill them all.
See? I told you.
Shall we send soldiers to track him down?
No.
You three, come.
- It's the wise men.
- Hide, quickly.
- So, any word of the new king?
- Yes.
Look for him in Bethlehem. You're free to go.
Our humblest thanks, Your Majesty.
When you find him, send word to me.
I dearly wish to know where he is
so that I, too, may honor him
with a gift.
You know, I think
he might be up to something.
He's using the wise men
to track down the new king.
Yeah! Plus, did you see him
crumple that flower?
- We have to warn the new king.
- Pack your bags, boys.
Looks like we're going to Bethlehem.
And now our tour will continue
past these pebbles on the path.
Watch your step. Watch your step.
And watch your step.
I blame you for this.
There they are.
Come on.
Mary.
Are you sure you don't want
to sit in the cart?
No, it's hard enough for you as it is.
Just let me fix my boot.
- I don't believe it.
- Really, I'm fine.
No, not that. That.
Bo?
Mary. You're in danger.
You need to listen to what I'm about
to say extremely carefully.
You ever feel like he's trying to talk to us?
Why is he here? Where did he come from?
She's not getting it.
Okay, new plan.
Can you two act like dogs?
- What do you think?
- Yes. I do a great dog.
- Dogs are my fourth best animal.
- Great. Just follow my lead.
"Look at me. I'm Mary. I'm so pregnant."
"I'm Joseph. I'm in a bad mood."
Wait, wait, wait. Is that supposed to be me?
It's totally you.
"No! Look! Here come the dogs!"
That's you guys.
Throw me a stick,
and I'll bring it right back.
What's this? It's a tail?
- I'm gonna get you.
- Seriously?
We're doing this
instead of the royal caravan?
No, Ruth, you're a scary dog. Just be meaner.
Meaner? You mean like this!
No! They got me!
If only a certain donkey had warned me.
There is something seriously
wrong with those animals.
I think Bo's trying to tell us something.
Come on, come on.
I think he wants a belly rub.
What? No. I mean, yes, always, but not now.
This is not working.
Guys, I hate to break this up,
but we've got trouble.
- Mama!
- Those guys?
Yeah, they've been following us
since we came down the cliff.
Couldn't you have pointed that out sooner?
No. They followed us right to her.
Well, why don't we hide
in that big flock over there?
That's what a sheep would do.
Yes. Great idea.
Bo, what are you...
- Joseph?
- Right behind you.
Okay.
You must be really thirsty.
I'm gonna grab some water. Do you want some?
Sure. Yeah, I guess I'll just take
a look at that wheel, then.
- Don't carry too much, okay?
- I won't.
Sorry.
- Fresh figs! Get your fresh figs here.
- I got them.
Hello, sir. You look like a man
who appreciates fine pottery.
I...
Hurry up. We need three buckets of water.
- Do you see anything?
- What are we looking for?
What...
Here we are, minutes away from being chopped
into tiny little pieces
by a knife-wielding psycho.
- We could've been riding with royalty.
- Look! They're here.
Dave, let's try and lead them away.
Ruth, you stay here and guard Mary.
If they find her, get our attention.
- Yeah. We should have a secret signal.
- Sounds great.
Help me.
Gosh. The signal. Okay.
- No.
- I'll take care of this.
Looks like it's up to me.
Nope, too big. Too big.
- Ruth, looks like it's up to you.
- Me?
I knew this day would come.
For the flock!
Look out!
- No!
- Get back! Get back!
Watch out!
Hold it up!
No!
Yes!
Bo, are you okay?
- What has gotten into you?
- That donkey did it.
He destroyed everything.
Did you do this?
- It was the donkey.
- Who owns that?
Oh, boy.
We stopped him!
That went great, right?
Hey, you big mutts!
- Come here.
- Hope your boss knows how to swim.
You want some of this?
What's the matter, guys? All tied up?
That's it, you're dead.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
- I hate that dancing bird.
- I know. He's so talented.
- Joseph.
- No, no.
I do not want that donkey
near you or the baby.
Go! Get out of here!
- Joseph, it's fine.
- Fine?
Mary, this is not going well, all right?
I just promised four people
I'd repair the carts that he smashed.
Yeah, trying to save her life.
Maybe if you pulled the cart,
Joseph would want you to stay.
- No, he is just too much to deal with.
- He's just a donkey.
"Just a donkey?" Yeah, he is.
Just a good-for-nothing donkey
that has only ever brought us trouble.
Come on, Dave. Let's go.
- Where are we going?
- Where do you think?
To join the royal caravan.
Where we'll finally do something important.
Bo, wait a minute. What about the star?
It means something. You said so yourself.
You follow the star. I'm done with that.
But what about our tiny flock?
Flocks stick together.
We're not a flock.
I never should have followed you.
Bo?
Bo!
We're gonna die. We're gonna die!
We're gonna live. We're gonna live!
Someone's gonna die.
Why should I feel discouraged?
Why should the shadows come?
Why should my heart be lonely?
And long for Heaven and home?
I sing because I'm happy
I sing because I'm free
His eye is on the sparrow
And I know He watches me.
Is that the royal caravan?
I can see them!
Royal caravan-van-van-van-van!
The royal caravan!
Dave?
I don't think I can go with you.
Of course you can. What do you mean?
Look...
I know we've always talked about
joining the royal caravan,
being a part of something important,
but now that we're here,
I don't think this is it.
You know, Mary may not be big and royal,
but she's important.
She's important to me.
I know this was our dream,
and even though I can't come,
I think you should go.
Say hi to the horses for me.
- Come on.
- No, really, I mean it.
Bo, yes, you're right.
The royal caravan was our dream.
But the best part
was that it was gonna be us.
If all I wanted was to flap
around a bunch of fancy wagons,
I could have gone and done that
a long time ago.
I mean, I can fly, you know?
You realize that?
Yeah. I guess so.
Look, you lead the way, and wherever you go,
your best friend Dave
will be right behind you.
You ready?
- No, no, no, no, no.
- Let me help.
- Mary, you're in no condition to help.
- Stop saying that.
- I'm fine.
- No, you are not fine.
- None of this is fine.
- Joseph, God chose us.
But why? Why us?
Look at us. We'll be lucky
just to make it to Bethlehem.
And we're supposed to raise the Son of God?
This must be part of God's plan.
Well, so far, this plan is going great.
I can't wait to see what happens next.
Mary, did you know
That your baby boy
will one day walk on water?
What are you looking at?
Mary, did you know
That your baby boy
will save our sons and daughters?
Lord, I can't do this.
All right? I am not the father of a king.
I'm just a carpenter. Please, give me a sign.
This child that you delivered
will soon deliver you
Really?
The donkey?
Stop it.
Mary, did you know?
Mary?
Hi, Ruth.
Look, I'm sorry for what I said back there.
It was mean, and...
I'm glad we followed you.
You know, that night I saw the star,
I tried to get my old flock to follow me,
but they wouldn't.
And so I struck out on my own,
which has been hard
'cause, well, I'm a sheep.
Thank you for coming back.
- Can you help me with these?
- Of course! You're back!
- Sorry, personal space.
- Come here.
Mary.
Are you okay? I am so sorry.
No, Joseph. You were right.
I was? About what?
This is hard.
Trust me, I know it is.
Just because God has a plan
doesn't mean it's going to be easy.
And that scares me.
I'm scared, too.
But I'm here. And I am yours.
And I will give everything that I have
to keep you and the baby safe.
I mean, I may not have a lot...
Speaking of which,
what happened to all our stuff?
- Bo!
- I always liked that donkey.
I always did. I didn't say it enough.
That's true.
- Hello.
- Did the baby kick?
No, that was something different.
Different? What "different?"
Like, baby's coming now?
We've got some time, but, yeah, I think so.
Okay! Nobody panic!
I've got the clothes. I've got the bag.
I've got the sheep. Why do I have the sheep?
Bo, can you carry her?
One dark night
Something said follow the light
So you look up and see the word
That's written upon the sky
Strong and wise
Keeping the Lord as your guide
And through the doubt you realize
He's with you all the while
Follow that star above you
Should the world try to break you down
There is one who waits for you
Though you can't see Him now
Thunder and rain surround you
But His love's just a breath away
If you follow your heart, follow the light
Follow that star
I have traveled
Many moonless nights
Cold and weary
With a babe inside
And I wonder
All right. Shall we?
What I've done
All right, buddy, just wait here,
and we'll be back out in a second.
And they're inside.
Thank goodness. This has been so stressful.
I don't know how we held it together.
Well, we made it.
Safe and sound in Bethlehem.
Something's not right.
Excuse me.
You.
- No, no, no.
- Easy. Easy, boy.
It's okay.
Just hold still.
Let me go!
No, you don't,
crazy-eyed, donkey-eating miller.
That's my best friend!
- Move on!
- Dave!
Dave, are you okay?
Where did they go? Who was that?
Bad news.
- I'm sorry. The inn is full.
- What?
But, no, can't you see
she's about to have a child?
What can I do? Blame the census.
You know what? We will pay double.
Just hold that thought.
I'll be right back.
- I left the money with Bo.
- Joseph?
Bo?
Where's Bo?
Joseph, we're running out of time!
Mary.
Bo...
Bo, where are you?
Ruth, I know we have had our personal issues,
but we need to set them aside and find Bo.
We have personal issues?
Dave, I think you are a delight.
I am a delight. Thank you for noticing.
Okay, time to activate Operation Rescue Bo.
She's here.
Down the street. Try them.
You don't understand.
We just came from there.
Sorry.
Where do we go now?
We will find a place.
We just have to keep looking.
So this is Bethle-ham.
It is pronounced "Bethle-hem."
- That's what I said. "Bethle-ham."
- "Hem."
"Hem." As if you're clearing your throat.
- Boys.
- That's what I've been saying.
- You need to get your ears checked.
- Boys, focus.
The new king's in danger.
Right. Let's go find him.
They've secured our restraints.
Yeah, and they tied us up, too.
We have to find the new king.
Wise men indeed.
Okay, okay, think. What do kings look like?
In most cultures,
a king is set apart from the plebeians
with an ornamental headdress.
A ornamel what?
They wear hats.
They're coming for you, Your Majesty!
Run for your life!
- Run like the wind!
- Will you cut that out?
We'll never find him tied up here.
- We have to go out and search.
- That's it.
I'm biting through the reins.
Don't you dare.
That is fine Corinthian leather.
Do you have any idea how much that cost?
- You kidding me?
- No, he's right.
Well, we'll have to untie
these knots ourselves.
Just follow my instructions.
First, Felix, we'll need you in the middle.
Deborah, on the left.
- Excuse me. Pardon me.
- No.
- Let me... Move.
- No. Over.
- Would you move?
- The other way.
- Sorry about that. Sorry. My bad.
- I got it.
- Move.
- No, around.
No, the other...
- The other left.
- Stop!
Would you stop pinching me?
Come on. Come on.
No, no, no. Don't do this. Please!
I can't let them down.
I could try praying.
Let's see...
Okay, how did Mary do this?
Never mind.
It's fine.
God? Hello?
I don't really know how this works
or if You listen to prayers from donkeys,
but I've seen Mary do this many times,
and I don't know what else to do.
My friends need help.
I thought, if I followed the star,
it would lead me to where I'm supposed to be,
but I failed them.
What do you want me to do?
Begone! Away with you!
- God?
- Now it's talking back.
There's nothing to fear, Zach.
It's all a figment of your imagination.
This really realistic vision
of a donkey who's talking to God
- and won't stop eyeballing you.
- Zach.
Pull yourself together.
What's your name, sweetie?
Bo.
Bo is a funny word.
Bo, Bo, Bo.
- Bo, Bo.
- What?
- Bo, Bo!
- He has a name?
- And she's singing him a song?
- I'm doomed.
- Bo!
- I kind of like that.
They're not usually like this.
You caught us at a bad time.
We haven't slept in nine months.
- Nine months?
- Not a wink.
So that explains your eyes.
What? What's wrong with my eyes?
Nothing.
Yep, no sleep at all
since that giant night light turned on.
- Light?
- All you can do
is lie awake and listen to the crickets.
Ta-da.
Sorry. So excited.
Zach and Edith don't like the spotlight,
but I think it's beautiful.
It's here.
I can't believe this.
- Me, neither.
- You don't understand.
That light, that's the star.
This is where it's been leading me.
But Mary... Joseph...
Guys, I gotta get out of here.
- Can you help me?
- I got you. I'm gonna chew him free.
- Woody.
- No. Try biting the...
I know! I'll sing you free.
That was beautiful, but not helpful.
I think I got a splinter in my tongue.
Step aside.
Yes, yes! That's perfect.
Now I just gotta get past that gate.
Has that ever worked for you?
No, actually.
Come on. Up you go.
Thanks, guys.
Gotta run. Mary's having a baby!
- A baby?
- I love babies.
Bring 'em back here.
There's plenty of room in the stable.
Great. Now we'll never sleep.
What?
No, no, no, no.
Bo, buddy, where are you?
Bo, are you there?
Bo? Bo!
Bo! Hey, Bo.
Bo!
- Ruth.
- You're here.
- Dave.
- We've gotta help Mary and Joseph.
I know. Where are they?
Yeah, we hadn't gotten that far.
The dogs are here.
We can't take them on our own.
We need to find help.
- You can count on us!
- We won't let you down!
They went that way.
What are we doing? We're not gonna
stop those giant, scary dogs
with a fluffy sheep and a tiny donkey.
Even with a very masculine and brave dove.
We need backup.
Where do you find a dog-eating
hippopotamus in Bethlehem?
A three-headed camel? Nice.
Help! Help!
Help! Anybody!
Look, a flock of sheep.
That kind of looks like my...
That's my flock.
Help.
Is there anybody else?
No? Okay.
Bo needs my help.
Okay, you can do this. Here we go.
Hey, everybody.
What's up?
It's me, Ruth.
Okay.
I know you guys think I was crazy
to leave and follow the star,
but you wouldn't believe
all the adventures I've had out there.
And the biggest one of all
is happening tonight.
I've made new friends,
and they need our help.
So, this time, you gotta follow me.
Guys?
This is important!
Fear not.
I bring good tidings of great joy.
For unto you is born this day a savior,
Christ, the Lord.
Told ya it was important.
I'm sorry. There's no room.
Sorry.
I'm sorry.
Joseph, I can't go any further.
All right, all right, Mary, here.
Just...
Here. Lay here.
Mary? Mary, look at me.
You're doing great.
Remember, God chose us for a reason.
This must be part of His plan.
Help us. Help us.
Please, God, help us.
Mary! Joseph!
Not good.
No, no, no, no, that's not good at all.
- Bo?
- Bo? You're back!
Buddy, we need somewhere to go.
Mary, let's go.
Guys, guys.
- I found them.
- We're all set.
It's not much, but there's plenty of light.
No, no, no, this isn't gonna work.
We can't have the baby here.
Mary, we need stronger bedding.
- You know, we need warmer...
- Joseph.
It's time.
Thank you.
Well, well...
Look who it is.
We should've eaten him
the first time we met him.
But, Rufus, if we had eaten him,
he would never have led us here.
We've been meaning to thank you.
Now, be a good little donkey and run along.
You've served your purpose.
You guys are pretty scary.
Yeah. And you might be stronger than I am.
But if you wanna get to my friends,
you're gonna have to get past me first.
No problem, donkey!
Getting past you is my middle name.
What is that?
What's what? I wasn't
supposed to look, was I?
Donkey kick!
You just made a big mistake.
You're mine!
Not gonna let you do this!
No, no, no, no, no.
No. Mary! Joseph!
Mary.
I'm sorry.
For the flock!
Coming at you, bro!
- I don't wanna die!
- Somebody, help.
It's just another cliff.
Grab hold of this.
Come on.
Bo?
Bo, you're doing it.
Excellent climbing form, Bo.
Be the wedge.
We're bad dogs.
You don't have to be.
You're free now.
Bo, where are you going?
We've got a baby to meet.
Come on.
After all that, it is a baby shower.
You were right the whole time.
You had it right as well.
It is a birthday party.
Literally, it's the day of his birth.
I'm gonna let 'em have this one.
Holy
O holy night
The stars are brightly shining
It is the night
Of our dear Savior's birth
Long lay the world
In sin and error pining...
Hey, little guy.
It's okay, Bo.
A thrill of hope
The weary world rejoices
Everybody, everybody, listen up.
There's this huge guy with two dogs
coming after Mary,
and if we don't do something now,
then the baby's not gonna...
Looks like...
Looks like you guys handled it.
Sweet.
This seat taken?
Everyone,
this is Mary and Joseph.
And that's their new baby.
The flock is growing.
No. Not happening. Don't even think about it.
It's okay. Let them in.
Look with your eyes.
See?
He's just a baby.
Look at him.
Thaddeus, are we good dogs now?
We have to try.
Is...
I'm sorry. Is this your stable?
No, no, no.
We've come to honor the new king.
I'm sorry.
King? Where? What...
What is he talking about? A king?
What's his name?
His name is Jesus.
For Jesus, gold.
Myrrh.
Do you guys like frankincense?
I never know what to get.
Thank you.
For the newborn king.
A thrill of hope
The weary world rejoices
For yonder breaks
A new and glorious morn
Fall on your knees
Guys, I carried a king on my back.
We're never gonna hear
the end of this, are we?
And I hope we never do.
You know, I think people
are gonna remember this night.
What happened here around this manger
will be celebrated for thousands of years.
Families will come together
and exchange presents and sing carols.
All to remember the grace of this moment
that we are witnessing right now.
- Okay, Deborah.
- She's back to talking crazy again.
Hey. It's okay.
Thank you.
Voices
O night
Divine
Bo?
When Christ was born
Come on.
O holy night
What have you been up to all night, Bo?
- Night divine
- Divine
O night
Divine