'Twas a long time ago,
longer now than it seems,
in a place that perhaps
you've seen in your dreams.
For the story that you
are about to be told...
took place
in the holiday worlds of old.
Now, you've probably wondered
where holidays come from.
If you haven't,
I'd say it's time you begun.
# Boys and girls #
# of every age #
# Wouldn't you like to see #
# something strange #
# Come with us #
# and you will see #
# This, our town #
# of Halloween #
# This is Halloween #
# Pumpkins scream #
# in the dead of night #
# This is Halloween #
# Everybody make a scene #
# Trick or treat till the #
# neighbor's gonna die of fright #
# It's our town #
# Everybody scream #
# In this town #
# of Halloween #
# I am the one hiding #
# under your bed #
# Teeth ground sharp #
# and eyes glowing red #
# I am the one hiding #
# under your stairs #
# Fingers like snakes #
# and spiders in my hair #
# This is Halloween #
# Halloween, Halloween #
# In this town #
# we call home #
# Everyone hail #
# to the pumpkin song #
# In this town #
# Don't we love it now #
# Everybody's waiting #
# for the next surprise #
# 'Round that corner, man #
# Hiding in the trash can #
# Something's waiting now to #
# pounce and how you'll scream #
- # This is Halloween #
- # Red and black #
- # Slimy green #
- # Aren't you scared #
# Well, that's just fine #
# Say it once, say it twice #
# Take a chance #
# and roll the dice #
# Ride with the moon #
# in the dead of night #
# Everybody scream #
# In our town #
# of Halloween #
# I am the clown #
# with the tear-away face #
# Here in a flash #
# and gone without a trace #
# I am the "who" when you call #
# "Who's there?" #
# I am the wind blowing #
# through your hair #
# I am the shadow #
# on the moon at night #
# Filling your dreams #
# to the brim with fright #
# This is Halloween #
# Halloween, Halloween #
# Tender Lumplings #
# everywhere #
# Life's no fun #
# without a good scare #
- # That's our job #
- # But we're not mean #
# In our town #
# of Halloween #
# In this town #
# Don't we love it now #
# Everyone's waiting #
# for the next surprise #
# Skeleton Jack #
# might catch you in the back #
# And scream like a banshee #
# Make you jump out of your skin #
# This is Halloween #
# Everybody scream #
# Won't ya please make way #
# for a very special guy #
# Our man Jack is king #
# of the pumpkin patch #
# Everyone hail #
# to the Pumpkin King now #
# This is Halloween #
# Halloween, Halloween #
# In this town #
# we call home #
# Everyone hail #
# to the pumpkin song #
# La la la la la la #
# Halloween, Halloween #
# Whee #
Whee!
- It's over!
- We did it!
- Wasn't it terrifying?
- What a night!
Great Halloween,
everybody.
I believe it was
our most horrible yet.
Thank you, everyone.
No. Thanks
to you, Jack.
- Without your brilliant leadership--
- Not at all, Mayor.
You're such a scream, Jack!
You're a witch's
fondest dream.
You made walls fall, Jack.
"Walls fall"? You made
the very mountains crack, Jack.
- The deadly nightshade
you slipped me wore off, Sally.
- Let go.
- You're not ready for much excitement.
- Yes, I am.
- You're coming with me.
- No, I'm not!
Come back here,
you foolish--
Ow! Oh. Oh!
Ooh, Jack, you made
wounds ooze and flesh crawl.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Hold it!
We haven't given out the prizes yet.
Our first award
goes to the vampires...
for most blood drained
in a single evening.
Our second
and honorable mention...
goes to the fabulous
Dark Lagoon Leeches.
Nice work, Bone Daddy.
Yeah, I guess so.
Just like last year.
And the year before that,
and the year before that.
# There are few who deny #
# At what I do #
# I am the best #
# For my talents #
# are renowned far and wide #
# When it comes to surprises #
# in the moonlit night #
# I excel without ever #
# even trying #
# With the slightest #
# little effort #
# Of my ghostlike charms #
# I have seen grown men #
# give out a shriek #
# With a wave of my hand #
# And a well-placed moan #
# I have swept the very bravest #
# off their feet #
# Yet year after year #
# it's the same routine #
# And I grow so weary #
# of the sound of screams #
# And I, Jack #
# the Pumpkin King #
# Have grown so tired #
# of the same old thing #
# Oh, somewhere deep #
# Inside of these bones #
# An emptiness #
# Began to grow #
# There's something #
# out there #
# Far from my home #
# A longing that #
# I've never known #
# I'm the master of fright #
# And a demon of light #
# And I'll scare you #
# right out of your pants #
# To a guy in Kentucky #
# I'm Mr. Unlucky #
# And I'm known throughout #
# England and France #
# And since I am dead #
# I can take off my head #
# To recite Shakespearean #
# quotations #
# No animal nor man #
# can scream like I can #
# With the fury #
# of my recitations #
# But who here #
# Would ever understand #
# That the Pumpkin King #
# with the skeleton grin #
# Would tire of his crown #
# If they only understood #
# He'd give it all up #
# if he only could #
# Oh, there's an empty #
# Place in my bones #
# That calls out for #
# Something unknown #
# The fame and praise #
# Come year after year #
# Does nothing for #
# These empty tears #
Jack.
I know how you feel.
Sally.
You've come back.
- I had to.
- For this.
Yes.
Shall we, then?
That's twice this month you've slipped
deadly nightshade into my tea and run off.
- Three times.
- You're mine, you know.
I made you
with my own hands.
You can make
other creations.
I'm restless.
I can't help it.
It's a phase, my dear.
It'll pass.
We need to be patient,
that's all.
But I don't want
to be patient.
No, Zero.
Not now.
I'm not in the mood.
All right.
Here you go, boy.
Mornin', gents.
Jack?
You home?
Jack, I've got the plans
for next Halloween.
I need to go over them with you
so we can get started.
Jack, please, I'm only
an elected official here.
I can't make decisions
by myself.
Jack!
Answer me!
He's not home.
- Where is he?
- He hasn't been home all night.
Where are we?
It's someplace new.
What is this?
Whoa!
# What's this? What's this? #
# There's color everywhere #
# What's this #
# There's white things in the air #
# What's this? I can't believe my eyes #
# I must be dreaming #
# Wake up, Jack! This isn't fair #
# What's this #
# La-la-la-la-la-la-la #
# What's this, What's this #
# There's something very wrong #
# What's this, there's people #
# singing songs, what's this #
# The streets are lined with #
# little creatures laughing #
# Everybody seems so happy #
# Have I possibly gone daffy #
# What is this #
# What's this #
# There's children throwing snowballs #
# instead of throwing heads #
# They're busy building toys #
# And absolutely no one's dead #
# There's frost in every window #
# Oh, I can't believe my eyes #
# And in my bones #
# I feel the warmth #
# That's coming #
# from inside #
# Oh, look, what's this #
# They're hanging mistletoe They kiss #
# Why, that looks so unique #
# Inspired #
# They're gathering around #
# to hear a story #
# Roasting chestnuts on a fire #
# What's this #
# What's this in here #
# They've got a little tree How queer #
# And who would ever think #
# And why #
# They're covering it #
# with tiny little things #
# They've got electric #
# lights on strings #
# And there's a smile on everyone, #
# so now correct me if I'm wrong #
# This looks like fun #
# Oh, could it be I got my wish #
# What's this #
# Oh my, what now #
# The children are asleep #
# But look #
# There's nothing underneath #
# No ghouls, no witches here to scream #
# and scare them or ensnare them #
# Only little cozy things #
# Secure inside #
# their dreamland #
# What's this #
# The monsters are all missing #
# and the nightmares can't be found #
# And in their place there seems #
# to be good feeling all around #
# Instead of screams, I swear #
# I can hear music in the air #
# The smell of cakes and pies #
# are absolutely everywhere #
# The sights, the sounds #
# They're everywhere and all around #
# I've never felt #
# so good before #
# This empty place #
inside of me is filling up
# I simply cannot get enough #
# I want it Oh, I want it #
# Oh, I want it for my own #
# I've got to know, I've got to know #
# what is this place that I have found #
# What is this #
Christmas Town?
Hmm.
Ho-ho-ho-ho!
- This has never happened before.
- It's suspicious.
- It's peculiar.
- It's scary.
Stand aside. Coming through.
We've got to find Jack!
There's only 365 days left
till next Halloween!
364!
Is there anywhere
we've forgotten to check?
- I looked in every mausoleum.
- We opened the sarcophagi!
I tromped through
the pumpkin patch.
I peeked behind
the Cyclops' eye.
I did,
but he wasn't there.
It's time to sound
the alarms!
Frog's breath will
overpower any odor.
Oh!
Bitter!
Worm's wart. Wh-Where's
that worm's wart?
Sally!
Is that soup
ready yet?
Ah.
Coming!
Lunch!
Ah, what's that?
Worm's wart!
Mmm!
And frog's breath.
Wh-What's wrong?
I-I thought you
like frog's breath.
Nothing's more suspicious
than frog's breath.
Until you taste it,
I won't swallow a spoonful.
I'm not hungry.
Oops.
You want me to starve.
An old man like me,
who hardly has strength as it is.
Me, to whom you owe
your very life.
Oh, don't be silly.
Mmm! See?
Scrumptious!
Did anyone think
to dredge the lake?
This morning.
- Hear that? Shh.
- What?
Zero!
Jack's back!
Yea!
Where have you been?
Call a town meeting
and I'll tell everyone all about it!
- When?
- Immediately!
Town meeting!
Town meeting tonight!
Town meeting
tonight!
Listen, everyone.
I want to tell you
about Christmas Town.
# There were objects #
# so peculiar #
# They were not #
# to be believed #
# All around things #
# to tantalize my brain #
# It's a world unlike #
# anything I've ever seen #
# And as hard as I tried #
# I can't seem to describe #
# Like a most #
# improbable dream #
# But you must believe #
# when I tell you this #
# It's as real as my skull #
# and it does exist #
Here, let me show you.
Ooh!
# This is a thing #
# called a present #
- # The whole thing starts with a box #
- # A box #
- # Is it steel #
- # Are there locks #
- # Is it filled with a pox #
- # A pox How delightful, a pox #
If you please.
# Just a box with #
# bright colored paper #
# And the whole thing's #
# topped with a bow #
- # A bow #
- # But why #
- # How ugly! What's in it #
- # What's in it #
# That's the point of the thing #
# Not to know #
- # It's a bat #
- # Will it bend #
- # It's a rat #
- # Will it break #
# Perhaps it's the head #
# that I found in the lake #
# Listen now #
# You don't understand #
# That's not the point #
# of Christmasland #
# Now pay attention #
# We pick up #
# an oversized sock #
# And hang it like this #
# on the wall #
# Oh, yes, does it #
# still have a foot #
# Let me see, let me look #
# Is it rotted and covered with gook #
Um, let me explain.
# There's no foot inside #
# but there's candy #
# Or sometimes it's filled #
# with small toys #
- # Small toys, do they bite #
# or explode in the sack #
- # Do they snap #
# Perhaps they just spring out #
# and scare girls and boys #
# What a splendid idea #
# This Christmas sounds fun #
# I fully endorse it #
# Let's try it at once #
# Everyone, please #
# Now not so fast #
# There's something here #
# that you don't quite grasp #
I don't know.
Do you get it?
Well, I may as well
give them what they want.
# And the best I must confess #
# I have saved for the last #
# For the ruler #
# of this Christmasland #
# Is a fearsome king #
# with a deep, mighty voice #
# Least, that's what #
# I've come to understand #
# And I've also heard it told #
# that he's something to behold #
# Like a lobster #
# Huge and red #
# When he sets out to slay #
# with his rain gear on #
# Carting bulging sacks #
# with his big, great arms #
# That is, #
# so I've heard it said #
# And on a dark, cold night #
# Under full moonlight #
# He flies into a fog like #
# a vulture in the sky #
# And they call him #
# Sandy Claws #
# Well, at least #
# they're excited #
# But they don't #
# understand #
# That special kind #
# of feeling #
# In Christmasland #
Oh, well.
Hmm.
There's got to be a logical way
to explain this Christmas thing.
You've poisoned me for the last time,
you wretched girl.
Oh, my head!
The door is open!
- Hello?
- Jack Skellington!
Up here, my boy.
Doctor, I need to borrow
some equipment.
Is that so?
Whatever for?
I'm conducting a series
of experiments.
How perfectly
marvelous.
- Curiosity killed the cat, you know.
- I know.
Come on into the lab
and we'll get you all fixed up.
Hmm.
Experiments?
Zero, I'm home.
Interesting reaction.
But what does it mean?
You can come out now
if you promise to behave.
Sally?
Oh! Gone again!
Hmm.
Oh!
# Something's up with Jack #
# Don't know if we're ever #
# going to get him back #
# He's all alone up there #
# Locked away inside #
- # Never says a word #
- # Hope he hasn't died #
# Something's up with Jack #
# Christmastime #
# is buzzing in my skull #
# Will it let me be #
# I cannot tell #
# There's so many things #
# I cannot grasp #
# When I think I've got it #
# then at last #
# Through my bony fingers #
# it does slip #
# Like a snowflake #
# in a fiery grip #
# Something here I'm not quite getting, #
# though I try I keep forgetting #
# Like a memory #
# long since past #
# Here in an instant #
# Gone in a flash #
# What does it mean #
# In these little #
# bric-a-brac #
# A secret's waiting #
# to be cracked #
# These dolls and toys #
# confuse me so #
# Confound it all #
# I love it though #
# Simple objects #
# Nothing more #
# But something's hidden #
# through a door #
# Though I do not #
# have the key #
# Something's here #
# I cannot see #
# What does it mean #
Hmm. Hmm.
# I've read these Christmas #
# books so many times #
# I know the stories #
# and I know the rhymes #
# I know the Christmas carols #
# all by heart #
# My skull's so full #
# It's tearing me apart #
# As often as I've read them #
# something's wrong #
# So hard to put #
# my bony finger on #
# Or perhaps it's really not as deep #
# as I've been led to think #
# Am I trying #
# much too hard #
# Of course, I've been #
# too close to see #
# The answer's right in front of me #
# Right in front of me #
# It's simple really #
# Very clear #
# Like music drifting #
# in the air #
# Invisible #
# but everywhere #
# Just because #
# I cannot see it #
# Doesn't mean #
# I can't believe it #
# You know I think this Christmas thing #
# is not as tricky as it seems #
# And why should they have all the fun #
# It should belong to anyone #
# Not anyone, in fact #
# but me #
# Why, I can make #
# a Christmas tree #
# And there's no reason #
# I can find #
# I couldn't handle #
# Christmastime #
# I bet I could #
# improve it too #
# And that's exactly #
# what I'll do #
Hee-hee-hee-hee-hee!
Eureka!
This year...
Christmas will be ours!
Patience, everyone.
Jack has a special job
for each of us.
Dr. Finkelstein!
Your Christmas
assignment is ready.
Dr. Finkelstein, to
the front of the line.
What kind of noise is that
for a baby to make?
- Perhaps it can be improved?
- No problem.
I knew it!
Doctor!
Thank you for coming.
We need
some of these.
Hmm.
Their construction
should be exceedingly simple, I think.
How horrible
our Christmas will be.
No!
How jolly!
Oh. How jolly
our Christmas will be.
- What are you doing here?
- Jack sent for us.
- Specifically.
- By name.
- Lock.
- Shock.
- Barrel.
Jack!
It's Boogie's boys.
Ah, Halloween's finest
trick-or-treaters.
The job I have for you
is top secret.
It requires craft,
cunning, mischief.
And we thought you
didn't like us, Jack.
Absolutely no one is to know about it.
Not a soul!
Now...
...tree...
...Christmas Town...
Ow! Hmm.
And one more thing.
Leave that no-account
Oogie Boogie out of this!
Whatever you say, Jack.
- Of course, Jack.
- Wouldn't dream of it, Jack.
# Kidnap Mr. Sandy Claws #
- # I want to do it #
- # Let's draw straws #
- # Jack said we should work together #
- # Three of a kind #
- # Birds of a feather #
- # Now and forever La la la la la la #
# La la-la la la-la #
# La la-la la-la #
# Kidnap the Sandy Claws #
# Lock him up real tight #
# Throw away the key and then #
# turn off all the lights #
# First we're going to set some bait #
# inside a nasty trap and wait #
# When he comes a-sniffing we will #
# snap the trap and close the gate #
# Wait, I've got a better plan #
# to catch this big red lobster man #
# Let's pop him in a boiling pot and #
# when he's done we'll butter him up #
# Kidnap the Sandy Claws #
# Throw him in a box #
# Bury him for 90 years #
# Then see if he talks #
# Then Mr. Oogie Boogie Man #
# Can take the whole thing #
# over then #
# He'll be so pleased #
# I do declare #
# That he will cook him rare #
# Whee #
# I say that we take a cannon #
# aim it at his door and then #
# Knock three times and when he answers #
# Sandy Claws will be no more #
# You're so stupid! Think now #
# if we blow him up to smithereens #
# We may lose some pieces and then #
# Jack will beat us black and green #
# Kidnap the Sandy Claws #
# Tie him in a bag #
# Throw him in the ocean #
# Then see if he is sad #
# Because Mr. Oogie Boogie #
# is the meanest guy around #
# If I were on his boogie list #
# I'd get out of town #
# He'll be so pleased #
# by our success #
# That he'll reward us too #
# I'll bet #
# Perhaps he'll make #
# his special brew #
- # Of snake and spider stew #
- Mmm!
# We're his little henchmen and #
# we take our job with pride #
# We do our best to please him #
# and stay on his good side #
# I wish my cohorts #
# weren't so dumb #
- # I'm not the dumb one #
- # You're no fun #
- # Shut up, I've got something #
# Listen now #
- # Make me #
# This one is real good #
# You'll see #
# We'll send a present #
# to his door #
# Upon there'll be #
# a note to read #
# Now in the box we'll wait and hide #
# until his curiosity #
# Entices him to look inside And then #
# we'll have him! One, two, three #
# Kidnap the Sandy Claws #
# Beat him with a stick #
# Lock him up for 90 years #
# See what makes him tick #
# Kidnap the Sandy Claws #
# Chop him into bits #
# Mr. Oogie Boogie #
# is sure to get his kicks #
# Kidnap the Sandy Claws #
# See what we will see #
# Lock him in a cage #
# and then throw away #
# The key #
Sandy Claws, huh?
It goes something
like this.
How about it?
Think you can manage?
A-one and a-two
and a-three and a--
Next!
Fantastic!
Now, why don't you all practice
on that? And we'll be in great shape.
Sally, I need your help
more than anyone's.
You certainly do, Jack.
I had the most terrible vision.
- That's splendid!
- No! It was about your Christmas.
- There was smoke and fire--
- That's not my Christmas!
My Christmas is filled
with laughter and joy...
and... this:
My Sandy Claws outfit.
- I want you to make it.
- Jack,
- please listen to me. It's going to be a disaster.
- How could it be?
Just follow the pattern.
This part's red. The trim is white.
- It's a mistake, Jack.
- Now, don't be modest.
Who else is clever enough
to make my Sandy Claws outfit?
- Next!
- I have every confidence in you.
But it seems wrong
to me, very wrong.
This device is called a nutcracker.
Jack, Jack!
We caught him! We got him!
Perfect!
Open it up, quickly.
That's not Sandy Claws.
- It isn't?
- Who is it?
Bunny!
Not Sandy Claws. Take him back!
- We followed your instructions.
- We went through the door.
Which door?
There's more than one!
Sandy Claws is behind
the door shaped like this.
I told you!
- You knock it off!
- Ow! Ow!
I'm very sorry for
the inconvenience, sir.
Take him home first!
And apologize again.
Be careful with Sandy Claws
when you fetch him.
- Treat him nicely.
- Got it.
- We'll get it right...
- next time!
You will be a decided
improvement...
over that
treacherous Sally.
Master! The plans!
Excellent, Igor.
# This time #
# Making Christmas #
- # Is so fine #
- # It's ours this time #
# And won't the children #
# be surprised #
# It's ours this time #
- # Making Christmas #
# Making Christmas #
# Time to give them #
# something fun #
# They'll talk about it #
# for years to come #
# Let's have a cheer #
# from everyone #
# It's time to party #
# Making Christmas #
# Snakes and mice #
# get wrapped up so nice #
# With spider legs #
# and pretty bows #
# It's ours this time #
# Altogether #
# That and this #
# With all our tricks #
# we're making Christmastime #
Here comes Jack!
# I don't believe #
# What's happening to me #
# My hopes #
# My dreams #
# My fantasies #
Ha-hee-hee-hee-hee-hee!
# Won't they be #
# impressed #
# I am a genius #
# See how I transform #
# this old rat #
# Into a most #
# delightful hat #
Hmm.
# My compliments from me to you #
# on this your most intriguing hat #
# Consider, though this substitute, #
# a bat in place of this old rat #
# No, no, no #
# Now that's all wrong #
# This thing will never make a present, #
# it's been dead for much too long #
# Try something fresher #
# Something pleasant #
# Try again #
# Don't give up #
# Altogether #
# That and this #
# With all our tricks #
# we're making Christmastime #
- # This time This time #
- # It's ours #
# Making Christmas #
# La la-la #
# It's almost here #
# And we can't wait #
# So ring the bells #
# and celebrate #
# 'Cause when the full moon #
# starts to climb, we'll all sing out #
# It's Christmastime #
Hee-hee-hee-hee-hee!
Kathleen,
Bobby, Susie.
Yes, Susie's been nice.
Nice, nice, naughty, nice, nice, nice--
There are hardly any
naughty children this year.
Now who could that be?
- Trick or treat!
- Huh?
Ya!
You don't look like yourself, Jack.
Not at all.
Isn't that wonderful?
It couldn't be more wonderful!
- But you're the Pumpkin King.
- Not anymore.
And I feel so much better now.
Jack, I know you think
something's missing, but--
- Ow!
- Sorry!
You're right.
Something is missing, but what?
I've got the beard,
the coat, the boots, the belt--
Jack! Jack!
This time we bagged him.
- This time we really did.
- He sure is big, Jack.
- And heavy!
- Let me out!
Oh, Sandy Claws.
In person! What
a pleasure to meet you.
Wh-Why,
you have hands!
- You don't have claws at all.
- What?
Where am I?
Surprised, aren't you?
I knew you would be.
You don't need to have
another worry about Christmas this year.
- Wha-- Wh-Wha--
- Consider this a vacation, Sandy, a reward.
It's your turn
to take it easy.
- B-But there must be some mistake.
- See that he's comfortable.
Just a second, fellas.
Of course!
- That's what I'm missing. Thanks.
- B-B-But--
You just can't-- Hold on!
Where are we going now?
Ho-ho-ho!
No.
- This is worse than I thought, much worse.
- Ho-ho-ho!
- I know.
Me on vacation?
On Christmas Eve?
- Where are we taking him?
- Where?
To Oogie Boogie,
of course.
There isn't anywhere in the whole world
more comfortable than that.
- And Jack said to make him
comfortable, didn't he?
- Yes, he did!
Haven't you heard of peace
on earth and good will toward men?
No!
Oh! This'll stop Jack.
What a joy
to think of...
all we'll have
in common.
We'll have
conversations...
worth having.
Don't do this!
Naughty children
never get any presents.
- I think he might be too big!
- Oooh!
No, he's not.
If he can go down a chimney,
he can fit...
down... here.
Well, well, well!
What have we here?
Sandy Claws, huh?
Oooh, I'm really scared!
So you're the one
everybody's talkin' about.
# You're jokin' #
# I can't believe #
# my eyes #
# You're jokin' me #
# You gotta be #
# This can't be #
# the right guy #
# He's ancient #
# He's ugly #
# I don't know #
# which is worse #
# I might just split a seam now #
# if I don't die laughin' first #
# Mr. Oogie Boogie says #
# there's trouble close at hand #
# You better #
# pay attention now #
# 'Cause I'm #
# the Boogie Man #
# And if you #
# aren't shakin' #
# There's somethin' #
# very wrong #
# 'Cause this may be the last time #
# you hear the Boogie song #
- # Whoa-oh #
- # Wah-ah #
- # Whoa-ho #
- # Ow #
- # Whoa-oh #
- # Wow #
# I'm the Oogie Boogie Man #
# Release me now or you must #
# face the dire consequences #
# The children are expecting me #
# so please, come to your senses #
# Ah, you're jokin' #
# You're jokin' #
# I can't believe #
# my ears #
# Would someone #
# shut this fella up #
# I'm drownin' #
# in my tears #
# He's funny #
# I'm laughin' #
# You really are #
# too much #
# And now #
# with your permission #
- # I'm goin' to do my stuff #
- What are you going to do?
I'm gonna do
the best I can.
# Whoa #
# The sound of rolling dice #
# to me is music in the air #
# 'Cause I'm a gamblin' Boogie Man #
# although I don't play fair #
# It's much more fun #
# I must confess #
# With lives on the line #
# Not mine, of course #
# But yours, old boy #
# Now that'd be #
# just fine #
# Release me fast or you will #
# have to answer for this heinous act #
# Oh, brother, you're somethin' #
# You put me in a spin #
# You aren't comprehending #
# the position that you're in #
# It's hopeless You're finished #
# You haven't got a prayer #
# 'Cause I'm #
# Mr. Oogie Boogie #
# And you ain't goin' #
# nowhere #
Hurray! It's Jack!
Think of us as you soar
triumphantly through the sky,
outshining every star;
your silhouette,
a dark blot on the moon.
You, who are our pride.
You, who are our glory.
- You, who have frightened
millions into an early grave.
- Ow!
You, who have, uh,
devastated the, the souls
of the... living?
Oh, no! We can't take off in this.
- The reindeer can't see an inch
in front of their noses.
- Phew!
This fog's
as thick as, as--
- Jellied brains.
- Or thicker!
- There go all of my hopes,
- Oh!
My precious plans,
my glorious dreams.
There goes Christmas.
No, Zero. Down, boy.
My, what a brilliant
nose you have.
The better
to light my way!
To the head of the team, Zero.
We're off!
Wait, Jack! No!
Ho-ho-ho!
Ha-ha-ha-ha-ho!
Good-bye, Jack.
My dearest Jack.
Oh, how I hope
my premonition is wrong.
# I sense there's something #
# in the wind #
# That feels like #
# tragedy's at hand #
# And though I'd like #
# to stand by him #
# Can't shake this feeling #
# that I have #
# The worst is #
# just around the bend #
# And does he notice #
# My feelings for him #
# And will he see #
# How much #
# he means to me #
# I think #
# it's not to be #
# What will become #
# of my dear friend #
# Where will his actions #
# lead us then #
# Although I'd like #
# to join the crowd #
# In their #
# enthusiastic cloud #
# Try as I may #
# it doesn't last #
# And will we ever #
# End up together #
# No, I think not #
# It's never to become #
# For I am not #
# the one #
Ho-ho-ho!
Ho-ho-ho-ho!
Hee-hee-hee-hee-hee!
Santa!
Santa?
Merry Christmas!
And what is your name?
- Uh, uh, uh, uh--
- That's all right.
I have a special present
for you anyway.
There you go, sonny.
Ho-ho-ho-ho!
Hee-hee-hee-hee-hee!
And what did Santa
bring you, honey?
Merry Christmas!
Hello. Police.
Attacked by Christmas toys?
That's strange. That's the second
toy complaint we've had.
Ho-ho-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha!
Ho-ho-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha!
Huh?
Oh, wait!
Whoa! Help! Help!
You're welcome,
one and all!
Where'd you spot him?
Fast as we can, ma'am.
Police. I know, I know,
a skeleton. Keep calm.
Turn off all the lights. Make sure
the doors are locked. Hello. Police.
Reports are pouring in from all over
the globe that an impostor...
is shamelessly impersonating Santa Claus,
mocking and mangling this joyous holiday.
Authorities assure us
that at this moment...
military units are mobilizing to stop
the perpetrator of this heinous crime.
- Jack. Someone has to help Jack.
- ...wherever you are,
- Where'd they take that Sandy Claws?
- Come back and save Christmas.
Look, Zero,
searchlights.
They're celebrating!
They're thanking us
for doing such a good job.
Whoa! Careful down there!
You almost hit us!
It's okay, Zero!
Head higher!
Are you a gamblin' man,
Sandy? Let's play!
Hmm?
My, my!
What have we here?
Hmm.
I'll get you out of here.
Ah! Lovely.
Tickle, tickle, tickle.
Tickle, tickle, tickle!
What? You try to make
a dupe out of me?
Who's next
on my list?
Ah, little Harry and Jordan.
Won't they be surprised?
They're trying to hit us. Zero!
Merry Christmas
to all...
and to all
a good night!
I knew this Christmas
thing was a bad idea.
I felt it in my gut.
Terrible news, folks!
The worst tragedy
of our times!
Jack has been blown
to smithereens!
Terrible, terrible news!
Attention.
Attention, citizens.
Terrible news.
There's still no sign
of Santa Claus.
Although the impostor
has been shot down,
it looks like Christmas will have to
be canceled this year.
I repeat, the impostor
has been shot down,
but there's
still no sign of Santa.
# What have I done #
# How could I #
# Be so blind #
# All is lost #
# Where was I #
# Spoiled all #
# Everything's #
# Gone all wrong #
# What have I done #
# Find a deep cave #
# to hide in #
# In a million years #
# They'll find me #
# Only dust #
# And a plaque #
# that reads #
# Here lies #
# poor old Jack #
# But I never intended #
# all this madness #
# Never #
# And nobody #
# really understood #
# Well, how could they #
# That all #
# I ever wanted #
# Was to bring them #
# something great #
# Why does nothing ever #
# turn out like it should #
# Well, what the heck #
# I went and did my best #
# And, by God #
# I really tasted #
# Something swell #
# And for a moment #
# why, I even touched the sky #
# And at least I left #
# some stories they can tell I did #
# And for the first time since #
# I don't remember when #
# I felt just like #
# my old bony self again #
# And I, Jack #
# The Pumpkin King #
# That's right #
# I am the Pumpkin King # Ha-ha-ha! #
# And I just can't wait #
# until next Halloween #
# 'Cause I've got #
# some new ideas #
# That will really #
# make them scream #
# And, by God, I'm really going #
# to give it all my might #
Uh-oh. I hope
there's still time...
to set things right.
- Sandy Claws.
- Hmm.
You wait till Jack
hears about this!
By the time he's through with you,
you'll be lucky if you--
The King of Halloween...
has been blown
to smithereens!
Skeleton Jack...
is now a pile of dust!
C'mon, Zero! Christmas isn't over yet.
What's that you said
about luck, rag doll?
Help! Help! Help!
Shhh!
Seven!
It's Oogie's turn
to boogie now.
One... two... three... four...
five, six, seven.
This can't be happening.
Ashes to ashes,
and dust to dust.
Oh! I'm feeling weak...
with hunger!
One more roll of the dice oughta do it.
What?
Snake eyes?
Eleven!
Looks like I won
the jackpot!
Bye-bye, doll face...
and sandman!
What the--
Hello, Oogie.
J-J-J-Jack!
But they said you were dead.
You must be...
double dead!
Oh!
Well, come on,
bone man!
Ooh-hoo-hoo-hoo! Ha!
Fire!
Ooooh!
Jack, look out!
So long, Jack!
How dare you treat my friends...
so shamefully!
No, no, no, no, Jack!
Now look what
you've done!
My bugs!
My bugs! My bugs! My bugs!
My bugs! My bugs!
My bugs!
Forgive me,
Mr. Claws.
- I'm afraid I've made a terrible mess of your holiday.
- Bumpy sleigh ride, Jack?
The next time you get the urge to take over
someone else's holiday, I'd listen to her.
She's the only one who makes any sense
around this insane asylum!
- Skeletons, boogie men--
- I hope there's still time.
To fix Christmas?
Of course there is!
I'm Santa Claus!
He'll fix things, Jack.
He knows what to do.
- How did you get down here, Sally?
- Oh, I-I was trying to--
- Well, I wanted to, to--
- To help me.
- I couldn't let you just--
- Sally.
I can't believe I never
realized that you--
Jack! Jack!
- Here he is!
- Alive! Just like we said!
Grab ahold, my boy!
Whoa!
Good news, folks.
Santa Claus, the one and only,
has finally been spotted.
Old Saint Nick appears to be traveling
at supersonic speed.
He's setting things right,
bringing joy and cheer
wherever he goes.
Yes, Kriss Kringle has pulled it out
of the bag and delivered Christmas...
to excited children all over the world.
# La la la la #
# la la-la-la #
- Jack's back!
- Jack?
- Jack's okay!
- He's all right!
# Jack's okay #
# and he's back #
- # Oh, yea #
- # He's all right #
# Let's shout #
# Make a fuss #
# Scream it out #
# Wheee #
# Jack is back now #
# Everyone sing #
# In the town #
# of Halloween #
- It's great to be home!
- Ho-ho-ho-ho!
Happy Halloween!
Merry Christmas!
- What's this?
- # What's this #
# I haven't got #
# a clue #
- # What's this #
- # Why, it's completely new #
- # Must be a Christmas thing #
- # What's this #
# It's really #
# very strange #
# This is Halloween #
# Halloween, Halloween #
# Halloween #
# What's this, what's this #
Careful,
my precious jewel.
# My dearest friend #
# if you don't mind #
# I'd like to join you #
# by your side #
# Where we can gaze #
# Into the stars #
# And sit together #
# Now and forever #
# For it is plain #
# As anyone can see #
# We're simply #
# meant to be #