Morning in Paris
The city awakes
To the bells of Notre Dame
The fisherman fishes
The baker man bakes
To the bells of Notre Dame
To the big bells as loud as the thunder
To the little bells soft as a psalm
And some say the soul
of the city's the toll
Of the bells
The bells of Notre Dame
Listen. They're beautiful, no?
So many colours of sound,
so many changing moods.
Because you know they don't
ring all by themselves.
-They don't?
-No, you silly boy.
Up there, high,
high in the dark bell tower,
lives the mysterious bell ringer.
-Who is this creature?
-Who?
-What is he?
-What?
-How did he come to be there?
-How?
Hush.
Clopin will tell you.
lt is a tale, a tale of a man...
And a monster.
Dark was the night
when our tale was begun
On the docks near Notre Dame
-Shut it up, will you?
-We'll be spotted!
Hush, little one.
Four frightened gypsies
slid silently under
The docks near Notre Dame
Four guilders
for safe passage into Paris.
A trap had been laid for the gypsies
And they gazed up in fear and alarm
At a figure whose clutches
Were iron as much as the bells
Judge Claude Frollo!
The bells of Notre Dame
Kyrie eleison
Judge Claude Frollo longed to purge
the world of vice and sin
Kyrie eleison
And he saw corruption
Everywhere except within
Bring these gypsy vermin
to the palace ofjustice.
You there! What are you hiding?
Stolen goods, no doubt.
Take them from her.
She ran.
Dies irae
Dies illa
Solvet saeclum in favilla
Quantus tremor est futurus
Quando judex est venturus
Sanctuary! Please, give us sanctuary!
Quantus tremor est futurus
Dies irae
A baby?
A monster!
Solvet saeclum in favilla
Dies irae
"Stop!" cried the archdeacon.
This is an unholy demon.
l'm sending it back to hell,
where it belongs.
See, there, the innocent blood
you have spilt
On the steps of Notre Dame
l am guiltless. She ran. l pursued.
Now you would add this child's
blood to your guilt
On the steps of Notre Dame
My conscience is clear.
You can lie to yourself
and your minions
You can claim that you haven't a qualm
But you never can run from
Nor hide what you've done
from the eyes
The very eyes
Of Notre Dame
Kyrie eleison
And for one time in his life
Of power and control
Kyrie eleison
Frollo felt a twinge of fear
for his immortal soul
What must l do?
Care for the child
and raise it as your own.
What? l am to be saddled
with this misshapen...
Very well.
But let him live with you in your church.
Live here? Where?
Anywhere.
Just so he's kept locked away
where no one else can see
The bell tower, perhaps.
And who knows? Our Lord works
in mysterious ways.
Even this foul creature
may yet prove one day to be
Of use to me
And Frollo gave the child a cruel name,
a name that means "half-formed."
Quasimodo.
Now here is a riddle to guess if you can
Sing the bells of Notre Dame
Who is the monster and who is the man
Sing the bells, bells
Bells, bells
Bells of Notre Dame
Good morning.
Will today be the day?
Are you ready to fly?
You sure? Good day to try.
Why, if l picked a day to fly,
this would be it.
The Festival of Fools.
lt will be fun with jugglers
and music and dancing.
Go on. Nobody wants
to be cooped up here forever.
Man!
l thought he'd never leave.
l'll be spittin' feathers for a week.
Well, that's what you get
for sleeping with your mouth open.
Go scare a nun.
Hey, Quasi, what's goin' on out there?
A fight? A flogging?
-A festival.
-You mean a Feast of Fools?
All right, all right!
Pour the wine and cut the cheese.
It is a treat to watch the colourful
pageantry of the simple peasant folk.
Boy, nothin' like balcony seats
for watching the ol' FOF.
Yeah, watchin'.
Look. A mime.
Hey, hey, hey, hey. What gives?
Aren't you
going to watch the festival with us?
-I don't get it.
-Perhaps he's sick.
Impossible.
If 20 years of listenin' to you two hasn't
made him sick by now, nothin' will.
Watching the Festival of Fools
has always been the highlight
of the year for Quasimodo.
What good is watchin' the party
if you never get to go?
Here, get away from me!
Go on, ya bunch of buzzards!
He's not made of stone, like us.
Quasi, what's wrong?
You want to tell ol' Laverne all about it?
I just don't feel
like watching the festival, that's all.
Well, did ya ever think
of goin' there instead?
Sure. But I'd never fit in out there.
I'm not normal.
Quasi, Quasi, Quasi.
Do ya mind?
I would like to have a moment
with the boy, if it's all right with you!
Hey, quit beatin' around the bell tower.
What do we gotta do, paint ya a fresco?
As your friends and guardians,
we insist you attend the festival.
-Me?
-No, the pope. Of course, you!
It would be a veritable potpourri
of educational experience.
Wine, women and song.
You can learn to identify
various regional cheeses.
-Bobbin' for snails.
-Study indigenous folk music.
Playin' dunk the monk!
Quasi, take it from an old spectator.
Life's not a spectator sport.
Ifwatchin' is all you're gonna do,
then you're gonna watch
your life go by without ya.
Yeah, you're human, with the flesh
and the hair and the navel lint.
We're just part of the architecture.
Right, Victor?
Yet, if you kick us, will we not flake?
If you moisten us,
do we not grow moss?
Quasi, just grab a fresh tunic
and a clean pair of hose, and...
Thanks for the encouragement.
But you're all forgetting one big thing.
What?
My master, Frollo.
Yeah. Oh, dear, yes.
Well, when he says you're forbidden
from ever leaving the bell tower,
does he mean "ever," ever?
Never ever.
And he hates the Feast of Fools.
-He'd be furious if I asked to go.
-Who says ya gotta ask?
-Oh, no.
-Ya sneak out.
-It's just one afternoon.
-I couldn't.
And ya sneak back in.
-He'll never know you were gone.
-And if I got caught?
Better to beg forgiveness
than ask permission.
He might see me.
You could wear a disguise.
Just this once.
What Frollo doesn't know can't hurt ya.
-Ignorance is bliss.
-Look who's talkin'.
Nobody wants to stay
cooped up here forever.
You're right. I'll go.
-I'll get cleaned up.
-Yes, sir!
-I'll stroll down those stairs.
-There ya go!
I'll march through the doors and...
Good morning, Quasimodo.
Good morning, Master.
Dear boy, whomever are you talking to?
My friends.
I see. And what are your
friends made of, Quasimodo?
Stone.
-Can stone talk?
-No, it can't.
That's right. You're a smart lad.
Now, lunch.
Shall we review your alphabet today?
Yes, Master.
I would like that very much.
-Very well. "A"?
-Abomination.
-"B"?
-Blasphemy.
-"C"?
-Contrition.
-"D"?
-Damnation.
-"E"?
-Eternal damnation.
-Good. "F"?
-Festival.
-Excuse me?
-Forgiveness.
-You said, "Festival."
-No!
You are thinking
about going to the festival.
It's just that you go every year.
I am a public official. I must go.
But I don't enjoy a moment.
Thieves and cutpurses,
the dregs of humankind,
all mixed together
in a shallow, drunken stupor.
I didn't mean to upset you, Master.
Quasimodo, can't you understand?
When your heartless mother
abandoned you as a child,
anyone else would have drowned you.
And this is my thanks for taking you in
and raising you as my son?
I'm sorry, sir.
My dear Quasimodo.
You don't know what it's like out there.
I do. I do.
The world is cruel
The world is wicked
lt's l alone whom you can
trust in this whole city
l am your only friend
l, who keep you, teach you
feed you, dress you
l, who look upon you without fear
How can l protect you, boy
Unless you always stay in here
Away in here
Remember what
I've taught you, Quasimodo.
-You are deformed
-l am deformed
-And you are ugly
-And l am ugly
And these are crimes
for which the world shows little pity
You do not comprehend
You are my one defender
Out there they'll
revile you as a monster
l am a monster
Out there they
will hate and scorn and jeer
Only a monster
Why invite their calumny
and consternation
Stay in here
-Be faithful to me
-l'm faithful
-Grateful to me
-l'm grateful
Do as l say
Obey
-And stay in here
-l'll stay in here
You are good to me, Master.
-I'm sorry.
-You are forgiven.
But, remember, Quasimodo,
this is your sanctuary.
My sanctuary.
Safe behind these windows
and these parapets of stone
Gazing at the people down below me
All my life, l watch them
as l hide up here alone
Hungry for the histories they show me
All my life l memorize their faces
Knowing them
as they will never know me
All my life, l wonder
how it feels to pass a day
Not above them
But part of them
And out there
Living in the sun
Give me one day out there
All l ask is one
To hold forever
Out there
Where they all live unaware
What l'd give
What l'd dare
Just to live
One day
Out there
Out there among the millers
and the weavers and their wives
Through the roofs and gables
l can see them
Every day they shout and scold
and go about their lives
Heedless of the gift it is to be them
lf l was in their skin
l'd treasure
Every instant
Out there
Strolling by the Seine
Taste the morning out there
Like ordinary men
Who freely walk about there
Just one day and then
l swear l'll be content
With my share
Won't resent
Won't despair
Old and bent
l won't care
l'll have spent
One day
Out there
You leave town for a couple of decades,
and they change everything.
Excuse me, gentlemen, I'm looking for
the palace ofjustice. Would you...
I guess not.
Stay away, child. They're gypsies.
They'll steal us blind.
All right, gypsy.
-Where'd ya get the money?
-For your information, I earned it.
-Gypsies don't earn money.
-They steal it.
You'd know a lot about stealing.
Troublemaker, eh?
Maybe a day in the stocks
will cool ya down.
Come back here, gypsy!
Achilles, sit.
Oh, dear, I'm sorry.
Naughty horse! Naughty!
He's just impossible.
Really, I can't take him anywhere.
Get this thing off me!
I'll teach you a lesson, peasant!
You were saying, Lieutenant?
Captain!
At your service, sir!
I know you have a lot
on your mind right now,
but the palace ofjustice?
-Make way for the captain!
-Go on, make way!
Make way!
-Everybody out of the way!
-You, make way for the captain!
-Make way!
-Make way, now!
Come on, boy. Achilles, heel!
-Stop.
-Sir?
Ease up. Wait between lashes.
Otherwise the old sting
will dull him to the new.
Yes, sir.
So this is the gallant Captain Phoebus,
home from the wars.
Reporting for duty, as ordered, sir.
Your service record
precedes you, Phoebus.
I expect nothing but the best
from a war hero of your calibre.
And you shall have it, sir. I guarantee it.
Yes.
You know, my last captain of the guard
was a bit of a disappointment to me.
Well, no matter.
I'm sure you'll whip my men into shape.
Thank you.
It's a tremendous honour, sir.
You've come to Paris
in her darkest hour, Captain.
It will take a firm hand
to save the weak-minded
-from being so easily misled.
-Misled, sir?
Look, Captain. Gypsies.
The gypsies live outside
the normal order.
Their heathen ways inflame
the people's lowest instincts.
And they must be stopped.
I was summoned from the wars
to capture fortune tellers
and palm readers?
The real war, Captain,
is what you see before you.
For 20 years, I have been
taking care of the gypsies,
one by one.
And yet, for all my success,
they have thrived.
I believe they have a safe haven
within the walls of this very city.
A nest, if you will.
They call it the court of miracles.
What are we going to do about it, sir?
You make your point quite vividly, sir.
You know, I like you, Captain. Shall we?
Duty calls.
Have you ever attended
a peasant festival, Captain?
Not recently, sir.
Then this should be
quite an education for you.
Come along.
Come, one
Come, all
Leave your looms and milking stools
Coop the hens and pen the mules
Come, one
Come, all
Close the churches and the schools
lt's the day for breaking rules
Come and join the Feast Of Fools
Once a year we throw
a party here in town
Once a year we turn
all Paris upside-down
Every man's a king
and every king's a clown
Once again it's topsy-turvy day
lt's the day the devil in us gets released
lt's the day we mock the prig
and shock the priest
Everything is topsy-turvy
at the Feast of Fools
Topsy-turvy
-Everything is upsy-daisy
-Topsy-turvy
Everyone is acting crazy
Dross is gold and weeds are a bouquet
That's the way on topsy-turvy day
Hey! Are you all right?
I didn't mean to. I'm sorry.
Well, you're not hurt, are you?
Here, here, let's see.
-No, no! No!
-There.
See? No harm done.
Just try to be a little more careful.
I will.
By the way, great mask.
-Topsy-turvy
-Beat the drums and blow the trumpets
Topsy-turvy
Join the bums
and thieves and strumpets
Streaming in from Chartres to Calais
Scurvy knaves are extra scurvy
on the sixth of Januervy
All because it's topsy-turvy day
Come, one
Come, all
Hurry, hurry
Here's your chance
See the mystery and romance
Come, one
Come, all
See the finest girl in France
Make an entrance to entrance
Dance la Esmeralda
Dance
-Look at that disgusting display.
-Yes, sir.
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
the pièce de résistance!
Here it is
The moment you've been waiting for
You know exactly what's in store
Now's the time we laugh
until our sides get sore
Now's the time
we crown the king of fools
You all remember last year's king
So make a face that's
horrible and frightening
Make a face that's gruesome
as a gargoyle's wing
Hey!
For the face that's ugliest
will be the king of fools
Why?
Topsy-turvy
-Ugly folks forget your shyness
-Topsy-turvy
You could soon be called
your highness
Put your foulest features on display
Be the king of topsy-turvy day
-That's no mask.
-It's his face!
He's hideous!
It's the bell ringer from Notre Dame!
Ladies and gentlemen, don't panic.
We asked for the ugliest face in Paris,
and here it is!
Quasimodo,
the hunchback of Notre Dame!
Everybody!
Once a year we throw a party
-Here in town
-Hail to the king
Once a year
we turn all Paris upside-down
What a king
Once a year
the ugliest will wear a crown
Girls, give a kiss.
We never had a king like this
And it's the day we do
the things that we deplore
On the other three hundred
and sixty-four
Once a year we love to drop in
where the beer is never stopping
For the chance to pop some popinjay
And pick a king who put the "top"
ln topsy-turvy
Topsy-turvy
Mad-and-crazy upsy-daisy
Topsy-turvy day
Quasimodo! Quasimodo!
You think he's ugly now? Watch this.
Quasimodo!
Now that's ugly!
Hail to the king!
Bon appétit!
-Where are you goin', hunchback?
-The fun's just beginning.
Master!
Master, please, help me!
Sir, request permission
to stop this cruelty.
In a moment, Captain.
A lesson needs to be learned here.
Don't be afraid.
I'm sorry.
This wasn't supposed to happen.
You! Gypsy girl!
Get down at once!
Yes, your honour.
Just as soon as I free this poor creature.
I forbid it!
How dare you defy me?
You mistreat this poor boy
the same way you mistreat my people.
You speak ofjustice, yet you are cruel
to those most in need of your help.
-Silence!
-Justice!
Mark my words, gypsy.
You will pay for this insolence.
Then it appears
we've crowned the wrong fool.
The only fool I see is you!
Captain Phoebus, arrest her.
Now, let's see.
One, two, three, four, five,
six, seven, eight, nine.
So there's ten of you and one of me.
What's a poor girl to do?
Witchcraft!
Oh, boys. Over here.
-There she is!
-Get her!
I'm free! I'm free!
Dang it.
What a woman.
Find her, Captain. I want her alive.
Yes, sir. Seal off the area, men.
Find the gypsy girl
and do not harm her.
I'm sorry, Master.
I will never disobey you again.
Stand back. Stand back.
Oh, he's hideous.
You, there, get away! Move on.
You!
Easy, easy. I just shaved this morning.
-Oh, really? You missed a spot.
-All right, all right.
Just calm down.
Just give me a chance to apologize.
-For what?
-That, for example.
You sneaky son of a...
Watch it. You're in a church.
Are you always this charming,
or am I just lucky?
Candlelight, privacy, music.
Can't think of a better place
for hand-to-hand combat.
You fight almost as well as a man.
Funny, I was going to say
the same thing about you.
That's hitting a little below the belt,
don't you think?
No. This is.
Touché.
-I didn't know you had a kid.
-Well, he doesn't take kindly to soldiers.
I noticed.
Permit me.
I'm Phoebus. It means "sun god."
-And you are?
-Is this an interrogation?
I believe it's called an introduction.
-You're not arresting me?
-Not as long as you're in here. I can't.
You're not at all like the other soldiers.
Thank you.
So, if you're not going to arrest me,
what do you want?
I'd settle for your name.
-Esmeralda.
-Beautiful.
Much better than Phoebus, anyway.
Good work, Captain. Now arrest her.
Claim "sanctuary."
-Say it!
-You tricked me.
I'm waiting, Captain.
I'm sorry, sir. She claimed sanctuary.
There's nothing I can do.
Then drag her outside and...
Frollo, you will not touch her!
Don't worry.
Minister Frollo learned years ago
to respect the sanctity of the church.
All right, all right. I'm going.
You think you've outwitted me.
But I'm a patient man.
And gypsies don't do well
inside stone walls.
What are you doing?
I was just imagining a rope
around that beautiful neck.
I know what you were imagining.
Such a clever witch.
So typical of your kind to twist the truth.
To cloud the mind with unholy thoughts.
Well, no matter.
You've chosen a magnificent prison.
But it is a prison, nonetheless.
Set one foot outside, and you're mine.
Frollo's orders.
Post a guard at every door.
Don't worry, Djali.
If Frollo thinks he can keep us here,
he's wrong.
Don't act rashly, my child.
You created quite a stir at the festival.
It would be unwise to arouse
Frollo's anger further.
You saw what he did out there,
letting the crowd torture that poor boy.
I thought ifjust one person
could stand up to him, then...
What do they have against people
who are different, anyway?
You can't right
all the wrongs of this world by yourself.
No one out there is going to help,
that's for sure.
Well, perhaps there's
someone in here who can.
l don't know if You can hear me
Or if You're even there
l don't know if You would listen
To a gypsy's prayer
Yes, l know l'm just an outcast
l shouldn't speak to You
Still, l see your face and wonder
Were You once an outcast, too?
God help the outcasts
Hungry from birth
Show them the mercy
They don't find on earth
God help my people
We look to You still
God help the outcasts
Or nobody will
l ask for wealth
l ask for fame
l ask for glory
To shine on my name
l ask for love
l can possess
l ask for God and His angels
To bless me
l ask for nothing
l can get by
But l know so many
Less lucky than l
Please help my people
The poor and downtrod
l thought we all were
The children of God
God help the outcasts
Children of
God
You! Bell ringer!
What are you doing down here?
Haven't you caused
enough trouble already?
Wait.
I want to talk to you.
Look, he's got a friend with him.
Yeah. Maybe today wasn't
a total loss after all.
-A vision of loveliness.
-The one in the dress ain't bad either.
-Way to go, Quasi!
-Congratulations.
-We knew you had it in ya.
-Got the girls chasin' ya already.
Actually, I...
You mustn't run too fast,
or she'll get away.
Yes, I know. That's what I...
Give her some slack, then reel her in.
Then give her some slack,
then reel her in.
-Then give her some slack...
-Knock it off, Hugo.
She's a girl, not a mackerel.
Here you are. I was afraid I'd lost you.
Yes. Well, I...
I have chores to do.
It was nice seeing you again.
No, wait!
I'm really sorry about this afternoon.
I had no idea who you were.
I would never in my life
have pulled you...
Up on the...
Stage.
-What is this place?
-This is where I live.
Did you make all these things yourself?
Most of them.
This is beautiful.
If I could do this, you wouldn't find me
dancing in the streets for coins.
But you're a wonderful dancer.
It keeps bread on the table, anyway.
What's this?
No, please! I'm not finished.
I still have to paint them.
It's the blacksmith and the baker!
You're a surprising person, Quasimodo.
Not to mention lucky.
All this room to yourself.
Well, it's notjust me.
There's the gargoyles
and, of course, the bells.
-Would you like to see them?
-Yes, of course. Wouldn't we, Djali?
Follow me. I'll introduce you.
-I never knew there were so many.
-That's Little Sophia.
And Jeane-Marie,
Anne-Marie, Louise-Marie.
Triplets, you know.
-And who's this?
-Big Marie.
Hello!
She likes you.
Would you like to see more?
How about it, Djali?
-We'd love to.
-Good.
I've saved the best for last.
I bet the king himself
doesn't have a view like this.
-I could stay up here forever.
-You could, you know.
No, I couldn't.
-Oh, yes, you have sanctuary.
-But not freedom.
"Gypsies don't do well
inside stone walls."
But you're not like other gypsies.
They are evil.
-Who told you that?
-My master, Frollo.
He raised me.
How can such a cruel man have
raised someone like you?
Cruel? Oh, no.
He saved my life.
He took me in when no one else would.
-I am a monster, you know.
-He told you that?
Look at me.
-Give me your hand. Just let me see it.
-What?
A long lifeline.
And this one means you're shy.
-Well, that's funny.
-What?
-I don't see any...
-Any what?
Monster lines. Not a single one.
Now you look at me.
Do you think I'm evil?
No! No, no.
You are kind and good and...
And a gypsy. And maybe Frollo's wrong
about the both of us.
What did she say?
Frollo's nose is long,
and he wears a truss.
Told ya! Pay up.
-Oh, dear.
-Chump.
You helped me. Now I will help you.
But there's no way out.
There are soldiers at every door.
We won't use a door.
-You mean, climb down?
-Sure.
-You carry him. I carry you.
-Okay.
Come on, Djali.
-Ready?
-Yes.
-Don't be afraid.
-I'm not afraid.
-Now I'm afraid.
-The trick is not to look down.
You've done this before?
No.
Wow, you're quite an acrobat.
Thank you.
-Check the alley!
-This way!
-I hope I didn't scare you.
-Not for an instant.
I'll never forget you, Esmeralda.
-Come with me.
-What?
To the court of miracles.
Leave this place.
Oh, no.
I'm never going back out there again.
You saw what happened today.
No. This is where I belong.
All right, then I'll come to see you.
-Here? But the soldiers and Frollo!
-I'll come after sunset.
But at sunset, I ring the evening mass,
and after that I clean the cloisters.
And then I ring the vespers, and...
Whatever is good for you.
If you ever need sanctuary,
this will show you the way.
-But how?
-Just remember.
When you wear this woven band,
you hold the city in your hand.
Hurry. You must go.
Check the alley.
Yes, sir. No one here, sir.
No one here, sir.
Check the street.
Hi, there.
I'm looking for the gypsy girl.
Have you seen her?
-Whoa, whoa! Easy!
-No soldiers! Sanctuary! Get out!
-Wait! All I want is to...
-Go!
I mean her no harm.
Go!
You tell her for me,
I didn't mean to trap her here.
But it was the only way
I could save her life.
Will you tell her that? Will you?
If you go. Now.
I'll go.
Now, will you put me down, please?
And one more thing.
-Tell Esmeralda she's very lucky.
-Why?
To have a friend like you.
Hey, there he is.
You ejected that tin-plated buffoon
with great panache.
The nerve of him, snoopin' around here,
tryin' to steal your girl.
-My girl?
-Esmeralda.
Dark hair,
works with a goat, remember?
Boy, I do. Way to go, lover boy.
"Lover boy"? Oh, no, no, no, no.
Don't be so modest.
Look, I appreciate
what you're all trying to do.
But let's not fool ourselves.
"Ugliest face in all Paris," remember?
I don't think I'm her type.
So many times out there
l've watched a happy pair
Of lovers walking in the night
They had a kind of glow around them
lt almost looked like heaven's light
l knew l'd never know
That warm and loving glow
Though l might wish with all my might
No face as hideous as my face
Was ever meant for heaven's light
But suddenly an angel has
smiled at me
And kissed my cheek
without a trace of fright
l dare to dream that she
Might even care for me
And as l ring these bells tonight
My cold dark tower seems so bright
l swear it must be heaven's light
Confiteor Deo
Omnipotenti
Beatae Mariae
Semper Virgini
Beato Michaeli archangelo
Sanctis apostolis
Omnibus
Sanctis
Beata Maria
You know l am a righteous man
-Of my virtue l am justly proud
-Et tibit Pater
Beata Maria
You know l'm so much purer than
The common, vulgar, weak
licentious crowd
Quia peccavi nimis
Then tell me, Maria
Why l see her dancing there
Why her smouldering eyes
still scorch my soul
Cogitatione
l feel her, l see her
The sun caught in her raven hair
ls blazing in me out of all control
Verbo et opere
Like fire
Hellfire
This fire in my skin
This burning desire
ls turning me to sin
-lt's not my fault
-Mea culpa
-l'm not to blame
lt is the gypsy girl
The witch who sent this flame
Mea maxima culpa
-lt's not my fault if in God's plan
-Mea culpa
Mea Culpa
He made the devil so much
stronger than a man
Protect me, Maria
Don't let this siren cast her spell
Don't let her fire
sear my flesh and bone
Destroy Esmeralda
And let her taste the fires of hell
Or else let her be mine and mine alone
Minister Frollo, the gypsy has escaped.
-What?
-She's nowhere in the cathedral.
-She's gone.
-But how? Never mind.
Get out, you idiot. I'll find her.
I'll find her if I have to
burn down all of Paris.
Hellfire
Dark fire
Now, gypsy
lt's your turn
Choose me or your pyre
Be mine or you will burn
-Kyrie eleison
-God have mercy on her
-God have mercy on me
-Kyrie eleison
-But she will be mine
Or she
Will
Burn
'Tention!
Good morning, sir.
-Are you feeling all right?
-I had a little trouble with the fireplace.
-I see. Your orders, sir?
-Find the gypsy girl.
Ten pieces of silver
for the gypsy, Esmeralda.
Lock them up.
Twenty pieces of silver
for the gypsy, Esmeralda.
Take them away!
-Poor miller.
-He's never harmed anyone!
Frollo's gone mad.
We found this gypsy talisman
on your property.
Have you been harbouring gypsies?
Our home is always open
to the weary traveller.
Have mercy, my lord.
I am placing you and your family
under house arrest
until I get to the bottom of this.
Ifwhat you say is true
and you are innocent,
then you have nothing to fear.
But we are innocent. I assure you,
we know nothing of these gypsies.
-Burn it.
-What?
Until it smoulders.
These people are traitors
and must be made examples of.
With all due respect, sir, I was
not trained to murder the innocent.
But you were trained to follow orders.
Insolent coward.
The sentence
for insubordination is death.
Such a pity.
You threw away a promising career.
Consider it my highest honour, sir.
Get him! And don't hit my horse!
Don't waste your arrows.
Let the traitor rot in his watery grave.
Find the girl.
If you have to burn the city
to the ground, so be it.
Kyrie eleison
Sir, we've looked everywhere
and still no sign of the gypsy girl.
I had the entire cathedral surrounded.
Guards at every door. There was
no way she could have escaped.
Unless...
It doesn't look good.
-It's hopeless. Absolutely hopeless.
-You're tellin' me.
I'm losin' to a bird!
But that poor gypsy girl.
I'm beginning to fear the worst.
I know. But now don't you say
anything to upset Quasimodo.
He's worried enough already.
Yeah, you're right. We better lighten up.
-Here he comes.
-Nowjust stay calm.
-Not a word.
-Easy does it.
-Stone-faced.
-Any sign of her?
It's a lost cause!
She could be anywhere!
In the stocks,
in the dungeon, on the rack!
-Nice work, Victor.
-No, he's right. What are we gonna do?
What are you guys talkin' about?
If I know Esmeralda,
she's three steps ahead of Frollo
and well out of harm's way.
Do you really think so?
Hey, when things cool off,
she'll be back. You'll see.
-What makes you so sure?
-Because she likes ya.
We always said you were the cute one.
I thought I was the cute one.
No, you're the fat, stupid one
with the big mouth!
What are you sayin', exactly?
Take it from us, Quasi.
You got nothin' to worry about.
Yeah. You're irresistible.
Knights in shining armour
certainly aren't her type.
And those guys are a dime a dozen.
But you, you're one of a kind. Look.
Paris, the city of lovers
is glowing this evening
True, that's because it's on fire
But still there's l'amour
Somewhere out there in the night
Her heart is also alight
And l know the guy
she just might be burning for
A guy like you
She's never known, kid
A girl does not meet every day
You've got a look
That's all your own, kid
Could there be two?
Like you?
No way
Those other guys
That she could dangle
All look the same from every
boring point of view
You're a surprise
From every angle
Mon Dieu above
She's gotta love a guy like you
A guy like you
Gets extra credit
Because it's true you've got
a certain something more
You're aces, kid.
You see that face
Ya don't forget it
Want something new
That's you.
For sure
We all have gaped at some Adonis
But then we crave a meal
more nourishing to chew
And since you're shaped
Like a croissant is
No question of
she's gotta love a guy like you
Call me a hopeless romantic
But Quasi
l feel it
She wants you so
Any moment she'll walk
through that door
For
A guy so swell
A guy like you with all you bring her
A fool could tell it's why she fell
For you-know-who
You'll ring the bell
You're the bell ringer
When she wants ooh-la-la
And she wants you-la-la
She will discover, guy
You're one heck of a guy
Who wouldn't love a guy
Like You
-You got a lot
-The rest have not
She's gotta love a guy like you
Quasi?
Quasimodo?
Esmeralda?
Esmeralda, you're all right!
I knew you'd come back!
You've done so much
for me already, my friend.
But I must ask your help one more time.
Yes, anything.
This is Phoebus.
He's wounded and a fugitive like me.
He can't go on much longer.
I knew he'd be safe here.
Please, can you hide him?
This way.
Esmeralda.
You'll hide here
until you're strong enough to move.
Great. I could use a drink.
Yes.
Feels like a 1470 burgundy.
Not a good year.
That family owes you their lives.
You're either the single bravest soldier
I've ever seen or the craziest.
Ex-soldier, remember?
Why is it, whenever we meet,
I end up bleeding?
You're lucky.
That arrow almost pierced your heart.
I'm not so sure it didn't.
l knew l'd never know
that warm and loving glow
Though l might wish with all my might
No face as hideous as my face
Was ever meant for heaven's light
Frollo's coming. You must leave.
Quick, follow me.
Go down the south tower steps.
Be careful, my friend. Promise
you won't let anything happen to him.
-I promise.
-Thank you.
Quick, we gotta stash the stiff.
Master, I didn't think you'd be coming.
I am never too busy to share
a meal with you, dear boy.
I brought a little treat.
Is there something troubling you,
Quasimodo?
-No!
-But there is.
I know there is.
I think you're hiding something.
No, Master. I... There's no...
You're not eating, boy.
It's very good. Thank you.
Seeds.
What's different in here?
Nothing. Sir.
Isn't this one new?
It's awfully good.
It looks very much like the gypsy girl.
I know you helped her escape!
And now all Paris is burning
because of you!
She was kind to me, Master.
You idiot!
That wasn't kindness. It was cunning!
She's a gypsy!
Gypsies are not capable of real love!
Think, boy. Think of your mother.
But what chance could
a poor, misshapen child like you
have against her heathen treachery?
Well, never you mind, Quasimodo.
She'll be out of our lives soon enough.
I will free you from her evil spell.
She will torment you no longer.
What do you mean?
I know where her hideout is.
And tomorrow at dawn, I attack
with 1 ,000 men.
We have to find the court
of miracles before daybreak.
If Frollo gets there first...
Are you coming with me?
-I can't.
-I thought you were Esmeralda's friend.
Frollo is my master.
I can't disobey him again.
She stood up for you. You've got
a funny way of showing gratitude.
Well, I'm not going to sit by and
watch Frollo massacre innocent people.
You do what you think is right.
What? What am I supposed to do?
Go out there and rescue
the girl from the jaws of death,
and the whole town will cheer
like I'm some kind of a hero?
She already has her knight
in shining armour, and it's not me.
Frollo was right.
Frollo was right about everything.
I'm tired of trying to be
something that I'm not.
I must be out of my mind.
Phoebus!
-I'm coming with you!
-Glad you changed your mind.
I'm not doing it for you.
I'm doing it for her.
You know where she is?
No, but she said
that this will help us find her.
Good, good, good. Great.
What is it?
I'm not sure.
It must be some sort of code.
Maybe it's Arabic. No, no. It's not
Arabic. Maybe it's ancient Greek.
"When you wear this woven band,
you hold the city in your hand."
-What?
-It's the city.
-What are you talking about?
-It's a map.
See, here's the cathedral and the river,
and this little stone must be...
-I've never seen a map that looks like...
-I've lived in the tower for 20 years.
And I think I know what
the city looks like from above.
-This is it.
-This is not it.
All right. Okay.
If you say it's a map, fine. It's a map.
But ifwe're going to find Esmeralda,
we have to work together.
Truce?
Well, okay.
Sorry.
No, you're not.
This looks like the symbol on the map.
But what does it mean?
I'm not sure.
I can make out an inscription,
but it's going to
take a few minutes to translate it.
Yes, well.
Or we could just go down those stairs.
Is this the court of miracles?
Offhand, I'd say it's
the court of ankle-deep sewage.
Must be the old catacombs.
Cheerful place.
Kinda makes ya wish
ya got out more often, eh, Quasi?
Not me. I just want to warn Esmeralda
and get back to the bell tower
before I get in more trouble.
Speaking of trouble, we should
have run into some by now.
-What do you mean?
-You know. A guard. A booby trap.
Or an ambush.
Well, well, well. What have we here?
-Trespassers!
-Spies!
-We're not spies.
-You've got to listen...
Don't interrupt me.
You're very clever
to have found our hideaway.
Unfortunately, you won't
live to tell the tale.
Maybe you've heard of a terrible place
Where the scoundrels of Paris
collect in a lair
Maybe you've heard of that mythical
place called the court of miracles
Hello, you're there.
Where the lame can walk
And the blind can see
But the dead don't talk
So you won't be around
to reveal what you found
We have a method
for spies and intruders
Rather like hornets
protecting their hive
Here in the court of miracles
where it's a miracle if you get out alive
Gather around, everybody.
There's "good noose" tonight.
It's a doubleheader.
A couple of Frollo's spies.
And notjust any spies.
His captain of the guard
and his loyal, bell-ringing henchman.
Justice is swift in the court of miracles
l am the lawyers and judge all in one
We like to get the trial over with quickly
Because it's the sentence
that's really the fun
Any last words?
That's what they all say.
-Now that we've seen all the evidence
-Wait, l object
-Overruled.
-I object.
-Quiet.
-Dang.
We find you totally innocent
Which is the worst crime of all
So you're going to hang
Stop!
These men aren't spies.
They're our friends.
-Why didn't they say so?
-We did say so.
This is the soldier
who saved the miller's family.
And Quasimodo helped me
escape the cathedral.
We came to warn you. Frollo's coming!
He says he knows where you're hiding,
and he's attacking at dawn
with 1 ,000 men.
Then let's waste no time.
We must leave immediately.
You took a terrible risk coming here.
It may not exactly show,
but we're grateful.
Don't thank me. Thank Quasimodo.
Without his help,
I would never have found my way here.
Nor would I.
After 20 years of searching,
the court of miracles is mine at last.
Dear Quasimodo.
I always knew
you would someday be of use to me.
-No.
-What are you talking about?
-Why, he led me right to you, my dear.
-You're a liar.
And look what else
I've caught in my net.
Captain Phoebus, back from the dead.
Another "miracle," no doubt.
I shall remedy that.
There'll be a little bonfire
in the square tomorrow.
And you're all invited to attend.
Lock them up.
No, please, Master!
No, no.
Take him back to the bell tower.
And make sure he stays there.
The prisoner, Esmeralda, has been
found guilty of the crime ofwitchcraft.
The sentence...
Death!
The time has come, gypsy.
You stand upon the brink of the abyss.
Yet even now it is not too late.
I can save you from the flames
of this world and the next.
Choose me. Or the fire.
The gypsy, Esmeralda,
has refused to recant.
This evil witch has put the soul
of every citizen in Paris
in awful jeopardy.
Come on, Quasi. Snap out of it!
-Your friends are down there.
-It's all my fault.
You gotta break these chains.
I can't. I tried.
What difference would it make?
-But you can't let Frollo win!
-He already has.
So you're givin' up? That's it?
These chains aren't what's
holding you back, Quasimodo.
Leave me alone.
Okay. Okay, Quasi.
We'll leave ya alone.
After all, we're only made out of stone.
We just thought maybe
you were made of somethin' stronger.
Forjustice, for Paris,
and for her own salvation,
it is my sacred duty
to send this unholy demon
back where she belongs.
No!
Quasimodo!
Sanctuary!
-Captain.
-Sir?
Seize the cathedral.
Don't worry. You'll be safe here.
Charge!
Come back, you cowards!
You, men, pick up that beam.
Break down the door.
Alone at last.
Citizens of Paris!
Frollo has persecuted our people,
ransacked our city!
Now he has declared war
on Notre Dame herself!
Will we allow it?
I think the cavalry is here.
Hey, isn't that...
-Feeble?
-Doofus.
Phoebus!
Sorry. Sorry.
Harder!
I'm free! I'm free!
Dang it!
Ready, aim, fire!
Are you sure that's how it works?
Works for me.
Achilles, sit.
Get off me!
Fly, my pretties! Fly, fly!
Put your backs into it!
Frollo, have you gone mad?
I will not tolerate
this assault on the house of God!
Silence, you old fool!
The hunchback and I
have unfinished business to attend to.
And this time you will not interfere.
We've done it, Esmeralda!
We've beaten them back!
Come and see.
Esmeralda, wake up.
You're safe now.
Esmeralda?
No.
You killed her.
It was my duty, horrible as it was.
I hope you will forgive me.
There, there, Quasimodo.
I know it hurts.
But now the time has come
to end your suffering...
Forever.
Now, now, listen to me, Quasimodo.
No, you listen!
All my life, you have told me
the world is a dark, cruel place.
But now I see that the only thing dark
and cruel about it is people like you.
Quasimodo?
Esmeralda!
She lives.
No!
Leaving so soon?
Look, up there!
Hang on!
I should have known you'd risk your life
to save that gypsy witch,
just as your own mother
died trying to save you.
What?
Now I'm going to do
what I should have done 20 years ago!
Hold on.
And he shall smite the wicked
and plunge them into the fiery pit!
Quasimodo! Quasi!
No!
Three cheers for Quasimodo!
So here is a riddle to guess if you can
Sing the bells of Notre Dame
What makes a monster
and what makes a man
Sing the bells, bells
Bells, bells
Whatever their pitch
You can feel them bewitch you
The rich and the ritual knells
Of the bells
Of Notre
Dame
Don't you ever migrate?
Good night, everybody!