We're all familiar
with the illegal poaching
of endangered
animals in the wild.
But never before has an animal in
captivity been slaughtered for its pelt.
Animal protection groups that
monitor the international trade
in game contraband
have further told us
that a white Siberian tiger is
so rare that the offer of a pelt
will surely draw the attention
of law enforcement agencies.
Shortly before dawn
this morning,
security staff at London Zoo
discovered the excoriated carcass
of its prized three-year-old
female Siberian tiger, Su-Ling.
Police sources have suggested
that the killing was contracted
by a private collector.
Oh, isn't that horrible?
Who'd do a thing like that?
...moved into the urban
zoological park.
We must ask ourselves if any
animal in the world is safe.
This is Tim Ryan
reporting from London Zoo.
What a bad day
for the animal kingdom.
Oh.
One day, very soon, Pongo,
I'm going to make a sale.
'Cause we're fast
approaching the point where
I'm going to have to start
eating your table scraps.
Oh, I was exaggerating.
Well, shall we?
It's not that bad, it's just very
important this meeting goes well.
You know how I am about meetings,
I tend to get a little...
Well, nervous.
When I get nervous,
I say things, I do things
I shouldn't say, I shouldn't
do and next thing we know...
It's freelancing. Probably.
He's got the best
instincts in the industry.
Since he was six, he's picked the
top-selling game every year.
Well?
What do you think?
Potentially good graphics,
reasonably entertaining premise,
the dog's well-conceived and
the environments are engaging.
But I'm not interested in a game
that has a chubby little dog
catcher as the bad guy.
Even girls won't like this game.
Sorry, mate.
Yeah, but wait, wait, wait.
Herbert, wait!
What if there were
a better villain,
you know, someone
you could really hate?
It's not hatred
that's important.
It's the desire to annihilate.
Top of the morning
to you, ma'am.
Morning.
Good morning. Miss De Vil's office.
Could you hold, please?
Yes, I'll be with you
in a moment.
Could you hold, please?
Thank you. Good morning. Miss
De Vil's office. Could you...
Good morning, Miss De Vil.
Good morning,
Miss De Vil.
Good morning, ma'am.
Good morning.
Anita, darling.
Oh, good morning, Cruella.
What a charming dog.
Thank you. Spots.
Yes, she's a Dalmatian.
- Inspiration?
- Yes.
Long hair or short? Short.
Coarse or fine? ANITA:
I'm afraid it is a little coarse.
Pity! But it was very fine
when she was a puppy.
Redemption. We need
to have a little girl talk.
Come to my office.
Bring the drawing.
Now, darling. Tell me
more about these spots.
I did leopard spots in the '80s.
Well, Dalmatian spots are a
little different, aren't they?
Cozy. Cuddly.
Classic. Less trashy.
Exactly.
Do you like spots, Frederick?
Oh, I don't believe so, madam.
I thought we liked
stripes this year.
What kind of sycophant are you?
Um...
What kind of sycophant
would you like me to be?
Frederick.
I'm beginning to see spots.
What would it cost us to start
again on next year's line?
Millions.
Can we afford it?
Well, yes...
Thank you, darling. Now go away.
I have to talk to Anita.
Alonzo.
Did you ask Anita if she'd
like something to drink?
Oh, I'm fine. Thank you.
Sit down, please.
How long have you been
working for me?
Uh, two years, last August.
And you've done wonderful
work in that time.
Thank you.
I don't see you socially, do I?
No.
And you're not very well-known,
despite your obvious talent.
Well. Notoriety doesn't
mean very much to me.
Your work is fresh and clean.
Unfettered, unpretentious...
It sells.
And one of these days, my competitors
are going to suss out who you are.
And they are going to
try to steal you away.
Oh, no. If I left, it
wouldn't be for another job.
Oh, really?
What would it be for?
Well, I don't know, um...
If I met someone...
If working here didn't
fit in with our plans.
Marriage.
Perhaps.
More good women have been
lost to marriage than to war,
famine, disease and disaster.
You have talent, darling.
Don't squander it.
Well, I don't think that
it's something we have to worry about.
I don't have any prospects.
Thank God.
Well, I should be
getting back to work.
Yes. Please do.
Alonzo.
The drawing.
Take the drawing from
Anita and hand it to me!
Is that difficult?
Thank you. Now go stand
somewhere until I need you.
I look wonderful in spots.
However, I would like
to make one small change.
Yes.
We could do this in linen.
It would be stunning in fur.
But you'll be wearing it to the
Chesterton Trials. That's in April.
Uh, fur would be inappropriate.
But it's my only
true love, darling.
I live for fur. I worship fur.
After all, is there a woman in all
this wretched world who doesn't?
Give it to Anita.
Oh.
It is rather amusing, isn't it?
What is?
Well, if we make this coat,
it would be as if
I were wearing your dog.
Woof! Woof!
Sorry, Pongo, I didn't mean
to take so long.
If I could just sell a game,
we might be able to get a car.
Come on.
Pongo!
Whoa!
Slow down!
Watch it! Watch it!
Oh.
Pongo!
Hey!
Pongo! Pongo! Pongo!
Ooh!
Pongo!
Turn!
No! Pongo!
Watch it!
Stop! Stop! Oh!
Pongo!
I don't think
he wanted to do that.
Here we go, Perdy.
Oh, now stop it. Okay, go!
Go fetch it.
Good girl.
Come on. Bring it back.
Come here. Come here.
Yeah. Good girl.
Okay.
Oh. Now, come on.
Let's go again.
Pongo!
Go on.
Hello. Who are you?
Oh, I got ya!
Very smart. Very funny.
Everybody had a good laugh.
Let go of that dog!
Stay out of it, lady.
Stop it, or, or... I'll hit you.
Today is not a good day
to threaten me, ma'am.
I don't care if it's a
good day or a bad day,
I'll hit you, nonetheless.
Whatever. Okay, I gave you
a good, proper warning.
Look, I've had...
Oh.
Now, release my dog
or I'll hit you again.
Oh.
Your dog? Yes.
That is my dog.
Will you let her go?
Excuse me.
He's a she.
Mm-hmm.
Hello, Pongo.
I beg your pardon, ma'am.
I'm sorry. My mistake.
What have you got in the
purse of yours? Rocks?
Oh, no. Bricks.
I've been paving my garden
and every time I see a discarded
brick, I just pick it up.
Yeah? How many did
you find today?
Uh, three. Three?
Oh, well. That's what I
would have guessed. Mmm.
Why are you all wet?
I went swimming in the pond.
Oh, you shouldn't have.
The water's filthy.
Mm-hmm. Yes
and it tastes like fish.
And, um, you've lost a
shoe, did you know that?
Yes, I do. As a matter
of fact, I did.
I noticed it running
down the gravel path.
Oh, I'm ever so sorry. I mean...
You know, I thought
if you were silly enough
to go swimming in a dirty pond
you'd be silly enough not to
realize you'd lost a shoe.
Actually, I crashed
my bicycle in the pond.
The only part of my body that
wasn't injured was my head.
But now, thanks to you. I got the
complete set of bodily injuries.
Well, it was nice being
assaulted by you, Miss...
Oh, my name is Anita.
Anita? And yours is Roger.
Um, I read it on your
dog's identification tag.
Oh. Oh! Yes. Well...
Nice meeting you.
I hope I didn't alarm you.
Oh, no. That's fine.
Since we both seem to have a
certain fondness for Dalmatians.
Yes.
Well, they certainly have a
certain fondness for each other.
Don't they? Yeah.
Well, Pongo...
Your roving eye's gotten me in
enough trouble for one day.
Why don't you come
with me? We'll go home.
Um, are you sure
you'll be all right?
Perhaps, you should
call your doctor.
I'll be fine. Fine.
Good luck with your bricks.
If you have a concussion, you
shouldn't be left alone, you know?
Pongo, you could
have gotten me killed.
You know that?
You risk losing your master for
a brief frolic with a female.
Come on.
Jolly nice human,
don't you think?
Fools aren't born, Pongo.
Pretty girls make them
in their spare time.
Shall we? Come on.
Excuse me.
Sorry. Thank you.
You have it all wrong, Pongo. I'm simply
trying to decide on a route home.
I has nothing whatsoever
to do with Anita.
If that's even what her name is.
Perdy.
What is it? Oh!
Pongo! Pongo! Easy! Easy! Easy!
Oh. Ah! Perdy.
Stop. Okay.
Perdy, stop!
Perdy!
Look out!
Ahhh!
Oh. Ah!
Oh, I've never
been rescued before.
It was very exciting.
And you were ever so sweet
to give me a kiss.
That wasn't a kiss. That
was mouth-to-mouth resuscitation.
Oh.
Besides, it didn't
work very well.
You're supposed to lie flat on
your back and remain still.
I couldn't really do it properly
with your arms around my neck.
I'm ever so sorry. No, no.
That's...
Quite all right.
Well, you give
a very good rescue.
Thank you.
Oh.
I think we have a problem.
I think
my dog is in love.
I think mine is, too.
Why is that a problem?
They are going to be
broken-hearted when you leave.
Oh.
Oh, I don't think I could bear to
live with a broken-hearted Dalmatian.
Yes, they are miserable
when they're lonely.
Well, we'd better
think of something.
I agree.
Do you want another
cup of marriage?
Excuse me. Tea?
Another cup of tea.
You said marriage.
Uh, marriage?
Yes, that's what you said. I
mean, you meant to say tea,
but it came out "marriage."
Oh, I'm sorry, uh...
Do you want another cup of...
Tea?
I do.
You... You do?
I will.
You will?
If you ask me.
Would you?
Yes.
For as much
as Roger and Anita
have consented together
in holy wedlock,
and have witnessed the same
before God and this company,
and thereto have given and pledged
their troth either to other,
and declared the same by giving
and receiving of a ring,
by joining of hands.
I pronounce that they be
man and wife together,
in the name of
the Father, and of the Son,
and of the Holy Ghost. Amen.
Amen.
God the Father,
God the Son,
God the Holy Ghost,
bless, preserve, and keep you.
The Lord mercifully
with his favor look upon you.
And so fill you with all
spiritual benediction and grace,
that ye may so
live together in this life,
that in the world to come
you may have life everlasting.
Amen.
All right.
Now, let me tell me tell you a bit about
this bloke, Skinner, before we meet him.
Now, supposedly,
when he was quite young,
his dog tore open his throat
and ripped out his vocal chords,
leaving him brutally scarred
and completely mute.
He cannot talk at all.
Now, pay... Look at me.
Pay attention,
this is very important.
There are two things you
must not do to Skinner.
All right. One. Do not look at
the horrendous scar on his neck.
Two. Don't talk to him.
Understand? Not a word.
Right.
Oh!
Look at the size of that scar.
No bloody wonder
you can't talk, mate.
Excuse me, just a minute,
would you?
God, bloody gruesome line
of work you're in, Skinner.
Sight of all these deceased
creatures gives me a shrinky winky.
Much obliged, sunshine.
How could she do this to me?
Morning, ma'am. Sit.
Tea? Er, please.
Er, please.
Thank you. Thank you.
Oh, well.
What a beautiful day, ma'am.
Blue skies, birds singing.
Laughter of school children
riding on gentle...
Get on with it, you imbecile!
Well, I...
I have here a present
from Mr. Skinner.
Oh.
It's magnificent.
Hello, my beauty.
Oh, God.
Come. Come with me.
Come with me, my darling.
Let me see you.
Oh.
You were a big bad boy,
weren't you, darling?
Yes, yes, yes.
Siberian tiger suits
madam very well indeed.
Mirror, mirror on the wall.
Who's the fairest of them all?
You are.
I remember you were always very good
at drawing when you were a little girl.
And now to be with you again
as you start a family of your
own is like a dream come true.
Oh, Nanny.
I don't think Roger and I are quite
ready to start a family yet.
Oh, that's a shame.
Ah, well. First, the puppies.
Then, the babies.
Puppies?
If I've done
my job right, Pongo,
when this new villain comes up, you're
gonna run from the room in a panic.
Gotcha.
It's unmistakable, dear.
It's the look
every woman gets
when she knows she's
going to be a mother.
Notice how tranquil she is.
Her eyes are soft and warm.
Though you might not see it,
you can certainly feel
that she's smiling.
It's the smile we wear when we're
guarding a precious secret.
And now that she's living
for others as well as herself,
she's eating more.
And every now and again,
for no reason other than
she's so happy with herself,
she sighs.
I think you're right, Nanny.
I think she does look different.
Oh, my goodness.
What is it, Nanny?
Anita, I think you're
going to have a puppy.
Uh... Oh.
Thank you so much.
A month's time
for a check-up, yes?
All right. Bye-bye.
See you again soon.
So?
Well, he said that
it's all great.
Um, baby's nice and big.
It's right about...
That's wonderful.
Oh, no. What?
Cruella?
Anita, darling.
Oh, Anita.
Those dazzling dogs.
And you must be Rufus.
Uh, no. It's Roger. And it's
a pleasure, Miss De Vil.
What's a pleasure?
Uh, making your acquaintance.
Such a sweet thought.
I wish I could reciprocate.
Tell me, darling, you
married him for his dog.
Oh, darling. I've missed you so.
I hate that you've taken leave.
Uh, but I'm still working.
You've been getting my sketches.
Well, it's not the same thing.
I miss the interaction.
And what is it that you do,
that allows you to support
Anita in such splendor.
I design video games.
Video games? Mm-hmm.
Is he having me on?
Oh, no. He's very good at it.
And it's a growing business.
Those horrible noisy things
that children play with
on their television,
someone designs them?
What a senseless thing
to do with your life.
Oh, did Anita tell you the news?
She's going to have a baby.
Is this true?
Yes.
Oh, you poor thing.
I'm so sorry.
We're very
excited about it, Cruella.
You can't be serious. She is.
Well, what can I say?
Accidents will happen.
We're having puppies, too. Oh.
Puppies?
You have been a busy boy.
Well, I must say that's somewhat
better news. I adore puppies.
I'll expect a decline
in your work product.
Oh, I shouldn't think so.
Be sure to let me know
when the blessed event occurs.
Oh, well, it won't be
for another eight months.
The puppies, darling.
I've no use for babies.
Cheerio. Cheerio, darling.
If I'm this nervous about your puppies, what
am I gonna be like when my baby arrives?
How can you be so calm?
Nanny!
Oh, my goodness!
Gangway!
Is there
something I can do?
Maybe... Maybe I can
be of some help.
Right. Get out,
peek in through the window and see
if those puppies have come yet.
Can I borrow your umbrella?
Be careful when you open it.
They're here!
The puppies are here.
You're a father, Pongo!
Two! Two!
You're a father twice!
- Make that three.
- Three! Three, Pongo! Three puppies!
- Oh, my goodness! Four!
- Four!
Fifteen!
Did you hear that, boy?
Fifteen puppies!
Fourteen.
We lost one.
I'm sorry, Pongo, I'm so sorry.
I wonder.
Fifteen! We have 15 puppies!
What... Oh!
Goodness, gracious!
It's a miracle!
Anita, 15! Fifteen again.
We must
call this one Lucky.
Look. Look at him!
Aww, hmm! Oh!
How's Perdy? She's tired.
Oh! Bringing 15 puppies into the
world, I guess she's got the right.
Yeah. They're so beautiful.
You can go in now, Pongo.
Here we are, Perdy.
Yes, it's Lucky!
Now make room,
you others.
There we are,
and well done, Perdy.
There's a good girl.
I'll leave you two alone.
I'm glad I'm only having the one.
Hmm.
Anita?
There you are. Where are the puppies?
They should've arrived by now.
How marvelous.
How marvelous!
How perfect...
Oh. The devil take it!
They're mongrels!
No spots. No spots at all.
What horrible little white rats!
But their spots
don't come till later.
You're sure?
Yes.
All right. Put them in a bag.
I'll take them with me now!
What? They were just born.
I can see that!
But, Cruella, the puppies have to be
with their mother for several weeks.
They're not ready to leave.
Fine, put the little brutes on reserve
for me. How much would you like?
They're not for sale.
Oh! You've come into
some money, have you?
Did you design some silly game that
would drive the delinquent kiddies
into frenzies of video delight?
As a matter of fact, I have...
No, no. No!
What Roger means to say
is that we're not sure
we're going to sell the puppies.
Anita, don't be ridiculous.
You can't possible afford
to keep them.
I'll pay twice what
they're worth.
Come now,
I'm being more than generous.
£500 Oh!
£7,500, fair?
£2 per spot!
Cruella, what would
you do with 15 puppies?
Yeah, that is irrelevant, Anita. She can't
have any because they're not for sale.
I'm getting very tired
of you, Roland.
Roger! Whatever! Take it.
Take it.
Take it!
Cruella,
the puppies are not for sale.
You're quite sure?
Yes. Yes.
All right.
Keep the little beasts.
Do what you like with them.
Drown them, for all I care.
You're a fool, Anita.
I've no use for fools.
You're fired!
You're finished! You'll never
work in fashion again.
I'm through with all of you!
I'll get even!
Just wait, you'll be sorry!
You fools! You idiots!
Good evening, madam.
Oh! Out of my way!
Hello, Pongo.
♪ Oh, everybody wants ♪
♪ to be a cat ♪
♪ Everybody, everybody ♪
♪ Everybody wants to be a cat ♪
Come on you two,
let's go home.
Thank you, Pongo.
They're here. I've got them.
Anita, Roger!
I'm in the living room.
Now, come on down
and have a look.
Oh, you as well.
You heard that, didn't you?
Wait till you see what I've
got for you in this bag. Ha!
Oh!
Jewel.
Aw!
Let me put this on you.
Dipstick.
Come on.
That a boy. Oh, yeah.
Yeah, yeah. I know. Mmm-hmm.
Fidget.
Here.
Two-Tone
I know, I know.
You all like to do that.
Here we go, here we go.
Wizzer. Wizzer.
Right, we're on.
Get...
Get your own.
Somebody didn't
finish their supper.
We're on a budget.
"Waste not, want not,"
that's my motto.
Who on earth?
Coming, coming.
Coming.
Good evening, madam.
Oh! My goodness.
It's all right, lady.
We're professionals.
Come here.
Let go of me.
Right, get her off!
I'm gonna...
Let go of me. Straight ahead.
Straight ahead.
All right. Don't push!
Help! Police!
In you go. No. Ow!
Fingers.
Let me out of here! Let me out!
Open the door! Open this door!
Oh, do shut up!
Police, police!
I'll see you go to jail for this
if it's the last thing I do!
Help! Police!
Well, the old bird
put up a good fight.
I like that. I like a bit
of sprit in a woman.
That's all right for you to say. You
didn't get smashed in the face.
Aww!
Give me the bag.
Come on, come on. Here.
All right. Come here, you.
Spotty little dog.
Good evening, General.
Montgomery, heel, boy!
Heel, boy, heel!
Jasper?
Do you know what I think?
What's that?
I think that bulldog knows
what we've just done.
It's a dog, Horace.
Dogs ain't got the brains
to figure things out.
Come on. At ease, boy.
Luckily.
Come on home.
I mean, I think... Pongo!
Perdy!
Police! Where are they?
Oh, no!
They've taken the puppies.
Anita! Oh! Roger.
Thank God, they're home!
Oh, thank goodness, you've come.
What happened? What is it?
The puppies. They were two men.
They've stolen the puppies.
I tried to stop them.
They locked me in the cupboard.
I shouted and shouted
but nobody came.
Ah, good evening, madam.
I sincerely hope I have not
disturbed your relaxation,
but I have some good news.
Did you get the puppies?
Affirmative.
All of them?
Every single one.
My faith in your
limited intelligence
is momentarily restored.
Oh!
You are too kind, madam.
We've got the 15!
Add them to the other puppies
we've already stolen.
And I have my cozy,
puppy coat.
I'll be wearing
Anita's dogs.
Right, well, I'm gonna fill my snoot
and go to bed. I'm dead tired.
I'm hearing dogs again, Jasper.
Oh! Shut up in there.
Tango-Foxtrot-23,
report progress on
missing canines, over.
You keep your
chin up. We'll do our best.
Thank you, Inspector.
Goodnight, ma'am. Goodnight.
He was most sympathetic.
He says they're going to do
the best they can.
For what that's worth.
Do you think they'll find them?
How're they gonna find 15
little puppies in a city this size.
If they're even in the city.
What can the police do?
What can we do?
What can anyone do?
Woof. Woof! Woof!
Pongo!
Did you hear that? What?
That noise? What noise?
That noise that I just heard!
Did you hear it?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
It sounded just like a complete berk
asking me irritating questions.
Oh, good. It's stopped now.
I'll be honest with you, mate.
This job is fast
losing its charm!
The housing stinks,
food's lousy.
The lavatory facilities
are appalling.
And so far, we haven't been
paid so much as one quid.
Oh! Will you stop moaning?
Look, this time tomorrow
night, it's all over.
We get our boodle, we'll be out of here
before you can say, "Dead puppies."
Now, go to sleep.
Mr. Skinner,
suspicions are mounting,
police are everywhere.
I want the job done tonight.
Can you do it?
Any way you want. Poison them, drown them.
Bash them on the head.
Got any chloroform? I don't care
how you kill the little beasts,
just do it and do it now!
Pongo and Perdy
will turn up, won't they?
If you ask me, they will.
I think they just went
looking for the puppies.
You know who did this,
don't you?
I, for one, wouldn't be
the least bit surprised.
She has a terrible
temper on her.
The dogs never cared for her.
Dogs have a sixth sense
about things like that.
They can smell ill intentions.
Roger. What? What's wrong?
Nanny, what did I do
with my portfolio?
Uh, it's in the nursery
closet, dear.
Anita?
She did steal the puppies
and this is why.
She's going
to kill the puppies.
Right, that's it. Time to let
the little yappers have it.
We ain't supposed to do it.
That's Skinner's job.
Well, Skinner isn't here, is he?
Besides, I don't see why that little
runt should have all the fun.
How'd you wanna do it?
Well, personally,
I think I favor the fire iron.
Right,
that'll be Miss De Vil.
Fix your shirt
and tart up your hair.
Good evening...
Hello?
Anybody there?
Maybe we was hearing things.
Oi!
Get out of my truck!
Yeah!
Go on, get out of here!
Clear out!
Yeah.
There's plenty more
where that came from,
should you elect to come back.
I don't believe it.
I don't
care what you say,
we bloody well
better be careful.
Yeah, that's right,
what we better be careful of
is the huge, thundering, macroeconomic
bulk of your stupidity.
I ain't taking
anymore lip from you, mate.
Oh, forget about that.
We have got 99 stinking
puppies to find and kill.
Now get on with it.
Here, puppies.
Pup, pup, pup, pup, puppies!
Come here, you speckled lab rat.
Ahhh!
Ugh!
Stay!
You...
Oh, come here I'm gonna
get you, you little...
Ahhh!
Cold.
Good evening, madam.
Good evening. Hello.
What are you doing up there?
I am... I was just fetching
the puppies, ma'am.
And where are the puppies?
Oh, there, you see, once again,
Madam has, like a laser,
gone straight to
the heart of the issue.
It's a quality
I've always admired.
"Where are the puppies?"
It's brilliant.
Well, let me just say,
um, right now, that I'm not
absolutely 100% certain
where the puppies are,
but if you'll just
give me a second,
I will check with my associate.
Uh, Horace!
Get down from there,
and catch those puppies!
Hopelessly stupid,
pathetic fools.
I'll find the bloody
mongrels myself.
You just had to let those
puppies get away, didn't you?
Never paying attention.
Oh, where was you?
Where... I was not splashing
around in the pond.
You've infuriated the old bag,
and if we don't get those puppies back
then it's quite literally our heads.
Oh, come on!
Right, you better get out
and check the tail pipe,
we've got
a condensation problem.
One of these days,
I'm gonna be full up of you.
Oh, do come on!
There, you see?
Turn the heater on, will you?
No.
Not with this thing
acting the way she is,
I don't wanna risk losing power.
I can't stand the cold no more.
I want heat.
Fire!
Too hot! Too hot!
Your suspicions were justified.
According to the staff, Miss De Vil left
earlier for a family property in Suffolk.
I have informed
the local police.
Officers there will be on the
lookout for your puppies.
And Miss De Vil.
I only hope we're not too late.
Oh!
This is extraordinary.
I'm reduced to tramping
through sewage,
because my two imbeciles can't keep
track of a bunch of infant dogs.
I do not believe it.
We got no truck, no dogs.
We are so dead. Number One
Dead Street, that's us.
Look!
Tracks.
I love you.
There you are, you see,
if dogs are so smart
they wouldn't leave tracks,
- for wary predators such as us.
- Yeah.
Now, I've always said, human
beings are essentially superior.
You know, blessed with
faculties of speech,
and thought and a couple
of other things.
Don't worry, I'm not gonna
ruin your little puppy coat,
I'm just gonna make
a few button holes.
Where are you, you filthy beast?
Oh, yes!
I love the smell
of near extinction.
Oh, oh, oh!
Stupidity, you see.
That's your problem, that's
what has been holding you back.
If it was up to you, you would
have taken hold of that wire,
set fire to your undershorts,
cooked your tongue before even
thinking it was electrified.
Point taken.
But what are the logs for?
You see,
we stand upon the logs
and hop over,
thereby avoiding
painful electric shock.
Brilliant. Right.
Mount the log.
Extend leg.
All right, now when
I count to three, we jump.
Ready?
Yes.
One.
Useless, disgusting creatures.
I'm sick to think
we breathe the same air.
Ah! Bingo!
Poor little things.
I'm gonna cut you off,
then cut you up.
Darling, red isn't your color.
Give me the hat.
Give me the hat,
or you'll become a hat.
Give it to me!
Oh!
Thank the Lord.
We're saved.
- There you go.
- Thank you, again.
- Much obliged.
- Nice and easy.
Watch your heads. Thank you.
This is lovely. Isn't it?
Nice and warm.
No animals neither.
You
beasts!
But I'm not beaten yet.
You won the battle, but I'm
about to win the wardrobe.
My spotted puppy coat is in plain
sight, and leaving tracks.
In a moment, I'll
have what I came for,
while all of you will
end up as sausage meat.
Alone on some sad,
plastic plate.
Dead and medium red.
No friends, no family, no pulse.
Just slapped between two buns,
smothered in onions,
with fries on the side.
Cruella De Vil
has the last laugh.
Oh!
Miss De Vil.
Yes.
We have a warrant
for your arrest.
Oh.
Is there something wrong?
Stop!
What's that up ahead?
Well, will you look at that.
I've come up with 98 pups.
The two adults make it 100 even.
We've got 100 here, sir.
Um, make that
101 Dalmatians, sir.
Congratulations.
You've just won
gold, silver and bronze,
in the morons' Olympics.
Who won the gold? Shut up!
My business. My reputation.
My life,
has been ruined because you
three incompetent twits,
let yourselves be outsmarted
by a bunch of dumb animals,
and you call
yourselves men, huh?
I've seen more intelligent
pieces of carpet.
They're here. Anita, Roger.
The puppies.
Oh, my goodness, look at them.
Oh!
Good boy.
They're happy to be home!
Oh, thank you, Officer,
how can we ever repay you?
Well.
Your dogs were the only ones
with identification tags,
we have no idea
which puppy goes where.
Our records indicate that so far nobody
has called to claim the other puppies.
Now, they need a home. Or,
well, they go to the pound.
Oh, no, no!
No, no, no. Roger we
can't, we don't have room.
Well, we'll get a bigger place.
We have 17 as it is,
what's a few more?
We'll work something out.
You'll have dozens
of children, you know?
Well, I won't have them
chewing up the carpets,
barking at all hours
of the night.
All right, everyone inside
before we all get cold.
Unload the puppies.
Get ready, get ready.
Ahhh!
Cool!
Excellent villain, mate!
Thanks, Herbert.
Congratulations.
Huh, what, yeah, thank you.
Thank you. See you in my office,
we've got terms to sort out.
Okay, good.
Excellent villain, mate.
I can barely believe
it, our baby is a year old,
we have a new house, a new life.
And we have each other.
We have Nanny.
And I have the three of you.
We have two wonderful dogs.
And they have their children.
And their step-children.
Their step-children
have children.
And their children
And speaking of children.
Roger, darling, I've
got the most wonderful news.
♪ Cruella De Vil ♪
♪ If she doesn't scare you ♪
♪ No evil thing will ♪
♪ To see her is to take ♪
♪ a sudden chill ♪
♪ Cruella Cruella De Vil ♪
♪ The curl of her lips ♪
♪ The ice in her stare ♪
♪ All innocent children ♪
♪ had better beware ♪
♪ She's like a spider ♪
♪ waiting for the kill ♪
♪ Look out for Cruella De Vil ♪
♪ At first you think ♪
♪ Cruella is a devil ♪
♪ But after time ♪
♪ has worn away the shock ♪
♪ You come to realize ♪
♪ You've seen her kind of eyes ♪
♪ Watching you ♪
♪ from underneath a rock ♪
♪ This vampire bat ♪
♪ This inhuman beast ♪
♪ She oughta be locked up ♪
♪ And never released ♪
♪ The world was ♪
♪ such a wholesome place until ♪
♪ Cruella Cruella De Vil ♪
♪ Cruella De Vil ♪
♪ If she doesn't scare you ♪
♪ No evil thing will ♪
♪ To see her is ♪
♪ to take a sudden chill ♪
♪ Cruella ♪
♪ De Vil ♪
♪ The curl of her lips ♪
♪ The ice in her stare ♪
♪ All innocent children ♪
♪ had better beware ♪
♪ She's like a spider ♪
♪ waiting for the kill ♪
♪ Look out for Cruella De Vil ♪
♪ At first you think ♪
♪ Cruella is a devil ♪
♪ After time ♪
♪ has wore away the shock ♪
♪ You come to realize ♪
♪ You've seen her kind of eyes ♪
♪ Watching you from under a rock ♪
♪ This vampire bat ♪
♪ Inhuman beast ♪
♪ She oughta be locked up ♪
♪ Never released ♪
♪ This world was such ♪
♪ a wholesome place until ♪
♪ Cruella De Vil ♪
♪ At first you think ♪
♪ Cruella is a devil ♪
♪ After time ♪
♪ has wore away the shock ♪
♪ You come to realize ♪
♪ You've seen her kind of eyes ♪
♪ Watching you from under a rock ♪
♪ This world was such ♪
♪ a wholesome place until ♪
♪ Cruella De Vil ♪
♪ So evil even her hair's ♪
♪ two-faced ♪
♪ Ain't like nothing ♪
♪ you've ever seen ♪
♪ She's the Dean of Mean ♪
♪ I need to mention ♪
♪ She's got some ♪
♪ doggone bad intentions ♪
♪ I mean, let's face it ♪
♪ A person like her could ♪
♪ really ruin your whole day ♪