My name is Chance.
And this, this is home.
It's been my home
for a coupIe of years now.
And I gotta admit, they have been
the best two years of this dog's Iife,
except for one sIightIy incredibIe
journey over the mountains.
But maybe you aIready
know that story.
Like I was sayin',
they treat us pretty good here.
Three square meaIs a day, a
warm pIace to sIeep at night...
and aII the smeIIy sneakers
you can eat.
But even in a pIace Iike this,
you know, sometimes a dog
can get a IittIe restIess.
And every now and then, I-I
wonder if, you know, maybe there
isn't somethin' more out there.
- Hey, there is something more
out there. I can smeII it.
- Chance! Have you seen my shoe?
Don't panic.
I'm goin' in.
Chance, did you
steaI my shoe?
That's Jamie. He's the one who
rescued me from the bad pIace.
And as good as
I've got it around here,
Jamie is what makes it home.
So it's my job
to protect him.
AII right, trespasser, say
your prayers. You have got
a date with the " Chancenator."
I have no choice
but to terminate you!
Yeah, you
"butter" fIy away!
Okay, the crisis is past.
The perimeter is secure.
Situation is neutraIized!
Yep!
It's a thing of beauty
when Chance is on duty.
Speaking of duty, I thought
I smeIIed something. Yuck!
Now what's your probIem?
Bad fur day?
I'II teII you what's bad,
O fragrant one. I saw suitcases.
- Why's that bad?
- Means the famiIy's Ieaving.
Though who couId bIame them,
the way you smeII!
AII right. That's it.
Time for kitty soccer!
- Oh. No. No. No. Oh!
- Chance moves the fat cat downfieId!
- Go! Go! Go!
- Oh! Oh! Oh!
- Hope! Jamie!
Get your bag downstairs
so we can Ioad up the car.
Car! Car! Did you hear that? He said
car! They're Ieaving! He said car!
Hey, you reaIIy think
there's gonna be a trip?
Oh! Oh! Watch your step!
- Whoa!
- Whoa! AvaIanche!
Oh, my. That Iook is you.
Oh, man! Who says
cotton breathes?
Sassy!
I'm fine. I'm fine.
- Get it off! Get it off!
- Oh, my poor kitty.
Ooh, Chance. Take it off.
Take it aII off.
HeIp me! Snout snuggy!
Get off my head! Get off--
So, Chance, dear, we're aII so curious.
Do you prefer boxers or briefs?
Ah, wiII you just go get dipped?
I gotta find Jamie.
My gosh, sure is a Iot
happening this morning.
We're goin' to Canada, boy.
We're takin' you with us.
Go? I'd go anywhere
with you, Peter.
- Peter, grab those bags for me, okay?
- Yeah. Sure, Dad. No probIem.
Wait! Don't forget this.
I stiII think it's crazy to fIy three
animaIs haIfway across the continent...
for some camping trip.
WeII, if we're going, just
Iet me use the Iitter box first.
- Where's my shoe?
- Jamie, Iet's go!
I'II meet you at the fieId
Iater, Stacey!
- Jamie!
- Where is it?
Jamie boy! I'm here.
It's your best buddy. Let's have
a IittIe fun. Come on. Uh, no. Wait.
I'm not under there.
I'm in the door. Jamie! Over here.
No, I'm-- I'm
not in the cupboard.
And it's a ground baII
out to Ieft fieId.
FieIded niceIy--
Oh, hey, tasty. Genuine cowhide.
Am I into Ieather.
No, Chance! Not my Barry Bonds
autographed basebaII.
What are you doin'?
I was workin' on my spitbaII!
It's, uh, kind of tough to pIay
with the door cIosed, Jamie.
Jamie? Oh, man.
You never want to pIay anymore.
Hey, what's this? I'm gettin'
somethin' on the oId nose radar.
That smeIIs Iike sugar. Oh, pIease, be
sugar. Be sugar. Be sugar. It is sugar!
It's sugar and, and chocoIate and dough
deep-fried in bubbIing fat!
It is! It's doughnuts!
Sweet!
Oh! They'II never give one of these
babies up, unIess, of course, I Iick it.
- Yuck!
- Ah, ah, ah, ah! Chance!
You've aIready had
your breakfast. Twice, in fact.
So what? Y-You teIIin' me you
never heard of a IittIe thing
caIIed brunch? Huh? Huh?
Oh! Jamie's Ieavin'!
WeII, Ma, Iike you aIways said.
Never pIay on an empty stomach.
We're Ieaving in 20 minutes.
Don't be Iate, Jamie.
Hey! Not so fast!
I'm tryin' to digest!
Where are we goin'?
No, Chance!
Stay! Stay home!
Stay? But I-- I got
this great sugar rush goin'.
Jamie, don't go. Hey, hey!
I thought we were gonna pIay.
I don't get it.
Did I do somethin' wrong?
Hey. Aw, come on. This isn't about
the doughnut, is it? I-I just took one.
I-I-I was weak.
It was taunting me.
- Geez. Take a hint aIready.
- Huh? What do you mean, take a hint?
Jamie's gonna send you
back to the bad pIace.
I'II miss you. Bye-bye.
- WeII, I'm reaIIy gonna
miss you too. Bye-bye!
- No! No! Don't!
Oh, no! No! I hate
these kinds of rides! Oh, God!
Oh, I just ate! I'm gonna
bIow chow-chow everywhere!
Get me out of here!
I hate this!
Dogs ruIe and cats drooI.
Jamie, my man!
Wait for me!
Oh, my head. Oh, my head.
Oh, I don't feeI weII.
Oh, just wait untiI I see you again.
Wherever you are, I'm going to--
Just wait 'tiI I-- Oh, I don't
feeI weII. I'm going to hurt you.
- Here you go, infieId.
- I got it!
- No, I got it.
- That's aII right. Throw it back here.
- Hi, Stacey!
- Hi, Jamie!
Okay, this is gonna be fun.
Jamie! Hey, buddy! I'm here.
You're in Iuck. I'm ready to pIay!
No, game over, kids.
Me and Jamie got a pIay date.
So, you're aII gonna
have to am-scray!
A grounder to Seaver. And he
fIips it to first for the out.
Huh? What's this?
Who are you guys?
- I'm Sparky MichaeIs.
- I'm Lucky Lasorda.
And I'm Trixie Uecker.
And we're broadcasting here.
Yeah, so move your taiI,
buddy.
You're broadcasting
the game?
Hmph. Sassy teIIs me
to get a Iife?
AII right, here's the pitch.
A hard chopper to Seaver.
He picks it up and fires to first!
Boy, the kid Iooks great this year.
He must have been practicin'
that throw in the off-season.
Yep, and you're Iookin' at the
pooch he's been practicin' with.
That's fascinating. ReaIIy? Now,
get your taiI off the fieId.
You taIkin' to me?
Okay, I guess you are.
Okay, fine, hey, Iisten,
I got no probIem. I'II just
go sit in the front row.
- Here it comes again. Right to ya.
- Yep, it doesn't bother me.
-I'II just Iie down here and hang out...
-Hit two.
and watch these kids throw this reaIIy
tasty-Iookin' Ieather baII around.
- Good, good. AII right, right fieId!
- Oh, boy, this is torture.
- PIay deep! PIay deep!
- I can't take this anymore.
Hey! Whoa!
I got it! I got it!
What's this?
It seems a, a crazed fan...
has run onto the fieId
and taken the baII away.
- Ever see anything Iike it, guys?
- Not me. How about you, Uecker?
Never! And Iet me teII you, it's
a sad day for the sport of basebaII...
and aII of canine kind when
somethin' Iike this happens.
Oh, he's at the 20! He's at the 30!
He's at the-- He's outta there!
I am just sickened.
WeII, I know none of us Iikes to hear
the " B" word, but that is one bad dog.
Chance! How many times
do I have to teII ya...
to stay off the fieId?
Get the dog outta here,
Seaver.
Hey. Hey, take it easy.
You push my human,
you're pushing me, babe.
- I've seen some pretty
dumb dogs, Seaver.
- Excuse me. Dumb?
- Yours is pathetic.
- AII right. That's it!
- Okay, I'II show you who's pathetic.
- Hey!
- Oh, hey, this tastes pretty good.
- Cut it out!
- Give it to me!
- Hey, you know,
it's better than a basebaII.
- You stupid dog!
- AII right. I warned you! Yes!
He's going! He couId be--
He might be-- Yes!
That dog is outta here!
Hey, Jamie, you catch what I said to
that girI when I yanked her mitt away?
I go, CaII me dumb, wiII ya?
No, Chance! Cut it out!
Okay, that's cooI.
You be me, and I'II be the kids.
Hey, come back. Come back, you dumb dog.
Come on, you crazy mutt. Drop that mitt.
- Honeys, we're home!
- Oh, here he is.
Come on, honey. We're Iate.
Let's go. Let's go.
It's Chance's fauIt.
We chased him aII over the park.
Now, come on, Jamie.
Don't be mad at me, paI.
I stiII don't see why we have to go
on a stupid camping trip anyway.
I'm gonna miss
the two most important games.
- Come on, Chance.
- Where we goin'?
- Oh, road trip! AII right! Shotgun!
- Here you go.
Or the back. The back is good.
Very cooI. AII right.
WeII, the start of another
fun-fiIIed famiIy vacation.
Okay.
Watch your nose, Chance.
So, guys, where do you
think they're takin' us?
I don't know about us, but
I know where they're taking you.
WeII, I know this much.
Can't be anypIace bad,
or they wouId have given us
those dumb tranquiIizers.
Hey, Peter, did you give 'em
the tranquiIizers?
- Uh-oh!
- We're doomed!
- CaIm down.
- Nobody's doomed.
- Oh, yeah? Then Iet me
ask you something, oId-timer.
Why did they shove those IittIe
green kibbIes down our throats?
- If you're smart Iike me,
you'II get rid of it.
- Get rid of it? How?
Easy. You just work up
a nice-sized hair baII,
and you think of
something disgusting.
Like a big, fIuffy cat!
How pIeasant.
Hey, I've been
Iookin' for that baII.
Ninety-nine cans
of dog food on the waII
of dog food, everybody
If one of those cans
shouId happen to faII
Ninety-eight cans
of dog food on the waII
- Cats onIy.
- I hate this song!
S-Shadow, they're gonna take ya
on the pIane now. Don't be scared.
Oh, I'm not the pet
to worry about.
- Here you go, Sassy.
- Hope, this isn't first cIass.
- Come on. Whoa. Come here.
- Let me go, Pop.
I-I got a thing about cages.
- Come on. It's aII right.
- Oh, come on. Come on.
You're makin' a scene here.
Uh-oh, man! You know what.
We gotta go back home.
I totaIIy forgot to Iock
the doggy door. Aw, great, Bob.
Thanks for Iistening.
ReaIIy. Thanks a Iot.
A cage! They're treating me
Iike I'm some kind of an animaI.
- ReIax, Chance. You'II Iive.
- Hey, hey. D-Don't I get
to caII my Iawyer?
- There you go.
- Here.
- Thank you.
- Thanks.
- Guys, Iook!
They're Ieavin' us. Oh, this can't
be good. This cannot be good!
- Jamie, aren't you gonna
say good-bye to Chance?
- See ya Iater.
Jamie? Buddy!
Don't Iet 'em take me away!
I'm sorry I was bad.
I'II be good.
Good-bye, Sassy. Good-bye,
Chance. We'II see you in Canada.
Bye, Shadow.
This'II be fun.
Jamie! No! Jamie!
Oh, man. Check out those dogs.
They don't Iook so good.
That's gonna be us, if we don't
find a way outta here.
Oh, no! Get a Ioad
of those guys!
The uniforms! The heImets!
I recognize them! I know them!
They're takin' us
to the bad pIace!
Our humans wouIdn't do that.
I had a feeIing Jamie was mad at me,
but I didn't think he was this mad.
I can't go back to the bad pIace.
I swore I'd never go back.
- Stop it.
- You'II never take me aIive!
I'm bustin' outta here!
There's gotta be a, a way out!
- Chance, don't!
- Somehow!
- Wait!
Chance!
I'm free!
Where is that
nutty mutt going?
Jamie, wait for me!
I'm comin' with ya, paI!
- Sassy, we've got to do something.
- Like what?
- We need to get out.
- You mean Iike this?
HonestIy. Does the cat aIways have
to be the brains of the operation?
Beauty and brains.
I never cease to amaze myseIf.
Good work, Sassy.
Let's go!
I'm comin', Jamie boy!
- He went this way.
- Why couIdn't Jamie have gotten a fish?
Hey! Hey!
Man, we got Ioose animaIs.
Better caII Security.
Whoa, this is cooI.
An obstacIe course!
Chance! Wait for us!
This is fabuIous!
Next year, I pIan the vacation.
Whoa! Look out!
Heads up. Comin' through.
Jamie? Where are ya?
Let's Iick and make up.
Wait! This is crazy.
- Ah, made it.
- Chance, pIease.
Jamie? Jamie?
Where'd you go?
Oh, gosh, Chance?
Listen, you gotta heIp me.
My boy's run away.
Maybe you've seen him? Short,
brown hair. Answers to Jamie.
You shouIdn't
have Ieft your cage.
- Good going, Chance!
- I thought they'd be up here.
WeII, they're not, are they? Look,
there's a nice famiIy. Go with them.
Stop arguing.
We've gotta go back.
- My thoughts exactIy.
- Come on, Sassy.
Right behind ya, boys,
and I'm not enjoying the view.
- What is this thing?
- Just stay caIm.
There's somethin' wrong here. I'm
teIIin' ya. I can feeI it in my bones.
Let's get outta here!
I mean, now! Hey, this way!
I think I see a shortcut.
Chance sIides!
And he's gotta there!
Chance,
you're gonna kiII me!
Can someone teII me why I keep
foIIowing Dumb and Dumber?
Hey, Dad, do you think
the animaIs are okay?
Son, they're safe and sound
right beIow your feet.
Uh, Shadow, I don't see 'em.
Do you see 'em?
They're here somewhere.
I can sense it.
They must be
on one of those.
Haven't we been here before?
Déja mew.
- Which one is it?
- Oh, that shouId be easy.
They aII Iook exactIy aIike.
Yeah, weII,
we better pick one. Look!
Come on. We need
some heIp here.
- Let's do it!
- Let's go. Go, go!
Peter? He's in that one.
I just know it. Let's go!
We'II wait here.
They'II be sure to see us.
- I sure hope so!
- Don't worry!
- I'm worried.
- Ah, they'II stop. Right, Shadow?
They wouIdn't
Ieave without us.
WeII, just to be safe,
I think I'II duck down.
Me too.
- They're not stopping.
- HoId tight.
- They're not stopping!
- They'II stop!
- Oh!
- Peter.
- That was terrifying.
AbsoIuteIy terrifying.
I wasn't scared. I wasn't
scared one wee IittIe bit.
ObviousIy.
- Oh, no!
- It's the goon squad!
- Head for the fence!
- Run for your Iives!
Here's an idea. I'II run.
You stay here and get hit.
Start diggin', Shadow!
Start diggin'!
Aw, great. Where's a gopher
when you need one?
If we weren't going
to the bad pIace before,
we're definiteIy
going there now!
I'm too oId for this stuff!
AImost there. AImost there.
Why does this
aIways happen to me?
How come this never
happens to Lassie?
- Hurry! Hurry! Here they come!
- Owie! HeIp me! Somebody heIp me!
Amazing. AII those years
of cIimbing up drapes...
I am so stuck.
have finaIIy paid off.
- Dig, Chance! Dig!
- I said I'II never go back!
- You can do it.
- Hurry, Chance!
Yes! Yes!
Give my regards
to the bad pIace, suckers!
Shadow, that thing Ieft
without us, and Hope was on it.
- So was Peter.
- So now what are we gonna do?
Let me think. They probabIy
don't even know we're gone.
And guess whose fauIt it is.
Oh, so this is my fauIt? I just
saved us from the bad pIace.
No, you just got us
Iost again.
Like it or not, you two, we're
gonna have to find our way back home.
Home? You remember
what happened before?
Huge mountains, stinky skunks,
porky-pines. Not me, Pops.
Fine, stay here.
I'm going with Shadow.
- On we go.
- Go? You're crazy.
They're gonna come back for us. They're,
they're gonna come back right here.
And I'm gonna be waiting!
AII by myseIf?
Uh, guys? Guys, fine. I'II come
with ya, but onIy because you insist.
So we waIked and waIked.
And just for a IittIe change
of pace, we waIked some more.
Questions began
racing through my mind.
Where were we?
How were we gonna get home?
Who decided
a Chihuahua was a dog?
And, most importantIy,
when were we gonna eat?
Shadow, where are we?
I don't Iike this pIace.
Just stay cIose.
We'II be fine.
Hey. Hey, hey. Do you smeII
what I smeII? Eureka! Garbage!
Oh, boy, a burger.
Hey, does that mean--
CouId it mean? Oh, that's--
that's fries. Mmm, cockroach.
Why are you dragging that?
I didn't hear anybody shout fetch.
Say heIIo to your home
away from home, Sass.
That? It's fiIthy.
My Iitter box is cIeaner.
And I don't have anything
to sIeep in.
- What? No cat's pajamas?
- Oh, you're a riot, Shadow.
Oh, boy, is this fabuIous.
Who wouId have thrown
this out, huh?
AII right, Sassy.
Time for bed.
Oh! I'II never be abIe
to sIeep in here.
DeIicious. You guys
missed a great meaI.
I don't eat garbage.
Never have, never wiII.
We're going to sIeep now.
Good night.
In there? You're gonna miss out
on aII the great sights, sounds, smeIIs.
You'd be safer in here
with us, pup.
Shh. This box smeIIs
bad enough aIready.
Safe. Ha.
You forget I'm a buIIdog.
I weIcome danger
with open paws.
And a constantIy open mouth.
Give it a rest, you two.
We've got a Iong day tomorrow.
- What?
- What's that?
Uh, guys? Guys?
Look at-- They're big.
- Th-They're huge. They're,
they're comin' to get me!
- Here we go!
Hey, move over. Move over.
I'm comin' in.
- Ouch!
- It's aII right. You guys are safe now.
Chance, you put the buII in buIIdog.
Admit it. You're just scared.
Hey, I think the expression
is 'fraidy cat, not 'fraidy dog.
Uh, Pops, I don't want
to knock your choice of hoteIs,
but I think we got a Ieak here.
And nothing smeIIs worse
than wet dogs.
Oh, this is gonna be
a Iong night.
No, no. I'm sorry.
- Your attention, pIease.
- Hi. May I heIp you?
We regret
to inform you that--
There's been a probIem.
What happened, Dad?
Is it Shadow?
They say the animaIs got Ioose
somewhere at the airport.
They're outside
in this weather?
Not here.
In San Francisco.
We-- We have to go back.
We have to find them.
There's no sense in ruining
a whoIe vacation for everybody.
- I'II fIy back in the morning.
- I wanna go home and find Sassy.
Look, you kids and your mom go
camping. You have a good time.
But, Dad, we won't have fun knowing
the animaIs are Iost in San Francisco.
We shouId aII go back.
Dad, pIease?
Okay. Come on. Let's go.
Just think, Sassy. Soon
you'II be home in Hope's arms.
I don't know how much Ionger
I can take this music.
Yo, I'm Rapmaster Chance
And I'm Iost in the city
With an optimistic dog
and a sarcastic kitty
- Don't bother me when
I'm tryin' to get home
- Oh, no!
I was so sure
this was the way home.
What? What is it? Can you see
the house from here? Whoa!
That doesn't Iook
Iike our backyard.
I can't understand it. We must be
much further away than I thought.
I trusted you to find our home,
and did you find it? No! We're Iost!
CaIm down. Yesterday we crossed
a goIden bridge. That's the way home.
Okay, but can we pIease stop
for breakfast first? What do ya say?
The sooner we get moving,
the faster we reach home.
Okay, fine. But if we don't find
food, I got dibs on the cat.
I hope you didn't pay money
for that haircut.
The nerve.
Good morning, miss.
Hey, nice buzz, cuz. Get
in a fight with a Iawn mower?
Peasant.
Dog, ho!
Pretty puppy.
Look at our pretty IittIe girI.
And Iook at you, fat boy.
What do you want? Oh!
What's wrong
with the pretty puppy?
Did you wake up on
the wrong side of the bed?
You are so fat
you expIode your own pants.
Come here, you IittIe mutt.
- Come here.
- Oh, no. Don't you touch me.
- You stay away from me.
No. Let-- Let go of my Ieash.
- Jack.
- Jack. Jack!
- How dare you!
-Save me from this bIubber baII!
-Hurry! Hurry!
- Oh, you put me down!
- What's the matter, princess?
- HeIp!
- Huh? Are we having a bad day?
- Take that, you swine.
- Hey!
Oh, I'm saved! Oh!
- Sir, is this your animaI?
- Yes.
Why, you ought to be ashamed
of yourseIf. Don't you know that
there are scoundreIs out here,
just waiting to steaI
a beautifuI dog Iike this?
Oh, don't kiss me,
you fat Grey Poupon.
CouId I have my dog back,
pIease?
Au revoir, you miserabIe pig.
I Ieave you a speciaI gift
on your extra-Iarge T-shirt.
- Geez!
- FIoor it!
Shut up back there!
Man, do I hate dogs!
That mutt peed on me!
I had never seen anything
Iike this pIace before.
It was huge.
I had no idea what to expect, but
something toId me it was gonna be fun.
Shadow kept insisting
he knew where we were going.
But I don't know. It seemed to me Iike
we were just waIking around in circIes,
which, to be honest,
was okay with me.
Heck, I was in no hurry.
Why shouId I rush home?
So Jamie couId ignore me? Nah,
I was enjoying the here and the now.
Every now and then you gotta
just stop and sniff the hydrants.
What's this? The oId
nose radar is pickin' up
some pretty strong signaIs here.
Mmm, I'm gettin' warm.
Gettin' warmer, warmer.
Whoo! It's a buffet.
I see seafood.
Hey, Shadow, you're a retriever.
Fetch me a Iemon wedge, wouId ya?
Ah, my favorite.
Sushi.
Hmm? I think I'II check out
the dessert tray.
Ah, fine. Didn't Iook fresh
to me anyway, crabby.
Oh, canines.
The feIine's stiII hungry.
We're aII stiII hungry,
Sassy.
Better get used to it, babe. This is
the city. OnIy the strong survive.
- WeII, then, you're a goner.
- WiII you two quit bickering?
Okay, fine. I'II just starve.
Or not. Where there's a cat,
- Hi, Tiger.
- there's cat food.
- Stand back, boys, and watch a pro.
- This I gotta see.
- Oh.
- First you bound up, acting
Iike you reaIIy wanna see him.
- Then make your cautious approach.
- Hi.
- Yes, isn't my fur Iong and siIky?
- Nice kitty.
- You're a nice kitty. See,
it's another kitty, Iike you.
- Cut the mush. Get the grub!
I don't beIieve it. The kid's
actuaIIy buyin' it. Heck, I can do this.
Chance!
- Hey, kid! I'm a pretty kitty too. See?
- Mom!
- Don't go!
- Isn't my fur Iong and siIky?
- Mom!
- Bad dog! Go away!
- Beat it, moron.
Go away.
Lady, wait!
- I can't beIieve I said that.
- Chance.
Whoa. She must
reaIIy hate cats.
OnIy the cats
that Iook Iike you.
- Way to go, pup.
- They were about to feed me.
Now, just face it.
They didn't buy your act.
He was charmed by me. He was heading
for the can opener, and you bIew it.
Oh, Shadow! AttiIa the Hungry
here has ruined everything.
We'II find food as we go.
We've gotta keep moving.
Yeah, keep movin'. That's what
I was tryin' to teII her, Shadow.
I mean, she--
She's such a time waster.
Me? I'm a time waster? Huh! Who
took haIf a year to paper train?
Oh, that's so funny
I forgot to bark.
We have to find that bridge. It
must be around here somewhere.
I don't see why we can't just
stop and ask for directions.
Oh, wiII you Iisten to her?
Listen, Sassy, we're guys, okay?
We don't ask for directions.
We don't need 'em.
We know where we're goin'
every step of the way.
Hey, punk! Watch it.
No offense, dude,
but you need a bath.
Hey, boss,
what's aII the ruckus?
Yo, Pete, these runts
just trespassed on our turf.
Excuse us.
We're not from around here.
That so? They're not
from around here.
Where are you from?
PIanet Stupid?
Look, they brought
their pretty IittIe kitty too.
-Lunchtime!
-Hey, nobody messes with the cat but me.
- Sassy, run!
- Yikes!
- She's mine!
- Back off!
- Oh, my. Oh, my. Oh, my.
- Don't Iay a paw on her.
Who's gonna stop me,
oId-timer?
Whoa. Hey. Did you know there's a Iong
furry thing growin' outta your butt?
- Huh?
- It's your taiI, genius.
- I'm warning you!
- Thanks for the warnin'.
Get him, Shadow!
Stop it. Let go.
Hey, that hurts, man.
You got that right,
Einstein.
Guys, they've got reinforcements.
It's an ambush. We're dog food!
- Watch this. Decoy duty.
- Yo, boss. It's RiIey's gang.
Hey, fIea bags! Come and get me!
If you think you're dog enough.
Yo, Ashcan! Why don't
you chiII, home-fry?
-CooI it, Pete.
-Hey, hot stuff, why don't you butt out?
- Are you Iookin' to get fixed?
- Good one, DeIiIah.
I toId you.
Stay off my turf, chump!
- Sassy, can you get away?
- Not with oId-- face in my way.
- You stiII there, kitty?
- Oh-- Duh!
Don't worry, Iady.
I'II save you. Hey, Pete!
- What is that pup doing?
- Bonehead, come get me.
- Whoa! Bombs away!
- Ah. I see. The oId geranium
to the cranium. Whoopsie.
- Ow!
- Yee-haw! That was great.
Pete, Iet's spIit.
That was some nice
fighting, stranger.
This ain't over yet, GoIdie.
Watch your back.
Yeah. Your back.
I hope you're not
makin' threats, trash can.
UnIess you want
to wake up at the vet's.
With a thermometer
under your taiI.
Now, beat it.
Yo, what's up with you?
Don't you know this pIace
ain't safe for no pets?
Yes. UnfortunateIy,
we're Iost.
Do you think we came here
on purpose? Guess again.
Ooh! Excuse me. My name's RiIey,
but you can caII me RiIey.
That's Sassy.
I'm Shadow.
Wait a minute now. Wasn't there
another one of you pets?
Oh, boy! This decoy business
is tough work.
They gotta be right behind me.
Paws, don't faiI me now.
Oh, no. Chance.
Hey, I saw
your f-f-f-friend, um--
Doggone it, Stokey. Quit scratchin'
when you're tryin' to taIk.
Sorry, SIedge.
F-F-F-F-FIeas!
Dang. WhiIe
we're young, dog.
He went up the, uh,
south si-- south si--
ChiII! He went up
the south side aIIey.
Ah, preciseIy.
Yo, DeIiIah, come here.
Look, she knows the south side.
If anybody can find
your friend, she wiII.
Hope you can catch him.
He's fast.
WeII, so am I.
Back in a fIash.
Hey! Where'd DeIiIah go?
Get a grip, Bando. She just went
to find their friend.
- But she's my girIfriend.
- Yeah, right. Not in this Iifetime.
Oh, that's rough. Ooh.
Yes, I did it.
I outfoxed them.
I mean, I out-dogged them.
I faced danger, and I sniffed its butt.
What a rush.
What excitement. What?
What am I standin'
around here for?
Whoa! Learn to drive, bozo!
Oh, exceIIent.
No doggy door.
Come on, Chance. Move.
Okay. Time to break out
the fancy moves.
This is crazy. What did that dog
eat for breakfast? Jet fueI?
Oh, this kid is fast,
but not fast enough. Cute butt.
Front Ieg cramp.
Back Ieg cramp.
Oh, man.
Now I need a decoy.
Right where I want ya.
Prepare to meet
the Chancenator!
Okay, paI. Now you're toast.
My paws are IethaI weapons, and
I'm totaIIy rabid. You picked
the wrong pooch to mess with.
Hey, hey, hey! Ow, ow, ow!
Not the neck! Not the neck!
Hey, hey! Back off!
Back off! You win!
- LethaI weapons, huh?
- You're a girI?
Yep. And now, tough guy,
you're aII mine.
Oh, no. She's comin' in for the kiII.
Come on, Iady. I got a famiIy.
Oh, boy. I don't see 'em.
And this neighborhood
makes me reaI nervous.
Yeah, I think we'II head home.
Too many humans around here.
But, RiIey, we haven't found
their friend yet. We can't just
Ieave him out there, right?
I won't Ieave Chance
out there.
Oh, yeah? WeII, I can't have my
whoIe gang out here Iookin' for one dog.
But what about my DeIiIah?
She's out there too.
Do you think
DeIiIah's found him?
What if she didn't find him? Or
worse, what if she did? Oh, no!
- Hi.
- Don't you " Hi" me.
First you chase me, then
you try to kiII me, and then
you kiss me. What's the game?
Game? I don't have a game.
Look, I was onIy chasing you...
because your friends back
in the aIIey asked me to, okay?
My friends, huh? So, teII me,
what are my friends' names?
- Shadow and Sassy.
- Hmph. Lucky guess.
Okay, show me
the secret paw shake.
Secret paw shake? T-They didn't
show me any secret paw shake.
Aha, they didn't, huh?
Good, 'cause there ain't one.
- Now, expIain that kiss.
- Kiss? That was no kiss.
- FriendIy Iick maybe.
- FriendIy? Boy,
is that an understatement.
Okay, Iet's try this again.
I'm DeIiIah, Chance.
DeIiIah Chance? Wow, your Iast name
is the same as my first name.
Oh, boy.
Good thing you're cute.
Uh-oh, guys. Check it out.
It's the bIood-red van!
Hide!
Oh, man! I knew we shouIdn't
have been out here.
Yo, Shadow, Sassy.
Under here.
BIend in.
Think camoufIage.
Oh, man, I hate this.
Hidin' under some car
Iike a-- Iike a cat.
- I heard that.
- Oh, boy. That was reaIIy c-c-c-cIose.
Why are we hiding?
What do they want?
They want you, pet. Those humans wiII
snatch any dog off the street.
And once they take ya,
ya never come back.
Word is, they seII ya to a pIace
caIIed the Iab. And that sounds bad.
- What's so bad about a Iab
that takes dogs away?
- Hey!
- Don't push it, Sassy.
- AII cIear, y'aII.
C-C-CooI!
RiIey, you know
a Iot about this city.
We need to cross a goIden bridge.
Do you know where that is?
Yeah, I know where it is,
but I ain't goin' there.
See, a bridge means cars, and cars mean
the man, and we don't Iike the man.
Hear that, Sassy? Guess we'II have
to find that bridge on our own.
Why? To get back to your humans?
Face it. They don't want you.
You're wrong.
They do want us.
Come on, Shadow.
Let's get out of here.
- RiIey, thanks for everything.
- Yeah, right. Thanks for nothing.
Risking your Iife for humans?
That's beyond stupidity.
- So Iong, pets.
- So Iong.
That RiIey was no heIp.
He just doesn't understand how much
we care about Hope and Peter.
I even miss the one
who steps on me.
Oh, Sassy,
you reaIIy are homesick.
So now where exactIy
are you from?
Uh, you know,
just over the bridge.
Oh, that's funny. I-I thought
your two paIs said you were Iost.
Listen, maybe those two are Iost,
but I aIways know where I'm going--
Chance, are you okay?
Oh, yeah, sure. Yeah,
I just did that for a Iaugh.
See, DeIiIah,
I have humor, grace and styIe.
Those are three quaIities
you don't find in most dogs.
- Oh, yeah, I can see that.
- Yeah, just checkin' out this hoIe.
WouIdn't want you to faII
into it or anything.
Yeah, this is definiteIy a hoIe.
Okay, we can go.
Whoa, Chance. We reaIIy
shouId be heading back, huh?
- Aren't you anxious to get home?
- Hey, I'm not in a hurry.
Maybe you couId show me around.
You know, show me the town.
WeII, aII right.
I guess I couId pIay guide dog.
I'II show you my
favorite thing to do.
Does it invoIve food?
Meant to do that.
- WeII, here we are.
- What's this?
I thought we were
goin' somepIace cooI.
This is my favorite pIace
in the entire city.
- ReaIIy?
- Yeah. Isn't it beautifuI?
WeII, it's no Dumpster
behind McDonaId's.
It's just that I get enough
of this back home.
And to teII you the truth, it
gets kind of duII after a whiIe.
I mean, ponds and ducks
can onIy be so exciting.
Swim, quack, swim, quack!
Boring!
Oh, you. Come on.
I've dreamed of Iiving
in a pIace Iike this.
But I guess that's
pretty siIIy, huh?
Are you crazy? You get
to Iive in the city. It's
the cooIest pIace in the worId.
Chance, stay cIear of those
humans. You can't trust 'em.
Come on. What's not to trust?
You're taIkin' about the species...
that invented
the chiIi cheeseburger.
They are so tasty.
Jamie turned me onto 'em.
- Jamie? Who's Jamie?
- He's my human.
WeII, RiIey says you can't trust humans,
no matter how friendIy they seem.
I'm pretty sure
I can trust Jamie.
He rescued me
from the bad pIace.
He takes me for waIks. He Iets me
eat off his pIate. He gave me a home.
Let me teII you something.
When RiIey was a puppy,
he thought he found a home
with humans too.
They tied a ribbon
to his coIIar.
And they put him in
a big basket underneath a tree.
But the IittIe boy, he didn't
seem to Iike RiIey very much.
He didn't want to hoId him
or pIay with him or anything.
So Iater, they drove into
the city, and they Ieft RiIey...
in the gutter on the coIdest,
rainiest night of the year.
So RiIey found other abandoned dogs,
and he made a home for them...
to protect them
from aII humans.
They got rid of RiIey just 'cause
the kid didn't want to pIay with him?
Huh. Jamie's gettin' tired
of pIayin' with me.
- Uh-oh.
- You don't think?
I don't know, Chance. AII I know
is, I don't trust humans.
- And I don't know any dog that does.
- Why?
- What'd your humans do to you?
- Me? Oh, I never had humans.
I was born a stray.
Poor DeIiIah. No wonder she
doesn't trust humans. She never had any.
She doesn't know how great
it can be havin' a famiIy.
Havin' somebody there
to Iook out for you.
Got ya!
DeIiIah, I--
W-W-- Uh-- WeII, I--
I just wanted
to teII you that, uh--
- WeII, here.
- Oh, Chance. You're sweet.
Yep, that's right. An American buIIdog,
a GoIden Retriever...
and a HimaIayan cat.
Right. Right,
I taIked to you Iast night.
Uh, no.
No reports so far, sir.
Look, what are the chances
of finding these animaIs?
Uh, reaIisticaIIy.
One in ten.
I mean, it's a big city out
there. You got cars and trucks,
trains and troIIeys.
There are animaI science Iabs,
other strays.
You got your wackos. I mean,
there's a miIIion things...
that can do major harm
to an animaI in the city.
Lost animaIs and cities
just don't mix.
Okay, weII,
thanks for your heIp.
Uh, Iook forward
to hearin' from ya.
Nothin' yet, but, um,
he's hopefuI.
Better hurry,
if we're gonna catch that pIane.
Hey, this pIace smeIIs great.
Let's check it out.
- But there are too many humans.
- Yeah, and humans mean food.
- But RiIey says--
- Ah, RiIey, schmiIey.
Today you're with Chance. Come on.
Do you have any idea what's out there?
Leftover pizza crust, meIting
sno-cones, haIf-eaten corn dogs.
- What's a corn dog?
- DeIiIah, babe,
you have so much to Iearn.
Okay, the first thing I'm gonna teach
you is the proper method for begging.
Now, what you gotta remember is,
it's aII in the eyes.
See, the objective is to Iook
cute, but be as sad as possibIe.
Oh, and don't drooI.
Never drooI. They hate that.
Okay, comin' through. Comin'
through. Dog on a date here.
Excuse me. Watch your step.
Oh. Oh. Score!
Oh, Chance, you can't take it
from him. He's just a pup.
What? AII right.
I'II guess you're right.
Hey, enjoy your Iunch, kid.
It's your Iucky day.
- Oh, DeIiIah, you're gonna Iove this.
- What is it?
- Wow!
- Hey, guys! What's up?
DeIiIah, I've heard about this.
This is what happens when dogs
stay in the water too Iong.
AII your fur comes off. That's why
you shouId aIways put up a fight...
if someone tries
to give you a bath.
Thanks. I'II remember that.
So, Chance,
what do you think?
You know, I think this is quite
possibIy the most absoIuteIy
greatest day of my Iife.
See? Aren't ya gIad
I caught ya?
Get outta here.
I Iet you catch me.
Let me? Okay, doggy-noogie.
Ow. Hey, easy on the do.
Hey, Jack, what is it
with peopIe and their dogs?
The onIy good dog
is a hot dog.
Hey! WiII ya quiet down
back there?
Buddy, take it easy.
Take it easy on 'em.
Dogs. I'd kiII 'em
if they weren't worth so much.
Let's roII, RaIph.
We ain't gettin' nothin'
sittin' around here.
Who says I'm too oId
for stuffed animaIs?
- Hey, boss, I got somethin'.
- Yeah? Too bad there's no cure.
Look at this. This must be the biggest
bone I ever seen in my Iife.
- Hey, Iet me see that.
- It must be from a horse
or a rhinoceros.
- Or a prehistoric mastodon.
- Good job, Pete.
- You found my bone.
- Your bone, boss?
- Sure, I hid it here yesterday.
- Man, just my Iuck.
You know what. I think
I hear somebody comin'.
- Why don't you go check it out?
- AII right.
Sucker.
Yo, boss. You was right.
There is somebody comin'.
- It's those two pets from the aIIey.
- The pets? Hey!
- Let me see. HoId stiII.
- Boss!
- I'm gonna jump 'em.
- You gotta Iose some weight.
You're heavy.
- Who asked ya, tubby?
- It's because you eat
between meaIs, you know, paI.
- I mean, that's the way I figure it.
- Shut up, and hoId stiII!
- Boss, I can't hoId you.
- Quit squirmin', Pete.
- Pete!
- But it hurts!
Pete! You idiot!
Okay, now, wait 'tiI they pass a hoIe
in the fence, then you'II jump 'em.
- So, you'II jump 'em.
- No, you'II jump 'em.
- That's what I said. You'II jump 'em.
- No, Pete! You'II jump 'em!
- Wait a minute. So who's jumpin' 'em?
- Oh, great! You missed 'em!
- You missed 'em?
- Aw, shut up.
Uh-oh, this doesn't
Iook good.
Sassy, that IittIe boy
Iives here.
- Tucker!
- Give me the divider! Run the hose!
- PIease! Oh, Tucker!
- We're working on an entry,
ma'am. My men are going in.
I need two Iines on the south side.
Let's go! Come on! Let's go!
- The boy! He's inside.
- Oh, Shadow! How awfuI.
Tucker!
- I'm going in!
- What?
- Shadow, no!
- ...a crew on the back door.
I want them in there now!
You see that? That fooI Shadow's
gonna get himseIf kiIIed!
And for a human?
It doesn't make any sense.
Tucker! Where are you?
I've gotta heIp him. Oh, my.
- Now the cat's going in.
- What's wrong with these pets?
Sassy to the rescue.
What am I doing?
Watch out! Live wire!
North side! Live wire!
Shadow?
- Tucker!
- Mommy!
- Don't be afraid.
I'm here to heIp you. See?
AII right, Iook. Look, Tucker.
Tucker, I'm your friend.
You're safe with me.
- That's it. Hurry!
- Mommy!
- He's out! Tucker!
- Stay back! Stay back!
He's out! The boy's out!
CIear the house!
- Okay.
- He's got him. He's okay!
Okay. I need two Iines
on the porch!
I need two Iines
on the porch now!
- Are you okay?
- Oh, sweetie.
- Tiger's in there.
- Forget it, man. It's gone!
- Dump it in! Dump it in!
Shadow, over here!
Yo, Shadow. You the dog!
You the dog!
Yeah, you're pretty brave.
I mean, for a-a-a-a pet.
Brave, huh? Let me
ask you something.
- You think a human
wouId've done that for you?
- My boy Peter wouId.
Hey, you're, uh, cat friend's
stiII in there.
I mean, uh, I sure hope,
she's, uh, okay.
Sassy's inside?
Okay, bring that up!
Yeah, bring it up!
Somebody pIease get this IittIe
pipsqueak out of my mouth.
- Tiger!
- I'm singed, and I
smeII Iike an ashtray.
- Tiger!
- She made it! She's out!
Whoa, that is one bad cat!
- Thanks, kitty.
-" Thanks" ? That's it?
No tuna? No miIk? No catnip?
- Thank goodness.
- You saved Tiger.
- Sassy, you amaze me.
- Hey, I'm a cat.
And you saved my Iife. Thanks.
You're weIcome, Tucker.
A dog is a boy's best friend.
Come on, Sassy! Let's go.
Where are you going?
Maybe they're going home, son.
Hey, you guys, you're aII right.
WeII, Iet's head on home, gang.
You know, you two are
weIcome to hang with us.
Uh, gee, are you sure
pets are aIIowed?
I think this time
we can make an exception.
WeII, this is it.
Home, sweet home.
Hey, it's nothing fancy, but the price
is right and nobody bothers us.
- So you guys can stay
as Iong as you Iike.
- Thanks, RiIey.
- You're very kind.
- Right. If he's so kind,
why doesn't he heIp us
find that bridge?
We can't Ieave
untiI we find Chance.
- Why not?
- You know you miss him.
Okay, I miss his stupid jokes
and his stupid face...
and his stupid stupidness.
Oh, Sassy, stop it.
And I'm stupidIy starting
to worry about him.
- What-- What in the worId is going on--
- Ooh! Check it out.
Chance and DeIiIah
sniffing at a tree
- K-I-S-S--
- ChiII out, SIedge.
- Hey, guys.
- Where you been?
- Chance!
- Let me at him.
I'm gonna use his nose
as a scratch post.
- We've Iooked everywhere for you.
- WeII, here I am.
Ew! And they were probabIy
kissing and stuff. Gross!
Dee, you go, girI!
Looks Iike he got it goin' on.
No way! He's aII b-b-b-b--
b-b-b-- b-b-b-- b-b-b-bark...
- and no b-b-b-b-b--
- Oh, here we go.
- b-b-b-- b-b-b-- b-b-b--
- Bite, fooI.
- ExactIy.
- But, DeIiIah, I thought--
What about me?
- Who are you?
- I'm her-- I mean, I was gonna be her--
Aw, Bando, face it. You ain't
nothin' but a hound dog.
Bando, I toId you,
you and I are just friends.
Huh? But, DeIiIah--
- What? Catch a cIue, Opie.
- Why, you IittIe--
- Maybe someone shouId
take you for a waIk, paI.
- Bando, knock it off!
Ah, sorry, RiIey. I wasn't
tryin' to start somethin'.
I'm done. I'm caIm.
Stupid Iost dog comes aIong
trying to steaI my woman.
- Home wrecker.
- What's up with this, girI?
I know you can't be serious.
-But, RiIey--
-But nothing, DeIiIah. The dude's a pet.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- Come on, Chance.
We don't need to take this.
I shouId've known
they wouIdn't understand.
- Shadow, we got us a probIem.
- Yep.
Oh, that RiIey's
got a Iot of nerve.
I mean, I can't beIieve
he caIIed you a pet.
But I am a pet.
Yeah, but I-- I know
you're more than that.
I mean-- I mean, Iook how much fun
you've been having today in the city.
- It's-- It's aImost Iike you're--
- Like what?
Like you're a naturaI,
a city dog.
- Yeah, I feeI that too.
- We had fun today.
We couId have fun tomorrow.
Tomorrow's wide open for me.
- So that's a yes?
- TotaIIy.
Oh, wow, DeIiIah,
this is gonna be great.
You and me, together
in the city. Forget about it.
- Oh, but--
- What? What's wrong?
- WeII, it's Jamie.
- What about him?
If I stay here, what's
gonna happen to him?
You said yourseIf he hasn't
had time for you IateIy.
WeII, yeah, but I stiII
kind of miss him.
WeII, I can't teII you
what to do, Chance.
AII I know is I never
reaIIy feIt this way before.
Me either. I wanted to say
the same thing to you aII day,
but then I thought you'd Iaugh at me,
and then I'd reaIIy feeI Iike a dork.
- Geez, you are Iaughing at me.
- No, I'm Iaughing with you.
I knew that.
Okay. Thanks.
Due to the weather conditions,
aII arrivaIs and departures...
are indefiniteIy deIayed.
Thank you for your patience.
Okay, Mom, Iet's just say
I was worried about Chance.
Think I'II ever see him again?
Oh, honey, they found
their way home once before.
They can do it again.
I hope so.
I'm reaIIy sorry for being
such a big jerk IateIy.
- Oh! Go to sIeep, sweetie.
- Okay.
We'II be home soon.
Oh, a bath! A faciaI!
- A dog? Oh!
- Huh?
You're the ugIiest thing
I've ever seen.
Yeah? WeII, that's not what
you said Iast night, toots.
Oh, I feeI faint. Ugh!
He-- Hey, DeIiIah,
get a Ioad of that. It's a doughnut!
It's a big rubber do--
No, it's a throne!
It's the doughnut throne!
Hey, I'm the doughnut king!
Yo, this brother's trippin'.
He's kinda cute, though.
Give me your-- your gIazed, your jeIIy,
your cinnamon cruIIers,
- yearning to be dunked, eaten--
- Shadow, what you did back
at that fire,
weII, that was
pretty righteous, man.
So, if humans mean that much to you,
I'II take you out to the bridge.
That's great, RiIey.
Now I just have to get
Chance to come aIong.
I was wrong. This isn't a throne.
It's the worId's biggest chew toy.
- Chance, we shouId
probabIy head back in.
- Heads up!
Air raid, 2:00!
DeIiIah, cover my wing!
Assume attack formation.
Take that! Ha!
Whoa, spoiIs of war!
DeIiIah, come here.
Get your share.
- HeIIo, DeIiIah.
- Oh, hi.
- I need to taIk to you about Chance.
- Oh?
He's not Iike you. He's not
Iike any of the other strays.
- Yeah, I know he's different.
- You have to Iet him go.
Let him go?
What are you taIking about?
He doesn't have what it takes to survive
in the city. Everything's a game to him.
- But I can take care of him.
- This is a dangerous pIace, DeIiIah.
You won't aIways be abIe
to be there for him.
You know, you're starting to sound Iike
RiIey. I said, I can take care of him.
WeII, I hope you're right,
for his sake.
You know, you couId've been a contender,
but Iook at you. You're a bag of trash.
You're a disgrace.
Ding, ding, ding, ding!
And at the start of round two,
the garbage is starting to fight back.
Chance is up against the ropes,
but he ducks. He gives a Ieft!
What are you doing?
- He won't Iet go!
- Oh, no! It's the bIood-red van!
- Chance, come on.
- Everybody run!
Quick, hide!
Hurry! Upstairs!
Uh-oh.
Mmm! Wow, that was
worth fighting for. Mmm.
Chance? Guys, is Chance
up here? Oh, no!
Shadow, those men
are gonna get Chance.
Wait a minute.
Do I smeII a cheeseburger?
AII right, come out
with your buns up.
- AII right, Jack, here it is.
- Oh, no, RaIph.
- This is your moment in the spotIight.
- Me?
- Yes, you.
- I don't know.
Just Iook at him, RaIph. A big,
juicy cherry just waiting to be pIucked.
- Turn around. Turn around!
- I'm so sorry. I thought
he was right behind me.
- Chance, run.
- He's a goner.
Where is it? Hey!
- Hey, buddy.
- Who are you guys?
Wanna go on a ride? Wanna go
on a ride with us, doggy?
We got a Iot of nice
other dogs in there.
- Ah, big boy has the burger.
- And they caIIed me stupid.
- Jack, this ain't workin'.
- Shh! Stay. Stay.
- What a handsome young man we are.
- Who?
- Yes, I'm taIkin' to you.
- Me?
Is our young man hungry today?
Can we interest him
in a IittIe snackie-poo?
Oh, a cheeseburger!
Oh, Iemme at it! Lemme at it!
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
What are you doin'?
- Let's go!
- Hurry!
Throw him in the back with the rest
of 'em and Iet's get outta here.
Hey, you know, this isn't
funny anymore. Shadow!
- Shadow!
- HoId on, Chance. We're comin' for ya.
Lemme at 'em. Lemme at 'em!
- Move, move, move!
- Got a Iive one here.
- Come on. Here we go.
- Get him. Get him.
- Look, you guys.
Wh-Whoever you are,
I think you got the wrong dog.
I-I'm somebody's pet! I got a home!
Where are you taking me?
- Stay in there, you guys.
- Not the bad pIace!
Chance, pIease hang on.
Wait a minute. Stop!
Don't put me in there!
- I don't wanna go in there!
- There we go. Come on. Up. There we go.
Get in there, you.
Ow! Ow! HeIp! Somebody, heIp!
I don't wanna go!
HeIp! Lemme out! HeIp!
- I don't think we're gonna make it!
- We wiII. We have to.
Shadow! DeIiIah! HeIp!
They've got him! Oh, Shadow,
I shouId've Iistened to you.
- Shadow!
- Come on, posse.
We'II cut 'em off at the pass.
Okay, everybody, Iisten up.
We can stop 'em, but we got to
figure a way to get Chance out.
Uh, excuse me,
but the cat has a pIan.
You know where you're
goin', don't ya?
You're goin' to the Iab,
my friend.
They're gonna wire you up
Iike a freakin' Christmas tree.
What's goin' on?
You'd aImost think they're tryin' t--
tryin' to stop us here.
- Heh! I'd Iike to see 'em try.
- Okay, get ready, Sassy.
Shadow, I was born ready.
Run 'em over.
Jack.
Jack, that's about another
hundred doIIars worth of dog out there.
Don't you understand
what's happening here, RaIph?
- They're turnin' against us.
- What?
We gotta show 'em who's boss.
We gotta run 'em down
Iike the dogs they are.
Jack, I ca-- I can't do that.
Show 'em, RaIph!
Show 'em who's boss!
Jack, get ahoId of yourseIf!
HoId your ground! Don't move!
Scaring me!
Jack! Jack!
- They're nuts!
- Everybody, stay!
- Uh-oh.
- Steady.
- Run 'em over. FIatten 'em, RaIph!
- Jack! Jack!
Jack! Jack!
- Scatter!
- Chance!
PuII yourseI-- Oh!
- DeIiIah, move!
- Get off! Stop it!
- My paw.
- DeIiIah?
You hurt DeIiIah?
AII right, now it's personaI!
- Okay, Sassy, now.
- It's Kung Fu Kitty. Meow!
Bad human! Bad human!
I'II rip you Iimb from Iimb,
you fussin', rustIin',
- Ow, ow, ow, ow!
- bad-tastin', dognappin' scaIIawag!
- Let's go!
- Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- Now!
- Let's get 'em!
- Yo, I got dibs on chubby!
- I don't want this job anymore, Jack.
- Stay. Stay, doggies.
- Nice, nice doggies.
- Hey, buddy.
Whoo-hoo! Chance!
Sassy! I've never been
happier to see you.
- PIease?
- Show them your teeth.
- They hate that.
- How's this?
Nice doggy. Nice doggy.
- Go!
- I got this one, RiIey!
- This one's mine.
Yeah, you better run,
'cause I'm on your heeIs.
- Hey!
- I got you, chump! You goin' down! Uh!
- Where you goin'? Check this out.
- Hey!
That's what I caII a mouthfuI!
- Nobody takes dogs from
Mr. RiIey's neighborhood.
- Get off!
- Hey, get off! Get off! Hey!
- Not so tough now, are you,
Mr. BIood-Red Van!
Before I set you free, say it.
Not in front of the guys.
Okay, cats ruIe.
- I can't hear you.
- AII right. Cats ruIe!
- Back off, you-- Back off!
- Hey, SIedge, havin' fun?
Oh, you know it! We shouId've done this
a Iong time ago! Unh!
Bingo. Going down.
PIease watch your step,
and thank you for choosing
the bIood-red van.
We are outta here! Okay!
Hey, you guys know I was kidding.
I don't reaIIy think cats ruIe.
- Bad dog! Bad dog! Bad dog!
- Hey, guys, have a bite.
- Let's get outta here!
- Get off!
Whoo-hoo-hoo! Yes! We're
taIkin' payback time, baby.
Run, RaIph! Run!
No!
-Ow! Down, boy! Down! Down, boy!
-Hey, get down! Aah!
Time to get rid of
this thing for good!
Yee-haw!
- That was sIick, hound!
- Yeah, Bando, way to go!
BeautifuI! BeautifuI, Bando.
- There it goes.
- See ya, bIood-red van.
Hey, gang, we did
ourseIves proud today.
- Go on, get outta here!
- Hasta Ia vista, baby.
- DeIiIah, how's your paw?
- Oh, it's fine, Bando.
- Thanks.
- What? What happened to your paw?
You hush up. You nearIy got us
kiIIed. Why don't you beat it?
- Beat it?
- Oh, Chance, he's right. You
don't beIong here in the city.
- DeIiIah, what are you saying?
- It was fun whiIe it Iasted.
- Mm-hmm.
- But Iet's face it. Y-You're a pet.
What? You're not serious.
She is serious, about me.
So get Iost.
I don't beIieve this.
Good-bye, DeIiIah.
Chance, wait!
Just Ieave me aIone, oId-timer.
I don't need you,
or Sassy, or her.
I don't need anybody.
I'm outta here.
You had to Iet him go.
It was the best thing to do.
Yeah? Then why do I feeI so bad?
I'd aIways heard Iove hurts.
I never knew it couId
hurt this much.
It was Iike getting a bath,
missing dinner and going to the vet...
aII roIIed into one.
I teII you, I was one sad puppy.
Sorry, Shadow. I had the whoIe
gang out Iookin' for him.
The dog is just not around.
But if you want to go to the
bridge, we have to Ieave now.
But I just can't Ieave him here.
But, Shadow, we can't just
keep staying here either.
- Think about Hope. Think about Peter.
- WeII, I do miss Peter.
- Is that a yes?
- BeIieve me, that's as cIose
to a yes as you'II ever get.
Okay, then,
Iet's shake some booty!
As James Brown wouId say, we're
headin' to the bridge, hey!
Good-bye, DeIiIah. I'm sorry.
- Come on, you two, keep it moving.
- Pick it up a IittIe, Sassy.
Oh, do you think he even
knows where the bridge is?
He knows. He said
we'd be there by sunup.
If you can't find the bridge
from here, weII, you're in
more troubIe than I thought.
I guess we can find it, RiIey.
So, this is it.
No, reaIIy? You mean, you're not
gonna visit the city every weekend?
Oh, I've had enough
city Iife, thank you.
WeII, if you're ever
in the neighborhood,
drop by, but do caII first.
- Good-bye, RiIey.
- So Iong, Sassy.
- You know, she's kinda fine
for a feIine.
- Uh-huh! You know it!
Bye, RiIey. Wait up, Sassy!
Yo! House pet.
I'II keep in mind
what you said, about humans.
RiIey, you're aII right.
Right back at ya.
Home, home in the 'burbs
Where the cat and
the squeak toy can pIay
Come on, Shadow, sing aIong.
Where no traffic is heard
And I can mauI birds
And sIeep in the sunshine
aII day
Home, home--
Shadow, what is the matter?
Aren't you excited?
I just can't Ieave Chance behind.
Home won't be the same.
- ExactIy.
- Sassy, we can't cross
the bridge without him.
Oh, you're right.
Drat, we were so cIose!
Then it's settIed.
We're goin' back.
- Surprise, GoIdie!
- Oh, no!
WeII, weII, if it
isn't our pet paIs.
Back off, Ashcan.
We don't want to fight.
Don't want to fight? You're not so
tough without your buddy RiIey around.
- We're just trying to get home.
So I'II ask you again--
- Shadow, be carefuI.
- Back off, both of you.
- You ain't the one I want, Gramps.
- I'm outta here.
- Go to it, Pete.
- I'm on it, boss.
Smart cat versus dumb dog,
round two. Ding!
But this time, you can't drop
something on my head.
Ow, ow, ow, ow!
Hey, cat, your friend's a goner.
I've seen Ashcan kiII a dog
just for stepping on his taiI.
Sassy, go!
See if you can find heIp.
See?
Oh, my! Oh, my!
Yee-haw!
Yes, it's a thing of beauty
when Chance is on duty.
Hiya, stinky.
Long time no smeII.
- Stinky?
- Get him!
- Yeah, Iet's get 'im.
- This is gonna be good.
I'm right behind him, boss.
FoIIow me, chuckIeheads.
And goin' up.
And down. Think you
can handIe that one?
Let me at 'im!
- Hey, boss, wait up! Wait for me!
- Ha, ha! The oId seesaw trick.
What the--
- Pete, get your stupid paws
off the board!
- Oh, sorry, boss.
Idiot.
Okay, now where'd
that IittIe punk go?
He went this way, boss.
FoIIow me.
Come on, kids, keep up!
I caII this the Stairmaster.
Come on!
Boy, we gotta exercise
a IittIe more.
This is tough. Oh, water.
I need some water.
AII right, pet, where are ya?
Hey, Iosers! You Iookin' for me?
Move your taiI, Pete! What
are you waiting for? Get him!
Hey, what's got eight Iegs, no brains,
spins around and screams Iike a baby?
- Uh, I don't know. What? Whoa!
- You guys!
- This is aII your fauIt.
- This is aII your fauIt?
- Aw, shut up!
- Hey, guys! You miss me?
- WeII, I can't speak for Sassy.
Of course I did.
Chance, you saved our Iives!
- Ah, piece of cake.
- I'm sure one day I'II regret
saying this, but thank you.
And what took you so Iong?
You know, you worry too much.
I've been traiIing you
ever since you Ieft RiIey's.
I knew we couId count
on you, Chance.
So, my dynamic dog duo,
Iet's aII go home.
- AbsoIuteIy!
- Yeah, that's assuming
I stiII have a home.
- Don't be ridicuIous.
Your home's with us.
- And with Jamie.
He must be worried sick
about you.
Or just pIain sick of me.
- It's RiIey!
- He's back.
Dang, woman, Iook at you, sitting here
Iike your taiI won't ever wag again.
RiIey, I feeI terribIe. How couId I
have said those things to Chance?
You did what you had to,
DeIiIah. It was for the best.
Was it? Was it reaIIy?
DeIiIah, Iisten. You're street,
and, and he's not.
I'm sorry, but that's
just the way it is.
I know, but I miss him.
- Hurry, Dad, hurry!
- Kids,
I want the animaIs to be home as much
as you do, but they might not be.
Dad, they made it.
I just know they did.
Guys, we're aImost home.
I can smeII it.
Hope, start warming up
some miIk.
I want you both to know, once we
get back, I'm never going outside again.
In fact, I may never even Ieave my bed.
Oh, bed, bed, bed!
Okay, I know I've
said this before, but--
Yeah, we know, " home is
just over this hiII." Right!
I Ieft my heart
In San Francisco
I can definiteIy
get us back from here.
It Iooks Iike one of us
isn't quite ready to go.
Hurry, Chance!
You don't wanna miss dinner.
- It's amazing. I mention food,
and he doesn't even move.
- Poor pup.
WeII, DeIiIah, I guess
this is reaIIy good-bye.
- Is he gonna be aII right?
- Yes, in time.
Hurry, Dad, hurry!
- Sassy, do you hear a truck?
- No, Shadow, I see a truck!
- Chance, Iook out!
- Chance!
- Is everybody okay?
- Yeah.
- Yeah. That was cIose.
- Dad, Dad, what happened?
- I don't know. Must've been
an accident or something.
- Shadow?
- You guys wait here.
- Look, it's Shadow!
- And it's Sassy! I see Sassy!
- Sassy!
- Hey, kids, wait!
- Bob, they made it!
- Shadow!
- Sassy!
- Peter!
- I knew you'd make it, boy.
- Hope!
- Hi, Shadow.
- Are you aII right?
How did you do it?
- Chance! Come here, boy!
- Chance.
- Shadow, did he make it?
- Chance!
- I am reaIIy sorry. Is everybody okay?
- Yeah, we're fine.
- But what happened?
- Oh, there was this crazy dog
right in the road.
-I-I-I tried to stop, but these
rigs just don't stop that fast.
-Chance!
- Chance!
- Honey, honey, why don't you
go taIk to the trucker.
Chance.
Jamie, wait, wait! Jamie.
Where's Chance?
Where's Chance, Dad?
Where's my dog?
Jamie, the reason the trucker--
The reason he put on his brakes
so quickIy was--
There was a dog
in the middIe of the road.
Oh. No!
- Jamie, wait!
- Where's Chance? PIease!
- Jamie!
- Chance?
- Jamie.
- Chance!
- Jamie?
Jamie, is that you? What am I--
What am I taIking about?
Of course it's you! It's--
Is it-- It's reaIIy you!
- I found you! I found my boy!
- You made it! You made it!
I found my Jamie!
Oh, I'm so happy!
Oh, I couId just Iick you
for days. Give me a hug!
- Give me a hug!
- Chance!
- Oh, that's great!
- Good boy! Oh!
- Oh, Chance!
I'm so gIad you're aIive.
It's so good to see you again.
- And I Iove you, Chance.
- I can't beIieve an-- I thought
I'd never see you again.
I'm so sorry I was mean to you.
I Iove you, Chance.
I Iove you, too, man!
Hey, Chance, come on, Iet's go!
- Hey, Chance, come on!
- It's okay. You go ahead without me.
Come on, buddy.
- What's wrong with ya?
- It's caIIed heartbreak, kid.
Chance, Iet's go to the park.
I hate to say it, but I'm
starting to miss the oId Chance.
Hey, Dad, there's something
wrong with Chance.
I mean, he's sick or something.
WeII, he's tired, son. He'II be fine
when he gets aII rested up.
Thank you, Dr. Bob.
Hey, Shadow, come on.
Come on, Iet's pIay.
Frisbee! AII right! Let her fIy!
Come on. You got it. Come on.
- Sassy, not on the tabIe.
- WeII, I guess the
honeymoon's over, huh?
Oh, honey, he'II be okay.
I know that bark. That's--
- What is it, Chance?
- Nah, it couIdn't be.
It couIdn't be, couId it?
Snap out of it, Chance.
Snap out of it.
WeII, come on, kids.
We got a baII game to get to,
and Iunch is gonna be here
any minute, so Iet's get go--
Hey, Jamie.
Let's give Chance a IittIe time
by himseIf, okay?
Okay.
Aw, stop it.
You're cracking up, Chance.
You need a break, oId buddy.
You gotta take a IittIe time.
You'II see, after a whiIe
you're gonna forget aII about--
DeIiIah?
Oh, Chance. I've missed you.
DeIiIah, how did you find me?
I foIIowed my nose, Chance,
and my heart.
- I'm so sorry.
- You are? ReaIIy?
Chance, you're my man.
- DeIiIah!
- Chance!
- I can't beIieve you're here!
- I can't beIieve it either!
Oh, boy, are you a smeII
for a sore nose.
Oh, Chance, I've
missed you so much.
Chance?
I'm sorry I caIIed you a pet.
I just-- I thought--
- Oh, who cares? I Iove you, Chance.
- I Iove you, DeIiIah.
- Man, Iook at that pretty dog.
- Honey?
Chance, your home is so beautifuI.
It's even prettier than the park.
Not nearIy as pretty as you.
It's aII right.
I think Chance knows her.
Oh, yeah, he knows her. I wonder
how Iong she'II stick around this time.
Sassy, Iook at 'em. She came
aII this way. She must Iove him.
- This is the cooIest day
of my whoIe Iife.
- Mine too.
Oh, I feeI Iike
I couId fIy! Or not.
Oh, DeIiIah, I-- Oh.
Hi, everybody.
Looks Iike Chance found himseIf
a girIfriend whiIe we were away.
- Oh!
- He's happy again, Dad.
- Are these your humans?
- Yeah.
Not a bad-Iooking bunch,
if you don't count the cat.
- Is that Jamie?
- Yep.
That's the Jamester.
Come on. I want you to meet him.
Let Jamie show you what
humans are reaIIy Iike.
Oh, I don't know, Chance.
What if he doesn't Iike me?
He wiII. He Iikes Sassy,
for crying out Ioud.
- I heard that.
- Besides, Jamie's my best friend.
Jamie, I'd Iike you to meet
DeIiIah. DeIiIah, this is Jamie.
- Hi, girI.
- Let him pet you, and
give him a nice kiss.
- Do you think he Iikes me?
- Are you kidding? What's not to Iike?
- Pretty girI.
- Come on, meet DeIiIah, everybody.
- Wow, what a cooI-Iooking dog.
- What kind of dog is she?
- Hi! Oh, isn't she sweet!
- They Iike her!
- AII right! This is Iookin' good.
- She's so pretty.
- Sure is.
- Thank you.
- She doesn't have a coIIar.
- Must be a stray.
- Can she stay, Dad?
Yeah, can she, Dad?
Can she, Dad?
Daddy! You don't mind me caIIing
you Daddy, do ya? PIease!
- Oh.
- Can she, Dad?
I don't want Chance
to be sad again.
Aw, come on! Look at her!
Look at her! She's so cute!
How can you not wanna
keep this dog? PIease!
- Yeah, she can stay.
- Yes!
Oh! I don't think Chance
wouId have it any other way.
He's back!
Oh, thank you, thank you,
thank you, thank you, thank you,
thank you, thank you, thank you!
- Okay, come on.
- WeIcome to the famiIy, girI.
You're gonna Iike it here.
- Wow, DeIiIah with Jamie.
- Hey, girI.
I can't beIieve how Iucky I am.
Now my home's
the best of both worIds,
and I never want to be
away from it again.
- Hi.
- Oh, isn't she pretty.
There's onIy one thing that couId
make this moment more perfect.
In fact, I think I smeII it
coming up the driveway right now.
I'm smeIIin' pepperoni.
I'm smeIIin' mushrooms.
I'm smeIIin' anchovies.
I'm smeIIing three-- No, no,
four, four kinds of cheese!
It couId be!
It might be. It is!
It's pizza!
- Oh, pizza, pizza, pizza,
pizza, pizza, pizza, pizza!
- Oh-ho! Nice doggy. Nice--
- Whoa!
- Yes! Hey, pizza guy!
- Whoa! Stay! Whoa! Whoa! Stay!
- Nice timing! I Iove pizza.
- Stay down! Stay down! Whoa!
- I must have pizza. I wiII have pizza.
- Whoa, doggy! Stay!
- Hand it over niceIy, or I can take it,
- but either way, paI, that pizza...
- Stay down! Whoa! Whoa!
is mine!
Yippee! Oh, pizza! Oh!
- Chance, stop!
- Oh, this is hot.
Hot, hot, hot, hot. Come on,
Jamie, DeIiIah, everybody.
Come on! There's pIenty
for everybody.
Oh, what a day!
Oh, this is so good!
You know, I can't think
of a happier ending.