[Man] Mars surface ops,
this is Houston. We're go for data.
[Man #2] Copy, Houston. Base pedal
temp good. Remote pedal actuator good.
Probe primary and auxiliary
transponders a-okay.
Shunt voltage three zero.
[Man #1]
D.S.N. uplink rate is now 61.101.
Copy. We'll see if we
can better that for you.
This is the probe's
We need all the data we can get.
Uh, standby.
We're getting a low current level here.
Voltage is down to, uh, 185.
[Man #2]
Here's our rock, fellas. One-one-niner.
- Beautiful.
- There it is again. There it is again.
Voltage down to 113.
- Can you repo the solar arrays?
- [Man #2] Uh, negative.
M.P.C. load is critical.
- [Beeping]
- Mars surface ops, we're losing the signal.
- We're losing the signal here!
- [Crackling]
Roger that.
Transmission terminated.
- Well, people, congratulations.
- [Smattering Of Applause]
We collected data
on over a dozen new rocks.
I'd say this was five years
and three trillion dollars well spent!
[Cheering]
[Brakes Screeching]
[Horn Honking]
[Tires Squealing]
[Grunts]
Come on, gentlemen, keep up with me.
I want an exclusive...
with that policeman who was
in the Santa Barbara shootout.
- I'll take it.
- Glad you could make it, O'Hara.
Prescott, it's yours.
Take Harrison and camera car five.
I want it for the 6:00.
It's no good at 10:00. You got that?
- It's no good at 10:00.
- What are you, a parrot? Get movin'.
I want footage of that 1st Monument Bank
that got knocked off down in Oxnard.
- I'm all over it.
- Van Gundy?
- Sir! - And get that security camera's videotape,
you got that?
- Yeah, mm-hmm.
- No tape, no story.
You got it, boss.
Whatever you say, boss.
I like Van Gundy. I need something on
that shuttle launch tonight at Vandenberg.
- Well, that's me. I know Vandenberg, chief.
- Chief?
Who are you, Clark Kent?
FFelix, it's yours.
Get interviews
with all the top brass involved.
Oh, take Brace with you. It's a good
story for her to cut her teeth on.
Brace? Are you sure? Because I usually
produce Brace's on-camera segments.
We're a team. I mean, we're more
than a team. Brace and I are--
You and my daughter are what?
- Um, nothing.
- That's right.
I didn't send Brace to all those
fancy English boarding schools...
to wind up with the likes of you.
Oh, O'Hara, I've got something here
that's right up your alley.
A senior citizens' tanning contest
being held tomorrow at Sunset Pier.
The Hawaiian Tropic Senior
Cocoa Butter Classic.
- Huh?
- [Reporters Laughing]
I want footage
of all the old farts baking,
an interview with the doctor on
the dangers of sunbathing, yadda, yadda.
Something to fill time
if my idiot weatherman runs short.
Mr. Channing? Mr. Channing?
Excuse me. Sir?
You hired me because I had ten years'
experience as a newspaper reporter.
Now, I will go to the ends of the Earth
to bring you a great story.
But I need the chance.
You know, Tim, when I look at you,
I see myself at your age.
- Really?
- And I was a moron!
- Huh.
- But you got a lot of nerve, O'Hara, and I like that.
Sometimes.
Okay, it's yours.
- B-B-B-But you said--
- Shut up, Felix.
You won't-- You won't regret this, sir.
You really won't.
O'Hara! You screw up this Vandenberg
thing, you're fired. Is that clear?
Yeah.
Crystal.
[Man Over Loudspeaker]
Attention, all personnel.
We are T minus five minutes
and counting.
We're here at the Vandenberg Air Force
Base, where for the first time,
- Cut. Brace?
- The shuttle Atlantis will be launched...
- Sweetie, could we lose the gum?
- Billy!
Excuse me, Sergeant.
- [Spits]
- I love show business.
Yeah, okay. Everybody back
to one, please. Here we go.
Same thing.
In five, four, three, two--
We're here at Vandenberg Air Force Base.
- We're here at Vandenberg Air Force Base,
- Where just minutes from now,
where just minutes from now,
the shuttle Atlantis will be launching for the first time...
- on the west coast.
- I understand that Project Deadhead...
I understand that Project Deadhead
is carrying a sophisticated satellite...
- to study the Fiona comet.
- To study the Fiona comet.
Yes, the satellite has
a specialized guidance system...
which will allow it to pass
closer to the comet than ever before.
Yeah, yeah.
Is Jerry Garcia on board?
What?
- Well, yes, actually.
- Yes!
Project Deadhead
gets its name from the fact...
that its payload includes
the ashes of famous rocker...
Jerry Garcia of the Grateful Dead.
How in the world
did you know that?
- It's my job to know that.
- It's my job to know these things.
Well.
[Cheering, Applause]
- Okay, Lizzie, go to Brace.
- [Cheering Continues]
All right, Brace, here we go.
The big wrap-up.
- And so, on this the night of the Fiona Comet,
- And so, on this,
the night of the Fiona Comet,
our thoughts turn...
to that satellite's only passenger--
Jerry Garcia.
- I'm Brace Channing--
- I'm Brace Channing for KGSC.
- Thank you, Captain Dalton.
- Thank you.
- God, you're beautiful.
- [Gasps]
- Thank you. So are you.
[Exhales]
And we're out.
- Tim, I'd like a word with you.
- And I'm dead.
- Colonel?
- Yes?
- You might want to take a look at this, sir.
- The Fiona Comet?
- So what?
- It's changing direction, sir.
That's impossible. Are you sure it's not
the trajectory of our own satellite?
Yes, sir. Uh, the comet's
just changed direction again, sir.
- It's gotta be the equipment.
- I've got down line confirmation.
No, sir. Our backup computers
verify all systems go.
It's-- It's coming down, sir.
- The satellite?
- No, sir. The comet.
Okay, let's go to general alert.
- Major, scramble the F-16s.
- Yes, sir!
- Sergeant, get SETI group on the line.
- Copy that.
Showtime, boys.
We got ourselves a U.F.O.
Excuse me.
- What's this?
- It's Capt. Dalton's telephone number.
Well, he's not really my type, but--
- You made me look such an idiot.
- Brace, come on.
- Let me explain.
- Just wait until I tell my daddy.
- No, Br-- Brace, come on!
- Billy!
- Wait a minute! Look, I--
- Nice knowin' ya.
Ooh-hoo.
Let us know where you end up.
- [Sighs]
- It wasn't a complete disaster.
Oh, compared to what?
- The Hindenburg?
- [Chuckles]
Titanic.
I'm sorry, pal.
[Chuckles]
Thanks. Thanks a lot.
Sorry.
The blues kept knockin'
upon my door
- [Radio Stations Changing]
- [Voice On Radio] Get your nose up! Pull up!
I said up, not out of joint!
We're goin' down!
- Mayday! Mayday!
- Oh, not another ticket.
[Engine Roaring]
- Whoa!
- [Tires Squealing]
[Electronic Bleeping]
[Breathing Heavily]
[Gasps]
- [Tires Screeching]
- Aaah!
Are you crazy?
You could have totalled my car!
- Did you see it? Did you see it?
- See what?
[Stammering]
There was a crash. A plane or some--
It was like a stealth fighter!
I don't know!
- It happened so fast!
- Oh, my God, a plane crash!
Well, that's terrible!
We don't even have any video!
Good! It's over here.
- [Brace] Tim, wait for me!
- Humans.
- Wait, not so fast! It's my story too, remember?
- [Electronic Beeping]
- [Tim] What was that?
- [Brace] Hmm? What was what?
It was this flicker, this--
this light that--
- Never mind.
- What, Tim?
Tim, wait!
Oh, my heel!
These are really expensive shoes,
you know!
- [Gasps]
- [Breathing]
Come on, Tim, where is it?
It was this huge thing!
It was this--
You know, it's really creepy out here.
[Grunting]
Ow!
Tim?
- You've got 30 seconds and I'm leaving!
- Hmm.
[Mumbling]
[Groans]
- Look at this.
- [Screams] What's that?
I don't know.
I-I-- I don't know.
- Is this your idea of a joke? - No, I swear to
you-- look at-- I mean, this thing was huge.
Oh, really? And I thought
you were one of the normal ones!
- [Alien Breathing Heavily]
- I am one of the normal ones, normally.
[Scoffs]
Ha ha ha.
Nice try, Tim.
You and me, alone on the beach, on
the night of a lunar eclipse, no less.
- I didn't make this up!
- Keep this as a memento of our last date.
Last date?
We haven't even had our first date!
- [Engine Starting]
- Well, consider this both.
- Brace? Brace!
- [Tires Screeching]
[Grunting]
Ahh.
Nurplex.
Ay-yi-yi-yi mmm!
[Car Sputtering]
[Inhales Deeply]
Humans.
- Come on, come on, come on.
- [Engine Sputtering]
- Savages!
- [Car Sputters, Turns Over]
[Backfires]
[Car Sputtering, Backfiring]
- Tim!
- Aaah! Mrs. Brown.
- Too much lipstick?
- Uh, well,
no, no, no, no.
No, it's just that you, uh...
kind of appeared, that's all.
I saved you some
of my special brownies.
Mrs. Brown, brownies. Get it?
[Chuckles]
- Yes! That's good.
- There you go.
- Thank you very much.
- [Chuckles] Did you see the eclipse?
Wasn't it très magnifique?
- Those French tapes are really paying off, aren't they?
- Oh, you noticed.
- [Chuckles] Thanks for the brownies, Mrs. Brown.
- [Chuckles]
Oh, Tim.
I wanted to remind you...
about the charity rummage sale
this weekend.
If you have anything you want to donate,
leave it in the garage and I'll pick it up.
Well, trust me, this will be
right on top of the pile.
- Ahh.
- Good night, Mrs. Brown.
One more thing I wanted to tell you,
Tim! Oh, good night, Tim!
[Sighs]
I'm havin' a bad night.
I couldn't agree with ya
more completely.
- Shut up.
- How do you do it?
- [Answering Machine Beeps]
- O'Hara here. Please leave a message. Make it short.
- Channing here. You're fired.
- Short enough for ya?
- [Receiver Clicks]
What more can I say?
When you're right, you're right!
[Wheezing]
[Coughing]
[Electronic Whirring]
[Gasps]
Hmm.
[Groans]
[Gasps]
Stay where you are, little Earth man,
and no harm will come to you.
Say, I wish I'd thought of that!
- [Tim] Hello?
- What more can I say? When you're right, you're right!
- Be silent.
- How do you do it?
I thought I told you to shut up.
I couldn't agree with you more--
[Muffled]
You leave me no choice.
Who's there?
I got a gun!
Static.
[Groans]
- Hey, buddy. Hey. Hey.
- [Moans Softly]
- Hey! [Grunts]
- That's it, Earthling!
- [Grunting]
- It's alive!
Hyah!
Okay, you wanna play games?
- Slide through.
- I must be going... [Grunts] nuts.
[Laughs]
One strike, no balls.
Over here, Tiger Woods.
[Chuckling]
[Blows Raspberry]
Aaah!
- Hey, look-- Jimmy Hoffa.
- Leisure suit from hell!
[Whimpering]
- I'm gonna...
- Ohh!
Mutilate you!
Come on!
Show your face... if you have one.
Where-- Where'd he go?
What the heck
was in those brownies?
When dealing with primitive life-forms,
sometimes one must
resort to primitive acts.
- Are you okay, Zoot?
- [Coughing]
If you don't mind my asking, where were you?
This alien was trying to kill me!
Don't be such a wet blanket.
Wait a minute.
Leave my mother out of this!
It's your fault we ended up
on this no-good, carbon-based,
- over-oxygenated, miserable excuse of a--
- [Knock On Door]
- [Woman] Tim?
- Oh, no. It's another one!
I know you're not asleep yet.
Tim, it's Lizzie!
[Gasps]
Blotz! It's Lizzie!
What's a Lizzie?
I would say a Model T Ford,
but this one has better tires.
- Ah-ooga! Ah-ooga!
- I know what a woman is, but what do I do with it?
Help, Mr. Lifeguard, I'm drowning.
I need mouth-to-mouth.
Ugh, saliva exchange.
I would never partake
in such an unsanitary interaction.
There must be some other way
to greet a female and then be rid of it.
- [Knock On Door]
- Tim! - [Gasps]
If it was me, I'd be he.
- Tim, please.
- Good thinking, Zoot.
Okay, Tim,
I'm picking up the hide-a-key.
- Gonna open the door.
- [Key Turning]
- Tim?
- Lizzie!
My dear friend or family member.
Uh, oh, my gosh.
Oh, inappropriate.
- Oh, boy.
- [Zoot] I told you they cover their flingdat here.
Lizzie, my dear friend
or family member.
You sound funny.
Are you catching a cold?
A cold, a virus?
[Deep Voice] Yes.
[Voice Changing] A contagious
bubonic plague. You better leave.
What? What in the world--
Are-- Are you a Trekkie?
Uh, yes, I am.
Okay, what's going on?
- What's going on?
- Tim, are you okay?
- You don't seem like yourself.
- Oh, I'm Tim, all right.
- Tim O'Hara, no reason to doubt it.
- Uh, what's going on?
Lots.
- Mmm.
- Lizzie.
- Yeah?
If you're my sister,
an explanation is in order.
[Chuckles]
Yeah.
- Does this mean that you and I are--
- Indeed.
- Now, if you'll excuse me, I have work to do, and you...
- What?
- Need... to go.
- Huh?
Wha--
- Human emotions.
- Crazy monkeys.
[Humming]
[Siren]
- [Beeping]
- [Chattering]
Welcome, sir.
Where's Coleye?
Examining mucus-type protoplasm.
Hmm. It's saline-based.
Good God, Coleye,
put that on a slide next time.
I want this stuff analyzed
and the cigarette dusted for prints.
- I want to know whose this was.
- There's more, sir.
[Coleye]
Quadroped becomes... biped?
It must have taken human form!
The footprints stop at the road.
We think someone
may have picked them up.
Evidence of a crash,
no spaceship and alien
in human form?
It's just like the incident of '64!
Keep your mouth shut, you idiot.
That incident is not only classified,
but it never happened, you got it?
- Yes, sir.
- Once again, we have no alien, no U.F.O.
If you can't get me either one,
then you'd better start
looking for another job.
Well, you heard him! Move it!
It's out there somewhere!
- So, move it! Go! Move!
- Yes, sir!
And God help the poor soul...
who picked him up.
[Screams]
Silence, subculturer!
- Let me down!
- Look what you did to me. Barbarian!
- As you wish!
- [Electronic Buzz]
- [Screams, Crashes]
[Grunts]
For a thief,
you are extremely clumsy.
- Thief? I'm not a thief.
- So I see.
Tim O'Hara.
You are a reporter.
Reporter? No.
I'm a producer, pal!
- Let me tell ya, I-- Aaah!
- [Electronic Buzzing]
Look, I didn't steal anything, okay?
I don't know what you're talking about.
- All right, all right.
- [Electronic Buzzing]
No! No!
[Coughing]
Warning, Tim O'Hara. Any attempt
to expose me will be useless.
Martians use 100 % of their brain
capacity, humans less than 10.
- I think we use more than ten.
- Your astronauts pee in their space suits.
Case closed.
[Grunting]
Okay. Okay, just--
[Electronic Whirring]
Whoa!
Okay, it's just a dream.
It's a very bad dream.
[Panting] Just-- Come on.
Wake up. Wake up!
What's with that?
- I believe it's called a nervous breakdown.
- Last night did not happen.
- I don't believe in aliens.
- I heard that!
To us, you are the alien.
If you must know,
I am from the planet you call Mars.
- And what, I'm from Uranus? I never--
- I was getting to you!
Don't get a crease in your Sputnik.
[Zoot] Please,
just introduce me to monkey boy.
This is my Zoot.
- A polymorphous Zootenex 3,000.
- Just look, don't touch.
- Your suit talks?
- [Scoffs] Incessantly.
Corduroys talk,
nobody gives them grief.
- [Zoot] Whoosh, whoosh, whoosh.
- Mars? Wait a minute.
[Stuttering] There's no life on Mars.
We've sent probes.
I'd try to explain it, but you people
still think "E" equals "MC" squared.
- You're still trying to analyze our rocks. Ha-ha!
- [Hydraulic Hissing]
Oh! Blasted sand particles.
They've completely crystallized
the vortex generator.
- Hey, do you mind? - [Knock On Door]
- [Mrs. Brown] Tim!
- [Gasps]
- Now what?
- Thank God, an eyewitness.
- Eyewitness? Negative.
- You must tell no one. - No offence,
but your ship is double-parked in my living room.
You're the biggest story
in the history of mankind!
There is intelligent life
out there in the universe!
I hope you're not including yourself
in that statement!
Tim, listen, I'm sorry to bother you
so early in the morning,
but I got a hold of your mail,
and I wanted--
Could you just-- please, come here.
Take a look at that!
[Tim]
Aaah!
Tim, you definitely need a maid!
Oh, hello!
- Greetings.
- Oh, I'm sorry to catch you in your... pyjamas.
- Pyjamas? [Muffled]
- [Stammering] Where's the spaceship?
- [Mrs. Brown] Spaceship?
- Right here.
Oh, for the rummage sale!
Does it come with an action figure?
- You're looking at him.
- [Chuckles] Oh. I don't believe we've met.
- No, don't touch him! He's a Martian.
- Tim, what's going on?
- [Stuttering]
- I beg your-- Mart-- Martin?
- Yes. Martin.
- No, no, no, no!
- He's a-- uh--
- Uncle!
- Martin.
- Oh.
- Well, it's a pleasure to meet you.
- He turns invisible, okay?
His suit talks--
he's got a talking suit.
He's got these things that
pop out of his head-- You just--
- Show her. Go ahead. Come on, give her the finger.
- Tim!
No, I didn't mean that.
I don't know what I mean. Forget it.
You'll have to forgive Tim, Mrs. Brown.
He lost his job last night,
and he's experiencing
a nervous breakdown.
Oh, poor dear.
- I hope it doesn't affect the rent.
- [Laughing Hysterically]
- Don't worry, I'm here to look after him.
- Ha!
He's very lucky to have
an uncle like you in his life, Martin.
And you, Mrs. Brown, are like a brilliant
quasar in the black hole of my day.
Oh! Call me Lorelei.
Lorelei.
The sound of...
pure mountain spring water
from the centre of the Earth.
Oh, my.
[Chuckles]
- [Slurping]
- [Stammering]
Oh!
[Chuckles]
I obviously misconstrued a custom.
I apologize.
I'm from... New York.
No, actually, it's--
[Stuttering] It's fine.
[Stuttering]
It's perfect. [Sighs]
- Oh, brother.
- Oh, Martin?
Yes, Lorelei?
Um, Mr. Brown... passed away
several years ago.
- I thought you might like to know that.
- Hmm.
Au revoir.
[Chuckles]
Hmm?
Just for the record,
a handshake will do for me.
[Scoffs]
You think that I actually enjoyed...
tasting that female's exoskeleton?
[Shudders] I merely used my data on
your primitive species to determine...
the optimum way
to avoid suspicion.
- Yeah, but what's the optimum way to get home?
- [Scoffs] Blotz!
I don't know, Zoot. Where on this
barbaric swamp of a planet...
can we find the makings
of an electron accelerator?
- [Zoot] Maybe your new girlfriend has one.
- Oh, that's very funny.
Excuse me. Fellas,
I don't mean to interrupt, but...
I-I, you know, I think I might be able
to help you find that electron thing.
We're toast.
I don't believe this.
You really think you can...
repair your ship
with all this junk?
Everything has been carefully chosen
for its potential to fashion...
a crude vortex electron accelerator.
Except for this.
A pooper scooper.
I have no idea what it does,
but it's fascinating.
Excuse me. Where are your
nuclear implosion couplers?
For a garden hose?
I'm never going to get off
this infernal planet.
[Zoot]
The I.Q. of a pancake.
You're right. Humans are truly
the amoebas of the universe!
Yeah, this from a guy
who talks to his tin foil suit.
- Hey, what was that for?
- It wasn't me, it was Zoot.
- [Zoot Laughing]
- Come here a sec.
Listen, you've been on Earth,
what, all of ten minutes?
- It's not so bad here.
- [Chuckles] That's what Neenurt said.
- Who?
- Exactly. One of my planet's most gifted scientists,
and now he's gone without a trace.
He arrived on Earth in 1964, and, I presume,
was abducted by your government.
I shudder to think what they did to him
in the name of science.
- What are they laughing at?
- [Laughing] Hey, space man!
- I've been discovered!
- [Electronic Buzz] - [Gasps]
- [Grunting]
- Sorry about that.
- Oh, my--
- What happened?
They don't know anything.
They were just making fun of your--
Making fun. I'm one of
the best-dressed beings on my planet.
[Man]
Yo, Elvis! Nice suit.
Well, Dorothy, I hate to tell you this,
but you're not in Kansas any more.
[Zoot] That's great.
The minute I turn my back,
you're getting into
someone else's pants!
[Martin] I need to blend in, and you stand
out like a putt stick at a blackbell convention.
[Zoot] I should have known
by the way you've been gawking...
at every T-shirt
and sweat pant we pass.
- Don't come apart at the seams!
- Why is Zoot always the last to know?
- All right, all right, all right!
- [Zoot Sobbing]
- Martian footage, take one.
- Zoot, this is tearing me apart too.
[Zoot]
I know I'm not what I used to be.
I mean, a stretch mark here,
a line stain there.
[Zoot Sobbing]
[Screams]
- Hey!
- Pervert!
It's not safe
for a woman around here!
I'm ready to blend in now.
- Outstanding.
- Martin, that outfit looks ridic--
- Stylin', bro!
- Thanks, bro.
[Chuckles]
Real cool.
I've got the touch on two planets.
I gotta get out more.
How did your Zoot take the--
Zoot, he's highly intelligent.
He understands.
Aaaah!
You used me, you buttonhole!
- Go and have your fling. Colours fade! You'll see!
- [Knock On Door]
- Hello?
- Huh? Oh, incoming.
Hello?
Man.
Oh, geez!
Talk about a tacky suit!
- [Chuckles]
- Tacky, huh?
Hey! Hey! What?
- Now turn the other cheek.
- [Slapping Sound] - Ow! Hey!
- [Shudders, Exhales]
- Catch you later, Spanky.
[Exhales]
All right, I'm bustin' out!
- There.
- Go ahead, try 'em all on.
See if I care.
Whoa!
If love is a crime, lock me up!
I'm guilty.
Look at her.
A perfect size six,
and never been worn!
Darling, don't speak.
Just come to me. [Chuckles]
Oh, this is crazy.
I'm a polymorph, and you're a polyester.
Yes, you're synthetic,
but I like that in a girl!
Give me some thread, baby!
[Kissing Sounds]
- Oh, what's this, Velcro? Ohh!
- Zoot!
Ah! No, thank you, little girl,
I don't want to buy any cookies!
You lecherous leotard!
Have you no shame?
Look who's talking,
Mr. Clothes Horse!
Now, in you go, or you'll take
a long walk on a short hanger.
Coming in for a landing!
Flaps down!
- [Flatulent Sound]
- I said bag it, mister!
All right, all right, you don't
have to throw me in the hamper.
[Grunting, Speaking Gibberish]
Dork.
- Next time, the dry cleaner.
- Bite these.
[Gasps]
You-- Blasted nurplex!
Oh, Venus, Neptune!
- Help me, Tim!
- Mm-hmm.
Tim, it's a little blue one!
No!
Give me that,
you age-impaired little blotz.
Mine! Gum!
- Mine! Nurplex!
- [Blows Raspberry]
- [Roars]
- [Screams]
[Screaming Continues]
Why wouldn't you give
the kid a piece of gum?
[Scoffs] Okay, sure, right.
Here, have one.
- Come on, let's go. No, no, come on.
- What are you doing?
- Trust me.
- Not the finger! Don't do the finger!
- Try some.
- Why?
- You don't want to try Martian gum?
- No, not particularly.
- Afraid, Earthling?
You know what, that is not bad.
- The centre's got a nice little zing to it.
- Notice anything different?
Hmm, no.
No, not really.
What time do you have?
Aaaah!
[Gasps]
- [Gasps]
- Spit, spit, spit.
[Groaning]
- [Groaning Continues]
- Everything okay in there?
- Zipper trouble.
- Yeeow.
[Breathing Heavily]
This "gum", as you call, allows me to take on
the outward appearance of a human being.
On you, it has the reverse effect.
Oh, so that's what you
really look like.
Don't be disgusting.
That was Fluvian Nurplex.
- Oh.
- We carry many different planets.
If you think that was bad,
this is Veenox Seven.
- Oh, well, that's--
- Don't ever mess with a Veenox Seven.
When it comes to Veenox Seven,
just say no.
Me man got fire
Me so on fire
feeling hot, hot, hot
All right, come on, the rest of you,
come on up on stage!
The sun, while you can get it.
The sand, the surf.
Usually, the beach conjures up
images of our youth,
but come on down to Sunset Pier today,
and your contraceptions of--
- Preconceptions!
- Contraceptions.
- Felix!
I said preconceptions!
I swear, preconceptions!
- Billy! Billy!
- Preconceptions! I know I said preconceptions!
I should listen to my parents
and be a doctor. I hate this!
- Ooh!
- [Gasps]
- Are we still rolling?
- Nobody said "cut."
- Feeling hot, hot, hot
- What do you think?
I think your bathing suit
should have a top.
[Stammering]
Cut! Cut! Cut!
- [Grunting]
- Felix!
[Sighs]
Felix is toast.
If Tim doesn't get here soon,
we could all be looking for work.
[Chattering, Indistinct]
Wait here.
What is the meaning
of this divergence?
- I gotta see some friends.
- Negative! Exclamation point.
We're wasting valuable time.
My ship must--
Look at that!
Do you have any idea
how fortunate you are?
The only water we get back on Mars
has to be squeezed from rocks.
- Well, surf's up, dude.
- Tim, I'm so glad you came.
- Hurricane Brace hit again.
- Oh, okay. Uh, Martin?
- I gotta go. I'll be right--
- Lizzie!
How nice to see you again.
- Have we met?
- Of course!
Not. How nice to see you again
for the first time.
I'm Tim's Uncle Martin.
- Oh, I--
- [Rumbling]
- I, uh--
- [Rumbling Continues]
- What was that?
- I must find nourishment.
- That came from your stomach?
- Stomachs.
Oh, he is-- [Chuckles]
He is such a kidder.
Listen, I'll be with you
in couple minutes, okay?
You just-- I'll be right over.
Tell her to--
We gotta get you-- ah!
[Stomach Rumbling]
Excuse me, could I have
a double dip--
actually, make that a triple dip,
chocolate chip, please.
- Yes, sir. - Tim, I need nourishment,
not coloured buckets of frozen lard.
Look, this is very nutritious food here on Earth.
We eat this for breakfast.
Tim, you don't need to try poison
to know that it kills.
Here, take this.
Give me five minutes, okay?
I have to go to the news van.
[Groans]
Blecch!
- [Brace] Felix!
- I said "preconceptions", I swear! Preconceptions!
You unprofessional little man! All you have
to do is come up with the dumb things I say!
[Felix Groaning]
- Billy!
- Brace! Brace!
- You'd rate this tantrum?
- About a seven-five on the Brace scale.
- I'll talk to Felix.
- You never told me about your uncle.
Are you--
Look, I'm glad you beeped me. We really
need to talk. This is really big.
- I know.
- You do?
Yes. Look, I've been thinking, and...
our friendship really means a lot to me,
and I don't want to screw that up.
- Okay.
- So I think it would be better...
if we just pretended that nothing
ever happened between us last night.
- What happened last night?
- Exactly!
I'm not sure I understand what--
Me either.
I guess we're both a little confused,
huh, Tim?
- [Gasps]
- Easy, easy.
I thought you were her. She's terrible,
Tim. How did you last so long?
She's a little high-maintenance,
but she's okay.
- Oh, lust is blind.
- Do we still have that hidden camera stuff somewhere?
You're sitting on it.
Why?
- Here, let me help you with this.
- Would you please?
- These words are way too big.
- Huh? Humidity?
- Hot.
- Oh, oh, oh, oh.
[Announcer]
Wave for everybody!
By God, if I were only 40 years older,
I'd be right there with 'em!
[Muttering, Indistinct]
- [Man] Miss Channing?
- Hmm?
- Could I have a word with you, please?
- Okay.
I've already signed it.
Come on, who are you guys, huh?
[Gasps, Muffled Screams]
Okay, guys, you're all set.
- Where's Brace?
- I don't know. She took off.
She quit!
And her dad gonna blame me!
Hey, what's going on
over there?
- [Crowd Clamouring]
- Uh, Billy, put that in my car.
- I gotta go.
- Call me!
Martin!
[Gulping]
- [Gasps]
- [Martin Shouting]
- I like it!
- Martin!
Tim, you're here!
You've got to save me from myself!
It's intoxicating.
Ooh, cookie dough!
- I need to get you back to the home!
- [Gurgling]
All they give him there is Jell-O.
There we go.
[Muttering, Indistinct]
Cookie dough!
[Crowd Clamouring]
[Beeps]
Martian footage, take two.
[Groaning]
[Groaning Continues]
- Chubby Hubby hangover, huh?
- [Groans]
[Tools Clattering]
I swear, I'll never
touch that stuff again.
One scoop's too many,
and a million aren't enough!
So, how's it coming, anyway?
Oh, I converted a blow dryer,
two elastic bands...
and an Acme Bug-Away insect bomb...
into a temporary electron accelerator.
- Is it working?
- Not at all, but on the positive side,
your garage is now cockroach-free.
Blasted rental!
- This is a rental, is it?
- My regular ship is in the shop...
for its mid-millennium tune-up.
Where's your, uh, you know,
your suit, Zoot... thing.
Oh ho, washing up.
- Owwww! Spin me, mama!
- ["I Feel Good"]
So nice, so good
Five more minutes, Zoot,
then into the dryer.
You're bringing me down, man!
[Groans] What I wouldn't give
to shed this grotesque human facade...
and let the cool Earth waters
caress my Martian skin.
- Oh!
- So why don't you?
Why not, indeed?
- ["I Feel Good"] - Move over, Zoot!
- Martin, I meant--
I meant out in the hot tub, out back.
It would be private, by yourself.
You mean spit out my Nurplex...
and revert to Martian form
right outside your domicile?
- Exactly.
- Oh, do you think that's safe?
Oh, yes, of course it's safe.
- I'll do it!
- Good. Let's go.
Oh boy, oh boy, oh boy, oh boy.
- Tim? Thanks.
- Yeah?
It's just a hot tub, Martin.
No big deal.
I don't mean just that.
I know I must have...
created complete havoc with your
simple life since the moment I arrived.
Anyway, I just wanted to say...
thank you.
[Whooping Excitedly]
Hello!
Would somebody please...
come and tell me
what's going on here?
All right, Miss Channing.
Do you know what this is?
This has been
positively identified...
by my team of experts
as your cigarette.
It was discovered
at the site of a U.F.O. crash!
- What?
- And on it are trace elements...
of what we believe
to be alien DNA.
- Alien?
- Oh, don't play dumb with me!
You are an alien...
inhabiting the body of a woman!
A very, very attractive woman.
Oh, please.
Dr Coleye, we've run the tests
on the other cigarette.
It's human DNA.
Oh.
So sorry.
An honest mistake.
So, Miss Channing,
do you have any idea
how alien DNA...
ended up on your cigarette?
I might. First of all,
let's talk about what's in this for me.
The safety of this entire planet
may depend on what you say to me.
There's nothing in it for you!
- [Frustrated Scream]
- Dr Coleye.
May I call you... Doctor?
Think about it.
When this story breaks,
you will be the most
famous scientist in history.
You will be on the cover
of Scientific... whatever.
You will be the man
that proves that aliens exist.
And I will be the woman
who tells the world your story.
We'll do it together.
Okay.
- [Opera]
- [Singing Along]
[Singing Opera]
- Tim?
- [Gasps]
What are you doing up there?
[Whispering]
My Uncle Martin's in the hot tub,
and I'm... watching.
Oh.
What a strange family.
You can, uh--
You can sleep here.
- You guys do sleep, don't you?
- Oh, most definitely.
Oh, great.
We have something in common.
You're very kind, Tim O'Hara.
- No, just very tired.
- Ohh, enjoy your rest cycle.
- [Electronic Buzz]
- I'll do the same.
I could use a little shut-eye.
- [Sighs] So could I.
- [Light Switch Clicks]
[Yawns]
- Rise and shine!
- Yeah, yeah right.
What's on tap for today, Tim O'Hara?
I feel like a million radix.
Hey, it's still tonight.
You've been asleep for 30 seconds.
Thirty seconds?
Wow, I really was tired.
[Martin]
What are we waiting for?
There's a whole metropolis out there
just waiting to be discovered!
[Tim] No, not in the middle
of the night, there isn't.
[Martin] I feel like ice cream,
and there's no time like the present.
[Martin]
Hello? Why aren't they open?
- What's wrong with this planet?
- I told you they don't open till 10:00.
- I could be first in line.
- They aren't gonna let you in when they do open,
not after that little stunt
you pulled yesterday.
[Electronic Buzz]
- We call that breaking and entering.
- [Electronic Buzz]
Ah, the smell of moist air.
I'll never forget this.
Your ocean!
Ice cream!
This primitive planet
may not compare to Mars,
but it's not the rotten rock
I thought it was.
Don't look now,
but I think we're being followed.
Impossible.
My acute sensory perception...
would have detected that immediately.
[Electronic Whirring]
Now it's working.
Hey! Hey, buddy!
- What are you doing?
- I've been discovered!
- I'm doomed!
- No, no, no, just calm down.
It's probably
just some tourist or something.
Besides, even if you did get caught,
you'd probably be, you know, welcomed.
Welcomed?
Tim, where do Earthlings put...
their most beautiful
and rare animals?
If I don't get that spaceship fixed,
I'm finished,
just like Neenurt.
[Zoot] Can you fix it?
'Cause I'm dyin' here.
I need a drink, is what I need.
[Humming]
Yeah.
Downy the hatch.
[Zoot Coughing]
- What was that?
- What in blazes?
- What is it?
- [Beeps]
Oh, blotz!
Zoot, an I.S.S.!
[Screams]
[Tape Rewinding]
- Blasted rental!
- [Tape Rewinding]
- Owww! Spin me, mama!
- So nice, so good
- [Tape Rewinding]
- [Tape Playing At Fast Speed]
- [Opera]
[Chuckles]
Uncle Martin, what are you--
[Phone Ringing]
- Tech department.
- [Tim] Hi, it's me.
- Oh, hi.
- What are you doin'?
Uh, research.
Have you ever got into your head how--
how you felt about somebody,
and then something they said or did
just suddenly changed your mind?
Well, yeah, I--
Could you come over?
Please, I really need to see you.
It's important.
Sure. Could you give me
like a half an hour?
- [Sighs] You're the best, Lizzie.
- Okay, see ya!
Oh, my gosh.
[Exhales]
[Martin Shouting]
- [Shouts]
- Martin?
- [Growling]
- I'm not like you.
I need more than
twelve seconds of sleep.
All I need is one lousy
electron accelerator...
for a vortex generator.
But can I build it?
No.
You'll do it. You just gotta
give yourself a little time, that's all.
Time! I have no time!
I just discovered
that this blasted rental...
is equipped with an I.S.S.!
- Yeah, what's that?
- Interstellar Safety System.
A detonation mechanism
designed to prevent...
advanced technology
from falling into the wrong hands.
It's timer activates automatically
at the point of a crash.
Okay, wait,
I heard "detonation" somewhere in there.
If I don't take off by 9:00 tonight,
you'll hear a lot more than that.
- Uh, how much more?
- [Makes Explosion Sound]
- Uh-huh.
- Lublick.
- Uh, you b--
- [Gulping]
[Belches]
Ahhh!
I know you've done your best
to help me, but it's no use.
[Gasps]
Oh, no.
I'm sinking into
a Martian depression.
Sinking? No, no sinking.
Come on, we gotta go fix this thing.
I'm falling apart, Tim.
Oh, no, you're not.
- [Sobbing]
- Come on.
- Yes you are.
- On Mars, when we get depressed,
we literally fall apart!
- [Screams]
- Okay, no problem.
Don't move, don't make it
any worse than it already is.
- What we're gonna do is we're gonna
put you back together. - [Screams]
Does it screw in?
It's not--
- Okay, just---aaah! No!
- I wanna go home!
- We're gonna put our heads together--
- [Gasps]
- Aaaah!
- [Knock On Door]
- Coming!
- Who's that?
- It's Lizzie!
- Lizzie? Oh, no.
You wait here.
- Where are you going with those?
- Just tidying up!
Give 'em back! Give me back my arms!
Give me back--
Why do I have to die here?
[Groaning]
Hello?
- Yoo-hoo!
- Don't move.
Tim!
Does anything in this room
strike you as odd?
- Tim?
- [Gasps]
[Martin]
Just a minute!
- Aaah!
- Would you just be quiet?
Coming! Lizzie!
Oh, Br-Br-Brace!
Tim!
Are you decent?
Oh, yeah! Yes, I am.
[Stuttering] What a surprise!
- Yes, now get lost!
- What did you say?
Uh, I'm lost.
I mean, [Chuckles]
I'm at a loss
for how beautiful you look.
Hey, hey, hey, hey--
[Screams]
Now, Tim, I hope you're gonna
let me make it up to you.
Oh, no, you don't have to do that.
I mean, that--
Well, you know, that's up to you.
I mean, if that's--
I brought a little peace offering.
- Where are your wine glasses?
- No, no, no--
That's the bedroom.
No glasses up there.
Oh, well,
maybe I'll get a little tour later.
- [Martin] Don't miss the bathroom!
- I'm sorry?
I have to go to the bathroom later.
Later.
Um, glasses are in the kitchen.
Why don't I go get them,
and you just...
kind of make yourself at home.
Okay.
- Fantastic apartment, Tim.
- Thank you very much.
- [Cork Pops]
- Ah, yeah, there we go.
Oh! What a slob!
[Humming]
[Martin Grunting]
Cut it out!
- Hey!
- Yes, let's fall in love
- Ooh!
- Why shouldn't we
- Fall in love
- Mmm, that's the spot.
Let's take a chance
- Ooh, yeah. Mmm.
- Why be afraid of it, ba-ba-doo-day
- Let's close our eyes
- [Moaning]
And make our own paradise
- Little we know
- Oh, oh, no, harder, like before.
- Ahhh.
- Oh, baby
- Where's the wine?
- Uh, uh--
Why shouldn't
we fall in love
- I'll get it.
- Now is the time for it While we are young
Let's fall in love
You know, I asked Daddy
about giving you another chance.
Oh, oh, good!
- Here we go.
- Oh, lovely. Thanks.
Hmm. You know, I thought
that crash of yours...
might make a kind of
cute little story.
- Oh, really? Good. That's--
- Mm-hmm.
[Grunts]
Ow, ow, ow, ow.
Cut it out!
- What was that?
- Uh, I didn't hear anything.
Tim, get rid of--
[Groaning]
Are you all right?
Yes, I just--
I really have to go to the bathroom.
- Well, hurry back.
- [Chuckles]
- Why shouldn't we fall in love
- Be a minute.
- Now's the time while we're young
- [Sighs]
Tim!
Get me outta here!
Stop making all that noise!
Tell her to stop punching me!
Besides, what are you doing...
letting that female
in your apartment?
I've been waiting a long time
to get Brace Channing into my apartment.
But you like Lizzie! I could tell
through your saliva exchange.
- Excuse me?
- Look, Tim, the other night,
when you were unconscious,
Lizzie came here.
- And you what, you kissed her?
- Yes-- No, no--
Well, you did.
I did a molecular
identiclone of your body.
- What? You what?
- You'd never understand.
You people think E-mail is amazing.
The point is, while I was you,
I tapped into your subconscious,
and trust me, you like Lizzie.
That's why I thought it was okay
for you to kiss her.
I-I-I didn't kiss her, you did!
[Gasps]
Bingo!
Tim? I let myself
in the back door.
Hello?
- Oh, isn't this nice?
- Lizzie, is that you?
Oh, you look, um, nice.
He's in the bathroom,
and he's all yours.
I got what I came for.
- Oh, this is great.
- Tim!
- We don't have a lot of time here!
- I'm confused, all right?
- Everything was going along fine until you came along.
- Don't kid yourself.
Even a substandard species
such as yours has feelings.
Just slow down for one millisecond
and look into your heart.
Whose face do you see?
Look, Brace, I think--
Lizzie!
Whoa!
Lizzie, no, wait, wait--
- No, please!
- This better be good.
Oh, it is. It is.
Uh, remember that guy
I was with at the pier yesterday?
- Your Uncle Martin.
- He's not my uncle.
He's a Martian!
- [Chuckles]
- Yeah.
- You are such a jerk!
- No, no, no. He's a Martian!
It's the truth. In fact,
he's the one who kissed you, not me.
- Really?
- Yeah.
His head's in my sink right now.
- [Grunts]
- Get some sleep. You look awful.
- Lizzie--
- And if there was anything kinky on that videotape,
you better get Brace to give it back.
[Zoot Grunts] Fine!
Since when did I become a mechanic?
- [Drill Whirring]
- Do I look like overalls?
Uncle Martin!
- [Scissors Snipping]
- [Zoot] Okay. Don't cut the red one.
- Or was it the blue one? [Mumbling]
- Ooh!
I can't see a thing down here!
Oh, thanks.
- [Electricity Zapping]
- Ow! Geez, that hurt!
- [Screams]
- No! - [Screams]
Lady, please!
Put a sock in it! Quiet!
The baby's sleeping!
Martin, I told you.
We gotta get to the...
TV station before Brace does.
- [Martin] Open the bag!
- Okay, okay.
- [Gasping] I can't breathe!
- I'm sorry.
- Where is that confounded Zoot?
- Zoot? Uh--
Zoot! Zoot! I think he's
in the middle of a spin cycle.
Leave him! Quick, Tim!
Get my arm out of the other bag!
- All right. Okay, okay, okay.
- Okay.
- Yes! Excellent! Toward the ship!
- Huh? What?
- Higher! Higher! Okay, here!
Here we go!
[Grunts] Yes!
- [Whimpering]
- [Martin] Easy. Oh, no!
- [Screaming]
- Oh, no! Don't send me to the shrink!
- [Whimpering]
- Ohh!
- What was that?
- Uh-oh.
Sweetie-pie,
this is the most amazing footage
I've ever seen.
Felix!
O'Hara's tapes are going on the 6:00.
- Van Gundy, call the network.
- Yeah?
Brace is going out live
with the story of the century!
[Martin]
I'm feeling a little carsick!
- Oh!
- Sorry.
[Martin Grunting]
I can't take it any more.
I can't take it any more!
- We're running out of time. Try and pull yourself
together. - Why? We're all doomed anyway.
Without my blasted electron accelerator,
the I.S.S. will blow!
I feel like a hacksaw murderer.
What the heck is
an electron accelerator anyway?
It's a simple low-amperage power source
that activates the main thrusters.
- Oh. Kind of like an alternator?
- What's an alternator?
- It, uh, turns over the engine in a car.
- [Gasps] A car?
That's it! That should work!
We're saved!
- Not quite.
- Yes, we are.
- Whoo-hoo! Ha, ha, ha.
- Listen, I've been--
I've been videotaping you.
I've got everything. I got the ship.
I got Zoot.
I even got you in your Martian form.
I was putting together a story,
and I was gonna get it on the air,
- but I couldn't do it.
- Why not?
Because I like you, Martin.
I like you. I--
And I'm sorry.
I-I just-- I'm sorry.
I I-- I apologize.
I shouldn't have lied to you.
- You're a good human, Tim O'Hara.
- Oh, oh, yeah. I'm a terrific--
Martin!
You're back!
And I like you too.
- Oh-ho!
- I've never had feelings before!
- Oh.
- [Chuckles]
Now, let's go fix my ship.
Yeah, okay-- No!
No, we got a problem-- the tapes.
- Brace goes on with the Martian story in five minutes.
- Oh, blotz.
Yeah, and I got to get these tapes and
get to Brace before she gets on the air.
But there's not enough time.
You can't be in two places at once.
Yeah. Wait a minute!
Come on!
Is there an alien amongst us?
- Is there an alien among--
- [Knocking]
Billy, now what?
I want to be Brace Channing.
Yeah, well, get in line.
I'm sorry.
I really don't have time
to do any auto--
- [Gasps]
- Quaint, aren't they?
These days, most of our young
are born cable-ready.
You're the--
[Gasps]
[Gasps] Daddy!
[Screams]
[Director]
Heads up. Four minutes to air.
First positions, everyone.
Tim! What are you doing here?
You look, uh, tired.
Oh, yeah. I was up all night with Brace
working on the alien story.
I made a couple of mistakes in tape number two,
but that's the corrected version.
Now if I could just get through this
without having to look in a mirror.
- Hmm.
- [Director] Coming up on three minutes to air.
[Grunts]
Tim!
- Martin, is that you?
- Does a wild bear blotz in the woods?
Good, good. Okay. Just--
Just read the copy as written. Go.
- Hi, Brace.
- [Chuckling Nervously]
- Congratulations, Brace.
- Yes, I'm Brace Channing.
[Man]
Let's hear it for Brace!
[Whistling, Applauding]
- Dr Coleye, you're going to become a very famous man.
- Thirty I.D. and open.
- [Announcer] KGSC.
- Ready camera one live.
- The news for southern California...
- [Grunting]
with anchor Howard Greenly and
on special assignment, Brace Channing.
- What the hell is she wearing?
- You know Brace.
- Yeah. Must be trendy.
- [Director] Fifteen seconds, people.
[Mr. Channing]
Sweetie-pie, get rid of the gum.
- Billy! - Come on, Brace!
- Leave the gum, Billy!
- Get the gum, Billy!
- [Man] Brace, ten seconds. - No.
Ready?
Camera two live in five--
- Give me the gum, Brace!
- No! No! No!
- Four-- - No!
- Leave it! Leave it!
- Three--
- Get the damn gum!
- [Roars]
- [Announcer] Are there aliens amongst us?
This report is being broadcast live.
- The gum is out.
- Oh, good. Thanks to you, Felix.
[Announcer]
And now, Howard Greenly...
- And cue Howard.
- And Brace Channing!
- Good evening. I'm Howard Greenly.
- [Groaning]
- What's up with her?
- I don't know.
...a story developing throughout the day
right here in southern California.
Our own Brace Channing has been
following the events as they take place.
- Brace?
- [Groans]
- What is she doing?
- Howard--
- Camera two go.
- No!
[Greenly]
Brace?
- Brace!
- Just read the copy!
[Groans]
Just get the nurplex.
What's going on here?
Is there an alien amongst us?
- Oh. It's all right.
- According to Dr Elliot Coleye,
chief biologist and head researcher
for the SETI group,
the answer is--
- [Gasping]
- Yes.
- She's an alien!
- She's not an alien. She's my daughter!
[Voice Tonality Wavering] What you're
about to see is that evidence...
[Squawks]
of the actual footage of the alien.
But I warn you--
it's appearance is unlike...
[Gasps] anything you are
likely to have seen before.
She's going under the table.
She's going under the table!
- [Continues, Voice Wavering]
- And go.
- Feelin' hot, hot, hot
- What the hell is this?
- Somebody mislabelled the tapes!
- Come on. Got it!
- I don't know. Let's go back live.
- Tim!
What is O'Hara doing with my daughter?
- I-I-I don't know. I--
- Get me out of here!
- [Chattering]
- [Muffled Screaming]
- [Shouting]
- Get me the network!
- You're a dead man, O'Hara!
- Come on!
I think that went pretty well,
don't you?
- [Muffled Shouting]
- [Martin] All right. Calm down.
Search everywhere!
Boy, her head was dark and empty.
- There they are! There they are!
- [Muffled Shouting]
Wait!
I think Miss Channing might have been
contaminated by the alien.
- Hmm?
- I'm just going to give her a quick examination.
[Muffled Shout]
No!
I'll just be a moment.
Ah.
There we go.
Let's see.
Am I forgetting something?
Oh.
[Humming]
There it is.
[Humming Resumes]
- Mrs. Brown! Down here!
- [Martin] Lady, please.
- [Both Shouting]
- Oh, this is darling.
- I'm gonna hurl!
- [Shouting]
This will make some child very happy...
if he's got a buck or two.
- Hey, Mrs. B. How are you?
- Hello, fellows.
Zoot!
Blotz!
My ship! Where's my ship?
- We only have two hours before it explodes!
- I'll check upstairs.
Hurry!
Zoot!
Zoot?
Where are you?
Blotz! You're not Zoot.
Where could he be?
I'm not leaving this planet
without Zoot. Tim!
Not upstairs.
- What's a "rummaggie" sale?
- "Rummaggie" sale?
R-- Rummaggie--
Rummage. Mrs. Brown.
- [Tires Squealing]
- [Siren Wailing]
- Looks like we got company.
- Blotz!
It's them!
After them!
- [Sirens Wailing] - Hang on.
- [Horns Honking]
- Ooh.
- I repeat, Gilford and Third.
Give me that thing.
I want a roadblock!
- We're never gonna lose 'em!
- Can't you drive any faster, you pinhead?
- Uh-oh, we're in trouble.
- [Martin] Maximum thrust!
- What?
- Stand on it, Stan!
- We're gonna crash!
- [Triggers Cocking]
- I think not!
- [Device Beeps]
[Tires Squealing]
- [Tires Squealing]
- Aah!
- Oh!
- Shoot it! Come on!
- They're shooting at us!
- Duck in that garage.
- What garage?
- There! - Hang on!
[Both Screaming]
Oh. Tim, why are we stopping?
- [Car Ignition Grinding]
- They're right there.
God!
- Get me that thing over there!
We're gonna flush 'em out! - Yes, sir.
- I dropped it!
- What? Dropped what?
- My molecular compressor!
- Here.
Use this.
- This won't work!
- No, use it to find it.
That'll do very nicely.
Now, get it in there!
Uh! Uh!
Nuts!
Ahh! I found it!
[Coleye]
We've got you now!
- Tim!
- I see it!
- [Martin Groans]
- [Tim] Sorry.
[Shouting]
- Faster. Faster.
- It's getting closer!
- I'm going as fast as I can!
- That's not fast enough!
[Screaming]
Martin! Martin, up ahead!
We're trapped! Quick, make us smaller.
We're not gonna make it!
Hang on!
- Are we clear?
- [Martin] Whoa-ho, I think we did it!
- I see light ahead!
- Oh. Whoa, whoa-ooh!
[Both Screaming]
- Where the heck are we?
- [Man] Hey, Elma, where's my new Field and Stream?
[Woman] It's in the bathroom,
right where you left it.
Oh, yeah.
I see it now.
By the way,
where's my tuna sandwich?
- You want it in there?
- Ha-ha. Ohh!
Why'd I eat that fourth burrito?
[Grunting]
- Uh-oh.
- [Grunting Continues]
[Flatulent Sounds]
- Do it. Do it now.
- [Device Beeping]
Uh! Uh, uh, uh--
[Screaming]
- Sorry, buddy.
- I'll get you, you son of a b--
- No!
- Sir, the police just had a crank call.
- A '62 Plymouth just came out of a toilet on Woodlawn.
- Aah!
[Martin]
Stop! Pull over! Pull over!
We need to talk!
Pull over!
[Brakes Squealing]
- Pull over there.
- Where? Oh.
- Get the alternator. I'll get the ship!
- Okay.
Oh, my goodness! Martin!
What's wrong?
Forgive me, Lorelei,
but this is urgent.
- You have something I need desperately.
- Oh, wow.
- Martin, don't say that unless you mean it.
- You don't know the half of it.
- I'm from another world.
- Oh, well, I could have told you that.
- [Grunts]
- Oh! Mmm!
Mar-- Martin?
Martin, come on!
When you look at the stars,
think of me.
- Oh. [Giggles]
- [Barks]
[Gasps]
Oh! Whew!
Feelings for an Earth woman--
I've gotta get off this planet.
I've got it!
I don't have the right tools,
so I'm having trouble getting--
Oh!
Or we could do it your way.
But wait! This means your vehicle
will cease to function.
I know how much it means to you.
Well, that's too bad.
Just had the darn thing washed too.
That's good!
That's--
Martin? Martin?
- [Coleye] Direct hit!
- Uncle Martin?
[Tim]
Hey! Hey, what--
Hey, you don't know what you're doing!
Hey, hey!
Don't mess with that spaceship!
It's gonna explode!
- Narrow the beam.
- Intensify.
[Lizzie Groaning]
I'm not flame-retardant!
We're in here!
Stop it!
- [Sobbing]
- We're gonna die.
- Die? And I'm still virgin wool!
- It's okay.
I'm scared! Hold me!
[Sobbing]
Oh, this is nice.
[Beeping]
[Coleye]
Easy does it.
Great.
- Wow. Fascinating.
- [Woman] Doctor.
It appears to be some sort of...
biomechanical transmitting device.
Doctor, there's some chewing gum
wedged back in his molar.
Leave it!
Pestering me with Juicy Fruit!
This guy's got a radio station
inside of his skull! Here.
We'll put this under the electron
microscope later. Whoa-ho!
Excellent.
Armitan's gonna be eating his words!
Perfect ending
to an already perfect day.
- He's a little pale. - I think he's having
a negative reaction to the tranquilizers.
Well, two CCs of adrenaline, stat!
- Doctor, I think we're losing him.
- [Yelling, Pounding]
- Nothing.
- [Man] Shut it down.
- Get ready to try it again. This time, full power.
- He's pointing to something.
- He's pointing to the thing.
- Pick it up. Pick--
Pick it-- Yeah.
No. No, no, no.
No, that one. That one.
Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
This. Do this.
- [Beeping]
- Yes!
[Shouting]
Whoa-oh-oh!
No. No, no. Oh.
- Tim!
- Oh!
All right, back off, Gomer.
Hey.
Give me that, dipstick!
You get Tim.
I'll scare the locals.
[Shouts]
- Let's get out of here!
- Call security!
- [All Shouting]
- Nobody will take on the suit!
My zipper is stuck,
and I'm mad as hell!
- Lizzie, what--
- Tim! Oh, are you okay?
- Fine, fine. Are you okay?
- Oh, you wouldn't believe--
- Yeah.
- [Beeping]
- We got to find Martin.
- Yeah.
Back off!
You heard me.
You don't understand. That spaceship's
gonna explode in 20 minutes.
- It is?
- On the floor. Now.
Excuse me.
Arnold, Jean-Claude?
[Shouts]
Not working. Oh.
- It's an empty suit.
- Empty suit?
Now you've done it, Grasshopper.
Whoo-aah!
Boxing?
[Chuckles]
- You should be boxing groceries.
- [Grunts]
[Laughs]
That tickles, ya big ox!
Say, aren't you
one of the Spice Girls?
- [Growling]
- Alley-oop!
[Crashes]
Beavis down, Butt-head to go.
So, is it true you peed your bunk
in summer camp? Ouch!
- [Screams]
- [Gasping]
Oh, Gee-- Tim! Lizzie!
- [Zoot Muttering]
- [Grunts]
- [Grunting]
- Ooh!
[Groaning]
- [Growls]
- [Screams]
- [Growling]
- [Groaning]
[Groaning Continues]
- Uh-oh.
- [Grunts]
- This is gonna hurt.
- Ooh!
- Ow!
- [Lizzie Gasps]
- [Blows Landing, Both Grunting]
- Lizzie!
The ship's going to explode!
Veenox Seven.
Chew this.
- [Punching Continues]
- [Tim] You gotta believe it!
Whoa-oh-oh-oh!
- [Growls]
- [Screaming]
- [Snarls, Roars]
- [Screams]
[Belches]
Uh-oh.
Did you do something with your hair?
Glad you noticed.
[Roars]
[Mutters]
Whoop!
[Sighs]
- I think I liked you better the other way.
- Oh, really?
- [In Raspy Voice] Well, that can be arranged.
- No, no. We gotta find Martin.
- Where's Zoot?
- [Moaning]
Oh, no.
Come on!
Doctor, he's gone.
He's not gone till I say he's gone,
so back off!
- Back off! Now!
- [Nurse] Charge the paddle.
- [Man] All right, we're charged.
- [Coleye] Clear! Clear!
All right. Clear!
- Come on, Martin.
- [Electricity Buzzing]
- Oh, damn!
- There's no pulse, Doctor.
All right, all right.
I'm calling it. 8:15.
- We're too late.
- [Zoot] No, hurry!
- [Man] Would you like me to do the autopsy, Doctor?
- Are you insane?
- You get out of here! Get out!
- All right. All right.
All of you idiots, you get out.
You get out.
- I'm goin'!
- You get right out. Clowns!
Come on.
Okay, my sorry little Martian.
Have it your way.
Let's open you up.
- [Lizzie] Assistance, Doctor?
- What? No! You--
Hey, wait a minute.
You're not--
- She came with me.
- Oh. - Clear.
[Electricity Zapping]
[Moans]
[Zoot's Voice]
Must... be together.
Zoot!
- [Gasps]
- Martin?
- Martin!
- [Groans] Tim! Lizzie!
- You're-- You're--
- [Zoot] Breathin', baby! I still got the touch.
Oh, you beauteous bathrobe!
[Laughs]
- Martin--
- Let's see cotton do that, huh? Easy.
- I got an image!
- [Martin] Okay, okay.
Martin! Martin!
- We don't have much time.
- Blotz!
- [Man, Over Loudspeaker] Shut down
and monitor all exits. - [Sirens Wailing]
[Men Chattering, Indistinct]
[Woman, Over Loudspeaker]
All units stand by for total lockup.
- Martin, can you get the lock?
- I think so.
- [Electricity Humming]
- Come on!
- [Man, Over Loudspeaker] Biotech units on alert.
- [Siren Wailing]
[Woman, Over Loudspeaker]
All non-security personnel...
- are to report to their holding areas.
- Come on. Stay down!
- Stay down.
- Here's a place!
All right.
Stand back, you two.
[Device Beeping]
- [Siren Wailing]
- What's going on? Where's the alien?
- There's been a slight problem.
- Open that gate. Let's find Dr Coleye.
- Yes, sir, yes, sir. Right away.
- Come on!
Let 'em through!
Here.
There. [Grunts]
Contact.
There.
I think that's going to work.
I'm gonna miss you, Martin.
- [Zoot Giggles] - You too, Zoot.
- You're so full of starch!
Hey, let 'em know how you feel!
[Chuckles]
You're the best pet I ever had!
Stop being such a baby blanket!
[Mutters]
Lizzie, my dear friend.
Take care, Uncle Martin.
I've done that before. It's very nice.
I highly recommend it.
Good luck, you two.
Something tells me
you're gonna miss your flight!
- Then in two minutes, we all die.
- You're lying.
Are you certain about that, Coleye?
- Because I'm not.
- What are you saying?
- Release him.
- Release him?
I have spent an entire career
trying to prove that aliens exist.
Now he's my proof!
Dead or alive,
he's staying with me!
Oh. Ohh! Ohh!
Whoa! Aah!
- Martin?
- I don't understand! I-- I--
Coleye, you always were a little blotz.
- [Coleye] What?
- Neenurt!
Ha ha ha! I haven't heard that name
in a long time.
- Pronounced properly, anyway.
- You mean it was you all along?
I can't believe this!
I should have known! You're a Martian?
I was--
Uhh! Aah!
[Screaming]
Waaah!
[Grunting]
- [Chuckling]
- Wait. You're the one I saw at the pier.
I was trying to get to you
before they did.
I've been trying
to hitch a ride home for 30 years!
What a beauty!
Oh, by the way,
I believe these belong to you.
[Gasps]
My antennae.
I can't go home without these. I have a
hard enough time getting dates as it is.
Mine's always giving me trouble too.
And everything's in black and white.
- [Groaning]
- And those commercials-- "Plop, plop, fizz, fizz"--
That gum lost its flavour in '66.
All right. Let's go.
Let's go. Come on.
- Got to go. Farewell.
- Come back for a visit sometime.
Maybe.
I'm beginning to see a glimmer
of potential among you Earthlings.
One word of advice: You'll never
completely advance as a culture...
until you take care of your oceans
and do away with daytime talk shows.
Goodbye, you crazy lovebirds!
Ah, stop being such
a hysterical housecoat.
- See ya, Zoot.
- Rollin', rollin', rollin' Keep them doggies rollin'
[Growling]
Aliens!
Wait! No!
Please! No! You can't!
Don't go! Come back!
No-o-o!
[Growls]
Aah!
What the--
Eeew!
Gum. Gum!
Wait, this is the alien gum!
Yes!
Wait, wait.
I wouldn't do that if I were you.
Well, you're not me, are ya?
[Laughs]
I can learn more about them...
from their leftover--
Wha--
That's brilliant!
I can feel every molecule of my body...
starting to change!
[Laughing]
Aah!
Oh, no.
Hold it! Don't move!
- No!
- Stop! Don't shoot! Get the tranquillizer gun.
No, not that, you idiots!
- I'm not a Martian.
- We got him, boys. Get the tranquillizer gun.
We've got one--
a real live Martian!
It's me. Coleye. No! No!
Aah!
[Man]
The truth is out there!
We are not leaving until they
listen to us! We've got proof!
I saw one!
He cloned my body!
He could be anywhere by now!
The truth is out there!
So that's the story here
from Santa Barbara City Hall.
- I'm Bill Randall, KGSC.
- [Crowd Chanting] The truth, the truth,
the truth, the truth, the truth!
It's all I--
- Hey, sleepy. Brought you some tea.
- [Chuckles]
Listen, I've been thinking. Now that
I really know what happened between us,
I think maybe we should just go back
to the way things used to be.
- Mmm.
- Our friendship really does mean a lot to me.
Yeah, well, I've been thinking too,
and, uh,
I think I've got enough friends.
[Whooshing Sound]
[Rattling]
- [Hissing] - One giant leap for man,
one step backward for Martians.
- Zoot?
- Hey, Tim, Lizzie! We're back!
- [Chuckles]
- Zoot-- [Grunts]
Oh! Geez!
Call a skycap, for cryin' out loud.
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
We've decided to stay here with you.
- Y-You what?
- I kept thinking how lonely I was gonna be without you.
And since you said
you were gonna miss me,
I thought I'd save us both
the heartache of separation.
Ya-hah! Whoo-hoo-hoo!
B-B-B-But, Martin, I can't miss you
if you don't go!
Exactly!
Isn't it wonderful?
Farewell, Neenurt!
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
Where's he going?
To Mars, of course!
[Whooshing]
- Whoo! [Chuckling]
- Wh--
Martin. Martin.
What are you doing?
Tim, since we'll be living together,
let's do something about this furniture.
- Living together? What do you mean--
- I say we get rid of this couch,
and buy a hyperbolic resting chamber
like normal beings have.
- No! No! You're not staying here.
- Hey, who wants ice cream?
- [Chuckles]
- Tonight I'm craving praline swirl.
- Martin-- You think this is funny?
- [Chuckling]
You haven't seen him eat ice cream.
It's not pretty!
Rocky road! Rocky road! Rocky road!
[Shouts]
- Martin, you can't-- He doesn't sleep.
- [Shouting Continues]
He doesn't let me sleep.
This can't happen.
I can't have a Martian for a roommate.
I can't. I just--
- Oh, maybe I can.
- [Chuckles]
Zoot! We've got cookie dough.
Want some?
Zoot.
Zoot, where are you?
Bartender, a Mai "Tide", please.
Ah, Victoria's Secret.
You people know how to live!
[Chuckles]
Lycra.