¶ Oh, walk that walk ¶
¶ come on, talk that talk ¶
¶ come on, tell me, baby ¶
¶ come on, tell me
that you love me ¶
¶ 'cause I love that talk ¶
on your feet!
I'm Doyle. You're my ride.
Let's go.
¶ Boom, boom, boom, boom, ¶
captain Doyle, sir.
Straight approach
to the I.Z. Is out.
Beaucoup n.V.A.
We're gonna have to
take the scenic route.
¶ Hey ¶
¶ well,
my temperature's risin' ¶
¶ and my feet on the floor ¶
¶ 20 people knockin' ¶
¶ 'cause they're wantin'
some more ¶
¶ so let me in, baby ¶
¶ I don't know
what you've got ¶
¶ but you'd better
take it easy ¶
¶ this place is hot, and I'm ¶
¶ so glad we made it ¶
¶ you gotta ¶
¶ gimme some lovin' ¶
¶ every day ¶
¶ well, I feel so good ¶
¶ everything is sounding hot ¶
¶ you better take it easy ¶
¶ 'cause the place is on fire ¶
¶ been a hard day ¶
¶ and I don't know what to do ¶
¶ wait a minute, baby ¶
¶ it could happen to you ¶
¶ and I'm just ¶
¶ so glad we made it ¶
¶ you gotta ¶
¶ gimme some lovin' ¶
¶ every day ¶
¶ yeah ¶
2:00!
Old grandpa Charlie's got a 51.
He's down there every
day, hopin' and waitin'.
Couldn't hit
the broad side of a...
whoo!
Bye-bye, Charlie!
¶ Well, I feel so good ¶
¶ everything is sounding hot ¶
¶ you better take it easy ¶
¶ 'cause the place is on fire ¶
¶ been a hard day ¶
¶ nothin' went too good ¶
¶ now I'm gonna relax, honey ¶
hey! ¶ everybody
should, and I'm ¶
got another one of those?
¶ We made it ¶
¶ hey, hey,
so glad we made it ¶
¶ you gotta ¶
¶ gimme some lovin' ¶
¶ whoo hoo ¶
thanks for the ride!
Bad rat? Rat here no good.
Make people sick.
Stick to snake.
No! No, thanks.
You captain Doyle? Yeah.
I'm jhon.
Where's captain Cahill?
Up trail,
but you rest.
We eat, then go.
I'll wait for you at the top.
Try it with a 60-pound pack.
Not your fault, huh?
Not used to air up high.
You know captain Sam?
Uh-uh. I know of him.
Where I'm from,
everybody knows of him.
He's a legend. So where is he?
Cahill.
Sam right there.
Where? Which hut? Where is he?
No, no. Sam right there.
Cahill?
Captain Samuel Cahill,
sog/op 39?
Hello?
Stop.
You're the guest of honor.
Um...
Took you longer than expected.
We're waiting for you.
Have a little trouble
on the hill?
Um...
They always
have a wine ceremony
to celebrate the arrival
of an important visitor.
Of course,
they'd have a wine ceremony
to celebrate
the arrival of Tuesday.
It's numpai... rice wine.
And it tastes like a combination
of sugar water and vomit.
It's a little early in the day
to be hammered, isn't it?
You have to drink it.
All of it.
And whatever you do,
don't spit it out.
It's an incredible
insult to the chief.
If that's it,
maybe we could go...
not quite. You have to meet po.
Po. Po. Po.
Po? Cahill: Yeah.
He's a village elder or what?
Kind of.
Here he comes.
Don't turn around,
and close your eyes.
Po will wanna touch your face.
Excuse me?
You don't want to insult po.
It's worse than
spitting out the wine.
Close your eyes.
Close my eyes.
This is serious
n.V.A. Territory, captain.
They know the montagnard
are helping us,
so they come around here
all the time
looking for any excuse
to give 'em hell.
Rule number one:
Don't give them one.
That's why you couldn't
fly here directly...
why I only come here
when it's safe.
And rule number 2?
Never forget rule number one.
I think I can remember that.
I leave here Saturday.
That gives me a week
to get you ready.
Oh, I'm prepared, captain.
I can do the job.
And how you gonna do it?
By the book?
There's a better way?
Huh. Look. I got
a few things to tie up.
Jhon'll show you around
and answer any questions.
Captain, I didn't come
here for a village tour.
My orders are
to go to the trail.
You don't start
movin' the big stuff
until after midnight.
Until then, captain Doyle,
I suggest you start
getting to know this village.
These people have been the difference
between life and death for me.
What's that?
The forest gave us so much,
we pay tribute for protection
of the good spirits.
So she's not just a big pet.
No, no. We use elephants.
My father, his father,
his father, forever.
War drives elephants South.
Dak nhe lucky to have one.
Dak nhe are blessed.
I'm happy for you.
Look, let's...
let's go see the trail.
Sam say we go later.
Yeah, I know, but you're
gonna be working for me now.
Forget Sam. Where's the trail?
I forget.
Candy you got?
No, no. Get... no.
No candy. Get away.
Please. Candy. I share.
Kids: Candy! Candy!
Candy! Candy! Candy!
All right.
All right. All right.
I only have one.
Understand? One.
One... hey!
Oh, this is great.
That's it?
Cahill: Ho chi minh trail.
Disappointed? I was.
I expected something a
little bit more established.
That's the beauty of it.
You call in an air strike,
blow the heck out of it,
and they move it.
They use it
to supply an entire army.
It never stops.
Oh, look at that.
Shoulder-fire
surface-to-air missiles.
Whoa.
Second set of s.A. Sevens we've
seen come South this week.
Really?
You bring bad spirit!
It wasn't my fault!
D-d-Doyle!
The kid took the candy.
He stole the candy,
and then he ran off.
It wasn't...
ok, it was my fault.
It was my fault.
I'm sorry about the elephant.
If I could bring him
back to life, I would.
We no want you. You go!
No, wait. Fine!
I never intended to work with
these people in the first place.
Maybe you can!
Maybe I can what?!
The tradition here is
that at high noon
on the last day of wapasat,
the new moon festival,
the king of fire enters on
top of the village elephant.
Now we have to do it by Friday.
That's pushin' it.
Wait. Do what by Friday?
Duan, I give you my word
that when the king of fire
enters the village this wapasat,
he will not do so
on his own feet.
He is going to get you
a new elephant.
I am not getting them
an elephant. No! No!
These people have risked
their lives helping us.
Well, then let's
get them a tractor.
A tractor would last
8 minutes in that big...
well, then don't
get them anything.
Oh, come on! What
are you talkin' about?!
You've been
in the jungle too long!
What about you?!
Will you both shut up?!
The village provides important support
for operations in the region.
If we don't get them an
elephant by Friday afternoon,
we lose the village.
We don't need the village.
It's as simple as that.
Well, maybe we don't
need the village,
but then again, maybe we do.
I think we err on the side of
caution this time, captain Doyle.
You two go out and
get them their elephant.
We'll need some men, sir.
5 should do it.
You get 2.
2 of the very best
and brightest I can borrow.
Now get outta here.
Whatever you do,
don't embarrass me.
Don't worry, sir.
Now, hold on a second.
Aren't we forgetting something?
Who's gonna lead this
delightful little operation?
I am. I am.
Well, I'm sure you both
have very good reasons.
The thing is,
I really don't care.
So odds or evens? One.
Evens. 2...3.
Marvin gaye:
¶ youse a son of a gun ¶
¶ oh, baby ¶
spec-4 ashford?
No, sir. He's in the hooch.
Ashford!
Haul your butt out here!
Sir? He ain't comin' out.
Why is that, red?
Well, he's short 7 days.
Goes back to the world
next Monday.
This man is taking no chances.
He ain't even come out
of his hooch for 2 days.
Troop.
Grenade!
Oh, that's really funny.
Who's the hilarious son of a...
my mistake.
Pack your gear
and be ready to move out
at 1300 hours.
You've been reassigned.
This is
some kind of joke, right?
It's a joke, all right.
You can't reassign me.
Sir, I'm catching the
freedom bird in 7 days.
168 hours.
I'm so short.
I'm so short...
1300 hours, ashford.
¶ Dang me, dang me ¶
¶ they ought to take
a rope and hang me ¶
¶ high from the highest tree ¶
¶ would you weep for me? ¶
Dang it. Dang it!
Spec-5 farley?
Yes, sir!
So what's the mission, sir?
Unless you can't tell me,
like if we're operatin'
on a need-to-know basis.
We are, and you don't.
Yes, sir.
Where you from, farley?
Iowa, sir. Or as my Uncle
Fergus liked to put it,
I owe a hell of a lot of
money on them farm loans.
He doesn't say much about it
since the thresher accident.
Mama likes to say you can
hardly tell anything happened
unless you get up real
close, but I beg to differ.
You been on a farm?
Yes, sir. My daddy
owns a dairy farm,
seein' as I bein'
from the corn state.
So you've had
experience with animals.
Yes, sir.
Just none of 'em good.
I don't know what it is.
Animals just
don't seem to like me.
Never have,
probably never will.
And that didn't make life
easier growin' up on a farm.
Tell you that.
Shoot, one of the main reasons
why I joined the army
in the first place.
Get away from
all the dang animals.
Gilman, hey, I need
25 submariners at 300 per. Ok?
Gilman, may I remind you
I have friends
with absolutely no regard for
the sanctity of human life, ok?
I say the word, I have your head in
a bag on my desk tomorrow morning.
Hang on. General. It's done.
425 per.
Pleasure doing business
with you, sir.
Yes, sir, and give my regards
to your lovely wife
and daughter.
I didn't mean
anything by that, sir.
I gotta go. I got a call
on the other line.
All right, thank you.
Gilman, so where were we?
I think
I had your head in a bag,
350? Done.
All right. Send them to general
John Richardson in danang, please.
Thanks, pal.
And, oh, by the way, gilman?
I'd still let somebody
taste your food.
I thought you were dead.
You mean you hoped I was dead.
What can I do for you guys?
You're a requisitions officer.
Well, we require something.
Not even funny.
We need an elephant
by tomorrow.
Or you don't you think
you could do it?
Please.
Spare me
the I-dare-you crap, Cahill.
Everybody knows I can get
anything anywhere anytime.
Just so happens I'm
startin' 5 days of r-and-r.
This time tomorrow I'll be sittin'
on a beach in Hawaii, my friend.
You're getting us the elephant.
Or what?
You gonna still try to hold that
business with the 64th over my head?
Come on. So the pork
was a little off.
A little off?
I know men who spent a week on the
latrine because of that pork.
It's old news, Cahill.
I got too many friends
in high places
to go down for something
small-time like that now.
Oh, I know other things
about you, poole.
Let me tell you
something, Cahill.
There isn't anything you know
that's gonna keep me from gettin'
on that plane to Honolulu.
Doyle: 180 Miles
in the middle of a war.
We can get a truck and drive
it up close to dak nhe.
That'll take about 3 days.
And another day to walk it in.
We'll get there by Friday.
Actually, I was thinking more
along the lines of air travel.
I lined up a cargo plane
to meet us at an airstrip
near ban don, ok?
We fly the elephant down
to this old CIA airstrip
about a 3-hour walk
from dak nhe,
then your montagnard friends
have their elephant
by 2:00 this afternoon, I'm
sitting on the beach in waikiki
in time to see the sunset.
And you wanted a week!
Good job, poole!
We're coming up on ban don now.
There's no place to land
in the rice paddies.
We'll have to go to an I.Z.
Behind the village.
It was real hot here
2 weeks ago.
Probably ok now.
Probably? We're gonna
land on a "probably"?
Lock and load!
Hey, this isn't that bad.
It's kind of peaceful, really.
All right, move out.
Well, Cahill,
you want elephants,
I give you elephants.
Beautiful elephants, I might
add, at no extra cost.
Knowing you, poole,
they're probably big
puppets with men inside.
Let's go.
Y b'ham?
Let me handle the negotiation.
I already talked to
this guy on the radio.
Thinks he's tough, but I'm
gonna crack him like a walnut.
Oh, you're killing me.
What's the problem?
I thought you could
negotiate anything.
I can with leverage. Problem
is we don't have any.
He doesn't care if he sells
the elephant or not.
We don't make his price,
he blows the deal.
What's his price?
Problem number 2.
He wants 60,000 piasters.
The requisition form
captain Doyle gave me
is only good for 50, so...
that's it?
Hell, 10,000 piasters...
that's only about 150 bucks.
We can raise that between us.
No. You tell him 50,000
is our final offer.
We can do it.
Private funds can't be used
for an official purchase
as per regulations.
It's also an order.
Understood? Tell him.
I get it. It's a perfect
way out for you.
You blow the deal,
and the mission is over.
It's what you wanted
from the beginning.
We're going back to the I.Z.
And call for a ride.
Let's go.
Poole, let's move it.
Ok, 50,000.
You're quite
a negotiator, Doyle.
Gracious sir, perhaps now
we could go to the river
and pick our elephant.
River? 50,000 don't
get elephant in river.
50,000 get you Bo-tat.
Bo-tat!
Uh-oh.
Beat it.
Bo-tat is she, not he.
Boy is linh.
Boy go with Bo-tat.
What? No, boy no go
with Bo-tat.
Boy go with Bo-tat.
We're going to a village
far away.
I'm sure linh's family...
boy has no family. All killed.
In the war?
No. Hit by falling star.
Yes, in war.
Which side?
It matter?
I think it's better
if the boy stays here.
He not belong here.
From north, not our people.
We might as well
take him with us.
N-no. We are not
taking a kid with us.
He'll be my responsibility.
No, captain. All right.
Anyone else here know
how to work an elephant?
I was in love with
a fat woman once,
but she never listened to me.
Oh. Mr. Y b'ham,
you must know how
to work an elephant,
right, sir?
I live with elephants
all my life.
I learn nothing?
Is this guy sarcastic,
or is it just me?
Great. Would you like
to come with us, sir?
20,000 piasters.
Deal.
Good job, Doyle.
I think Mr. Y b'ham
would be a wonderful choice.
Just one problem.
What?
He doesn't stare into space
because he's a wise old soul.
He does it because
he's blind as a bat.
Y b'ham not blind.
Y b'ham can...
y b'ham is blind.
10,000 piasters?
Farley: It's a nice view.
Ashford: What nice view?
All I can see
is an elephant's butt.
Parlez-vous francais?
Any luck?
I tried vietnamese,
Cambodian, French,
and 3 dialects of jeh.
Keep an eye on him.
He's on an elephant.
He's hard to miss.
You know what I mean.
We don't know which side
killed his family.
It could've been us.
He might hate Americans.
We don't know, and until we do,
he can't be trusted. Doyle...
he right. Linh
can't be trusted.
Linh no trust Americans.
Americans not trust linh.
Everything's number one, a-ok.
That elephant just came along
to say good-bye, right?
You're not actually thinking
of putting that on my plane?
What's the problem?
It's an elephant.
Yeah, but, major...
no, no, no. You see,
you cannot put an elephant
on an airplane.
Suppose it starts to panic
and starts moving around?
I lose trim,
the plane goes down.
We all buy the farm.
That's important,
what he just said.
No, no, no.
It's not getting
aboard the plane
unless it's dead.
Now, I'd be happy to oblige...
If you've all grown
too attached to it.
No!
Linh, it's ok.
No one's gonna shoot Bo-tat.
Doyle.
Poole.
Do you have a package
for a Dr. David poole,
d.V.M., on board?
Yeah, I do.
Here we go, gentlemen.
Animal tranquilizer.
She won't move an inch.
Bo-tat's gonna take
a big nap-nap.
Hey, nice try,
but I don't care.
See, my orders say nothing
about lifting an elephant.
Gentlemen, you have a good war.
Ahem, major, maybe
you should read this.
Ok?
This operation's top-secret,
and that's why
you never heard anything
about our large mammal
friend over there.
As a matter of fact,
if anybody asks,
you're moving
a shipment of tuna.
Tuna?
Tuna.
Moving an elephant.
What elephant?
You got 10 minutes.
Gentlemen, I'm responsible
for anything
that goes onto that cargo hold.
Now, if that thing
even twitches,
you're gonna see
an elephant fly.
Hey, that's funny.
All right, yeah.
What's with the letter?
John westmoreland.
Top priority.
Got 8 left.
Now, couldn't get
elephant tranquilizer
'cause the only place
that has it is the London zoo.
It would take too long
to ship, so...
And what's that?
Water buffalo tranquilizer.
It's not as strong,
but my vet guy says
you just give her a little
more, it should work.
My word.
I guess we give her one now,
and then we give her...
One later if she needs it.
How are we supposed to get her
to swallow one of these?
Well... ahem... actually,
according to this,
she's not supposed
to swallow it.
Well, Dr. David poole...
oh, no, no, no, no.
I said I would
help you guys out,
but putting my hand
up an elephant's ass
was never part of the deal, no.
On 3?
Oh... No.
Please, please, please, please.
Ok, what do you have?
Evens. Ok.
1, 2, 3...
Oh.
Heh heh heh heh.
Doyle: Don't you move,
you big suitcase.
Oh, that's horrible.
You weird.
Good thinking, poole.
Well, come on, let's go.
Let's get her on the plane
before this stuff kicks in.
Come on, come on.
Linh thought you joking.
Bo-tat not get on plane.
Excuse me?
Bo-tat no like be on plane.
How often does she fly?
Bo-tat no like plane.
The kid's right.
Let's get a truck.
The plane is here.
We're taking the plane.
Bo-tat no like plane.
Kid... I'll handle it.
Well, then handle it.
Hurry up.
She goes down out here,
you'll never get her inside.
Linh... you nice American?
You think you number one?
You number 10.
You all number 10.
Cahill!
Bo-tat...
that's the way. Come on.
Heads up.
You number 10.
Tell her to lie down.
What'd you do to Bo-tat?
Tell her to lie down
so she doesn't hurt herself.
Tko. Heh heh heh.
What'd you do?
She's ok, linh. She's not dead.
You killed everything.
You killed Bo-tat.
She's not dead.
You make it die.
You killed Bo-tat.
Cahill: She's fine.
She's just sleeping.
¶ Your love ¶
¶ is lifting me higher ¶
¶ than I've ever ¶
¶ been lifted before ¶
¶ so keep it up ¶
¶ quench my desire ¶
¶ and I'll be at your side
forevermore ¶
¶ you know, your love ¶
¶ your love keeps lifting me ¶
¶ on lifting ¶
h.A., what's the first thing
you're gonna do
when you get home?
First thing?
Hug my mom and
give her a big kiss.
Second thing.
Second thing?
Get her some kleenex.
She gonna be bawling
her eyes out.
So what about you, captain?
What's waiting for you
back in the world?
Uh...
A hammer.
My brother's
got a roofing company
in fort lauderdale.
Wants me to be a part
of that. Can't wait.
Been dressed in green too long.
Time to get a real life.
Ahh...
Hey, hey, hey, hey,
what are you kissing?
What is that?
Oh, it's nothing.
Come on, what is it?
It's stupid. It's, uh...
When I first got to 'nam,
I was in the main administration
building in da nang,
feeling scared and...
Nervous like we all do
and thinking about home.
I was walking past
this coke machine,
a bottle of coke
just dropped down,
so...
Drank that bottle of coke
and kept the cap for luck.
So has it worked?
Well, I don't really
believe in that stuff,
but, you know...
2 years without a scratch.
Who knows?
I'll buy it.
Nah, man, I couldn't.
Come on, $20. I'll buy it.
Keep your money, man. I...
$40.
Well, hell, if it means
that much to you, I mean...
he just got it off the bottle
he's been drinking.
Captain,
major wants a word with you.
Hey, farley, look at this
great big beautiful beast.
How can you not like
something like that?
Well, sir, I tell you...
uhh... ow.
Yeah?
Yeah, we got a nasty headwind.
Give baby the other
dose, captain.
Poole,
we have to give
the elephant the second pill...
farley had a little run-in
with the second pill, captain.
Well, how much longer
will she stay out?
Well, one of these
things is supposed
to knock out a water
buffalo for 6 hours.
And Bo-tat's about the size
of 3 water buffaloes...
how much longer
do we have, poole?
We got another hour, easy.
Ok.
I, uh...
I was using the metric system.
Tell me you did that.
Uhh.
Doyle: Whoa!
It's awake!
What was your first clue?
Dump it.
All: Whoa!
Whoa!
Bo-tat!
Come on, come on,
come on, come on!
All: Whoa!
Hey!
Ashford: Aah!
Doyle: Hey, hit the button!
Hit the button!
Get back there and shoot it!
Shut it! We're gonna die!
No!
Hey!
Uhh!
Back in the pit, pilot boy.
All right.
Linh: Bo-tat! Bo-tat!
Bo-tat! Bo-tat! Bo-tat!
Hey! Hey!
Wait! Wait a minute!
You can't leave me here!
Hey! Hey!
I'm going to call lbj!
I knew it! Uhh!
Uhh!
Guys?
Guys? Wait up!
Stop!
No, no, no.
Bo-tat scared! Bo-tat need me!
Yeah, well, all I need is for
you to run off and get lost.
Let me go!
Cahill: Doyle, let him go.
If I let him go, we might never
see him or the elephant again.
Well, if you don't let him go,
you'll never see Bo-tat again.
That's for sure.
I'll go with him.
All right.
Farley: Come on.
Yep. There we go.
Bo-tat understand American.
Bo-tat,
we're going to take you
to a beautiful land
high in the mountains
where you'll be
loved and respected.
Where the air is cold and fresh
and the water
is cool and sweet.
It's the land where
you came from, Bo-tat.
It's where you belong.
Come with me.
Doyle: We're about here,
which means we're not
that far from tuy hoa,
maybe about 10 Miles.
We can get there tomorrow
and get ourselves a truck.
An elephant on a truck for 150
Miles in the middle of a war.
Piece of cake.
Poole: Gilman, you know
those solid gold dog tags?
They're yours.
All you got to do
is get me out of here.
Ah! Man, I just can't
spend the night in here.
Just send... poole!
Poole! Hang on a second...
poole! Give me that!
What are you doing?
Rustling up some
accommodations, captain.
I can have beer and steak
and... and padded cots here
in, like, half an hour.
Maybe even some ice cream.
And then, I figured,
since you guys don't
really need me anymore,
I could sort of head
back with the pilot.
If all the enemy within 5 Miles
doesn't already know we're here,
they sure as hell will
when a huey lands.
Come on, give me a break, will you?
I got you the elephant.
I'm supposed to be sitting in
the middle of a beach right now
worried about my tan line,
not out here in booneyville
worrying about snakes.
Snakes? Snakes?
You're right, poole.
You shouldn't be here.
Give me the radio.
I'll call general Richardson.
I'm sure he can
get you reassigned.
Break out rations, gentlemen.
This is home tonight.
I'll bet you wish you had your lucky
bottle cap now, don't you, you smart ass?
Linh: What are you doing?
H.A. Is going home soon, linh.
He wants good luck to make
sure he gets there safe.
You want good luck?
Don't tell me,
you have an ancient
vietnamese bottle cap
you're willing to sell me.
Linh not sell anything.
Here, elephant is good luck.
You want good luck,
you touch Bo-tat.
Yeah, right.
So what's bad luck?
Um, don't whistle in dark.
Snake will come out
and bite you.
Snakes?
It get worse.
Yeah?
If you see owl at night,
someone in your family die.
Wow. So that's the worst?
No. No?
Owl nothing compared to crow.
You see crow any time,
that very, very bad luck.
So what happens
when you see a crow?
I tell you,
if you see a big black bird,
you run away.
You know what?
This country's
really beautiful.
I mean, I am shocked.
Yeah, it is great, isn't it?
Kind of reminds me of home.
Oh, yeah?
They got a lot of rice paddies
in cornpone, lowa,
do they, farley?
Oh, no, that's Arkansas.
I just meant... you meant what?
Tell me exactly what you meant.
Tell me exactly what
it is about this place
that reminds you of home, huh?
What is it?
The spirit-crushing humidity?
The disease-bearing insects?
Or is it the special feeling
that comes from the knowledge
that at any given moment,
a sniper's bullet could come
spiraling towards your forehead?
Is that it?
Poole, I'm getting this weird
feeling you don't like it here.
What's wrong with you?
I love it. Everybody loves it.
Bet you're the only
American in Vietnam
who would rather
be someplace else.
Enough.
Hey! Hey, come on!
Gimme... gi...
ohh.
Let's keep moving.
Where are you going? Hey!
They're going to help.
For the love of... Cahill,
don't get me wrong.
I would like nothing more
than to skip through the
countryside doing good deeds,
but we don't have the time.
We have to get
a truck, remember?
It won't take long.
Besides, we might even
get something out of it.
Maybe they'll
give you the stump.
You go play good samaritan,
I'm going to go to the
road and do our job, ok?
Go. Go play. Go play.
Bye, now.
Doyle: Where is everyone?
They'll be back in a minute.
Big stump.
America won something today,
and we didn't even
have to shoot anyone.
Oh, yeah?
Well, we lost 2 hours,
and we still don't
have ourselves a truck, so...
Yeah. How about an old diesel
with a 16-foot flatbed?
You think that ought to do?
One of our developing
agencies gave them a truck.
But they rarely can afford gas,
so they gave it to us for
pulling out the stump.
¶ Hang on, sloopy ¶
¶ sloopy, hang on ¶
¶ yeah ¶
¶ yeah ¶ ¶ yeah ¶
¶ yeah ¶ ¶ give it to me ¶
so how long you had Bo-tat?
Forever. She belong father.
Huh. What happened
to your father?
He die.
Well, how'd that happen?
Do you think it was our side?
I don't know.
I hope not.
¶ Hang on, sloopy ¶
¶ sloopy, hang on ¶
¶ hang on, sloopy ¶
¶ sloopy, hang on ¶ ¶ yeah ¶
¶ yeah ¶ ¶ yeah ¶
¶ yeah ¶
¶ hang on, sloopy ¶
¶ sloopy, hang on ¶
¶ yeah ¶ ¶ yeah ¶
¶ hang on, sloopy ¶
¶ sloopy, hang on... ¶
we got a leaky radiator.
I'll try to patch it.
Poole, I speak the language.
It's a joke.
Any more joking,
I'll call you know who.
Hey, stop!
Bo-tat need move.
Food.
Water.
She hungry.
She thirsty.
Now!
All right. All right.
All right, h.A., farley,
take her down to
that fountain there
and give her some water.
We'll give her food
when we get it.
Ah! Oh... Bo-tat!
Jeez, what you
been eating, baby?
One... one minute?
Ashford: Drink up, Bo-tat,
we don't want to
overstay our welcome.
One moment?
Hey, farley,
w-where's she goin'?
Oh, no.
Captain Doyle!
Captain Cahill!
Help.
Linh: Bo-tat! Bo-tat!
Bo-tat!
Linh, stop that elephant!
Ashford: Come back here!
Come back!
Stop!
Excuse me.
Watch out for the elephant!
Aah!
Whoa!
Ashford: Is he all right?
Farley: Oh, man!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Hey, um, sorry
about your chickens.
Linh, we got to turn the
elephant back this way.
We need to bring it back...
we need to bring the
elephant back this way.
Farley: Turn him around
and bring him...
hey. Hey...
whoa. Whoa... whoa!
Farley: H.A.!
Help!
We gotta go this way!
Let's go.
Wait, we haven't
even done the...
Oh, my God.
Cahill: Let's go.
¶ You better think ¶ ¶ think ¶
¶ think about what
you're trying to do to me ¶
¶ think ¶ ¶ think, think ¶
¶ let your mind go,
let yourself be free ¶
¶ let's go back,
let's go back ¶
¶ let's go way on
to way back when ¶
¶ I didn't even know you ¶
¶ you couldn't have been
too much more than 10 ¶
¶ just a child ¶
¶ I ain't no psychiatrist ¶
¶ I ain't no doctor
with degrees ¶
¶ but it don't take
too much I.Q. ¶
¶ to see what
you're doin' to me ¶
¶ you better think ¶ ¶ think ¶
¶ think about what you're
tryin' to do to me, yeah ¶
¶ think, think ¶
¶ let your mind go,
let yourself be free ¶
¶ oh, freedom... ¶
gimme your hand.
Come on!
Wait up!
Come on! Captain, slow down!
¶ Freedom ¶ ¶ freedom ¶
¶ freedom ¶ ¶ freedom ¶
hurry! Hurry! Come on, farley!
Aah!
Eww. Go. Go.
Whoa... unh!
That doesn't sound very good.
I know. We don't
have time to stop.
If they weren't after us
before, they will be now.
That guy at the feed depot
wasn't the only n.V.A.
They try to blend in.
They all got
that same damn haircut.
Cahill: Ohhh.
Hey, w-where's he goin'?
Doyle: Poole, where you going?
Saigon.
Get back here.
Poole, do you want me to
call general Richardson?
Yeah, Cahill. Yeah, I do.
Ok? Call general Richardson.
Let me get him on the
line here for you, ok?
Because I am sick and tired...
I...
That's it. I've had it, ok?!
Ok, I was on a plane
that almost crashed,
I came this close to being
killed by an angry mob,
and now... Look at my uniform.
It's covered in elephant crap.
So, if you think
that I really give a damn
whether or not you call
general Richardson
and tell him that I
slept with his wife...
Doyle: Huh?
Oh!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hold on, hold on.
You slept with the wife
of general "kill 'em all and let
God sort it out" Richardson?
I thought it was his daughter.
Oh, yeah. He woulda
been fine with that.
First off, poole,
Saigon's the other way.
Second, the nearest
town in any direction
is hau bon, which is
30 Miles upstream.
And third, the only
hope in hell you have
of getting out of here
alive is to stay with us.
Doyle: It's cooked.
Ashford: What are we
gonna do, captain?
We wait.
Things come along
when you need 'em.
My motto's
"have a little faith."
Yeah, well, my motto is
"explosives and plenty of 'em."
Load the truck with all the
claymores and grenades we've got.
String one of the
claymore's trigger wires
to the door.
N.V.A. Comes along, goes
to open the door, kaboom.
If we're lucky, it might
even take out the bridge.
Lucky for who?
The people around here
use this bridge every day.
That's enough already.
We're in a war here,
in case you don't remember.
If you're right about the n.V.A.
Being after us,
they're gonna be
coming down that road
for one reason
and one reason only...
to kill us.
Their lives
are my responsibility,
so excuse me if I don't
get all choked up
at the thought of disrupting
some local peasant's
daily commute.
How do you know the n.V.A.'S
gonna be the first ones here?
What if it's
a bunch of school kids
who are goin' home?
You ever think about that? No!
Why? Because guys like you
don't think things through!
Me? What about you?!
You've got 5 people and an
elephant risking their lives
so you can go home
with a clear conscience.
You're afraid when
you're up on the roof
with your brother
in fort lauderdale
and you're lookin' back over
your sparkling military career,
you're not gonna like
what you see!
You're afraid
Vietnam's gonna wipe out
everything you did before,
so you want to do one
good thing before you go.
Which is great.
But your one good thing isn't pulling
a kid out of a burning building
or diving on a grenade.
It's this!
And because it's this,
it means it involves us!
But you didn't think
about that, did you?!
No!
Why? Because guys like you
don't think things through!
Hey, come on, sirs,
break it up.
Break it up, sirs.
Aah!
Oh, God! Oh-oh-oh-oh-oh!
Gimme your hand.
Gimme your hand. Pull him in!
You ok?
Whew!
Ok?
Yep...
I'm real happy
about my decision
to stick with you guys.
Uh, at the risk of
rekindling hostilities,
what do we do now?
Like I said,
have a little faith.
¶ Ha ha ha ha ¶
Is that my ears,
or has your singing
actually gotten worse?
Must be your ears.
It was as bad
as it already could be!
Doyle: Have
a little faith, my eye.
You knew this boat was coming.
My first tour, I was
stationed at hau bon.
Every Wednesday afternoon,
monsieur Goddard and the Marie
antoinette would drop in.
He gave us
the best intelligence
on the location of the v.C.
We ever got.
What... what can I say?
I love America.
Yeah. Hey.
You gave the v.C.
Their best intelligence
on our location, too.
I can't help it, you know.
I love everybody.
Would anyone
like some wine here?
Yeah. Yeah.
Wine?! No!
What is this, the opening
of an art gallery?!
No. This is a war.
The green beret motto
is "free the oppressed,"
not "eat, drink, and be merry."
Yeah, now it is.
Aww.
What did I do? What did I do?!
I should be on some
high-priority mission
with a group
of crack commandos.
Instead, I'm in an episode
of mchale's Navy,
starring dumbo, Mr. French,
and the 3 stooges!
D'ng lai.
That mean stop.
D'ng lai?
Dee. That mean go.
Dee?
You try.
Dee!
Uh... d-d-d... uh... uh...
D'ng lai!
Good.
You know 2 of 3
most important words
for elephant.
What's the third?
Huh?
It means get off me.
Poole.
Can you get more of that
water buffalo tranquilizer?
You really enjoyed that,
didn't you, Doyle?
Linh was right.
You are weird.
Poole.
Poole: Yeah, yeah.
As much as you want.
Ok.
We get off past
hau bon tonight.
Tomorrow we take
one of these trails
which, God willing,
isn't in enemy hands,
over one of these ridges,
down into pleiku.
Friday morning we fly Bo-tat
to the airstrip
near the village.
By noon we walk her in.
Piece of cake.
Get down!
Doyle: Stay down!
Everyone stay down!
Farley. Hold your fire.
They're out of range.
They're gonna have us
in 5 rounds.
I know this. I'm artillery.
Give them a moving target.
Zigzag.
Keep moving.
Linh, what's wrong with Bo-tat?
She hurt here.
Oh, sh...
oh, no, she's seasick.
Look out... she's gonna blow!
Eww!
Years from now
my kid's gonna ask me,
"daddy, what's the worst
thing you saw in the war?"
After this, there's no contest.
Doyle: Can't you get this
tub to go any faster?!
You are going to sink my boat.
Maybe not.
Gilman, who would
I actually know
that could get me
your head in a bag?
It was a joke, pal.
Yeah, I was kidding.
I love you, man.
Like a brother.
What are you, nuts?!
Where am I gonna find
a triumph spitfire
in the middle of Vietnam,
you rotten little rat?!
Ok, ok, I'm sorry. I apologize.
Ok. All right, you got it.
Just patch me through to
firebase cheo reo now, ok?
And direct to artillery.
I don't have time
for channels or anything.
Ok. He's puttin' me through.
Son of a... heh heh.
Right here. Hang on.
Uh... Yeah...
We're on the song ba river
being pursued
by n.V.A. In a boat.
What? Yeah,
this is hotel Alpha.
Who's this? Barney?
Hey, Barney, what's up, man?
What you doin'...
h.A.! H.A.! I'm sorry.
Uh, cheo reo, we
need your help pronto.
Request fire mission
and expedite.
Call for battery fire
at grid coordinates
bravo Romeo 354...1105 niner.
Fire one marking round.
Barney, that was perfect, man!
No, it wasn't perfect.
It almost hit us!
Give 'em other coordinates.
Captain, we're moving. Those
coordinates are gonna be perfect.
Right about... Better be right.
Fire for effect!
Better be right. Now.
Ha! Whoo! Whoa!
Yeah!
Hey, hey. I'm gonna
start callin' you
the brown bomber!
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Brown bomber.
You wanna try it on?
I found a place where
we can spend the night.
Farley: Hey, sir,
what is this place?
An ancient temple.
Buddhist?
Actually, it's tam giao.
A little buddhism, a little
confucianism, and a little tao.
What's with all the elephants?
The elephant
is the God in tam giao.
Not a God.
Father of God.
In beginning,
elephant were white,
and they fly in the air with
the clouds and the rain.
One day, elephant fly down and
go into side of queen Maya...
While she sleep and dream.
She have baby.
Prince siddhartha,
the gautama Buddha.
Elephant, father of God.
Linh, that story
you told was great.
I... I loved the bit
about the flying elephants.
Uh, just one thing, though.
It might be better if you
started, "in the beginning,
all elephants were black."
All right, this
is our only option.
We have to take this trail
over this pass into pleiku.
Is the pass secure?
Tch. I don't know.
We could find out
at this village
unless you think 5
Americans and an elephant
waltzing into town might
arouse suspicion.
Hmm. Not at all.
We could send in linh.
No one would suspect him.
No, we can't do that.
Why not?
You know why.
We can't take that chance.
I got it. Wait.
Doesn't matter to me
who killed your family.
I imagine it doesn't
matter to you, either.
V.C. Killed
mother and sister...
But linh not know
who killed father.
Linh and father going home...
There was big light.
Everything happened fast.
People yell, shoot gun.
Father hold linh tight.
Bo-tat run.
They shoot Bo-tat.
Father and linh land apart.
Father get up, run
to linh, and fall down.
He shot.
Linh not move.
Bo-tat save linh.
Men shoot Bo-tat more times.
Bo-tat no stop for many Miles.
Bo-tat save me.
Were you hurt?
You said you couldn't move.
No, I said I not move
because I too scared.
Father die because I not help him.
I scared.
No, no, linh, that's not why.
Yes, I scared!
Of course you were scared.
I'd be scared.
Anyone would be scared.
Linh.
It wasn't your fault.
Who fault?
People.
People far away, linh.
People who've never been here.
Linh no understand.
How did you get to ban don?
American take linh.
Said take linh back
to mountains someday.
Never did. Lie to linh.
I'm gonna take you
back to the mountains, linh.
I promise you.
Linh father was a good father.
Number one father.
I'm sure he was.
Yeah.
Oh, man, I just went
to go take a whiz.
I didn't want to
desecrate the temple.
Forget about it. It's done.
He probably went to get
some food or something.
Whatever the reason, they're gonna
find out we're here pretty damn soon.
He's just a kid.
I know. I have to go get him.
I'll get the elephant to pleiku
and we'll meet you there.
Excuse me, guys, una momento.
But how are we gonna
move old Bo here, huh?
Linh taught farley
the basic commands.
No, he didn't.
Ok, sir, he did, but...
Take someone with you.
I screwed up. I'll go.
Th-that's funny. My... my
legs don't work.
Poole: Ah, hell. I'll go.
Kid's got my watch.
Ok, do the foot. Get... get her
to do the foot and get up.
Let's go.
Come on.
I don't... I don't know that one.
All right, can you
guys give me hand?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Here' take the gun.
Take the gun.
Put your foot on my leg.
Ok. One... do you wanna jump in?
On 3, h.A., 1...2...3.
Ok, I'm up. I'm up.
Good job. Good job.
I don't know about this, sir.
I guess that means she's ready.
I think she's mad.
Doyle: Come on.
This way. Take us
around the village.
Farley, this way!
He didn't teach me how to turn.
Then stop her!
Ok, ok. Uh... Dee!
I mean... I mean,
Dee d'ng. D'ng. Dai!
Farley!
Uh!
Tell my mom I love her!
Stop!
Stop, darn it,
you crazy animal!
Ohh!
Whoa! Aah!
Bo-tat?
Farley, you wild a driver.
Ha ha.
Sam!
You all right?
Yeah. Huh?
They worked him over
pretty good.
He hit me this many.
So, when I tell him you
in hau bon, he believe.
You told him
we were in hau bon?
Kid, why did you come here?
You want to find out
if trail ok...
But linh is the only one
who can ask.
Before linh caught,
linh find out trail ok.
You trust linh now?
Yeah.
I trust linh now.
You guys do this hug a lot.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Bo-tat!
No!
Yee-hoo!
¶ Aow! Walk that walk ¶
¶ come on, talk that talk ¶
¶ come on, tell me, baby ¶
¶ come on, tell me
that you love me... ¶
canceled?
What do you mean
the mission is canceled?
Turns out Doyle was right.
We don't need the village.
While you two
were off on safari,
the ho chi minh trail
moved again,
and intelligence estimates are
it's gonna stay where it is.
The village is of
no strategic interest.
"No further
strategic interest"?
Major pederson, sir,
we're so close.
Let us finish what we started.
We just have to fly
the elephant to...
to where, Cahill?!
To that old CIA airstrip
near the village?
The n.V.A. Blew the heck
out of it 3 days ago.
You have no place to
land your elephant.
The airstrip's gone.
End of mission!
What about linh and Bo-tat?
Who?
The boy and the elephant, sir.
Well, you ship them back to
where you picked them up.
Where are you going?
I can't tell you.
Ashford: Why not?
'Cause if I tell you,
you'll try to stop me.
If you don't try to stop me,
you'll be court-martialed.
The mission's been canceled.
I have a feeling the
captain's gonna ignore that.
What are you gonna do, steal
a truck from the motor pool?
If that's what it takes.
Oh, hell!
If we're gonna steal a truck,
we might as well steal a plane.
What?
You worried because
there's no airstrip?
We don't need one.
Remember when
we first went to pederson
and I said,
"let's get them a tractor"?
What if we had?
How would we have
gotten a tractor in?
Tractors don't need airstrips.
Poole.
Yeah?
Ok, we're gonna
need parachutes...
we?
Poole: Yeah, captain.
We.
H.A., farley, are you in?
Yeah.
Ok.
You take one step toward dak
nhe with that elephant,
you can kiss your sweet
military career good-bye.
Yeah, well,
maybe we all need to do
one good thing before we go.
E-easy now, easy.
Hey!
Shh!
This is insane.
Bo-tat's not a tractor.
Poole, did we just hear
a heartfelt human emotion
come out of you?
Yeah, it was.
I feel bad for her.
Don't tell anybody I said that,
ok, you guys?
It's top secret, ok?
So top secret, we're not
even getting clearance
from the tower.
Radio's silenced
and nobody knows anything.
As a matter of fact,
this never happened.
Sir, they've stolen
a 123 out of pleiku.
When?
About 5 minutes ago, sir.
Damn it!
Get on the radio
and tell 'em to get back.
That whole area is jammed
with n.V.A. Anti-aircraft.
Yes, sir.
Cahill: Don't
be nervous, poole.
I just never
have jumped before.
Well, neither has she.
Does she look nervous?
All right, listen up.
Bo-tat and the crate
are on a static line.
Now, the drogue will trigger
the parachute to open
the second
she's out of the plane.
Now, you three are gonna
jump before Bo-tat.
Free fall for a count
of 10, and then pull.
Ok? Got it?
We want to make sure
you don't get tangled
in Bo-tat's lines going down.
And we want you to be clear
of our large friend
before she lands.
Now, captain Cahill and I
are gonna stay on board
until Bo-tat gets off.
Once she's off,
we're gonna go, ok?
Sam: Any questions?
Linh get one?
Well, no, linh.
You have to stay on the plane.
Well, maybe he...
linh could take mine,
and, uh, I could, um,
stay on the plane. I mean...
but linh go with Bo-tat.
I'm sorry, linh.
It's too dangerous.
You can't.
You promised you take linh
and Bo-tat home to Mountain.
You will go home.
You'll see Bo-tat
in a day or 2.
But first you have to
go back to the base
with the pilot. There's no...
you lie! You lie!
Hey.
Hey, you're right.
I did say I'll get you home,
and I will.
I'll stay with you
on the plane.
I'll get you to the mountains.
I'll get you back to Bo-tat.
You just can't go with her now.
Oh! Whoa! Whoa!
Here comes another one!
Oh!
Take us down below the radar.
Pilot: This isn't a fighter.
This is a cargo plane.
Do it!
Aah! Aah!
You can't drop
from this altitude.
We'll go back up when we
get closer to the village.
Doyle: No, now.
Do it now! Now!
Doyle: Ah, jeez!
Looks like we're all
gonna be jumping.
Can you get us in
over the village?
One pass, then we bail.
We're going now!
Get ready.
Change of plans, linh.
Pilot: We're coming in
on the village!
I'll be right down.
Stand by!
Ready?
Yeah. Ok.
Go! Go! Go!
I... I can't go, guys. I... I
left something back inside.
I gotta... I can't do this.
I'm an office guy, man.
I work in an office
behind a desk!
Ashford: Isn't
this great, chief?
It's moving!
Farley: Isn't this fun, poole?
No! Bo-tat!
Hold on tight!
Linh: Aah!
Sam: Hold on!
Aah! Aah!
Aah!
Get it! Go!
Hold on, Bo-tat. Hold on.
I'll get you.
Oh!
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
Whoo!
Yeah!
Thank God!
Poole: Please, God,
get me through this.
I'll never lie again.
Please. Uhh. Oh!
Hoo! Whoo-hoo-hoo.
Farley: Whoo!
Farley, you're dead.
Swear to God.
I'm gonna kill you.
Ashford: Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
Whoa! Whoa!
Aah! Aah!
Linh like hug. Hug good.
Sam: Be careful. Be careful.
Keep everybody back.
All right. Very good.
Is she ok?
Everything number one a-ok!
Hey, where's h.A.?
Get me a ladder!
Doyle: Back her up, linh!
Come on, sweetheart. We gotta
get you ready for the ceremony.
Good girl.
Uh-oh.
Unh!
Drop your weapons!
You bring elephant very far.
Very admirable.
I congratulate you.
Too bad you go
to all this trouble
for nothing.
Bird, if I were you,
I'd get the hell out of here.
Elephant going to die.
Drop your guns! Drop your guns!
Drop... drop 'em!
Roger, whiskey tango. Over.
Crossbow 6 out.
What did he say?
Well, the good news
is that capturing nguyen
and his men
has made you a hero.
And the bad?
Recon photos are indicating
that the trail has moved
back this way again.
Pederson wants you to stay.
That is bad news.
I have to go now, linh.
You not like it here.
I love it here.
I love this place more than
any place I've ever been.
You not like linh.
You know that's not true.
Then why you go?
Just like you had
to go where you belong,
I have to go where I belong.
You forget linh?
When I forget how to breathe.
Take her easy, linh.
Safe trip home.
Oh, thank you. Good luck.
Thank you.
Hey, hope to be
in special forces, too,
one day, sir.
Thanks. Good job, soldier.
Thanks.
Captain.
Ever need anything...
Ok.
Yeah.
Doyle: Sam.
When you're standing on a roof
with your brother
in fort lauderdale...
I think you're
gonna like the view.
You watch Bo-tat?
Yeah. I'll watch Bo-tat.
Have fun.
Cliff Edwards: The horsefly.
I seen a dragonfly.
I seen a housefly.
Cliff Edwards: See,
I seen all that, too.
¶ I seen a peanut stand,
and heard a rubber band ¶
¶ I seen a needle
that winked its eye ¶
¶ but I be done seen
about everything ¶
¶ when I see
a elephant fly... ¶
Jim Carmichael: With the wind.
¶ When I see an elephant fly ¶