THE THREE MUSKETEERS (2011)
Cardinal Richelieu,
these men, they...
Please help me, Your Eminence.
Please, please have mercy. Please.
He defaced your carriage and
stole valuables from inside.
But it's just a coach.
Please, I was hungry.
My family hasn't eaten
for days. Please.
Please. In the name of God,
I beg you.
Very well.
In the name of God.
Oh, thank you,
Your Eminence.
Your place in heaven
will always be assured.
Of course.
No. No. Don't!
No, please!
Please, God.
No! No!
One less mouth to feed.
Getting sloppy, Girard.
Why don't you do yourself a favour?
- Surrender.
- My sister's honour is at stake.
How many times do I have to
tell you? Nothing happened.
- I know what I saw, D'Artagnan.
- Girard, I told her I was leaving for Paris.
She wanted to give me something
to remember her by.
- Liar!
- This is stupid, Girard.
All I want to do is get to Paris
and join the Musketeers.
You, a Musketeer?
Fantasy!
My father was a Musketeer,
the King's personal bodyguard.
The King was assassinated.
Your father was a failure...
a disgrace
to the Musketeers.
- What did you say?
- Your father was a disgrace.
My brothers will avenge me.
Already?
Charge! Charge!
Get him!
He's mine!
Come back!
He went that way!
We'll get you,
D'Artagnan!
In the meantime, give
my regards to your sister.
What should I do
with the Musketeer flag?
Burn it.
Musketeers.
By joint edict of His Majesty
the King, Louis Xlll...
and His Eminence
Cardinal Richelieu...
the Musketeers are
officially disbanded.
In preparation for
the coming war with England...
the ranks and commissions are forthwith
transferred to the infantry.
You'll be notified
and told where to report.
Until such time,
return to your homes.
- And who will protect the King?
- The Cardinal's guards...
have already assumed
that responsibility.
You are ordered
to disperse.
Should even one of you resist,
the entire corps...
will be arrested
and imprisoned.
All for one...
and one for all.
Well, there's nothing more
to be said, is there?
Your Eminence.
An impressive performance.
I especially admired that last touch.
"All for one
and one for all. "
If I didn't know better, I should have
thought you wanted them to riot.
It would have given us
an excuse to arrest them.
Hardly necessary.
The Musketeers
are finished.
Not entirely.
There are three.
Three?
I sent a patrol to find them.
They haven't returned yet.
I want those Musketeers,
not excuses.
Bring them in at once.
Follow me.
No loose ends this time,
Captain Rochefort.
Athos.
Porthos.
Aramis.
Do you have any idea
what you've done?
I've saved you and your friend
from these bandits.
These "bandits" are
the Queen's own bodyguards.
The Queen? I'm sorry.
I- I had no idea.
- What's your name?
- D'Artagnan.
D'Artagnan.
A Gascon?
I've come to Paris
to join the Musketeers.
Then I'm sure I'll be
hearing your name again.
- Would that please you?
- Ladies-in-waiting...
are forbidden to socialize
with Musketeers.
I'm not a Musketeer yet.
With that kind of courage,
you will be one soon enough.
Good luck, D'Artagnan.
And thank you for the entertainment.
I enjoyed it immensely.
Wait! You didn't
tell me your name!
Constance!
Constance.
Come along.
Is this Musketeer
Headquarters?
No, this was
Musketeer Headquarters.
Oh, you mean
it's been moved.
No, I mean the Musketeers have been
disbanded. They no longer exist.
Feel free to poke around
for souvenirs if you wish.
But I just got here. How am I supposed to
become a Musketeer if they've been disbanded?
I say you've got
quite a problem.
You're not being
very helpful.
You need a lesson
in manners, boy.
Anytime.
Why don't you meet me outside
the city, by the ruins?
Let's say noon.
I'll be there!
There he is.
Come on. Out of my way, man!
Out of my way!
How dare you touch me!
D'Artagnan!
Get your hands off me!
- D'Artagnan!
- Here. Hold this horse for me, all right?
I'll be right back.
You got it? Thank you.
My word!
- Sorry. Sorry.
- Excuse me!
This sash was a gift to me
from the Queen of America.
There's no Queen of America.
I beg to differ, infant.
We're on quite intimate terms,
unless you can prove otherwise.
Here's my proof.
Oh, I see. It's twit of the month,
come to challenge the mighty Porthos.
- Thinks he's lightning with a sword.
- With the mighty who?
- Don't tell me you've never heard of me.
- The world's biggest windbag?
Little pimple...
meet me behind
the Luxembourg at 1:00...
and bring a long wooden box.
Bring your own.
"The Lord God took the man and put him in
the garden to till it and care for it...
but of the fruit of the tree,
which is in the midst of the garden...
God hath said,
'Ye shall not eat of it.
Neither shall ye touch it,
lest ye die. '
And the serpent said
unto the woman, 'Ye... "
Madam, I'm flattered, but I am
here to tutor you in theology.
Forgive me, Monsieur Aramis, but when
you started talking about original sin...
I lost control
and became impassioned.
It won't happen again.
Please go on.
Well, there's nothing unholy
about expressing one's emotions.
On the contrary, religion
should be experienced...
in an all-embracing way.
We should feel free to express
our spirituality.
Yes, darling.
- Let me in!
- My husband!
- You're married?
- Yes, I'm married.
Oh. We must pray
for our sins.
On second thought,
God's often busy.
Out of my way, woman!
No!
Thank you. You broke
my fall perfectly.
- But I do apologize for the inconvenience.
- Get off me!
- If there's one thing I can't abide, it's rudeness.
- You fell on me.
- And I apologized for it.
- Well, your apology's not accepted.
I hope your sword
is as quick as your mouth.
- It's quicker.
- Ah. A duel then.
A duel.
Meet me behind the Carmes-Deschaux
Monastery at 2:00.
- I'll be there.
- As will I.
Three duels in one day.
- Homesick?
- Cardinal Richelieu.
You surprised me.
I often have
that effect on people.
I can't imagine why.
I'm really a very
gentle person.
You seem a little unhappy
in your new home.
Lonely.
Is that the same thing?
Austria's loss
is France's gain.
I'm not sure the King
shares your opinion.
We've barely spoken
since our wedding day.
Whenever we're together,
he seems so... uncertain.
Arranged marriages
can be difficult.
Your father and I
thought yours...
would bring Austria and France
closer together.
Countries align more swiftly
than people, I'm afraid.
What a pity.
Love is, I think...
wasted on the young.
His Majesty, the King.
Cardinal Richelieu,
I've been looking for you.
- Your Majesty.
- Anne. I didn't know you were here.
- W-Would you like me to go?
- No. Please stay.
- Your Eminence, I demand an answer.
- Perhaps if I knew the question.
I just learned that you went ahead
and disbanded my Musketeers.
- You approved the decision.
- But not the timing.
I intended to address them myself
and explain the situation.
These men are not just my
personal guards. They are my friends.
A thousand apologies,
Your Majesty.
We are on the brink
of war with England.
The Duke of Buckingham plans
to invade La Rochelle within the month.
We'll need the Musketeers in
the field if we are to defeat him.
I thought it best
to act quickly.
I will be the judge
of what is best...
for me and for France.
Of course.
Forgive me.
He is becoming as troublesome
as his father.
He's a foolish boy
and barely that.
That foolish boy
is about to become a man...
which is all the more reason
for us to act quickly.
- Have our loose ends been tied up?
- Two patrols have been sent.
I trust, Captain Rochefort, that you
are doing everything in your power...
to rid us of these rebels.
Don't let having only one eye
impair your vision.
The loss of the other
would be most inconvenient.
What is this?
We were having a private party
celebrating the demise of the Musketeers.
- Go away.
- Athos, is that any way to greet our guests?
Gentlemen, don't be shy.
Come in.
- Your friends have been expecting you.
- You're under arrest.
Under whose authority?
Mine.
Hello again, Cyclops.
Let's see, when was the last time
we had the pleasure of his company?
I believe it was the day he was
cast out of the Musketeers.
Conduct unbecoming a Musketeer.
That was the charge, was it not?
You should know.
Three of you stood against me.
- It was the least we could do.
- You are hereby ordered...
to surrender your tunics
and your commissions at once.
You can, of course, refuse...
become outlaws,
hunted men.
But why not
come along quietly...
for old times' sake?
- Did I miss anyone?
- Congratulations, Porthos.
- You brought down the house.
- Oh, drat.
I was trying
to hit Rochefort.
You go back and
you tell the Cardinal...
we will continue to perform our sworn
duty, which is to protect the King.
And we will use every means
within our power to fight him.
Bold words.
I look forward to ramming them
down your throat.
Rochefort. Isn't that
a smelly kind of a cheese?
Your manners have not
improved yet. You're late.
Are you in a hurry to die?
Here come
the grave diggers now.
Athos, you cannot
fight this boy.
- Why not?
- I'm fighting him.
- Not until 1:00.
- I have a duel with him too.
Not until 2:00.
Let's get on with it then.
Wouldn't want you to be late
for your future engagements.
You're a Musketeer?
- You're all Musketeers?
- You choose your opponents well.
- Or should I say foolishly?
- I've been looking all over for you.
Now you've found us. We have
some business to attend to...
unless, of course, you'd like
to make it for a later date.
No. I'm a man of honour.
But believe me when I say that
killing you will bring me no pleasure.
I'll be with you gentlemen
in a moment.
- Oh, he's a feisty little fellow.
- Feisty indeed.
There they are!
Only a fool would try
and arrest us twice in one day.
- You're under arrest.
- A fool.
The boy's of no interest to me.
He's free to go.
You coming peacefully,
or do you intend to resist?
Oh, don't be so stupid. Of course we intend
to resist. Just give us a moment, all right?
Five of them, three of us.
Hardly seems fair.
Maybe we should give them
a chance to surrender.
- Excuse me, but there's four of us.
- It's not your fight.
You're not a Musketeer.
I may not wear the tunic, but I believe
I have the heart of a Musketeer.
- Warrior.
- Poet.
- You got a name, boy?
- D'Artagnan.
- Athos, Porthos and Aramis.
- Hello.
- Nice to meet you again.
- Pleasure.
Everyone acquainted?
Now we are prepared
to resist you.
God, I love my work.
Take a look
at our young friend.
By god, he's still alive.
May the Lord forgive you for
any sins you may have committed.
Amen.
What's he doing?
Last rites. Aramis takes death
very seriously.
- Is he a priest?
- He used to be one of the Cardinal's students.
You, boy...
are arrogant, hot-tempered
and entirely too bold.
I like that.
Reminds me of me.
Don't encourage him. By helping us, the
boy has made himself an outlaw as well.
- Not if he leaves Paris right now.
- I can't leave now.
- I just got here.
- Go home. Find a wench.
Raise fat babies.
Live a good, long life.
What about the motto of the Musketeers:
"All for one and one for all"?
Wake up, boy.
The Musketeers are just a dream.
Halt!
Long live the Musketeers!
He's mine.
Go on. Get out of here.
Go on!
- My sword!
- It's magnificent.
Where did you steal it?
It belonged to my father.
Your father?
Well, now it belongs to me.
I collect swords, you see.
I take them from
men I've killed.
- Well, I'm not dead yet.
- You and the Musketeers...
are responsible for the killing of the
Cardinal's guards, an offence punishable by death.
They interrupted a duel
we were fighting.
A deed also punishable
by death.
It's been a busy day.
Tell me where to find
the Musketeers...
and I will give you back
your father's sword.
Give me back my father's sword,
and I'll cut out your heart.
Idiot.
Like your father.
- Take him below.
- Yes, sir.
Hey, boy!
Leave us.
Milady de Winter.
Your Eminence.
Your beauty would make even
the most chaste of men...
think of... impurity.
I don't believe you suffer
the burden of chastity.
Perhaps you're right.
I was making an observation,
not an offer.
A word of caution, Milady.
A snap of my fingers, and you could
be back on the block where I found you.
And with a flick
of my wrist...
I could change
your religion.
You're very persuasive.
For a moment I forgot that your lovers
have a tendency to end up dead.
Love has its risks.
So does duty.
The precision with which you
disposed of your husband...
or should I say your
ex-husband, Lord de Winter...
was commendable.
Not to mention
helpful to our cause.
- I do what is necessary.
- Yes.
I have a new mission which
requires your singular talent.
- What is it?
- You will carry this treaty to the Duke of Buckingham.
You're making an alliance
with England?
The King has
left me no choice.
The boy is beginning to believe that
he should rule France instead of me.
- God forbid.
- You're to leave at once for Calais.
A ship called the Persephone
will carry you to England.
She sails Tuesday
at midnight.
Buckingham's signature
must be next to mine...
before the King's birthday,
Friday.
Consider it done.
And doing so
will earn you...
the gratitude of a king.
Until that day,
Your Eminence.
Or should I say
"Your Majesty"?
"Majesty" sounds good.
Looking for me?
Kneel. Were you taught
no respect for a man of God?
Cardinal Richelieu.
How much did you overhear?
Hardly a word, Your Eminence.
The voices were much too low...
- and with all the noise from the prison...
- What's your name, boy?
D'Artagnan.
Oh, yes. Your father
was a Musketeer.
He died while
protecting the King.
The dream of every warrior:
dying nobly
for King and country.
Tell me, D'Artagnan, what noble
business brings you here?
I came to join
the King's Musketeers.
- Bad timing.
- So I've heard.
Like the Knights
of the Round Table...
the Musketeers have
outlived their usefulness.
And so have
your three friends.
Tell me where they are,
and I will spare your life.
- I can't tell you what I don't know.
- Give my regards...
- to the headsman and your father.
- Wait!
- You object to losing your head?
- Yes. I like it where it is.
Then tell me
what I want to know...
and maybe you will keep it
a while longer!
I don't know where they are.
And if you did?
I wouldn't tell you.
I admire your courage,
D'Artagnan.
You might have made
a fine Musketeer.
But now we'll never know,
will we?
They're bringing him now.
It's your time, lad.
Step down.
Milady left at midnight
by private coach.
A remarkable woman. The most
beautiful I've ever known.
And the deadliest.
Which would explain
my attraction.
How is our young daredevil
holding up?
He's wishing he never heard
of the Musketeers.
D'Artagnan!
Don't lose your head!
Fear not, my son.
We are with you always.
All for one...
one for all.
Now this axe was a gift to me
from the Czarina of Tokyo.
Stop! Stop! Stop!
Stop! Stop!
My carriage!
Gentlemen, your carriage,
compliments of the Cardinal.
Stop! Follow them!
Come on! Come on!
D'Artagnan!
The Cardinal's
sacred snack chamber.
And what have we here?
Is he a man of God
or a man of gold?
D'Artagnan, would you be so kind
as to redistribute this wealth?
Throw the coins, lad.
The people are hungry.
Well done.
Those Musketeers are a menace.
They must be stopped.
The boy knows our plans.
One thousand gold pieces
on each of their heads...
dead or alive.
I prefer dead.
They're firing at us!
- Champagne?
- We're in the middle of a chase, Porthos.
You're right.
Something red.
For a chase, the Cardinal recommends
his excellent '24 cabernet.
You can't have any.
You're too young.
Take the reins, boy.
Thank you.
The picnic was delicious.
The champagne was excellent.
Remind me to send
the Cardinal a note.
The Cardinal!
We have to hurry!
- You two have a date?
- No, it's the Cardinal. He's conspiring against the King.
- Tell us something we don't know.
- He sent a messenger...
with a secret treaty
to a man named Buckingham.
- The Duke of Buckingham?
- Do you know him?
He rules England the way
the Cardinal rules France.
There's a ship called the Persephone.
It's waiting in Calais...
to take the messenger to England;
it sails Tuesday midnight.
We get that treaty, we can prove
the Cardinal guilty of treason.
Calais is over
200 leagues from here.
Is the Cardinal aware of the fact
that you have this information?
Yes.
- Turn here. Here!
- Right here?
That's it.
Next time you drive.
Give me the reins.
Stop in the name
of the Cardinal!
Over there! To your left!
Stop the Musketeers!
Unhitch the horses.
This is the end of the line, gentlemen.
I hope you enjoyed the ride.
- Very much so. Thank you.
- Porthos, the brandy.
Ooh, what a waste.
- Up the hill!
- They're over there!
- Hurry!
- It's headed for the powder wagon!
Run for it!
Run! Run!
Your Eminence, the Musketeers
have been sighted on the road to Calais.
Thanks to
our winged friends...
every mercenary and bounty hunter
in France will be waiting for them.
All for one...
and more for me.
And I said, "Marquaise...
as I told you
at the Sausage Festival...
a queen is no different
from a barmaid in the dark...
though less practised
in the arts of massage. "
Right? D'Artagnan, if you're
going to be a proper Musketeer...
you will have to be schooled in the
manly art of wenching. Right, ladies?
First subject.
Very good.
Very good indeed.
Let the schooling begin.
The secret to wenching
is in the first kiss...
for in that first kiss, a lasting
impression is made. Right, ladies?
If it is... If it is weak,
she'll think you're weak.
If it is comical, she'll
think you a clown. With me?
Weak, weak.
Comical, clown.
And as a Musketeer is never weak
and only rarely a clown...
your first kiss must be
all the things that you are.
Like this.
See? You may, uh,
speak first if you like:
your name, her name,
an endearment or two.
Trust me. Words are a complete
waste of time at this sensitive point.
Only the wrong words are
a complete waste of time.
The right words can make a more lasting
impression than a thousand of Porthos' kisses.
- Not likely.
- Ah, see?
Shall I demonstrate?
As morning hues of sun-swept
fire caress your passionate face...
alone with thee a pure desire
to worship untold grace.
My soul would cry
in silent prayer...
toward hours swept apart.
Your essence warms the evening air
as I dance into your heart.
- Shakespeare.
- Aramis.
- Cheating.
- It was beautiful.
Thank you.
Very well, D'Artagnan.
Your turn.
As morning hues
of sun-swept...
- Fire.
... fire caress your poisoned face...
Bravo!
The boy's a natural!
Ooh. A lively tune.
I'm inspired to dance.
Why is Athos
sittin' by himself?
He takes his drinking
very seriously.
Not to worry. He'll be his
usual charming self by morning.
Ho-ho-ho!
A lovely time.
Athos, why don't you
come join us?
You fight like a man. Let's see
if you can drink like one.
I'll drink anything
you put in front of me.
Famous last words.
What should we drink to?
Let's drink to love.
To love. Let me tell you
a story about love, D'Artagnan.
I knew a young man once,
a Count.
Feared he would
never fall in love.
One day he met a woman.
This woman was more than beautiful.
She was intoxicating, mysterious...
everything he'd ever dreamed of.
He felt his heart would burst
if he couldn't have her.
- What happened?
- The poor idiot married her.
- Isn't that what people do when they fall in love?
- Shut up and listen to me.
They were riding through
the forest one day.
She was thrown from her horse
and knocked unconscious.
When he rushed to her side,
he noticed a mark on her body...
something he'd never seen before, something
she'd managed to keep hidden all this time.
What was it?
The brand of the fleur-de-lis...
the mark given to those who are
to be executed for murder.
Count was crushed. The woman he loved,
his bride, had betrayed him.
She'd lied to him. When
she came to, she swore...
that she'd been falsely accused of
these crimes, but he didn't believe her.
He rejected her for
her lies and for her past.
Then he banished her
from his province.
When the guards came to take her
away, to be executed, she...
She was still professing
her undying love.
Soon after, the Count realized
how much she had meant to him...
but it was too late.
His betrayal was far greater
than hers could ever have been.
He gave up his title, his land,
everything he believed in...
never to be seen
or heard from again...
all because of love.
Whoo. May I
have this dance?
How's your head,
D'Artagnan?
I'm beginning to wish
the Cardinal had chopped it off.
- Would you stop whistling, please?
- I'm not whistling.
Well, somebody's whistling.
- Barmaid's kiss left him dizzy.
- I hear it too.
- Sounds like a...
- Cannonball!
Oh, I hate cannonballs.
- The Cardinal has a long reach.
- Get out of here!
Flank left.
Fire!
- There they are!
- Kill the Musketeers!
We'll split up.
D'Artagnan rides with me.
- We'll see you in Calais.
- Or hell.
- Split up!
- We need heads for the reward.
The first time
you saw D'Artagnan...
did you need the laces
in your corset loosened?
Yes. And I felt
my cheeks flush.
- But your hands were cold.
- My knees trembled.
- But your heart was pounding?
- Yes.
But I don't understand
why I feel this way.
- We only met for a moment.
- A moment is all it may take.
Do you think so?
When my father promised me
to Louis, I was furious.
The thought of marrying
a complete stranger...
someone I'd never even seen...
I thought
I'd never be happy...
and that I'd never find love.
But then, the first time I saw
him and our eyes met, I knew.
What did you know?
What you knew in your heart
when you first saw D'Artagnan.
What if he doesn't
feel the same?
We must never give up hope.
I'll get your robe.
What are you doing here?
Forgive me, Your Majesty.
I need your help...
and could not, in good
conscience, wait another minute.
On what matter?
I'm worried about
the King's happiness.
In what way?
I'm afraid he's fallen into
a dreadful melancholy...
and wishes to postpone
his birthday celebration.
Perhaps he's concerned with more important
matters, like the coming war with England.
Which is exactly why the
celebration must be held:
to show the world
that the King of France...
can face an enemy on any field;
to show France...
who is King.
He will listen to you.
I will talk to him.
Thank you.
I have always said...
that you are as intelligent...
as you are beautiful.
I am not worthy
of such a compliment.
Oh, but you are.
It is difficult to be
a man in the service of God.
It is assumed that certain...
wants...
desires...
are void from my existence.
But after all...
I am still a man.
Your sacrifice brings you
closer to God.
Yes.
But it is not God
to whom I wish to be close.
I want you to consider...
to know all that we might
accomplish together.
For France.
I think you should leave.
Remember,
kings come and kings go...
but one thing remains the same...
and that is me.
- Do you think we lost them?
- I don't know.
I hope we're close to Calais. My horse
could use a rest, and my rear is killing me.
You're a good man, D'Artagnan...
much like your father was.
- You knew my father?
- Only by reputation.
His death was mourned
by all Musketeers.
How did he die?
He uncovered a plot
to assassinate the King.
He was led into a trap by a fellow
Musketeer and then murdered.
A Musketeer?
There they are!
Well, we didn't lose them.
I'll try and hold them off as long
as possible. You ride on without me.
I can't leave you here,
not like this.
A Musketeer's first duty
is to protect the King.
You ride on to Calais
and intercept the Cardinal's messenger.
- There's too many of them!
- Go, or I will shoot you myself!
Take these.
Don't let me down.
- I'll never forget you!
- Go!
Back.
Advance.
Yes! Now lunge.
One, two, three, four.
Now disarm.
Excellent.
Forgive me for being late,
Your Majesty.
I was wrestling with an
important affair of state.
Excuse us, please.
Your Eminence...
I've been hearing some very
troubling rumours about you.
There are so many
to choose from.
Betrayal.
Ah, yes.
That is usually the first.
Let me see if
I remember it correctly.
While the English
attack from without...
the wicked Cardinal
undermines from within...
forging a secret alliance with Buckingham
and placing himself on the throne.
But, really, Your Majesty,
why stop there?
I have heard much more
festive variations.
I make oaths with pagan gods...
seduce the Queen
in her own chamber...
teach pigs to dance
and horses to fly...
and keep the moon carefully hidden
within the folds of my robe.
- Have I forgotten anything?
- It does seem rather farfetched.
Sire, if there are any doubts
about my loyalty...
they will be laid to rest when we appear
together to celebrate your birthday.
Ah, my birthday. You know, I've
been meaning to speak to you...
The Queen has just been telling
me how eager she is to attend.
Anne is coming?
The entire nation is anxious
to celebrate the birth of its King.
It will be an event to remember.
I promise.
Whoa. Whoa.
- What is it, Henri?
- There's a body in the road, Milady.
It's a young man.
He appears to be injured.
He's handsome.
Put him inside.
With me.
Welcome back.
Did you dream?
- Where am I?
- We're in Calais.
Calais?
Tuesday! Midnight!
Where are my clothes?
Do you have a name, or shall
I make one up for you?
My name's D'Artagnan.
D'Artagnan. I like that.
I'm the Countess De Winter.
Milady.
- Countess?
- By marriage.
- But my husband's dead.
- I'm sorry.
I've learned to live with death.
Uh, Milady, I'm grateful
for all that you've done...
- but I've got...
- What?
Important business.
How mysterious.
Does it require clothes?
Yes, I need my clothes.
I'm afraid they won't be ready
for at least an hour.
Until then, you're my prisoner.
Would the prisoner care for a drink?
Well, I am thirsty.
What brings you to Calais?
I'm on a mission for the King.
- I've heard that before.
- I'm serious.
You're young.
Young men
are given to exaggeration.
However, if you'd like to
entertain me with a story...
I love a good adventure.
I came to Calais to stop a spy.
- A spy?
- Yes.
I believe you.
Aren't you afraid?
- A Musketeer isn't afraid of anything.
- I knew it.
I knew you were a Musketeer
the moment I saw you.
- You did?
- Of course.
But, D'Artagnan, if this spy
were to find out you're here...
your life
could be in grave danger.
A Musketeer
isn't afraid of danger.
I'm dangerous.
Aren't you afraid of me?
You're not dangerous.
Then what am I?
You're beautiful.
Beauty. Danger.
They are the same.
Milady, I'm sorry...
Oh, my god!
Parker!
- Kill him.
- You can kill me...
but a surprise waits for you
that even Buckingham can't prevent.
You're young and vain...
but I don't know
if you're clever.
I know how you love
a good adventure.
Take him with us.
The bodyguards are waiting
outside, Milady.
All right.
- Can I help you, Lord de Winter?
- Milady de Winter, is she here?
- Oh, no, I've not seen her.
- She murdered my brother, old man.
Let's take the back stairs.
We are the Countess de Winter's
party, arrived from Paris.
Permission to come aboard!
Permission granted!
Take us to your captain.
What are you, deaf?
Dead. They're all dead!
Not all of us.
Porthos the pirate!
- Pirate?
- I told you I was famous.
Sabine.
Athos.
Stop!
I thought you were dead.
Cardinal Richelieu
took pity on me.
You are the spy.
I've learned the value of lies.
They've kept me alive.
The treaty. Give it to me.
No.
I will shoot.
Be kind.
Aim for my heart.
Countess De Winter...
I will not be so kind.
The treaty outlines Richelieu's plan
to forge an alliance with Buckingham.
- No mention of the King?
- None.
However, the agreement is contingent upon
a demonstration of the Cardinal's power.
A demonstration?
What kind of demonstration?
I don't know.
I know someone that does.
I wish to speak
with your prisoner.
She dies in the morning.
There was a time I would have
given my life for a kind word from you.
I could not give it.
I was a fool.
Is it true what he says?
Did you kill his brother?
I have become the nightmare...
you once thought me to be.
But not before.
- Not us.
- No.
Do you know
of the Cardinal's plans?
- I do.
- Tell me.
Will you have
my life spared?
No, I cannot.
Society demands swift justice.
I'll take my secret
to the grave.
Sabine.
You will die for your crimes.
There is nothing I can do
about that now.
But how you choose to leave
this world is up to you.
What has this world
ever done for me?
"'I am the resurrection and
the life,' sayeth the Lord.
'He who believeth in me
shall never die. "'
We forgive you for your crimes.
Die in peace.
On your knees.
No!
- What is this?
- Sabine...
forgive me, please.
I do forgive you.
The Cardinal intends
to assassinate the King...
on Friday
at his birthday celebration.
God's justice be done.
Amen.
The King's life is in danger.
We have work to do.
Impressive.
And he can do that every time.
- And he has no qualms about...
- None.
He believes a man should
honour no kings before God.
A man of faith.
How reassuring.
Whatever you're paying him,
double it.
I want the King's birthday
to be a memorable event.
And, uh, rehang this painting
in my chamber...
just as it is.
It was always a little
too flattering.
Horsemen!
- Over here!
- What does it say?
Well, over there.
Search the perimeter.
I'll try to find the King.
- But wh...
- Go!
You look beautiful.
Thank you.
Is something wrong?
- Cardinal Richelieu.
- Yes?
He is an evil man.
Do not believe
every rumour you hear.
He is powerful.
I ride through the countryside every
day; I've seen the uses of his power.
Power sometimes frightens.
But here in the palace
I've seen it too.
- I know.
- What shall we do?
I'm not sure,
but we will do it together.
Get back!
- Captain, protect Their Majesties! Get them inside!
- Richelieu!
Kill those Musketeers!
They're trying to murder the King!
Save the King!
Go with God.
I like this.
I think our young friend
could use some help.
Hold this.
- It's about time!
- Come, D'Artagnan! We're saving the King!
You have failed!
Oh. You are so naive.
Things couldn't be more perfect
if I'd planned them myself.
The King of France dies at the
hands of his own personal guard!
Grief-stricken, terrified...
the huddled masses
turn for comfort...
to their devout
spiritual leader...
who...
ever so humbly...
assumes the throne...
with the Queen by his side.
- I would rather die.
- That can be arranged!
But first, your reluctant
husband will be found...
pierced through the heart
by the sword of a Musketeer...
the same sword that failed
to protect his father.
- I hope we're not interrupting.
- On the contrary.
You're right on time.
Follow me.
- Leaving so soon?
- Oh, you know. I abhor bloodshed.
- Especially your own.
- Stand aside.
You are under arrest,
charged with treason.
You, of all people, should know
that the Cardinal...
does not answer
to the laws of men.
Then you'll answer to God.
You first.
Aramis.
- This sword belongs to me.
- So it does.
Let's see if you're as brave
a man as your father was.
And as foolish.
Is he dead?
Gently. Gently.
Oh!
You see? There is a God.
We're being followed.
Do something about it.
My god.
Which one do we take?
- I've never been here before.
- Split up.
Whoa, ugly!
Whoa.
You smelly...
lump of lard!
Impressive.
Damn it!
How pathetic.
Killed by the same man
that killed his father.
You killed my father?
Oh, yes.
As I will you.
Well, well.
One thing is certain:
You are no Musketeer.
I might have been mistaken.
For you, Father.
- Where have you been?
- Taking care of something ugly.
Richelieu!
You're too late, Musketeers!
By now the Duke of Buckingham's
signature is next to mine.
The alliance is complete!
That would be difficult, considering
the treaty never left France!
A minor problem.
I will return twice as strong...
and the throne will be mine!
I think not.
You will never harm...
another soul ever again.
My promise to God.
Wait!
Well done, Your Majesty.
Are you all right?
Yes.
Arise.
Is this the man
who saved my life?
His name's D'Artagnan, Sire.
D'Artagnan, I am in your debt. What can
I do to repay the courage you've shown me?
Your Majesty, his heart
has but one desire...
and that is to become
a Musketeer.
Then approach.
Kneel.
This world is an uncertain
realm, filled with danger...
honour undermined
by the pursuit of power...
freedom sacrificed when the weak
are oppressed by the strong.
But there are those who
oppose these powerful forces...
who dedicate their lives
to truth, honour and freedom.
These men are known
as Musketeers.
Rise, D'Artagnan...
and join them.
Long live the Musketeers!
Your father would be proud
of you; you are a Musketeer.
What do we do now?
What's next?
- Well, we protect the King.
- Protect the Queen.
- In the name of God.
- And France. Correct?
- France, indeed.
- D'Artagnan!
My sister's honour will not
wait a moment longer.
- I'll handle this.
- D'Artagnan.
We also protect each other.
All for one...
and one for all!
Run!
When it's love you give
I'll be your man of good faith
When in love you live
I'll make a stand
I won't break
I'll be the rock
you can build on
Yeah
Be there when you're old
To have and to hold
When there's love inside
I swear
I'll always be strong
And there's a reason why
I'll prove to you we belong
I'll be the wall
that protects you
Yeah
From the wind and the rain
From the hurt and the pain
- Yeah
- Hey
Let's make it all for one
And all for love
Let the one you hold
be the one you want
The one you need
'Cause when it's all for one
It's one for all
When there's someone
that should know
Then just
let your feelings show
And make it all for one
And all for love
When it's love you make
I'll be the fire
in your night
Then it's love you take
I will defend
I will fight
I'll be there when you need me
Yeah
When honour's at stake
This vow I will make
Yeah
That it's all for one
And all for love
It's all for love
Let the one you hold
be the one you want
The one you need
'Cause when it's all for one
It's one for all
Yeah
When there's someone
that should know
Then just
let your feelings show
And make it all for one
And all for love
Don't lay our love to rest
'Cause we can
stand up to the test
We got everything
And more
Than we had planned
More than the rivers
That run the land
We got it all
- In our hands
- Yeah
Now it's all for one
And all for love
It's all for love
Let the one you hold
be the one you want
The one you need
'Cause when it's all for one
It's one for all
When there's someone
that you know
Then just let
your feelings show
When there's someone
that you want
that you need
Let's make it
All
All for one
And all for love