Smile, damn you.
Smile!
Shut the door.
What do you want?
I have a job for you.
What kind of job?
It's heavy work.
Digging.
We'll need another man.
- When do you want it done?
- Some night soon.
Where?
The graveyard.
Unless you're afraid.
The job pays two dollars.
Take it or leave it.
I'll take it.
But the job pays three dollars.
Unless you think
I deserve more.
No. Three dollars
seems fair enough. Yep.
¶¶
And where do you think
you're going?
Go back to sleep, sid. I'm
just runnin' away from home.
Again?
This time for sure.
Me and Joe Harper and Ben Rogers
is goin' to new Orleans...
To be steamboat men. Not
if I tell aunt Polly.
I knew you were gonna be your
annoying little self, sid.
So I rigged up
a little surprise for ya.
There.
And so you don't get lonely...
now, that right there is the most
poisonous spider in the whole world.
If you knock that glass over,
she's gonna be pretty angry.
'Course, it could just be
a little harmless fruit spider.
But, only one way
to find out, right?
Howdy, boys!
Hey, muff.
Yeah, hey, muff.
Where are you headed
this hour of the night?
We're runnin' away from home.
Uh-huh.
I used to do that all the time,
until home ran away from me.
Where'd they go?
As far away as they could.
Come on.
Don't let me stop you.
Hey, when ya comin' back?
Never!
Yep, never!
Never, huh?
See ya tomorrow.
Bye, bye, Hannibal. Good-bye!
We're gonna be steamboat men.
Left and bring her into the wind, Mr.
Harper. Aye, sir.
Steady, now, steady.
Steady it is, sir.
Next stop, new Orleans.
Nothing can stop us now.
- Hard to port! Hard to port!
- What's port?
To the left!
No, it's right!
To the right then. Just pull it, Joe.
Pull it!
Come on, Joe!
Pull!
All right. Tom, tom.
Tom! Tom!
Tom!
You all right, tom? Yeah, yeah.
Of course I'm all right.
If it hadn't been for...
Whoever it was,
you'd have been a goner.
Town? Town. Come on.
Bye, tom.
Mornin', everybody.
What's for breakfast?
Well, you can start...
With this.
Eeow.
Couldn't I just have
some scrambled eggs?
Tom, I have a notion
to skin you alive.
Sneaking out 'til all hours!
Worrying a body to death!
Yeah. Shall I get
the switch?
I swore to your mama, my own sister, on her
deathbed that I would raise you proper.
And you're doin' a fine job. No.
I know I am not doing
my duty by you.
I'll get the switch.
No!
I'll just be obliged
to make you work tomorrow.
Tomorrow? Couldn't I
just take a whippin'?
I have got to do something, and I
ain't got the heart to hit you.
Now sit.
¶ toot, toot ¶
¶¶ ¶ toot, toot ¶
¶¶
Are you feeling okay, tom?
Hi, Billy. I was havin' so much
fun, didn't even hear you comin'.
Fun? Whitewashin'
this here fence.
Nah. That ain't fun.
That's work.
Billy, if this was work,
would I be doin' it?
Ain't every day a boy gets
to whitewash a fence.
Say, tom?
Hmm?
Let me whitewash a little?
Aunt Polly's awful particular
about this fence.
Just a little.
I'd like to help you out, bill.
Honest injun.
But if you were to tackle this here fence,
and anything was to happen to it...
I'll be real careful.
What'll you give me?
Uhh...
oop! Oooh!
Huck!
You're back! Where'd you go?
Where've you been?
Well, I'm a traveler.
I go lots of places.
Go upriver, downriver.
No place particular.
I'm bound to pass through here
sometime.
You're the one who pulled
me out the other night.
I felt like a swim.
Come on.
I'll show you my place.
So how long you been
livin' here, huck?
About a month.
A month, huh?
Uh-huh.
Well?
Whoa!
Last week, aunt Polly whupped me for swipin'
a pie that was coolin' on the windowsill.
But it wasn't me.
Figured it was sid.
- He wanted it, but I beat him to it.
- I oughta punch you in the nose.
You're welcome to try.
Maybe later.
So, when you're not stealin' food
and savin' folks from drownin',
what do you do all day?
Whatever I want.
Sure are lucky.
Yep.
I'm a free man.
Go wherever I want when I wanna go there,
do whatever I want when I want to do it.
It's as simple as that.
It's good to see ya.
What's that for?
It's what friends do.
We friends?
It's up to you.
If your aunt Polly
catches you and me,
she'll whup you
from here to St. Louis.
This has nothin' to do with her. We was
friends before. Don't you remember?
Yeah, I guess we were.
Now we're friends again.
Yeah, I guess we are.
We won't do it again,
will we?
Will we? I can't hear you.
Uh-uh.
Thomas Sawyer!
Sorry I'm late for school,
Mr. dobbins.
Well, what's your excuse
this time?
I stopped to talk
with huckleberry finn.
Thomas Sawyer!
That is the most
astounding confession...
I have ever had to listen to.
Yes, sir.
You are not unaware...
That it is forbidden
to converse with that...
Idle wastrel?
No, sir.
I-I mean, yes, sir.
You know, of course, that I shall
have to punish you. Oh, no.
No, Mr. dobbins, please. You
wouldn't make me sit with the girls.
Once again, Thomas Sawyer,
you have outsmarted yourself.
Ahh, ahh, ahh, ahh, ahh.
Grade seven's green book.
"A Missouri maiden's farewell
to Alabama."
"Alabama, good-bye.
I love thee well.
"For, yes, for a while
do I leave thee now.
"Sad? Yes.
"Sad thoughts of thee
my heart doth swell...
"And burning recollections
from my brow.
"For I have wandered through...
"Thy flowery woods.
"Have roamed and read here
tallapoosa's stream.
Have listened
to Tallahassee's... "
who belongs to this peach?
Becky Thatcher,
do you belong to this peach?
You will not abandon unconsumed
food in my school. Do you hear?
Whoa!
Whew!
Hello, huck.
Hello, yourself,
and see how you like it.
Whatcha doin' here?
Lookin' for jackasses.
Under a bridge?
I found one, didn't I?
You gonna let her
do that to you?
It's 'cause she likes me.
She pushes you off a bridge 'cause
she likes you? Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
I think you're both crazy.
Hey, huck, what you got
in the sack?
A dead cat.
Wagon run over him.
Guts come out both ends.
What's a dead cat
good for?
To cure warts with.
I got one.
How's it work?
You take your dead cat to the graveyard
on the day somebody wicked's been buried.
When the devil comes, you heave
your dead cat at him and say,
"devil follow corpse.
Cat follow devil.
Warts follow cat.
I'm done with you."
That'll fetch any wart.
Sounds right.
- So when you gonna try?
- Tonight.
Let me go with ya, huck.
You might get scared.
I ain't scared of nothin'.
Dead seems kinda lively tonight,
don't they?
Baah!
Be careful!
Hmm.
- Who are they?
- The two on the right ain't so bad.
The skinny one's doc Robinson,
and the fat one's muff Potter.
Muff wouldn't hurt a fly.
That third fellow there?
That's injun Joe.
Injun Joe?
You know him?
Let's just say I met him once,
and I ain't in a hurry
to meet him again.
They're goin' for
one of them old graves.
That's it. That's it.
W-would it be all right...
If we stopped for a...
A little libation?
What?
I need me a drink.
No! Haul it up!
And hurry.
Yep! C'mon, c'mon.
Pry it open. Tip it over.
Murrell!
One-eyed murrell?
My God!
Put the coffin back.
Cover up your tracks.
Hey, not so fast. Get
your hands off me.
Gimme that box. Doc, Joe, let's
talk this over like gentle...
what'd you do that for?
That's just not right.
Is it, doc?
Come here.
Come on, now. I got ya.
It's a treasure map.
Oh!
Murrell's treasure?
Murrell's lost treasure?
By glory, we're rich!
It's mine!
Oooh!
No.
What are you doing
with that thing?
We gotta tell the sheriff.
I ain't tellin' nobody.
Unless you're dumber than I think you are,
you're gonna keep your mouth shut too.
But we seen a murder.
Yeah. And there's gonna be two more
murders if we squeak on injun Joe.
Killin' us would mean less to
him than drowning a few cats.
I guess you're right.
We can't tell nobody.
You're damn right.
Just to make sure
you don't change your mind,
we're gonna swear an oath.
We'll write it down
and sign it in blood.
Our blood?
Unless you wanna go back and
borrow some from doc Robinson.
You do it. I ain't
much good at writin'.
Damn!
I lost my marble!
We've got bigger things
to worry about.
Now, would you please
write this down?
I'm sorry.
Huck finn and tom Sawyer...
Swear they'll keep shut...
About what they seen.
May they drop down dead
if they ever tell a soul.
And rot.
Now we sign it.
"H" is for huck.
"F" for finn.
Thanks.
I'm gonna kill you, tom Sawyer.
No-o-o!
No!
Bad dream?
Ow! Mother, mother!
Tom hit me with a pillow!
C'mon! C'mon!
Right down here.
Hey, tom!
School's been called off.
Why? What for? There's
been a murder.
I didn't do it!
I swear, I didn't do it!
What happened to your face? I-I-I don't
know, but I swear I didn't do it.
Look what I found!
It's muff Potter's knife.
I sold it to him last winter. I
say lynch him. Lynch him now!
- You've gotta believe me!
- No.
- I saw the murder.
- Hang him up.
Oh. Oh, Joe.
Thank the lord.
You tell them now.
You tell them...
you tell them it ain't me.
Tell us what you know.
Yeah, I passed through here
last night.
And I saw muff and doc Robinson...
Diggin' up that there grave.
Then in a drunken rage,
I saw muff stab the doc.
String him up!
That ain't the way it happened.
I swear.
We found the map...
To murrell's treasure.
And then Joe and doc got to fightin'.
Murrell's treasure.
You hear that, people? More
drunk talk from muff Potter.
Murrell's lost treasure
is an old wives' tale.
I know the history
of this entire county,
and I'm telling you
it doesn't exist.
But I seen the map!
I say you're lyin'.
I say there ain't no map.
- And there never was.
- String him up!
Who all thinks muff Potter's
a drunk,
a liar and a murderer,
raise your hand!
I say we hang him!
All right, folks. Let's just hold on here.
Now, hold on.
Thank you.
Now, you folks wouldn't be trying
to deny me the pleasure...
Of presidin' over a trial,
now would ya?
You all right,
Mr. Potter?
After all, what would be the point
of having a new judge in town...
If you won't let me judge anything?
We all know he's guilty!
Ow! Hey! We all know you're
an idiot, ed dobbins.
Listen to me,
you pointy-headed ghouls.
Muff Potter may be
the scum of the earth,
but he deserves a fair trial,
and I aim to see he gets one.
Judge, how soon can you
get this business started?
I should be able to start hearin'
evidence day after tomorrow.
Settled. Now, the rest of you good
citizens, you be on your way.
Let the law do its job.
Come on.
Let's go, muff.
I didn't do it, tom.
I swear, I didn't do it.
¶ There's gonna be a hanging
there's gonna be a hanging ¶
you wanna drop dead and rot?
Muff's innocent, huck.
We gotta help him.
We ain't gotta do nothin'.
You'd let him hang
for somethin' he didn't do?
It ain't no skin off my back.
What if we could get the map?
We could prove muff was tellin' the truth,
and it wouldn't make us break our oath.
Only one little problem. That
map is in injun Joe's pocket.
Well, if you're scared... why should
I stick my neck out for muff Potter?
'Cause we know he didn't do it.
So?
So not doin' anything about it is wrong.
Says who?
What if it was you in muff's shoes?
It ain't.
What if it was me?
If you was that stupid,
maybe you'd deserve
what was comin' to you.
It's not what friends do, huck.
I thought we was friends.
Maybe I don't know
what you're talkin' about.
¶¶
Hello, tom.
Hey, Becky.
Sorry I pushed you
in the creek yesterday.
You can push me in
if you want to.
I would. I just don't
feel like it right now.
Thank you.
What's the matter, tom?
Oh, nothin'.
You can tell me.
I won't ever tell anybody.
Here.
This is for you.
Thanks.
You ever been engaged, Becky?
No.
How do you do it?
Well, you gotta tell the person
that you love 'im.
Then what?
Well, then you're 'spose
to kiss.
Really?
Sure.
You first. I love you. There.
Now you gotta say it to me.
Turn your face away.
And you can't tell anybody ever.
I won't.
I love you.
Well, I... Guess everything's
done but the kissin' part.
Here.
Oh, tom, it's, it's...
what is it?
It's your engagement ring.
It's beautiful.
It sure is. Why, when I was
engaged to Amy Lawrence, she...
what? You mean,
I'm not the first?
Yeah. But, Becky, that was ages ago.
Two months at least.
I hate you.
What?
I hate you, and I hope you die!
What'd I do?
Guys, that's injun Joe.
Run!
This here belong to any of you?
Hah!
Uh, anybody come to see me, sheriff?
Muff, don't be stupid.
Nobody cares about you. Nobody's
gonna miss you when you're gone.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Injun Joe's on the move.
What made you come back, huck?
I figured if you did it alone,
you'd probably splotch it up.
Yeah, probably.
You better watch your mouth.
Some kid dropped a marble
in the graveyard.
You see this here?
He's got my marble.
Agh!
Eh, probably a drunk.
It ain't muff Potter. It's so.
The only stumblin' he's gonna be
doin' is at the end of a rope.
Shut up,
Partner.
Yeah, Joe...
Come on, move!
Let's move.
Watch it. Watch it.
C'mon, hit me.
Nice little pirogue
you got there.
Come on, lefty.
All right, lefty.
Get it out.
That's it, that's it.
Double hold.
Now, c'mon.
All right, separate apart.
Go ahead.
I guess we can use muff's raft.
Yeah. I doubt he'll be
usin' it anytime soon.
We better hide the raft and
camp out 'til first light.
Huck?
Huck!
He's just drunk asleep.
Shouldn't be too hard
to get that map.
Yeah. Let's get it
and "git."
Ain't ya comin'?
One map don't need
the two of us.
I'll wait here.
Go.
Them goddamn wild boars.
Hah!
You had to sneeze.
Muff's raft must've
washed away in the storm.
I guess we'll have to take the
long way back to Hannibal.
But I'll tell ya, your ol' aunt's
gonna tar the head off of you...
If she finds out you've been
out with me all this time.
What?
It's the old haunted house. So?
Ghosts don't come out
'til night anyway.
Then what was that?
I don't know,
but it's gettin' closer.
Then what are we
standing here for?
Tom. Tom.
What was that?
They say this place is haunted.
Ahh!
With rats maybe.
Let's go to work.
According to murrell's map,
it should be
right next to the fireplace.
Hey, dig faster,
you stinkin' hog.
I'm doin' all the work.
That's a damn lie! I'm diggin'
like a chick on the beach.
Move over.
Ahh!
Quit your bellyachin' and dig.
You sure about the fireplace?
Ain't that what I said?
Well, if it's the right place,
he sure buried it deep.
- I'm halfway to China.
- Just keep diggin'.
You see?
Right here.
Fireplace!
I think I found somethin'.
Great snakes!
I gotta get outta here!
Shut up!
You screamin' coward.
That wasn't ghosts.
It was cobwebs!
Now, c'mon!
Well, no need to hit me.
God, that's heavy!
Go ahead and knock it off.
Quick.
Good lord! Look at you.
You beautiful money.
Hello, Texas and the good life.
No!
What?
We'll wait.
'Til after the trial.
I've got to testify.
Make sure muff takes the blame
for doc's murder.
- Where're we gonna keep it in the meantime?
- Number two under the cross.
Load up. I've got some things to take care
of in town. Number two under the cross.
Look who's doin'
all the darn work.
Raining like pouring pigs
on a rawhide. Well...
no more map.
No more muff.
Number two under the cross.
If you ask me, we're better
off not knowin'. Why?
Why? 'Cause we're pushin' our
luck messin' with injun Joe.
It's the best way I know of
to get killed.
Yeah. They say he's the best knife
fighter on the whole Mississippi.
No.
My pap's the best.
Taught injun Joe
everything he knows.
Your pap knew injun Joe?
They met in jail.
See, my pap was always runnin' from the law,
'cept when he was beatin' me like a rented mule.
Anyways, he taught Joe
how to throw a knife.
He taught me too.
Huck, you hear that?
Them's church bells.
Nah. It ain't Sunday. Oh.
Them's funeral bells.
You're right.
He sold it to Doug Tanner...
no, wait.
Mickey Douglas got the marble
from his cousin in St. Louis...
Who traded it to Alfred temple,
who sold it to... Johnny Miller.
No, wait.
Alfred sold it to...
Just tell me who owned it last, boy.
Tom Sawyer owned it last.
But it don't matter now
'cause now tom's dead.
That's too bad.
I'm so sad.
Yeah, that's it.
Run, fat boy.
Run!
Tom Sawyer's hat.
They found it in the wreckage
of muff Potter's boat.
The mighty Mississippi
claims another life.
And while there's some comfort
in knowing...
Tom's fate,
- he was so young, just a boy.
- Hey, that's my hat.
And a good boy.
It's me.
They think I'm dead.
Can you believe it?
Boy, this is the best trick that's ever been
played in the history of Hannibal ever.
They actually miss me.
What do you think of that?
I don't know. I ain't never been missed.
I can't believe it.
I can't believe he's gone. I wish I
could see him just one more time.
I'd tell him
I love him.
And I'd hold him close,
and I'd kiss him...
Right in front of everybody.
Hey, I'm still here. Huck!
...His spirit,
a bit mischievous.
We have to admit, there's a little
bit of tom Sawyer in all of us.
I know I speak for everyone
when I say...
I am going to miss him.
I'm beginnin'
to miss me too.
To accept this loss... how long
you gonna make your aunt suffer?
What are you talkin' about?
Look.
She does look kinda sad,
doesn't she?
Aunt Polly,
please don't cry.
You got all these people
bawling their eyes out for ya.
- Go home, tom.
- Lord, we'd give anything...
To have tom back with us
right now.
Amen.
It's tom Sawyer!
Tom! Tom!
Oh, tom!
Hello, Becky.
Becky Thatcher!
Now that you're alive again,
tom Sawyer,
you should set your mind
to being useful.
A young man doesn't want
to waste his time...
Foolin' folks and
fallin' out of church ceilings.
She is absolutely right.
Come on. We're going home.
Ow! Ow!
Aunt Polly, I just fell
15 feet onto a hard floor. Ow!
I don't say it wasn't
a fine joke, tom.
But to keep everybody suffering
while you had a good time!
Hang you, tom! Can't you
ever learn anything?
I've a mind to having you whitewashin'
the whole town for what you did.
Shall I get
some more soap, mother?
I don't know why you're smilin', sid.
You're next!
Ahh.
Huck, whatcha doin'?
I'm packing.
What for?
It's time to move on
down the river. Why?
Why? 'Cause it's what I do. I never stay
long in one place. I gotta keep movin'.
What about muff Potter? We tried.
It didn't work out.
But the trial's tomorrow,
huck. But, huck...
look! I don't leave places
'cause I want to.
I leave 'cause sooner or later they're
gonna find me and run me out.
I'm sick and tired of it, tom. I'm
gonna beat 'em to the punch this time.
I thought we was friends, huck.
You thought wrong.
I ain't got no friends.
I ain't got time for 'em.
But if I did have one,
I'd want him to be like you.
Hah!
You lose something?
It... it ain't mine.
Don't you lie to me, boy!
You know that is my marble.
Reason I didn't recognize it...
Is I lost it two, three
months ago in a graveyard.
Now...
Fetch me the knife.
I said, fetch!
Give it to me.
You'd like to stick
that thing in me, wouldn't ya?
You'd like to gut me good,
wouldn't ya, boy?
Well, here's your chance.
Go ahead.
I dare you.
You didn't kill me, boy.
Big mistake!
'Cause if you tell anybody
what you know,
I sure as hell
am gonna kill you!
Hey, muff.
Hi, tom.
How you feelin'?
Not so good.
They treatin' you okay?
It's an awful thing
that's happened, tom,
and now I gotta swing for it.
Give her a try.
Maybe not.
I'm innocent.
I didn't do it.
I swear!
I done a lot of crazy,
drunk things in my time.
But I never killed anyone. You
gotta believe me. I do, muff.
You do?
Yep, I do, muff.
How come?
Well, I know you, muff.
I mean, sure when you get drunk,
you're awful disgusting...
And you smell too.
But I know
you wouldn't hurt a fly.
Oh... muff, muff,
please don't cry. Please.
You been mighty good
to me, tom.
Better than anybody else in this
town, and I'm not gonna forget it.
I swear I'm not.
Let me shake your hand, tom.
You'll have to come through the bars.
Mine's too big.
Little hands.
But I know they'd help muff
Potter a power if'n they could.
Tom?
Tom? Tom!
Why, tom, it's not bedtime
for another hour.
Are you feeling all right?
You don't have a fever.
What's ailing you?
Aunt Polly,
what if you swore an oath...
Promising
not to tell somethin',
but the something you promised
not to tell needs tellin'?
Hmm.
I guess you can't break
the oath.
You'd drop dead and rot.
Not good.
And on top of that, someone will
cut your neck with a knife.
Not good at all!
But if you don't tell,
somethin' worse will happen...
To someone
who doesn't deserve it.
Tom, for as long as I can remember, you
have been nothing but trouble to me.
Most of the time you are
selfish and irresponsible.
But you're a good boy.
You've got a good heart.
And I believe you'll know
the right thing to do.
And you'll do it.
Just follow your heart.
Muff's a goner.
And you're sure,
beyond any shadow of a doubt,
that this is the implement...
Upon which a transaction
resulting in purchase...
Between yourself
and the accused, as vendee,
took place?
I, uh... could you repeat
the question, please?
You're sure
this is the knife...
You sold?
Sure, I'm sure!
Last winter.
Aha!
And, um, is the beneficiary...
Of the aforementioned
transaction present here today?
If you're askin' me about muff
Potter, I can tell you that he...
could you, please,
point out
the owner of this knife?
Are you blind?
He's sittin' right there.
Say the name, please.
Potter! Potter!
Muff Potter!
Everyone knows
it's muff Potter.
Muff Potter!
Thanking you.
That will be all.
Take the witness.
No questions.
So I went
on up to the cemetery.
I like to sit up there
and watch the stars.
Anyway, I saw muff drunk.
Real drunk and in a rage.
And he lifted the knife...
And he stuck it in the doc.
Over and over and over.
'Bout four times
he stuck 'im...
'Til he was dead.
Take the witness.
No questions.
Mr. aycock,
I would be obliged if you would at
least pretend to defend Mr. Potter.
Order!
There will be order
in this courtroom!
You may step down.
Thanking you,
your honor.
By the oaths...
Of honest citizens...
Whose simple word
is above suspicion,
we have fastened this crime,
this awful crime,
beyond all possibility
of question...
Upon the unhappy prisoner.
Muff Potter is guilty of the murder of Dr.
Jonas Robinson!
We rest our case... here.
- Well said.
- That's a gift.
Counsel for the defense.
Do you have a defense?
Indeed we do, your honor! Good.
The defense calls to the stand
Mr. Thomas Sawyer.
Wha...
whatcha doin'?
Thomas Sawyer, do you solemnly
swear to tell the truth,
the whole truth and nothin' but
the truth, so help you God?
I, uh...
- I, uh...
- Tom.
Do you swear to tell the truth?
- It would certainly be the first time.
- Stop it!
I do.
Then have a seat, son.
Mr. Sawyer, where were you the twenty-eighth
of this month at the hour of midnight?
I was in the graveyard...
Sir.
What were
you doing there?
Tryin' to get rid
of warts, sir.
Were you close to the grave that
muff Potter was digging up?
I... I...
I...
this is a waste of time.
Thomas Sawyer wouldn't know the truth
if it kicked him in the teeth.
The boy's an outright liar!
I was there!
I saw the murder!
Doc Robinson wasn't stabbed four times.
He was stabbed three times.
He is right! And I ain't
told that to a soul!
It wasn't muff.
Muff even tried to stop it.
But injun Joe
took muff's knife...
And stabbed the doc.
It was injun Joe.
Tom!
Stop right there!
Go get him! Let's go!
Tom. don't just stand there.
Go after him!
All right, all right.
All right. He's fine.
Tom, are you all right?
He's fine. Sit down. Sit down.
Oh, my darling!
Good job. Yes, sir.
he's a brave boy.
Hey, Joe!
Gonna do some diggin' without me?
No, Joe. I was, uh...
I was just gettin' these tools together in
case you come back. Oh, am I glad to see ya!
I don't think
you're glad to see me.
I think you was gonna go to
number two under the cross...
And get the treasure
for yourself!
I wouldn't cheat ya!
That's right.
You wouldn't cheat me 'cause you're
smart enough to know if you ever did,
I just might have to kill you.
Injun Joe's far, far away from here.
Believe me, tom.
And Mary's taking
the flowers as usual.
I'll need you and sid to carry the jam. Tom,
mind you don't eat any on the way there.
I ain't goin'.
You're not going to the picnic?
Shut your head, sid. Tom, now I
know you're scared, and rightly so.
But right now you're a glittering hero, and
the whole town'll be wantin' to see you.
It's not your place to be
worrying about that injun Joe.
I hear a detective came up from St.
Louis. They say he found a clue.
Yeah, well, you can't
hang a clue for murder.
Did you hear that?
What?
I thought I heard somethin'.
- Where?
- Maybe...
At the front door.
Well, go see, sid.
One moment, please!
Oh, tom, there's an Indian
gentleman to see you.
Tom! Wha...
tom! Sid!
Shh.
You scared?
You should be.
Huck, what are you doin'?
Remember this? Yeah.
But, huck...
according to this, you should be
dead and rottin' right about now.
I had to help muff.
Not helpin' him
would've been wrong.
I know, but...
You swore an oath, tom.
Don't that mean anything to ya?
Yeah, of course it does.
It's just...
it just felt like
the right thing to do.
Huck, it was the right
thing to do. No!
You swore an oath, tom.
You swore!
What was I supposed to do, huh?
Just lay back and let muff Potter swing?
You tell me, huck!
You know you ain't never been in
more trouble than you are right now!
- Injun Joe's gonna kill you.
- You think I don't know that?
Just don't expect me to stick around
and save your little neck this time.
I don't.
Good.
'Cause I ain't goin' to.
Then why'd ya come back?
I don't know.
To tell you to be careful.
I've been to your funeral once.
I ain't goin' again.
Huck! Hey, huck!
Muff Potter's my friend.
When a friend's in trouble,
you can't run away.
If you go to the crossroads
and you listen to the wind,
it'll tell you all the important things that are
gonna happen to ya in the next twelve months.
Now, you may be wantin' to tell,
you may be wantin' to fuss...
Hmm?
Come back here.
I'm gonna get you!
Tom, don't...
sid, now don't...
Come back here!
I'm not done with you yet!
I sow hemp seed; And he
who is to be my husband,
let him come and harrow it.
Look into the mirror, and you shall
see the form of your husband.
Come and get some pie, gals.
Come on, sid! Come here.
Got another spider for ya!
Na-na-na-na.
Hey, Becky.
Oh, no!
What? What'd I do? We're
gonna be married.
Huh? You needn't look
so disappointed.
I don't like it
any better than you do!
Every one of 'em was dead.
And every one of 'em...
Was smilin'.
Well, I run out of stories.
How 'bout we go
look at the cave?
Come on, boys and girls,
let's go look at that cave!
Everybody stay together.
No wandering off!
So he said, "me?" In a silly voice.
So I said...
hello, sir. This truly
is a wondrous place.
God's own cathedral, your honor.
Well put, Mr. Potter.
Be careful, Rebecca.
I will. You children stay
to the forechambers.
You heard the judge.
Now, listen to him.
"Be careful, Rebecca. Stay close
to the forechamber, Rebecca."
I'll go where I please.
I dare ya.
¶ Ring around the Rosie
pocketful of posies ¶
¶ ashes, ashes
we all fall down ¶¶
it's beautiful.
I've been here a million times.
Satan's cathedral.
Well, I'll find a cavern you haven't
been to, and I'll name it myself!
I'll name it myself.
- Come on, move it. Come on.
- I'm here.
Stragglers, move on. That's it.
Good-bye, muff.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's the last of 'em.
Looks like that about does it.
Here, I don't mind
if I do.
I don't mind
if you do, either.
Excuse me, judge. I was
wondering if you'd seen tom.
He was with my Rebecca. They were chasing
each other around in the back of the cave.
I'm assuming they came out
with everybody else.
What is it, sheriff?
What's wrong?
I was out makin' my rounds, and
I seen the tavern door open.
So I went on inside, and there he was
lying there deader than a mackerel.
Emmett. Big ol' knife hole
in his back.
Ain't but one man
throw a knife like that.
Look at this one. This one's beautiful too.
I'll name this one.
We call it Aladdin's palace.
Hello!
Hello?
Hello! Hello!
Hello! Hello! No.
No, Becky, stop!
Stop, Becky, stop! Don't
tell me what to do!
Tell me what to do.
Becky!
Gentlemen, my daughter Rebecca and tom
Sawyer are both lost in the caves.
And injun Joe has come back
to take his revenge on tom.
Now, be on your guard. Injun
Joe has already killed twice.
The sheriff and I believe that he
will not hesitate to kill again.
Judge? Judge.
Judge, I'd like to help ya.
All right, muff.
Let's go!
This way.
What's this cavern called, tom?
I don't know.
It's just rock.
- Judge!
- Any luck?
Over here, judge.
What is it, muff?
There's been a cave-in.
There are other ways out.
Okay? N-now...
Becky!
I, I think we're gonna be
stuck here forever.
Don't worry, Becky. I'm gonna
get you outta here. I promise.
Run, Becky, run!
Hah!
This way! This way!
Through here. Through here.
Go! Go!
Hurry, hurry!
Becky! Go, go.
- Hurry up.
- Tom!
Tom!
Becky.
I think we lost him.
It's one-eyed murrell.
He must've been hiding here
when the army came to get him.
Looks like he got lost
and slowly... died.
Come on.
Please be careful.
This way, Becky. Not so loud, tom.
He'll hear us.
Number two under the cross!
What are you talking about?
Becky, look!
Go on.
I'm right behind you.
Tom, come on.
Find your father.
Bring him back.
It's dangerous.
Hurry!
Looks like I got it all!
The treasure... and you!
Hey!
I know you.
Huck?
You're pap finn's boy.
Blueberry!
Huckleberry.
Your daddy was the best knife
fighter on the Mississippi.
Did he teach you?
He taught me.
Ah.
Then let's see what you got,
river trash.
I ain't river trash!
Come on!
You got guts, boy!
And in a minute,
they're gonna be on the ground.
Let's see you hit this!
So, why'd you come back, huck?
When a friend's in trouble,
you don't run away.
I guess
injun Joe got his treasure.
No, no, he didn't.
The chest, I couldn't lift it.
It was too heavy.
I had to dump out
all the coins.
Here comes our hero!
There he is!
Gimme your hand.
It's all right.
Come on out.
Bring 'em over here.
You're a good boy!
Three cheers. Three cheers for
the richest boys in Hannibal.
Hip, hip, hooray! Hip, hip, hooray!
Hip, hip, hooray!
Thank you, judge.
Thank you.
Young man,
what's to become of you?
Have you begun to think
about your future?
No, ma'am. I never really
much had a future.
Well, you've got one now.
And you best begin!
You are indeed our hero, tom!
You're a hero, tom.
You made the front page!
Congratulations.
So proud.
Fine boy, tom.
Mighty nice.
Hannibal's proud
of our fine young man.
Huck! Hey, huck!
Hey, who are you?
What are you doin' here?
- Huck?
- What do you think?
Well, I think one of us
has lost his mind.
The widow Douglas
is gonna adopt me.
The widow?
You're givin' all this up,
move into town?
Why not? Why not? I'll
tell you why not.
Huck finn goin' to church?
Huck finn goin' to school?
I start tomorrow mornin'.
I gotta sit down.
Huck?
Huck, say it ain't so.
I gotta get goin'.
I promised the widow I'd take
her to the church social.
Church social?
All right, that's it!
That tears it!
I ain't gonna stop ya. I'm stayin' here.
Somebody's gotta carry on.
Suit yourself, tom.
I hope things work out for ya.
Nights out here get awful cold.
Well, you know where to find me
if you change your mind.
And you know where to find me.
Huck!
Huck, wait for me!
You comin' along?
I guess I got to. Somebody's
gotta look out for ya.
Civilization can be
a pretty dangerous place.
So...
You ready to go put some gray
hairs on your aunt's head?
Whatcha got in mind?
¶¶