Gimme some slack.
Careful, boy. You could be his breakfast.
Hey, don't do that. Why not?
He's mine.
I shipped him all the way from San Francisco.
He's a family dog.
I'm going to teach him to fight.
Good fighting dog can make
a lot of money up here.
Hey, are you up here for the gold?
You got that right.
Well, It's out there just waiting
for somebody to pick it up.
These are friends of mine.
This here's Luke, Tinker.
Didn't get your name.
Jack. Jack.
What's your hurry?
You guys ever heard of a
man named Alex Larson?
Alex Larson? He's my old pal!
Practically brothers.
Why Beauty here saved Alex's life
more than once. Ain't ya, Beauty?
He'd do the same for me. Back off, buddy.
You fellas don't really
know Alex Larson, do you?
What did I tell you?
You can't fool these city boys.
Ah, we don't know him,
but we can find him.
If he's a gold man,
and who ain't up here,
he'll be on his way up
the golden staircase.
Golden staircase?
Chilkoot Pass.
About two or three miles outside of town.
You'll need some help hauling
your gear to the top though.
I said, "Back off." Hey, easy.
Sorry. We don't mean to crowd you, boy.
Good luck to you, Jack.
See you later.
Yaah! Go on now! Yaah!
Hey! Hey!
Watch where you're going.
Hey!
I've been robbed.
Welcome to the Yukon.
How high is that golden staircase?
About a mile, but it'll seem like more.
Yeah, well, I can make it up that far.
Hey, I'll sell you a map of a place
where there's plenty of gold.
Come on, kid! Move it!
Hey, do you know where I
can find Alex Larson?
Yeah. Yeah.
Over there.
Are you Alex Larson?
It depends who's asking.
I sent you a letter.
Anybody who knows me knows I can't read,
so they don't write.
Anybody who writes me,
I figure I don't know them.
Well, I'm Jack, Scott Conroy's son.
I'm looking for somebody to
take me to my father's claim.
Who's in there? Name's Dutch.
My father sent me his
maps before he died,
and he sent something else.
He sent me gold.
There was gold dust in the envelope.
If you take me out to his
claim, I'll cut you in.
What's so funny? Everybody finds
That's what keeps you digging.
But you have to strike it...
And your father didn't.
Go home and find a regular job.
You wouldn't last a day out here.
I'm a good worker.
I just want what's mine.
I'm asking you to give me a chance.
Skunker.
Yeah. What is it?
Alex, I was dreaming you, me and Dutch
was living it up in Frisco.
Get the dogs ready.
I hope Dutch appreciates this ride
'cause you should have died at the digs
and saved us a trip back.
Are you going near my father's claim?
Scott Conroy's boy.
What?
Let me see that face, kid.
Come here.
My God, Alex.
He's the spitting image of his old man.
And I knew your pa well. Clarence Turson.
Jack Conroy.
You throwing in with us?
Yeah, I'd like to.
No. No?
No?
You're taking him with you and
you are not going to take me?
He looks half-dead already.
Hey!
I'm... No offense.
Give me a stick of that
gum, and I'll forgive you.
It's hard to get it up here, and it makes
my breath smell real fresh.
Yeah. Hey, don't
He's just tired. That's all.
He already knows there's gold there,
and he wants it for himself.
Whoa, boy. You got the
hunters on the wrong dog.
Listen, if you don't want to
take me, then I'll go by myself.
I'll get rich by myself, too.
I think he's crazy enough to do it, Alex,
and you know he doesn't stand a chance.
Come on, Alex.
He's Scott's boy. Look at him, huh.
How much trouble could he be?
All right.
I'll take you as far as Klondike.
Fall behind, and I'll
leave you where you drop.
Understand? Yes, sir.
You're going to regret this.
Nah, Alex.
Ho, Digger! Come on, boy!
That a boy, Digger, pull!
Ho! Mush! Come on, boys!
Come on boys! Good boys! Good!
Whoa!
Alex, I got a loose harness on Blue.
Okay, mush! Come on, Trix!
That a boy!
Mush!
Pull, Digger! Come on, boy!
That a boy, Digger! Pull!
Mush! Mush! Come on, boys!
Whoa!
Are you all right, kid? I saw something.
In the woods.
Wolves. They've been trailing
us for a couple of hours now.
Game's scarce. They must be starving.
Think they are after us?
The dogs.
Wolves won't jump a man,
unless hunger's got them totally crazed.
Let's get going.
Wolves be the devil on earth.
Kid, give me a piece of that gum
again, will you? It calms me.
I'll carry it for you, okay?
Come on! Mush, Digger!
Mush! Come on, boys! Pull!
Mush! Let's go!
All right!
Mush! Come on, pull, buddy!
Quit playing around!
Mmm-hmm.
You put that top a little
close to the fire, don't you?
I don't want to freeze to death.
What's he doing? Cleaning his teeth.
How'd they get dirty?
Oh, gee!
Watch it.
Whoops!
Yeah, I know it's a little fishy,
but you can put your head the other end.
Told you, too close
Nice weather.
What are you doing?
The only things my dogs
drag are things we need.
That's my property.
You want them?
You carry them. Hold
it, hold it, hold it!
I'm going to feed the dogs, fellows.
You're not going to kill each
other while I'm gone, are you?
We'll wait till you come back.
Oh, boy, here comes the fishies.
They smell good, too.
You guys know who loves you.
Here you go. Here's one for you.
And here's some fish for you, Betty.
Ow. Don't bite the hand that feeds you.
Seven pieces of fish for seven dogs,
and you didn't get any.
What are you mumbling about?
Seven fish for seven dogs.
Digger didn't get fed.
I swear there was a
wolf in with the dogs,
and I fed the damn thing!
Well, how would a wolf
get in with the dogs?
He's dreaming again.
Relax.
Fire's going.
They will keep their distance.
Alex, did I ever tell you
my uncle was a wolfer
down in Montana?
When I was little, he used
to lower me in the hole
and have me shoot the cub
puppies for the bounty.
I hated doing that.
Get some sleep, Skunker.
Whoa! Whoa.
- We gonna go around?
- Yeah, the dogs
Just go slowly and stay to the left.
Help me balance this. Come here.
Let's keep it
Oh! Oh! Oh! Hey, easy! Oh!
Ohh! Ah!
My books!
Damn it, kid. Forget the books!
Look out!
Aah!
Hang on, kid. I got you.
Hold on there. Now stand up.
Dig your feet in.
Just stand up. Get your feet up!
Come on!
Got to, uh, get the rope untangled!
Stay!
Come on, Jack! You can do it, kid!
Reach up there!
Get clear! Get clear of the sled, Jack!
Ow!
Aah!
Whoa!
Jack, stay right there!
Don't move on that ice!
Don't move!
Jack!
I'll get the ammo!
Come here!
- Help me!
- Help!
Told you not to move!
Help!
Hold on! Hold on! Help me!
All right! Here's the rope!
Come on, kid! That a boy!
Just get your clothes off.
That's it! Keep moving! Take it easy!
That a boy!
Get this off and I'll get the blanket.
He's turning blue.
That'll get you warm! Put it on!
Get the fire going before
he freezes to death!
Hurry up! Take your shirt off!
Help me!
It's gonna be too wet.
Come on! Keep moving! That's it!
Books.
Keep moving! That's it!
That's it! Come on!
Now we're cookin'!
It's going. Come on, get
him over here, Alex!
Sit down there, boy!
Put your hands under your arms!
Keep your fingers moving!
Now, let's get the rest
of these wet clothes off!
That's starting to feel good, huh?
I'm sorry, Alex. I was
trying to get the ammo,
and I... Stop talking and drink this.
Drink it. Pine needle tea.
Tastes like hell,
but it keeps the heart pumping.
I'll get Dutch.
- What's left?
- Three cartridges.
Damn! It's like being naked out here.
"He's Scott's boy." "How
much trouble could he be?"
We've got company.
Shield the firelight from your eye.
Look hard.
Let's get the dogs safe.
George, Digger...
- Betty...
- Settle down.
Get down in there.
Look!
It's a female, Alex!
That bitch is part dog!
That's why she's afraid of the fire.
She's a decoy. She draws the dogs out
so the pack can eat them.
Digger! Come back here!
- Digger!
Darn! Come back!
Digger, come back here or I'll whup you!
Digger! Come back here!
Digger!
Digger, come here!
Damn you, don't be fooled.
Get over here!
Digger! Come back!
Digger!
Hey! Are you crazy?
Skunker! Skunker! Come back!
Digger, get out of the way!
Don't waste the bullets!
My God.
Digger!
Digger, get back here! Skunker...
- Skunker!
- Digger!
They're right behind you.
Come back here. Skunker!
He's gone.
Nothing we can do.
Sorry, Skunker.
We didn't have a chance to say goodbye.
Go to sleep.
Help me. Come on.
Let's pack up.
Hey! You all right?
Yes! But how did you find us?
Followed the smoke from your fire.
Thank God.
You saved our lives.
What chance would a wolf cub have
of surviving on his own out here?
None, without the pack.
Come on. Come on
Whoa.
Is there any good reason why
we can't just bury him here?
I don't think he'll know the difference.
I gave him my word.
Okay.
Look, the white fang.
This wolf is part dog.
You know, I'm glad Dutch is dead
because I'm ready to kill him.
Whoa! Whoa!
Look, you old weasel!
Look at that!
You're home!
You're home now! Home!
Okay! Okay! Come on!
Let's move out.
The Klondike is still
a good two days away.
You going to say anything?
You know what? What?
I never really liked the bastard.
Come! Come! Come here. (GREY BEAVER
Come here. Good, good.
Over here. Over here.
Looks like he's going to
be a good working dog.
Over here. Come on.
Come on. Okay, Harry.
Hi, Joe. Hi, Alex.
Take good care of him.
Sure will. Okay.
What are you going to do for money?
Well, I got 50 bucks in my boot.
You'll be all right.
You can get a dry bed and breakfast
at the edge of town.
Tell Dave I sent you.
He'll give you a good rate.
Okay. Uh, where are you going?
To see a friend.
Okay. Listen.
Get yourself a partner.
Yeah. You're right.
Don't go off on your own.
Hey, don't worry about me.
Good luck.
Uh, thanks.
Keep your
Heather, sit on my lap
here and give me a kiss.
Shut up, Clyde. I'm working.
In pants? Why don't you put
on a pretty dress for us?
'Cause I couldn't do this.
Whoa!
Don't you love me anymore, Heather?
I can't tell you how
beautiful you really are.
I'll get the bags.
Oh.
Who's that? He's Scott Conroy's son.
I brought him up here.
Remarkable.
He looks like Scott. Mmm-hmm.
Belinda Casey. Jack Conroy.
How are you? Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
Do you work here?
I own the place.
Oh. Right.
Would you like a drink?
Yeah. I'd love one.
Shouldn't you be at Bradford's?
Yeah. Uh...
Uh, pleasure meeting you.
Uh, bye, Alex.
Bye.
All right.
There you go. Three more!
Comin' through!
Miss Casey!
Oh, Jack! Hi. Hi.
How are you? Can I carry that for you?
Yes, you certainly can.
Got it? Yeah.
So how'd you make out? Did
you find someplace to stay?
Yeah, I did. Uh, huh.
Do you know anybody else here?
Uh, just you and Alex. Uh-huh.
Well, would you like
to join us for dinner?
Yeah. I'd love to.
Good. Come by in an hour. Okay.
You heard they made Alcatraz
into a prison? Didn't you?
No. When I lived there, it was
used for immigration, I think.
Not anymore. Now they've got
federal prisoners there,
you know, soldiers that
deserted during the war,
and some of the Indians from Arizona.
Indians? Oh, that's horrible.
I'll get some dessert.
Would you like some coffee?
No, thank you.
Get out of here. Now.
Take me where I want to go.
No.
Then I'm staying.
I'll think about it,
if you get out of here in two seconds.
You're not leaving? Yes, ma'am.
It was delicious. Um...
Could I borrow that book?
I promise I'll return it.
Good night, Alex.
Good night.
You know, I think he really likes you.
And how about you, my dear Belinda?
You're crazy!
The lines are wrong.
What makes you the expert?
Experience.
It'll be hard for us to control.
Does that mean we're partners?
It means that I'll take you
to your father's mine.
That's all it means.
I'll miss you. I'll miss you, too.
Next year, we'll have that
hotel in San Francisco.
Come on, Alex. Kiss her. I won't look.
This time, you'll see.
- See ya!
- Bye!
Belinda!
Feed the ducks.
Oh, you are a romantic, aren't you?
- Who are they, Alex?
- They are Hand Indians.
I know the chief of this tribe.
We'll stop here for the night.
We've come to see Grey Beaver.
Good to see you, my friend.
And you. It's been a long time.
Jack, this is Grey Beaver.
The boat is taking water.
We have to re-tar it.
Fine.
What's his name?
Mitah.
What does that mean?
White Fang.
Hi, Mitah.
Can I pet you?
No. I just wanted to pet him.
Dogs are for work.
Maybe they'd work a little harder
if you were a little more friendly.
We make fire. Kill with sticks.
Cause soul to fly.
We are their gods,
that is why they obey.
Not because we're friends.
Mitah.
You boys want a stick of gum?
Well, here you go.
Thank you very much for dinner.
It was very good.
I can't sleep when it doesn't get dark.
You'll get used to it.
They'll never let you forget.
Listen, it's not food.
You're supposed to chew it,
not swallow it, all right?
Fetch, Mako. Fetch, Mako.
I won't forget you.
Thank you so much.
You're here.
Your father wanted to
be buried on the claim.
When I was younger, I used
to think he was a hero.
My mother would tell me all these stories
about where he was and what he was doing.
I never knew what was true.
He said he wanted to
give us a better life.
All we wanted was for him to stay.
What took you so long getting up here?
It's been a year.
My mother got sick.
She pulled through?
No.
Sorry.
I know you want to keep moving,
but I've got to try it here,
settle in here.
The gold is further north.
Why don't you try it here, Alex?
There must be gold here. I
know, I know we can find it.
It's not a bad spot.
I'll get you started.
Holy biscuits!
Look at that dog.
That ain't no dog, you idiot.
That's a wolf.
Come on, let's go.
Take him down there.
Let's see what happens.
All right. Come on!
Oh!
Go get him!
Go on!
Yeah.
Damn, I want that animal.
Get Buck out of there.
Buck.
Buck, easy, boy.
Easy, Buck.
Get back!
Sorry. I'm overstocked as it is.
Down, boy. Sit! Sit! Easy.
Mitah. No.
Is he yours?
Look what your wolf done to my dog here.
Who's gonna pay for the damages?
You know it's illegal to bring
wolves into town, don't ya?
Luke. Go find us a mountie.
He'll straighten this out.
Wait.
Here.
Not interested in furs, chief,
but I'll take that wolf off your hands.
No. It's not for sale.
That's too damn bad.
'Cause now you're gonna
spend some time in jail.
Go find him, Luke.
No!
How much?
You know something, chief?
You're shrewd.
Come on.
This wolf's gonna make us a lot of money.
Get in there.
Looks like he's taken to the place.
Come on. I'll buy you a drink.
Huh?
I don't believe it.
Hey, wolf!
Hey, wolf.
Watch those teeth.
Go!
My hands hurt.
My head hurts. My feet hurt.
Let's get some dynamite
and blow the whole damn mountain up.
Huh? What do you say?
That would be too easy.
What's the story in that one?
Well, it's about this man who...
He builds a machine. It
takes him into the future.
I can teach you to read.
You teach me to read,
I'll make you a miner.
Deal.
All right, wolf. Let's see what you got.
Come on, wolf! Yeah! Yeah! Come on!
Come on!
Come on, wolf! Hold him!
Come on, wolf. Come on. Come on!
Let's see what you got! Come on!
Come on! Come on! Come on!
Whoa!
Come on, boy! There you go.
Oh, that's it. That's it. Come on!
Yeah! Yeah!
Oh.
I think he's ready.
Wolf, don't you let me down. Get mad.
Come on. Get mad. Get
in there and kill him.
You understand? Come on!
Come on!
Let's get him!
I'll give you a 20.
Here's five, Frank.
Gentlemen. On three.
One,
two,
three!
Kill him!
Tear him up, wolf! Tear him up.
Come on, wolf, tear him up!
Get in there! Get in there, wolf!
Yeah! Yeah!
Yes!
Come on. Come on.
Come on, wolf. You did good.
It's a pleasure taking your money, Sykes.
I'll be back, Smith.
Next time, bring a live dog.
Okay, wolf. Come on.
I want you to get mad and
get in there and win.
You understand me?
Understand? Whoa.
All right, on three.
One, two, three!
Come on! Go in! Go in! Yeah!
Yes.
One, two, three!
Come on. Come on!
Get him.
Easy, boy.
You done good tonight.
I brought you something extra.
Now, take it easy. Here you go.
All right, you just keep
on hating me, wolf.
"It took days for the boys
"to reach the secluded hideaway.
"No one had set foot into the housey..."
House. House. Not housey. House.
House.
House. House.
"For years.
"When the door was finally opened and..."
F... F... F...
Foul? Like the birds?
No, no.
Fowl like the birds is F-O-W-L.
This is F-O-U-L.
Foul like a bad smell, like rotten...
Like your socks smell foul.
I washed them.
Yeah, well, use some soap, would you?
If you'd spend as much time
digging as you do washing...
I do more than my share around here.
That's a laugh.
Who do you think does all the cooking?
You do, you definitely do.
And with the way you cook,
I'm lucky to still be alive.
Then do your own damn cooking!
I'm not your wife.
Yeah, that's for sure.
You're too damn ugly.
That's U-G-L-Y.
Maybe we ought to head
into town tomorrow.
We need supplies anyway.
That's a good idea.
Unbeatable!
Get away from that cage!
Get him away, Tinker!
Get back.
Mr. Sykes.
Step aside, gentlemen.
What have you brought for us today?
Where's the rest of him?
That's a bulldog. He's pretty.
They're killers, you moron.
Look at them jaws.
Shut up.
That's Cherokee. I've seen him fight.
Your dog's unbeatable, right?
I've got 5,000 that says
he won't be after today.
What's the matter, Smith?
Too rich for your blood?
Let's do it.
Gentlemen, on three.
One, two, three.
Get him, wolf!
Cherokee!
Come on!
Oh!
Oh, damn.
Flip him over!
Come on, wolf. Get up! Get up!
Come on, kill him!
Get up!
Hey, that's White Fang.
Stay out of it.
It's over.
Not yet, it ain't.
Come on, wolf! Get up and fight!
Somebody give me a hand here.
Get this dog off him!
Let go of him.
Don't break those teeth!
Let go, dog.
Mounties! Mounties!
Hey, kid! Hey!
Kid, that's my wolf!
Yeah, he was.
I paid for him when you robbed
me in Skagway. Remember me?
Oh, yeah.
You stay.
Hey, you two. Keep an eye out for me.
This ain't finished yet.
He's lost a lot of blood.
At least he won't have to fight anymore.
Good night, Jack.
I remember the good old days
when dogs used to pull men.
He needs to be in the cabin
so I can take care of him.
I'm not sleeping in the
same room with a wolf.
You're wasting your time.
He was tame once. You saw him.
He was.
He's not anymore.
Don't give up on me, you hear?
Congratulations.
You've got a healthy wolf on your hands.
Now get him outside.
I can't do that by myself.
Hold out a piece of meat.
All right.
I'll unhook him.
Look at him watching my hand.
They beat him bad.
There's no taming him now.
He was taught to hate.
All he needs is a little bit of kindness.
Try it without the wood.
You try it without the wood.
Easy. Easy.
Okay.
All right.
Are you crazy?
No. I know what I'm doing.
I hope.
Just gonna untangle this.
Here we go.
Turn him loose.
He belongs in the woods.
Okay, Fang.
I know you don't want to hurt me.
But you're right. I
shouldn't have done that.
I shouldn't have tried to force you.
I don't know what they did to you,
but everybody's not like that. I'm not.
It's gonna be all right.
So you come on out when you're ready.
You forgot something.
Just wait.
Now what?
You hungry, boy?
Yeah, of course you're hungry.
You're always hungry.
Where you going?
Looks pretty good, huh?
Hey, White Fang. Hey.
See, that was pretty good, huh?
Hey, hey.
Not so bad, huh?
Want a little more maybe?
Hey, hey. Come on, boy.
It's okay.
I'm a pretty nice guy.
Maybe a little more?
Hey.
Come on. Hey.
White Fang, hey, look at this.
Want a little more maybe?
Hey, hey. Come on, boy.
It's okay.
Yeah, not so bad. Not so bad.
Don't tell me you're not hungry.
Here you go. Here you go. Here you go.
Moving slow.
Huh? Huh? Huh?
I'm sorry.
Huh? Little more?
Here you go.
I'm not going to hurt you.
That's not so bad.
That's all right. That's all right.
You're gonna be okay.
Hey, hey, hey. Huh?
That fool.
Watch out!
Put the rifle down. Put it down.
He won't hurt me.
See?
Scared the hell out of me.
I told you he was intelligent.
Let's go! Come on!
Come on! Oh! Ho! Ho!
Up!
Come on. Get it.
All right. Come on!
Hey, hey. Whoa! Get back here.
I'm gonna go back in
and get one more load.
Don't. It's late.
Come on, boy.
Jack!
Help.
Jack.
Alex, help!
Jack! Help!
Help! Alex!
Hey, buddy.
Are you all right?
The sky never looked so blue.
No, it can't be.
What?
Holy mackerel!
We're rich. Aren't we?
It's just like we dreamed of.
It's gold, all right.
If the quality is bad,
it won't be worth much.
No sense getting crazy just yet.
You're sure you don't want
to take him with you?
No, there'll be too many people.
Okay. Bye-bye.
Listen, don't get caught
up in anything there.
Just get in,
get it tested, and get back here.
Soon as I can.
What are you gonna do without me?
I'll yell at the wolf.
I guess he's coming with me.
I'll pick up a new window.
How you doing?
I'd like to have this tested.
I'm on claim number seven
right below Discovery on New Creek.
Now I assume you want to
deposit this with our bank?
Yes.
What is it, huh?
I hope he's been fed.
Here it is.
Fee and deposit paid for by Scott Conroy
in his name and his son's.
You Jack Conroy? Yeah, that's me.
I'd also like you to add
Alexander Larson's name.
It's your gold.
Oh, he's completely recovered.
All right, we got to get going.
You just got here, Jack.
Well, we've got some things to do.
Don't forget what you came for.
Oh, right. Come on, White Fang.
Take care, Jack, and be careful.
I will. Bye-bye.
Come on.
What did they say?
Who?
The assayer. Who else?
What's wrong with you?
Well, read for yourself.
"The
"quality of gold
"found at the claim of Jack
Conroy and Alexander..."
"Larson, tested and
weighed by the assayer
"at Klondike City on the
11th day of August 1898
"is found to be 98% pure." We're rich.
We are rich!
"Very rich," that's what the guy says.
The guy says, "Very rich."
He says we are filthy, stinking rich.
Whoo!
While you were gone,
I did some thinking.
I'd like you to come back
with us to San Francisco.
Be part owner of our hotel.
So what do you think?
I think it sounds like a good idea.
I'll name it after your father,
Royal Scott Hotel.
To your father.
Good friend.
Dream on, boys.
There's something on the roof.
You must have been followed.
I was careful, Alex. I did what you...
White Fang, get under here.
Come on.
They stuffed the pipe.
Stay down!
Put this over your head.
It will help you breathe.
They can't stay in there much longer.
Hold your fire until they come out.
Maybe they're dead.
That's Comin' 'Round the
Mountain, ain't it?
I hate that song.
That will keep them guessing.
They ain't taking the hint.
Let's move in.
Get in there, Tinker.
Well, earn your keep.
Aah!
Hey, get him off me!
Get him off of me.
Hey!
Easy, easy, easy.
Easy, easy.
Hey, look at this now.
Hey, fellas, look at this now.
Hey, go get us some mounties, would you?
Yes, sir!
Come on, everybody. Free drinks.
Come on in.
Free drinks?
I'm right behind you.
Free drinks on Alex Larson.
Don't ask me twice!
Come on, here we go.
Don't shove, now!
Get another keg of beer!
If we are going to catch
that boat in Skagway,
we've got to leave soon.
You know you can't take him with you.
He'll be miserable in the city.
He has to run free.
That's his magic.
He thinks you are a wolf.
You take care of yourself, all right?
Go on. You're free. Go on.
Go on. Get out of here!
Listen to me. Go, go! Go!
Go!
Go on! Go!
Listen to me. Go!
Get out of here! Go!
Go on!
Get out of here!
Oh, here he is, Alex.
Where's the wolf?
I let him go.
Bye, Heather.
Don't let them get away with anything.
I won't. Bye.
I can't believe this
is actually happening.
Alex, I got to tell you something.
I can't leave.
Not yet.
I'm gonna go back to the claim.
Miss Casey.
So long.
Your father would be proud of you.
I'll keep an eye on your gold for you.
You better. And leave a room open for me.
I have to.
You're part owner.
White Fang.
Come on.