The reason for calling
this conference at this moment
is that we are convinced
that we have overcome
the major financial crisis,
a crisis in severity
unparalleled in world history,
and that, with its relaxation,
confidence and hope have reappeared.
Happy days are here again
The skies above are clear again
All anybody talked about
was the Great Depression,
how bad things were and how
the good times were around the corner.
I must've worn out every corner
looking for those good times,
before realising
my destiny lay somewhere else.
Anywhere else.
Happy days are here again
Your cares and troubles are gone
There'll be no more from now on
Happy days are here again
The skies above are clear again
Let us sing a song of cheer again
Happy days are here again
Ready, Sonora?
You don't want to be late for school.
Be right there.
- Where's your sister?
- She's coming, Aunt Helen.
Sonora, quit lolly-gagging!
Sonora, what are you doing?
What have you done?
What am I gonna do with you?
No, Aunt Helen, don't, please!
You'll wear it and that's final.
No more back talk!
Get out!
I don't even want to look at you!
Come here, Lightning, what's wrong?
Whoa, easy.
Hold still, let me get...
There. There you go.
That's better, huh, boy?
Isn't that sweet?
Nice haircut, Sonora.
Who cut it?
A blind man with a butcher knife?
- The ugliest haircut I've ever seen.
- Ugly? She should look in a mirror.
- Come on, Lightning.
- Where to? The glue factory?
- He's the best horse in the county.
- Yeah, sure!
He is. Lightning can out-jump
any horse around.
Can he jump that fence over there?
- He can jump twice that high.
- Prove it.
- I don't want to be late for school.
- Chicken!
You're just scared. Go on, do it.
I dare you.
I double-dare you.
OK. You just watch.
I think my big mouth
just got us into trouble.
Come on, Lightning. Come on.
- She's gonna do it!
- Go on, Lightning.
Come on.
Let's get out of here!
Wait! Get back!
Help!
The noun of the sentence is 'boy'.
The verb of the sentence is...
- You're late, Sonora.
- I'm very sorry, Miss Simpson.
- You're getting detention for this.
- But it's not my fault. The cows...
I don't want to hear any excuses.
Take your seat.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Moo...
Class! Class, quiet! Quiet!
Clarabelle... Oh, my God.
Sonora, leave this room immediately.
Young lady, remove yourself.
You must leave!
Sonora Webster is officially
suspended from school for one week.
I'm informing your aunt.
No one talks to her.
She's not here!
Two red ones and... a green one.
No, ma'am, please, right here.
Sonora, tell your aunt that her blue
thread will be here in a few days.
- OK, I will.
- There you go, Arnette.
I'm going over to see Sarah.
I'll see you at the house.
"Young girl...
"...diving horses.
"Willing to travel."
Thank you, ma'am.
- You ready?
- Let's go!
What are you doing with Lightning?
- I sold him.
- No, you can't!
- Why? I didn't do anything wrong!
- You let the cows out this morning.
- That was an accident!
- And got suspended from school.
Ever since your mom and dad died,
you've been nothing but trouble.
Let me go!
Sonora? What are you doing?
Nothing.
I took you and Arnette in
because you're my sister's children.
But ever since you came here,
you've been nothing but a burden.
There's a depression going on,
there's extra mouths to feed...
So I've decided
I'm gonna turn you over to the state.
The state?
They'll feed you and take care of you
until you come of age.
You're just gonna kick us out?
No, Arnette'll stay here with me.
It's just gonna be you.
You're going tomorrow, you hear?
Yes, ma'am.
Come on, now... help me with supper.
Get off of there!
Everything you got!
Yes, sir!
- Fight! Fight!
- There's a fight over here!
They caught him cheating.
I thought this was a friendly game.
You're hiding an ace in your hat,
and we're gonna find it.
You better say your prayers.
Looks like I was wrong. Let him go.
I apologise.
You crumpled my hat.
But that's OK, I like it like this.
I'll see you, fellas.
- Got cold soda.
- Let me have one.
Balloons on a stick! Right here!
A nickel a piece, any colour!
Son of a monkey turned fire...
Damn!
Let me help.
- Never had a girl spit on me before.
- It'll take the sting right out.
Selling hot dogs can be
a dangerous job.
This? This isn't my job.
It's temporary until I get my act going.
- What kind of act?
- I'm still experimenting.
But it will be death-defying.
It will definitely defy death.
- There you go. Feel better?
- Uh-huh.
- It's a funny way of cooking hot dogs.
- It's my own invention. Want one?
- I don't have any money.
- It's on the house for fixing my finger.
I'm Clifford Henderson.
Sonora Webster.
Good to meet you.
- Where can I find a Dr W F Carver?
- Through there, across the fairgrounds.
Thank you.
- Thanks for the hot dog. Take care.
- Thanks for...
...spitting on me.
- That's the last thing I wanna do.
- I got a show to run!
- I missed a couple.
- You missed three!
- Is chasing women more important?
- No, but it's a lot more fun. Have that.
Get outta here, son. Load the truck.
Dr Carver?
This is your lucky day.
You don't need this any more.
I'm here to answer your ad.
- Who are you?
- Your new diving girl!
- No, you're not.
- Why not?
- One thing, I don't like you.
- You don't know me.
Secondly, you're interrupting my
business, and thirdly, you're too puny.
I don't know what a diving girl
does exactly, but I can do it.
- 'Cause I can do anything!
- Good! Then you can get outta here.
I am a very busy man.
I do not have time to play
with children. Now, get off that chair.
Give me a chance.
I only want a chance.
Let me explain.
A diving girl has to be strong.
A diving girl has to be brave, fearless.
A showman!
Now, there is a diving girl!
You gotta have more...
You gotta have more
than what you got.
Well, I'll get it.
What's your name?
Sonora Webster.
Let me tell you something.
You go out there, cross the fairgrounds,
turn left at the gate, and keep walking
until you get to the bus station.
I'm not gonna leave
until you give me a job.
Have a good trip!
Al?
- Dr Carver sent me to see you.
- He did?
Yeah. We just talked, and he thinks
I'd make a perfect diving girl.
- That's what he said?
- Uh-huh.
- He said you'd explain the show to me.
- Sure. Come on.
The show's real exciting.
And that's the tower.
OK. Fine. Thank you very much.
You dropped this.
So, now I'm a babysitter!
- You're not afraid of heights, are you?
- Me? No.
- How do the horses jump?
- We train them.
- Don't they get scared?
- If they do, we don't let them near.
- You push them off?
- No, they jump on their own.
We don't use any devices.
- Do the horses ever get hurt?
- No. Just the riders.
It's rough.
You travel around, barely getting by.
The old man, he's tough.
He'll push you till you break.
Go back to where you came from.
You don't want to be a diving girl.
I've a glorious idea for a new poster.
A falling shot of me.
And, in the corner in an oval frame,
a picture of my face, smiling.
- I'll think about it, Marie.
- It'll sell lots of tickets.
Maybe Movietone will come,
take a moving picture?
- I'll think about it, Marie.
- Hi.
- We're not buying pencils today.
- Miss your bus?
- I won't leave till you give me a job.
- She wants to be a diving girl.
That's a wonderful idea!
She could bring glamour to the act.
- What are you doing?
- This way, he gets used to my smell.
That's right.
Indians used to do that on the plains.
Really? I thought I just made that up.
- Can you handle a wheelbarrow?
- I was born handling a wheelbarrow!
- Can you shovel manure?
- Manure's my speciality.
I believe that.
Are your family looking for you?
- No.
- I'll not give you a job as a diving girl.
But we're leaving for Virginia
and I could use a stable-hand.
- You interested?
- Yeah!
- Let's go to Virginia.
- All right.
Virginia! I couldn't believe my luck.
I'd never been to another state before.
I was really seeing the world now.
Even if my view was more of where
we'd been, I wasn't gonna complain.
I finally had a real job, helping
with the horses in the off-season.
And I was staying in the most
beautiful house I'd ever seen.
Things were definitely looking up.
From here on,
my life was gonna be just swell.
You wouldn't mind giving me a hand,
would you?
Get them horses ready.
Hurry up! We've a lot of work to do!
Lord knows what shape the barn's in.
It's OK. I got everything under control.
Sonora! Come get this horse, please!
Wash him down and make sure he's dry.
Can you manage that?
Hi, Al! How're you doing?
- Red Lips, easy! Whoa!
- Hold him. Hold the horse!
Come here with this horse.
Get him in the stable.
You can't handle the animal,
don't go near him.
- Nice horse, huh?
- It's spooked. Where'd you get him?
I won him in a poker game.
Full house, queens over threes.
- Looks loco to me.
- He needs a little training.
Do what you want,
just keep him from hurting people.
Come on, just one little bite.
Come on.
I should know the horses
if I'm to be a diving girl.
- You think you can do it?
- If Dr Carver gives me a chance.
He's not gonna give you a chance,
unless...
if you rode up on this horse he might.
We could train him.
- What are we waiting for?
- Not now. First thing in the morning.
- All right.
- The old man can't know.
- It'll be our secret.
- OK.
Al, get up!
Come on, wake up.
We're supposed to start training.
Oh, right...
Easy, boy, easy.
- Easy, boy, whoa. Whoa.
- Attaboy.
- Whoa. What's this horse's name?
- I don't know.
- It's gotta have a name.
- All right. How about Clarence?
- That's no name for a horse.
- If you're so smart, you pick one.
Lightning.
Stay behind.
Keep your whip on the ground.
Come on, go, go, go!
Let him see the whip.
Come on!
Easy, boy. Here, you take him.
- What's your secret wish?
- My secret wish?
- What did you always want to be?
- Well...
I wanted to be a showman
like my dad. Not any more.
What do you want to be now?
Anything but like him.
What's your secret wish?
To get to Atlantic City,
where all your dreams come true.
- You believe that?
- With all my heart.
It says so right here.
See?
It's the greatest show place in America.
And someday, I'm gonna be there.
- What happened to your parents?
- Died. They got the fever.
- Where's your mom?
- She's gone.
- Where?
- I don't know. She left a long time ago.
She left because of my dad.
- Now, just sit there. Don't rush it.
- You worry too much.
- Are you hurt?
- No, I'm fine.
He's got ticklish flanks.
Never use your heels.
I figured that out
as I was flying through the air.
He's doing good, though.
So are you.
Come on, we got a lot of work to do
before the old man wakes up.
Nice and easy.
OK?
Good boy.
- You like the movies?
- Like them? I'll be in them some day.
- How are you gonna do that?
- Be discovered, of course.
Diving horses is great exposure.
You're pretty enough
to be in the movies.
- You sure look nice tonight.
- Thank you.
Al's taking me dancing
at the Silver Palm.
- Dancing?
- Oh, yes. Al's a terrific dancer.
- Smooth as hot honey.
- That's nice.
You poor thing.
- Who does your hair?
- I do.
You should take care
with your appearance.
Having no natural beauty of your own,
you really need to help yourself.
Have a good night.
- Don't tell me how to run my business.
- You should sell the show.
You're running all over the country
for 10 cents a ticket?
It's old and tired.
Times have changed, it's 1932.
We got the Empire State Building,
aeroplanes crossing the ocean.
This cowboy stuff is old-fashioned.
Like your fringe jacket.
- That's a gift from Buffalo Bill Cody.
- Exactly, it's from another century.
- Would you pass the peas, please?
- Sonora, I see you got your hair... done.
- Did you do it yourself?
- I went to the Clip 'N' Curl.
Would you pass the peas?
It's good pork chop, Marie.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- I like your dress.
- You scared me!
Sorry.
It's a hot night.
A good night to go swimming.
- Who? You and Marie?
- No. You and me.
- No, thank you.
- Come on, I know the perfect place.
I'm not going swimming.
Come here.
- I gotta go.
- Sonora, wait!
Sorry.
Good night.
Roosevelt received one of the
largest demonstrations for a candidate.
Now let's resume
to the Skylark Ballroom Orchestra...
Don't drink out of the bottle.
- You better watch yourself.
- What's that supposed to mean?
She's young.
She don't know any better.
- I don't want you messing up her life.
- I haven't done anything.
Keep it that way.
Hey!
What?
Put the milk away.
- Nice day, huh?
- Yeah, I suppose so.
My goodness, would you look at that?
- What are you doing?
- Riding.
- Do you know anything about this?
- I'm as surprised as you are.
So you can ride.
- I can dive, too, given a chance.
- Ridiculous!
She deserves a chance.
- You do, do you?
- Yeah.
- Can you make a moving mount?
- Never tried.
If you can mount him while he's moving,
I'll let you train to be a diving girl.
It beats shovelling manure. Come on!
Reach out, touch the harness.
Get used to the rhythm.
When he passes, grab the harness
and pull yourself on. Concentrate.
You ready?
Whoa! Stay there, don't move.
Does your nose feel broken?
No. But I don't know
what a broken nose feels like.
- All right, let's get you in the house.
- Ls that it?
You gonna quit?
Let me look at the nose.
The nose ain't broke.
- She can still ride. Do it again.
- She's hurt.
Shut your gate!
- Sonora, you don't have to do this.
- It's all right, Al, I can do it.
Nothing's handed to you in this world,
Sonora. You gotta earn it.
You gonna cry?
I never cry.
Good. Let's go.
Don't be in too big a hurry,
just sense the horse's rhythm.
- Attagirl!
- I did it, boy! We did it!
All right!
OK. Good!
Now you can train to be a diving girl.
Come on down. Go get cleaned up.
- What are you trying to prove?
- She did it, didn't she?
You push too hard.
- Well, she didn't quit.
- What? Like me? Like my mother?
No matter how hard anyone tries,
it's not good enough for you.
Stupid old man.
- No, Al!
- Come on!
Al!
Al, where are you going?
I should've left a long time ago.
I can't keep fighting him.
He doesn't care about me or anybody.
The only thing he cares about
is his stupid show.
Please don't go.
I'm sorry.
Write me.
I promise.
Dear Sonora, I hope you understand
why I had to leave.
I keep thinking about you.
I miss you. Please write me.
- ls that the mail?
- Yeah.
Did I get anything? Any letters?
Nope.
- I'll show you how.
- He's used to me.
- Don't tell me my business.
- She has a point.
Get down.
Just watch and you'll learn.
Don't use your heels.
She used her heels.
I hate that horse!
- ls it as bad as it sounds?
- She always wanted to be an actress.
Is she gonna be OK?
She's dislocated her shoulder.
The doctor's putting it in a sling.
I can't take any more of this.
Lord!
She'll be stove-up for six weeks.
Six weeks?
- We got a booking in three days.
- Where will you find a diving girl?
The tower's not as high as it looks.
Honest. I've been there.
- Hi. Remember me?
- Yeah. Hot dogs.
- Not any more. My stand burned down.
- Sorry.
Dr Carver gave me a job.
I'm your new groom.
That's great.
- I heard you're diving today.
- My first time.
- Nervous?
- Me? Nervous? Heck, no!
- Sonora?
- Come in!
- You all right?
- I feel great.
Good, good.
- My bathing suit doesn't fit.
- You'll grow into it.
- What if it falls off?
- We'll give refunds.
Do it just like we practised, right?
Keep your eye on the harness.
- Don't forget to...
- ...grip.
And don't forget to put your head
to the side. Right? All right.
- You'll do fine.
- There is one thing.
Do I have to bow? I'll feel stupid.
I don't care if you fall on your head,
you will smile and bow.
- But I just...
- Bow.
What if I can't do it?
What if I lose my nerve?
- You'll do it.
- But what if I can't?
Will you hate me?
If you feel nervous, look for me.
I'll be in front of the crowd.
Still don't want to bow.
Sonora and her brave horse, Lightning!
Sonora, ladies and gentlemen,
and her brave horse, Lightning!
Sonora, ladies and gentlemen!
Sonora!
We got a new diving girl!
And a new diving horse.
- Do we get to be on a poster?
- Yeah. "Marie and Sonora, diving girls!"
I refuse to share billing
with a stable-hand.
Marie, she made the dive.
She is not the star of the show. I am!
You are, but we got two diving girls.
Well, since I'm the star, I'd like more
money and a bigger dressing room.
- There's a depression!
- More money, a dressing room.
And a better poster, or I quit.
I can't do that, Marie.
- Well, then, I quit.
- Don't be stubborn. You can't quit!
I am an actress, not a circus performer!
The next time you see me,
I'm going to be a big star!
And you will still be shovelling manure!
All spring, we travelled from one fair
to the next, doing three shows a day.
Lightning got better with each dive.
And I wasn't bad, either.
Everything was going great,
except for one thing.
Now and then it seems to me
It weren't so bad what used to be
Here and now it seems so true
This feeling blue, wishing
Wishing it just weren't true
My dreams are gone
yet I linger on
As hope drifts into despair
All around us
The blues surround us
Why, Lord, is life so unfair?
Now and then it seems to me
It weren't so bad what used to be
Here and now
Through and through
This sinking down
This feeling blue
And I'm wishing
Wishing it just weren't true
What are you doing now?
Finishing that letter to Franklin County.
He promised he'd write me.
Why doesn't he?
Thanks for your time.
We'll see what we can do.
What if we can't book another show?
That's why I'm driving
to Franklin County to find work.
- What if there isn't?
- I'll keep the show open, I promise.
If he doesn't, I will.
Now, listen. Keep those horses
fed and watered.
It's very important.
- We won't be back till morning.
- Don't worry.
I know.
Hey, Red Lips.
Lightning!
Lightning, what's the matter?
Come on, get up.
What's wrong?
Al.
- What happened?
- I don't know. He's awful sick.
Easy, boy, easy.
What is it, Al?
What's wrong with him?
- Did Red Lips eat this hay?
- No.
It's mouldy, it's given him colic.
We gotta get water into him.
Where's the tactron?
In the barn.
It's gonna be OK, boy.
Hold this here, while I pump.
Hold it there. Good.
All right, come here.
Take this and, when I tell you to, pull.
All right, pull! Come on!
Pull! Come on, Lightning!
Come on, boy.
- Whoa!
- That's it!
Good boy, Lightning. Good boy.
- Come on, we gotta get him moving.
- Come on, Lightning.
- He'll be OK?
- Yeah, he'll be just fine.
Would somebody please say something?
I thought you could use a hand
with the show.
Ain't no show.
So, why didn't you answer my letters?
I didn't get any letters.
I wrote you just about every day.
What did you say?
- Stuff.
- What kind of stuff?
You know... stuff.
I got a telegram from a John Slater
from Atlantic City.
- Atlantic City?
- At Steel Pier. A six-month contract.
You did this?
Someone once told me
it's where all your dreams come true.
You didn't say anything.
- Slater just said he'd think about it.
- What did you tell him?
I told him the diving horse show
was very exciting,
and that my father
was mean and stubborn.
And that he was the greatest
showman on earth.
On the boardwalk in Atlantic City
Life can be peaches and cream
Cinderella, you will find your fella
Someone that you've waited for
In romantic, enchantic, Atlantic City
Down by the old New Jersey shore
Yep.
You know, Sonora,
sometimes people make mistakes.
It's hard to admit when you have.
- Are you OK? You look pale.
- I'm fine.
When Al was gone all those months
and you didn't hear from him,
I did...
I did something that...
- Are you sure you're OK?
- I'm fine. I'll pull over to take a breather.
- Why did we stop?
- I wanted a little breather.
- Good, I'm hungry.
- Rest, and we'll set up a picnic.
Dad, when we get to Atlantic City,
the first thing we gotta do
is buy you a new suit.
- Double-breasted?
- Yep. With pinstripes.
Yeah.
And now, as we've all read,
the book of God's word:
"Ashes to ashes, dust to dust,
"we now return the spirit
of our departed brother..."
- Your dad wanted top billing or nothing.
- We get top billing?
- See for yourself.
- Al, that's me!
- It sure is.
- That's me and that's Lightning!
You know Frenchie?
He was gonna throw this away.
- That thing's a piece of junk.
- I'm gonna fix it all up.
- What are you gonna do with it?
- I'll think of something.
Ladies and gentlemen, presenting...
Ladies and gentlemen, we now present
Carver's high-diving horse and girl rider!
I was rehearsing.
"Ladies and gentlemen..."
I never introduced a show before.
Should I wear this suit tomorrow?
- I don't think it'll help.
- Come here!
"Ladies and gentlemen..."
Stay here.
Introducing...
There was a time I couldn't imagine
spending my life with just one person.
Now I can't imagine
spending it without you.
I love you, Sonora.
I thought I lost you.
What?
What is it?
This is what you should wear.
Turn around. Let's see how it looks.
Shoulders back.
Now raise your arms a bit.
Higher.
Higher!
- Whoa!
- Easy, easy!
- He's jittery.
- He's not used to the noise.
- Maybe we should jump Lightning.
- He's not well enough yet.
Sonora, Sonora Webster,
I want you for my wife.
Will you marry me?
Take my hand in marriage
and make me a happy man.
- What are you doing? Are you crazy?
- About you.
I've never been so embarrassed!
All you have to do is say yes.
Yes! Yes! Yes!
It's just tinted glass. When things
get better, I'll get you a real one.
Are you gonna marry me, yes or no?
Yes! Yes! Yes!
Yes.
Go on, we got a show to do.
Take him.
- Are you all right?
- I'm fine.
- Is Red Lips hurt?
- I don't think so.
Come on.
Are you sure you're all right?
Just stunned. When I hit the water,
I had my eyes open.
- Clifford, is he OK?
- He seems OK. What about you?
- Let's get you to the doctor.
- I'm not bleeding, no broken bones.
Let's get him to the stables.
Excuse me, but you must be still.
Sorry.
- What about Slater?
- He was concerned...
- Tell him not to worry. I'll be fine.
- Why didn't you see a doctor sooner?
They stung a little, that's all.
- Your eyes were open?
- Yes.
It caused a slight haemorrhage,
which has continued for days.
The blood has clotted and detached
the retina in both eyes.
What does that mean?
Her condition is permanent.
No, it's not!
I'm sorry.
Why are you sorry?
I'm gonna rest and then get back
to work, it's only temporary.
I'm not blind.
It's a real tough break.
Now, about the show...
This may not be the best time to talk,
but business is business.
That diving tower wasn't cheap,
the publicity...
Publicity?
I don't care about your publicity!
Are you crazy?
I'll give you a break.
You can close the show for one week.
- But that's all.
- I can't train a new girl in a week.
You better come up with something,
or I'll sue you for breach of contract.
One, two, three, four,
five, six...
One, two, three...
The blues are here,
right next to the greens, all right?
- Blues... greens.
- Right.
Al, Sonora, I wanna show you
something. Come on!
Know what that is? Death.
Know what I just did? I defied it.
It's amazing, Clifford.
It's swell, isn't it?
My very own death-defying act.
I'm very proud of you, Clifford.
If you want something bad enough,
anything's possible.
- Seen my shoes?
- They're by the sofa. I'll get them.
- I'll do it.
- They're right here.
- Your lipstick's a little smeared.
- Thank you.
What?
- You got a problem with your socks.
- What's wrong?
One's red and one's green.
I like it though.
That's the latest fashion.
It's all right, it's all right.
It's gonna be rough for a while,
but I'll be here to help you.
It'll take time to adjust, if you want,
we can move the wedding back.
- There's not gonna be a wedding.
- What?
Don't marry me
because you feel sorry for me.
I'm marrying you because I love you.
I don't want that kind of love.
I don't want you cutting my food,
getting my socks,
cleaning up my messes.
- As soon as my eyes clear up...
- They won't.
- Yes, they will, it's temporary.
- It's not.
It is!
Let me go!
Sonora, you must accept this.
You're human with limitations.
You can't run away from it,
you can't hide from it or change it.
It's permanent.
I know.
I'm real sorry about what happened.
When Al told me you were hurt,
the movies had to wait.
- Marie, we're ready for you.
- Excuse me, honey.
- Here I am.
- Put her on the horse?
Have me stand next to it.
- That's great, great!
- Why did you decide to come back?
I love the audiences. When Al called
my mother, I was auditioning for a movie.
- How long will you be here?
- It's M-A-R-I-E.
Excuse me, sis, you're in the shot.
Could you move?
Sonora? What are you doing?
- I've been thinking.
- About what?
- I wanna dive again.
- Honey, you can't, it's impossible.
- I can do it, I know I can.
- Sonora, you've gotta be realistic.
With Lightning.
Al, he knows what I'm thinking,
and I know what he's thinking.
Absolutely not. It's too dangerous.
I have to do this.
Please, I need your help.
Here it comes.
Here it comes again.
You OK?
Again.
Here, watch your step.
Are you nuts?
You have Marie to do the show.
This has nothing
to do with your show.
Do you think she can do this?
Look me in the eye
and tell me she can do this!
It's just what I thought.
Close out all other sounds
and listen to his hooves.
Don't go to the horse,
let the horse come to you.
Let your hand slide up his shoulder
to the harness.
When you feel the harness, grip.
Let the horse's momentum pull you up.
That's it!
Are you all right?
- This isn't working.
- Just a little more time.
No. I don't want you hurt.
We tried, it didn't work.
This can't be done, and it's going
to end right here. Understand?
Yes.
Hi. Are you OK?
I gotta introduce the show.
I'm OK.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we now present Carver's
high-diving horse and girl rider.
In a daring 40-foot plunge on horseback!
- Can I talk to you for a second?
- What's going on...? Clifford!
Open up, Clifford!
Open up this door right now!
It is the only act of its kind in the world.
The safety of the rider depends on
the intelligence and skill of the horse.
It is an act with no electrical device,
no mechanical apparatus, no force,
and no cue of any sort...
Ladies and gentlemen,
for safety, hold your applause...
I'm proud to present the most
popular act in Steel Pier's history...
- Carver! What is going on here?
- I don't know. I'll find out.
- There's a girl climbing the tower!
- Oh, no. Sonora!
They don't want to see
a blind girl kill herself.
Sonora, don't!
Sonora, no!
- Carver!
- No, Sonora! No!
Did you see that?
She was wonderful!
That last dive began 11 years of diving
blind. The audience never knew.
I'd found my destiny, not in faraway
places, but within myself.
I also found happiness with Al.
We were married that fall
and had a wonderful life together.