(THEME PLAYING)
- JP: Roger, Do you believe in heaven?
- ROGER: I guess.
That's where they
say my mom went.
- Maybe, that's where my dad went.
- Probably.
(SIGHS) Maybe your mom
and my dad are friends up there.
- ROGER: That could be.
- JP: Cause your my best friend down here.
You're my best friend too, JP.
JP: Roger, how come Maggie's house
is called a foster home?
ROGER: I don't know.
Maybe the first people
who let other people's kids...
- ...live with them were named "Foster."
- JP: Oh.
So, If we stay there
a long time...
...do we gotta change
our name to Foster?
- ROGER: No way.
- JP: Good.
Besides, we're not gonna
be there a long time.
- Really?
- Yeah, somethin' good's gonna happen.
JP: Yeah, somethin' good.
Maybe today, even. It could happen.
- (TRAIN APPROACHES)
- (TIRE SCREECHES)
RANCH: (ON RADIO) So, the Angels
trying to break a 14-game losing streak...
...face the Toronto Blue Jays
here this afternoon at Anaheim Stadium.
- (TIRE SCREECHES)
- Maggie, we're back!
- So, where you been?
- Just riding around.
You said be back by 5:00.
I can't tell time yet.
Are we back by 5:00?
Close. Come on, JP,
get your bike in.
- Roger? You have a visitor.
- Yeah?
- He's waiting inside for you.
- Is it?
- ROGER: Dad?
- MAN: Hey.
- Dad.
- Suprised to see me?
Yeah.
You look kinda scrawny. Don't
they feed you enough in this place?
- Yeah.
- Where you been? I was waiting.
Just ridin' around the stadium.
- Angels still your team?
- Yeah.
They're in last place.
- Runs in the blood.
Family that likes losers.
(SIGHS)
So, I came to say
that I'm goin' up north.
I know I said when I came
it'd be to get you, but...
(SIGHS) Things ain't workin' out that way.
I did what I could with ya.
Maybe if your mom was alive,
it'd be different.
I, uh-- They had me sign
this thing, this paper...
...some kind of release thing.
Uh, just gotta go to
court to make it final.
You understand
what I'm sayin', don't ya?
- Y-yeah.
- Okay, I'm glad we got that outta the way.
- Where's the pickup?
- Oh, I traded it in.
The bike's better for travellin'.
D-Dad, when we gonna be
a family again?
From where I'm sittin'.
I'd say when the Angels win the pennant.
- DAD: You stay outta trouble, son.
- (ENGINE STARTS)
MAN (ON PA):
Number 27., shortstop Steve Acker.
RANCH WILDER (ON RADiO):
So with the Angels down by seven...
...it's now one ball
two strikes to Acker...
the fourth batter to face
Gates here in the eighth.
- Come on. Strike him out!
- Yeah! Strike him out!
(CONTINUES)
Burn it in there.
- Come on, Angels!
- Let's stay in this.
RANCH:
Gates takes the sign...
checks the runner at first
and delivers.
Acker lofts the ball
high into left field.
MAN: Gates, you stink!
Norton and Williams
both going for the catch.
- I-I got it. I got it.
- And this'll be Ben Williams's call.
(BOTH GROAN)
And Williams and Norton collide,
and the catch is blown!
- (BEN PANTING)
- (NORTON GROANS)
- Boy, they're bad!
- (ALL EXCLAMING) Ohh!
And with another example
of his infamous temper...
manager George Knox calls time out.
He will have a word
with his pitcher, Frank Gates.
I don't think it's
gonna be a happy word.
RANCH (ON RADIO): And it looks like Knox
is going to take Gates out.
Gates doesn't look
too pleased about this.
- Gimme the ball.
- It ain't my fault.
You need a new outfield.
GEORGE: You're outta here!
Gimme the ball!
You want the ball?
Here you go. Go get it!
- RANCH: Gates has thrown his ball...
- And my glove? Go get it!
- and glove into the stands.
- Go on! Get outta here!
- GEORGE: You're finished, Gates!
- And Knox has attacked his own pitcher!
BOTH: Uh-oh!
MESSMER: Skip, Skip.
Let him go, Skip.
- Get off me! You're crazy, Knox!
- You're washed up! You'll never pitch again!
RANCH: They're clearing
the benches!
- Now both teams are on the field!
- Hey! It's not our fight!
RANCH: George Knox
has created total chaos!
- GEORGE: Hit him one for me, Gates!
- I can't find him!
- You're crazy!
- GATES: You can't manage a team!
RANCH: This is outrageous!
- George Knox fighting off his own players.
- (SIGHS) Surprise, surprise.
RANCH: And they're trying to keep
Knox and Gates apart.
- Come on! - I said, let me go!
- You stink, Knox!
UMPIRE: Knox! You're outta here!
Come on, Ump.
Leave him in!
JP: Yeah! Don't throw him out!
MAN: Hey! What are you kids
doin' up there?
- (GASPS) Uh-oh!
- You better have tickets for that tree!
Game's over for us, JP.
We gotta go!
That's right, clear off!
Go on. Get outta here!
You heard me! Don't let me catch
you twerps around here again!
- GEORGE: You kickin' me out? That's good!
- Yes, I'm kicking you out!
'Cause you been stinkin' up
the calls all day! - You're gone!
GEORGE: You can't kick me out, 'cause I'm
leavin'. You get that? I'm outta here!
RANCH: And Knox will watch
the rest of the game in the locker room.
- (TURNS OFF)
- Murphy's out of his mind
to put up with this nonsense.
- You thinkyou can do any better?
- (SCOFFS) Blindfolded.
Well, when you were managing, boy,
you had a lot of trouble. I remember--
- (SIZZLES)
- Zip it, pal.
You have to ask yourself what is
going on with this team and how long...
will owner Hank Murphy put up with
this kind of behaviour from his manager.
RANCH: I thought I'd seen it all,
ladies and gentlemen, but with...
George Knox calling the shots,
you never know what will happen.
ROGER:
Careful, JP. Let's go.
(THUMPING)
Why do you idiots
do that after we've lost?
RAY: It's for good luck, man.
DANNY: After fifteen straight losses,
I say we find somethin' else to rub.
- Like Triscuit's head.
- Hey, don't even think about...
- touchin' me anywhere.
- Fatty pants.
WHIT: You know, maybe we
should do this before we lose.
(ALL CHATTERING)
TRISCUIT: Aw, not again! They got
the wrong kind of salami!
Can't hit home runs
if Knox doesn't let you play.
Hey, I can hit it. You gotta--
You gotta choke up and bear down.
RAY: Then you'll get your own home run.
- Hey, how's the arm?
- It's feelin' strong.
You'll be pitchin' no-hitters
any day now.
MAPEL: ♪ We are the boys of summer
and it's a big bummer ♪
♪ No matter who we play,
we give the game away ♪
♪ 'Cause we can't win,
That would be a sin ♪
♪ We even lose the games before ♪
- Save it, Mapel!
- ♪ they begin ♫
- (ALL GASP)
- AUBREY: Oh, no!
- Bummer.
- One more loss!
One more loss which
could have been a win!
You call yourselves professionals!
I have never, ever seen
a worse group of 25 players!
You don't think as a team,
you don't play as a team...
you don't even lose as a team!
GEORGE: You all got your heads
so far up your butts...
you can't even see
the light of day!
GEORGE: One more loss and I'll--
and I'll do this...Aah!
- to each and every one of you!
- Ho-ho-ho!
GEORGE: I want you here,
in uniform, at 9:00 tomorrow!
We're going back to work
on fundamentals!
-Fundamentals? In the middle of the season?
-I thought the game started at 1:00.
It does started 1:00!
And you a jackass!
- No, I'm a pitcher.
- (GEORGE GROANS)
- You can be a pitcher and a jackass.
- Si.. Is very common.
Ahh.
(THUD)
HANK: Tough loss, George.
I can't take it anymore.
You have to start trade them.
All of them, now!
HANK: I can't trade 25 players.
No, no, no! I can't win with
these guys. And nobody can.
There's a thing called talent.
- They don't have it.
- This isn't Cincinnati, George.
No one expects you
to win big with these boys.
I came here to manage
a winning baseball team.
You just hang on, partner.
You'll ride through the dark days.
DAVID: Mr. Knox, we're waiting on the field!
We're waiting!
What's that?
David Montagne, administrative
assistant for media relations.
You're scheduled to do Ranch
Wilder's postgame show here...
- And he's been waiting.
- Oh, the press are all scum.
They're meant to be kept waiting.
- And Ranch Wilder's worse than scum.
- RANCH: Whose fault is that?
That is not my fault.
What ever happened to Barney or
Bailey, or whatever?
You fired him, and they
hired me on Monday.
Then I can't officially
fire you until Friday.
Make a note.
GEORGE: Oh, what a waste.
Uh, where, where, where?
- Right here.
- All right, all right.
- (SIGHS)
- Microphone?
Thrown out of the game.
I imagine the commissioner's
fine will be hefty.
Oh, god.
We're on in 3, 2, 1.
RANCH: And we're back with
Angels manager George Knox.
- This was a tough loss today.
- Any loss is hard.
But this one really got to you.
You leave Cincinnati after
ten years of winning ball clubs.
although the really big one always
seemed to be just out of reach--
and you come out here
to manage our Angels.
Now, expectations were high that
you could turn this team around...
but that just doesn't
seem to be happening.
- Season's only half over, Ranch.
- And your club's in last place.
You oughta know how one incident
can change the course of events.
Well, you know, you play
the game, you take your chances.
Sometimes you're just in the
wrong place at the wrong time.
- Yeah, you're an expert at that.
- I could say the same about you.
- Well, actions speak louder than words.
- (CAMERA SWICHES)
Well, that'll wrap things up
here-
- Hey, I'm still on the air here.
- GEORGE: Oh, yeah?
Aah!
We're speaking with Angels manager
George Knox. George?
And, uh, we'll be right back.
MAGGIE: Oh, Roger,
you haven't eaten a thing.
ROGER: I'm not hungry.
MAGGIE: Miguel, you have to miss
the baseball game tomorrow.
I'm sorry. Your social worker called,
and you have an interview.
She'll be here at 11:00.
Good. I don't want to go to
the game anyway. Angels never win.
- (SCOFFS)
- I wanna go to the game.
They could win. It could happen.
Yeah, and you could drop dead
after dinner with food poisoning.
- Leave him alone!
- MAGGIE: Boys!
Hey, look what we've got
for dessert. Jell-O.
- Yea!
- It's not really Jell-O.
It's cat brains
with food colouring.
She kills 'em at night
and feeds 'em to us to save money.
- Shut up, Miguel.
- Roger!
You know we do not use
those words in this house.
JP: Meow!
And you know I would never use
food colouring on my cat brains.
Okay, did we wash
our faces? Yeah?
Brush our teeth?
Been to the bathroom?
Did you pick the lint from
between your toes? Yeah?
- Did you say your prayers?
- BOTH: Yeah.
Oh, yeah? Night.
- ROGER: Night, Maggie.
- JP: Good night, Maggie.
- I didn't say my prayers.
- I didn't wash my face.
What's lint again?
- Shut up, butt-head!
- Why do we gotta sleep in these-
sleeping bags? I haven't
peed the bed in a long time.
(SIGHS) You peed
the bed last week.
And she makes us sleep in these
sleeping bags...
'cause she too old to bend
over and tuck in sheets.
She isn't too old.
She's got a lot to do.
Did you guys pray?
I pray every night you go to bed
without buggin' us...
with a thousand stupid questions.
Maybe tomorrow you'll meet
a nice family, Miguel.
JP: I'll pray for that.
It could happen.
God--
if there is a God--
if you're a man or a woman,
if you're listenin'...
I'd really, really like...
a family.
My dad says that'll only happen
if the Angels win the pennant.
The baseball team, I mean.
So, maybe you could
help 'em win a little.
Amen.
Uh, "a-women" too.
(KNOCKS ON DOOR)
Come in.
You wanted to see me?
- You feelin' any better today, George?
- Why would I be feelin' better?
Commissioner fined you $5,000
for jumpin' Gates.
HANK: And word has it Ranch is pressin'
civil charges for you poppin' him.
(CHUCKLES) Come to think of it, I have
felt better since I slugged Wilder.
- Your pistol's smokin', pal.
- I hadn't made the connection.
Look, I know you and Wilder
have been at each other's throats...
since you were players.
Yeah, we've been at each other's
throats since he spiked my knee-
and ruined my career.
- Accidents happen, George.
- It wasn't an accident.
When you slide into a catcher
with your nails up, it's on purpose.
I was comin' into my best years.
Now, don't go makin' more
cow-pies to step in, George.
HANK: You got enough manure
on your boots now.
Control yourself today.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(KIDS SHOUTING)
Ladies and gentlemen, a reminder
that every Wednesday is kids day.
- Whoa! I see better seats!
- Youngsters age 12 and under...
- Much better seats!
- Come on, J. P., come on.
Come on!
All right!
- ANNOUNCER: Thank you.
- ROGER: Great seats. JP: Yeah.
- ROGER: This is much better than the tree.
- JP: I'll say.
Hey, Skip.
Trainer says I'm ready to pitch.
When am I gettin'
off the injured list?
How's never sound?
You're here 'cause
you got a contract...
that pays you to be here.
You blew your arm out.
- Played on too many pain pills.
- Pain pills?
You were the one
stuffin' 'em down...
my throat five
years ago in Cincinnati.
Hey, it was your decision
to swallow 'em. I had a brain.
When you were finished,
I traded you.
I never thought I'd get
stuck with you again.
Why, you rotten--
(COUGHS)
That's not contagious, is it?
- (MEL COUGHS)
- Outta my way.
I got a ball club to manage.
(SINGING)
And the rockets' red glare
The bombs bursting in air
Gave proof through the night
That our flag was still there
Oh, say does that star-spangled
banner yet wave
O'er the land of the free
And the home of the brave
(ALL CHEERING)
I guess no matter how many times
you hear that song played...
in a major league stadium
on a warm afternoon...
it's still emotionally evocative.
Drop dead.
I got sunscreen in my eye.
Will I win, will I win,
will I win, win, win?
Aw!
- Yeah!
- (SINGING) Jose, can you see
Wait a second. The first word
is "Jose"? I thought it was--
It's Jose. We know.
Wow! It's about a Spanish guy!
- (SINGS) Jose, can you see
- I don't believe him, eh.
It's so easy.
RANCH: Whit Bass takes the mound
with his trademark slide.
His oddball antics are by now
well known to the fans.
WALLY: That's right, Ranch. This season
alone we've seen him lick dirt...
eat bugs and floss his
catcher's teeth in the dugout.
(TURNS OFF)
- (TURNS ON)
- None of that, may I add,
seems to have helped his pitching.
He's two and eleven.
ANNOUNCER: Leading off forthe BlueJays,
number 22...
third baseman Orrin Farley.
RANCH: And after hardly any
warm-up, Bass signals he's ready.
MAN: Come on, Whit Bass!
Just throw strikes!
Hmm?
Hmph. Hmph.
(YAWNS)
Huh?
Aah!
RANCH: First pitch of the game.
And the Angels have an
error and a man on base.
So the fifth inning goes into the books
with the score nothing to nothing.
The Angels thus far have been able to
keep the hard-hitting Blue Jays silent.
But as we head into the sixth,
The Jays have the middle
of the order coming up...
with the ever-dangerous
Asher Lazzato leading off.
ANNOUNCER: Number 31, left fielder
Asher Lazzato.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
RANCH: Bass sets...
and sets and sets again.
Please, just throw the ball.
RANCH: Here's the pitch.
And Lazzato smashes
one to deep center!
I don't think Williams
will get to this one!
ROGER: Oh!
- VERNE: Oh, wow!
- BEN: Aah!
RANCH: And Ben Williams
makes a miraculous catch!
Holy cow!
How did he do that?
Yeah, holy cow!
How did he do that?!
RANCH: That, sports fans, is a play
you're going to see run...
in baseball highlights
for years to come.
Get me something here!
- Come on, come on!
- We got it.
What are we waiting for?
Get me something!
I'm hangin', I'm hangin'!
This is dead airtime!
- Did you see that?
- Yeah, awesome.
They were just sucked
down right from the sky.
- Who?
- Those guys.
ROGER: Those guys in
sparkling pajamas.
What are you talking about, Roger?
What guys in sparkling pajamas?
You didn't see 'em?
Those guys carrying Williams?
- I don't know.
- Hey, mister, did you see that?
Lucky catch.
No, did you see what
happened with the clouds?
Did you see the people with
Williams when he caught the ball?
Huh?
There were shiny people out there.
- Flying, shiny people.
- (BEER GULPS)
Yeah, well, tell
your parents about it.
But the--
ANNOUNCER: Number 58,
the Irvinator...
Irving Nator.
(BURPS)
You didn't see 'em?
It was a real good play, Roger.
- I saw that.
- AL: Yes! Yes!
Amazing play. I love it when
they come from above like that.
From-- From above?
The sky deal. It's a
good entrance for 'em.
- You mean you saw 'em?
- The angels?
- Angels?
- AL: 'Course I saw 'em.
They're with me.
The little one's a rookie.
He just got off his training wings.
You mean tho-those are real angels?
Accept no substitutes.
ROGER: Who are you?
Just call me Al. No one
can see me or hear me but you.
- W-Why me?
- You asked for help, and we're here.
We come and go.
It's an "as-needed" situation.
Who you talkin' to, Rog?
- What are you talkin' about?
- (CLICKS TONGUE) Tubby's back.
I'm vapour. Keep your nose
clean and your heart open.
You got angels around, sonny.
We'll be in touch.
Oh! (GASPS)
Al! What--
(AL BURPS)
(CLICKS TONGUE)
- Who's Al?
- He's the--
MAN: What's your problem?
Are you sick or something?
Yeah, maybe.
RANCH: With two outs, this is
the Angels' last chance...
to put away the Jays
before extra innings.
Next up is Messmer who unfortunately
has been hitless in his last 26 at bats.
ANNOUNCER: Number 14,
catcher Triscuit Messmer.
Here we go again.
VERNE: Oh, wow!
VERNE: Oh, my gosh!
Oh, my gosh! Oh no!
RANCH: And that one, ladies and gents,
is headin' downtown...
and Messmer breaks a bat
and the Angels' losing streak...
as he crashes a home run
in the ninth--
- To win the game.
- (HANK LAUGHS)
- Aah! Aah!
- Ha!
- Yeah!
- Yeah! Yeah! All right, guys!
Oh, yeah! Yeah!
We won?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
How did that happen?
Yeah! Ha! Ha.
But you didn't see
the angel with him?
We won.
No, but-- but there were angels
in the outfield and in the infield.
Yeah, nine of'em.
- (SIGHS)
- ANNOUNCER: Ladies and gentlemen,
ourfinal drawing this afternoon...
will give three lucky winners a chance
to be photographed on the field...
- with manager George Knox.
- That's a prize? Mm-mm-mmm.
The first winning ticket
is number 477380.
- I won.
- What?
JP: You do it.
I don't wanna have my picture taken.
I don't like strangers.
Jeez! What's goin' on around here?
- (LAUGHING)
- Don't forget,
the next series
versus the Oakland A 's...
opening Friday here...
- at Anaheim Stadium.
- Who's he?
MAN: I can see you kids don't know
your baseball. That's Mel Clark.
Mel Clark? Whoa!
He pitched three shutouts
in a row for Cincinnati in 1986.
- Well, that's right.
- My dad used to talk about him.
You used to be Mel Clark?
Yeah, I used to be.
- MAN: Come on, son. Let's go.
- That's it. That's all, folks.
Okay, we have three
photo ops. It'll be quick.
Give 'em publicity stills.
It'll be quicker.
They want a picture with you.
They're all kids.
- I-I hate kids.
- Yeah, I guessed that.
(WHISTLES)
First kid!
JP, wait! Well-- He--
Looks like a prison photo.
Uh, would either of you mind smiling?
The team did just win.
It was a mistake.
This team can't win.
They won. Cause there
were angels out there.
Huh?
Real ones. I saw 'em.
Two angels came out of the sky
and they picked up Ben Williams.
And another angel hit Messmer's
home run. That's why the bat broke.
Great, a psycho kid. David,
you'd think they'd screen these people.
It's true! Ask Williams
about it. Or Messmer.
They'll tell you something's
goin' on. You'll see.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
- Honey, why aren't you asleep?
- I gotta ask you somethin'.
Do you believe in angels?
What do angels gotta do
with you bein' out of your bed?
No, I really wanna know.
Do you think they're real?
(SIGHS)
Well, there are a lot of amazing things
in life that just can't be explained.
Uh--
I believe in, uh...
the possibility of miraculous
things happening.
That's what makes every day
of our lives worth getting up for.
So, um--
Yeah.
I guess I do believe in angels.
Yeah?
Me too.
Good night, Maggie.
MAGGIE: Night.
(SIGHS, LAUGHS)
Nice catch yesterday, Ben.
How did it feel? Or did it all happen
so fast you don't even remember?
BEN: I felt weightless, like
somebody had me by the arms, Skip.
How'd I do that?
TRISCUIT: It wasn't like
a regular homer. you know?
It felt like someone was swingin'
with me. Very strange.
I could feel some added power
comin' from somewhere.
It must've been those chilli dogs
I ate before the game.
You know, that third one
tasted kinda funny.
Chilli dogs.
(KNOCKS ON DOOR)
I'm looking for Roger Bowman.
Does he live here?
Yeah.
I'm George Knox from
the California Angels.
Roger won a photograph
at last Friday's game.
Oh!
Uh-
I'd really like to
give it to him myself.
- Uh, you're Roger's mom?
- Nope.
Aunt? Grandma?
No, no.
We're not related.
This is a short-term
foster care facility. I run it.
- Roger is a ward of the state.
- Oh.
Uh, s-so Roger, he--
he's got a wild imagination?
- Always making up stories?
- No, actually.
He's very grounded.
Fact is, most kids who are
taken away from their parents
by the court system.
Have a good handle on reality.
I bet.
ROGER: Mel Clark strikes him out.
Cincinnati wins.
MAGGIE: What do you want from him?
Why are you really here?
Uh, young fans.
League needs more of em.
Roger?
- I got your pictures.
- Thanks.
- Yeah.
- I didn't know you were bringing 'em.
ROGER: Hmm.
- Looks like a prison photo.
- ROGER: Yeah.
Uh, you-- you said you thought
you saw something at the game.
Yeah, angels. Real ones.
Wh-- Why do you think
there would be...
real angels at the ball game?
Maybe 'cause I prayed for 'em?
Nothing you were doing was helping.
I just figured it couldn't hurt.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Does he talk?
Of course he talks.
He just doesn't like strangers.
Uh, me either.
I don't even like my friends.
Uh, these angels you thinkyou seen,
do you suppose they're coming back?
- If they feel like it, I guess.
- Oh, this is crazy.
I must be losing it.
What I meant to say is...
Uh, do you wanna come
to the game tomorrow?
I have an open seat
next to the dugout, and you can...
get your Aunt Maggie or
whoever she is to come along.
- I don't go to baseball games.
- Oh!
- But, uh, yeah, you can go, Roger.
- Can J.P. come too?
Okay.
RANCH: After their
victory over the Jays...
the Angels open a three-game series
against the visiting Athletics.
Winning the last game may
have given these Angels a boost.
Sizing up the team, I'd say
they look a little bouncier today,
wouldn't you, Wally?
(CLICK) Absolutely, Ranch.
As we saw in last game--
RANCH: Keep it minimal, Wally.
They'll like you better.
(CLICK)
RANCH: We're 20 minutes
away from game time,
and there are already
more people in the seats...
than there were for
the last five games combined.
Here. Here you go.
Take that. Just take it, okay?
DAVID: Do you want anything else?
Uh, yeah, peanuts, maybe,
and nachos, if you could.
Yeah.
Aah!
- Sorry.
- DAVID: My linen suit!
What do I do? Mustard stains.
That's hot water.
Cold water. Uh, club soda.
Club soda.
- I got soda!
- DAVID: Ow!
(GASPs)
I'm all wet.
DAVID: Get up in front of me.
Right now! We're gonna dry off.
Leave your popcorn there.
- Hey, what happened to you?
- Those kids, they're evil.
The big one might be lucky,
so keep him happy.
- JP, let's go!
- We gonna win today, kid?
- Maybe.
- Maybe?
I don't know.
It's your team.
Don't remind me.
Sit down!
(SLURPS)
Oh, please, don't drink me.
No, no, no, don't, don't, don't!
- AL: Aah!
- VERNE: Got it!
GARY: My, my!
- How'd you get-- How'd you get--
- Shh. Shh, shh, shh, shh.
AL: This is between you and me,
little guy. No one can see me but you.
Remember?
Oh, hi.
AL: Sit down, already.
I left in a hurry yesterday.
I forgot a few of the rules.
Numero uno:
don't tell anyone about us.
Now, I heard you already told
the little kid and el capit¹n.
But nobody else.
We hate recognition.
We're a very sensitive group.
If people know we're around,
I wouldn't be able to get an angel...
within a mile of this team.
Okay. Uh, are you guys
gonna help out today?
We'll see.
We never make commitments.
We go and come and come and go.
We're a capricious crowd.
Wh-- What's cap--
What's-- What's capricious?
Just keep your chin up and your
eyes open and enjoy the game.
- Aah!
- (GASPS)
You popped Al!
- Who's Al?
- Al's the boss angel.
- He was just here, but he's gone now.
- Next time will you tell me sooner?
I'd like to try and see one.
ROGER: Mr Knox, over here!
Over here! Over here, Mr Knox!
Mr Knox, Mr Knox, over here!
Mr Knox, come on,
come on! Mr Knox!
I just saw an angel!
- You saw an angel?
- Yeah. In my Coke cup.
- In your Coke cup?
- Yeah.
Okay.
I gotta get back to the dugout.
What should I do
if I see another one?
Kid, I was thinking of you
as a sort of good luck charm...
not as someone
who spiritually hallucinates.
What's that?
It means if you see anything
weird, keep it to yourself.
But wait! You should know.
You're the manager,
and the angels are here to help...
and if I don't tell you,
you're not gonna know--
Calm down.
In baseball, we got signals.
Make some kind of signal.
Okay? I can't come over here
every couple of seconds.
Um, I'll go like that, okay?
Oh, okay. You do that.
That's fine. Okay.
And we--
And we can't let David know.
Yeah, right. Absolutely.
We can't tell David.
Can't tell anyone.
Thank you.
- Here.
- Yeah.
Thanks.
Thanks. Oh, and excuse me, David,
wh-- where are the nachos?
(CRUNCH)
I'm saving them for later.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
- Sorry!
(LAUGHING CONTINUES)
ANNOUNCER: Number 17,
first baseman Tom Brewer.
RANCH: Bass takes the sign.
Here's the pitch.
And it's lined to left...
- for another base hit.
- AUBREY: Oh, no!
- Shit! Damn!
- So it's more bad news...
- Shit!
- for manager Knox...
as he does his dance
in the dugout.
RANCH: Mapel waits for the pitch.
- Strike!
- GEORGE: Strike?
Aw, come on, now!
That's no strike!
If that was a strike, th-th-th-then you
blind as a horse's ass!
(GASPS)
GEORGE: Jesus! Come on.
Let me have some-- Gimme this.
- Mr Knox.
- I want your hats off.
- Yeah?
- It's nacho butt.
Go buy the kids nachos.
Anything but nachos.
- Buy them Angels jackets.
- It's 90 degrees outside.
Get your butt up there, now!
- (SIGHS)
- You know, uh,
it's been four innings,
and no real angels yet.
And, you know, I was just thinking,
maybe you shouldn't swear so much.
I bet the angels don't like it.
Sh-Shoot!
Get on, you stupid sons of--
I'm kiddin'!
Man, he is a deadbeat, this one.
Let's keep the profanity down!
- Huh?
- I mean it! No swearin'!
That eliminates all speech
for most of the team.
RANCH: So here in the ninth,
the Athletics have opted
to bring in reliever...
Tom Ruddy to pitch
to Angels heavy hitter
Ray Mitchell.
- Oh-ho, wow!
- What happened?
There's an angel
right next to Hemmerling.
Uh, David, I-I need a drink.
- You have drinks.
- I don't want these.
- I want something else.
- What else?
Uh, coffee.
You drink coffee?
- Yeah. Of course. All the time.
- Yeah, all the time.
What do you think we are,
little kids or something?
Now, get me a cup or I'll scream.
How do you take it?
In cups.
ROGER: Mr Knox! Mr Knox!
Come over here. We got one!
Hey.
What's goin' on?
- There's an angel with Hemmerling.
- What?
There's an angel massaging
Hemmerling's shoulders.
(SIGHS)
This is ridiculous. I don't know
what you see,
but there's no one
with Hemmerling.
ROGER: She's rubbin'
his shoulders.
- Huh?
- A-A-And what should I do about it?
Put him in.
Pinch-hit.
I-I got Mitchell coming up.
He's my best hitter.
Hemmerling can't hit
the broad side of a barn.
I can't substitute my worst hitter
for my best hitter.
If you want a hit,
you'll put in Hemmerling.
It's crazy! Wacko.
- You forget about it. Ah!
- But he's got an angel.
Wait a minute. What's the worst thing
that could happen?
Are we gonna fall
out of last place? Heh.
Sit down, Mitchell.
You're up, Hemmerling.
ALL: Huh?
- What are you talkin' about?
- Yeah, what are you talking about?
You heard what I said.
You're out and you're in.
- You gotta be stupid!
- Hey, get your stuff!
- Right.
- (LAUGHING)
- Damn! Damn!
- Aah! Aah!
As Mitchell was getting ready
to lead off,
Knox has suddenly
decided to pinch-hit.
And he's bringing in Danny Hemmerling,
the utility infielder...
who is known, sports fans, for his
glove, but definitely not for his bat.
Hemmerling for Mitchell?
Go back to Cincinnati!
- Strike!
- (CROWD BOOING)
Where they go?
- Damn!
- UMPIRE: Strike!
GEORGE: See the pitch?
VERNE: Oh, my gosh!
Holy cow! Are you kidding me?
What the--
- (SINGING) For goodness sake
- VERNE: Oh, wow!
I got the hippy-hippy shakes
Yeah, I got the shakes
- Ah, I can't stand still
- Go, go! Come on! Come on!
ALL: Unh!
Hey-Hey, uh--
- Yeah, I get my fill now
- ALL: Aah!
- Whoa!
- Unh!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Yeah, it's in the back
- MAN: Ah-ha!
- Ooh, the hippy-hippy shakes
(ALL SHOUTING)
Unhh!
Go, go, go!
- VERNE: He may score.
- UMPIRE: Throw it! Safe!
- VERNE: He will score!
- BOTH: Yeah!
RANCH: Hemmerling scores
for the first time this season,
and the Angels win the game.
This will go down
in the record books.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is unbelievable!
This is insanity! I've never
seen anything like this.
And, obviously, neither
have these umps.
I don't know. (WHISTLES)
ROGER: Yeah!
Yeah! All right! Whoo-hoo!
Something's going on
with this kid.
(PLAYERS CHEERING)
Ladies and gentlemen, can we now say
the Angels are on a winning streak?
Or were these last few games
just a small blip on the screen
of a terminally ill patient?
Only time will tell.
What is going on?
Where are my stats? I'm on the air!
- My ass is hanging on the air...
- No, it's not!
and there are no stats.
There were how many errors?
- There were a lot of errors, Ranch.
- Not as many as in this booth.
Let me tell you, this is not baseball.
This is not baseball.
- Ow!
- Hey, David!
Whatever your duties were before,
forget 'em.
From now on, these boys
will be at all our games.
- BOTH: All right!
- That's your job.
Mr Knox, I want to remind you, you are
gonna fire me on Friday, aren't you?
- You've bonded with the boys.
- Bonded?
- Hey, you're gonna stick around, David.
- Yeah, stick around, David.
- Hey, you got job security.
- Job security?
- (SHUTS DOOR)
- Who knew?
So, you're right.
Hemmerling came through.
- Yeah, 'cause of the angel.
- Aw, whatever.
- No, we got angels helping the team.
- Ah, well, that may be,
but we're winning.
Yeah.
All the games, man!
Can you believe it?
GEORGE: When we're on the road,
you should watch the games on TV.
We'll figure out a way
for us to talk on the phone.
You mean, the phone in the dugout
you're always yelling into...
and-and banging against
the wall and spitting at?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, that phone.
Cool! (LAUGHS)
What a game. First time Hemmerling
got a hit, let alone a home run.
It's 'cause of the angels.
They helped him.
Get in.
Come on.
We don't have all day.
- J.P. doesn't ride in cars.
- What's the problem? He gets carsick?
ROGER: Sort of.
He used to live
in a car with his mom.
He slept in the front seat
all curled up like a cat or something.
When he gets in a car,
his stomachache comes back.
(BUS HONKS)
(OPENS DOOR)
- I'll call you tomorrow.
- All right.
- Thank you for the ride home.
- He speaks?
(CLOSES DOOR)
- Hi. You guys have a good time?
- Hi.
- A blast!
- We won!
- Great.
- Where's Miguel?
I got him all sorts of stuff.
Miguel got placed in a foster home
this afternoon.
- He got placed?
- Miguel's gone?
Mmm-hmm.
Where? With who?
A real nice family
from Northridge.
I'm gonna miss him.
I really liked Miguel!
I only have a licence
for short-term care.
You know? M-Miguel's been here
for, what, six months?
- I think seven.
- Seven months. Right.
That's what happens, you know?
I mean, you understand that, Roger.
Oh, don't feel bad, Maggie.
I bet we see him again.
Maybe in court or something.
Oh, Roger.
God forbid.
- JP: Roger?
- ROGER: What?
Are you asleep?
If I was asleep,
how'd I be talkin' to you?
You could be "sleeptalking."
(SIGHS) Look, I'll give you a dime tomorrow
ifyou don't say another word.
Okay.
JP: Roger?
(SIGHS)
You can forget that dime.
Do you think your parents
are gonna ever come get you?
I don't know. Mom's not alive,
but my dad's gonna come get me.
ROGER: I'm sure of it.
You think my mom's
gonna ever come get me?
Maybe, you know.
It could happen.
Yeah, it could happen.
- JP: Roger?
- What?
I'm happy you see the angels.
Me too.
JP: Good night.
RANCH: It's a beautiful day
here in Anaheim...
as the resurgent Angels
prepare to meet their longtime
nemesis, the Detroit Tigers...
who have won the first five games
of their Western road trip.
WALLY: They've been the hottest team in the
league for the last few weeks, Ranch.
ANNOUNCER: Ladies and gentlemen, a reminder:
the most popular--
...coming up next week
with Cap Night...
this year featuring a totally white cap
with red pinstripes and the Angel logo.
It's free for the first 50, 000 fans
entering Anaheim Stadium.
- I see an angel.
- Already?
I gotta go bathroom. I can't go alone.
Bad guys might get me.
We just came back
from the bathroom.
- Gotta go now. Sorry.
- Gimme your Coke.
Gimme the Cracker Jacks.
Stand up.
DAVID: Go.
- What's-- What's up?
- We got an angel.
But the game hasn't started.
She was with Mel Clark.
Aah! Impossible.
She was there. That means Mel
should start the game today.
- Mel's arm is gone.
- I don't care. He should start the game.
Uh-uh. No way! And besides,
he's not even on the active roster.
If the angel pitches with him,
he'll be awesome.
You really do see something,
don't you?
Yeah, I do.
Good. All right.
You're off injured reserve
and you're starting today.
- You talkin' to me?
- Yeah.
So get your stuff together.
RANCH: Starting pitcher announced
for this game was Dan Prince...
but just moments ago,
the Angels made a dramatic change...
and activated the
long-injured Mel Clark.
League rules specify that up
until the first pitch is thrown,
the roster can be altered...
although I can't ever remember
this happening so near game time.
- Me neither, Ranch.
- Easy, Wally. Less is more.
These warm-ups
should be interesting.
Over the plate, Mel!
- WALLY: Clark looks a little rusty.
- MEL: Unh!
RANCH: Too much time
in the whirlpool, Wally.
I'm checking to see if Dan Prince
pulled a muscle during his warm-up.
There must be some logical explanation
as to why George Knox...
would make such a bizarre change.
I have personally checked
the stats, sports fans...
and Mel Clark hasn't started a game...
In this decade.
WALLY: He looks mighty
nervous out there.
RANCH: Not as nervous
as George Knox.
RANCH: Clark takes the sign.
Talk about heat!
- Messmer felt that one.
- Ow!
- VERNE: Oh, my gosh! Holy cow!
- Wow!
- Are you kidding me?
- What an amazing pitch!
You damn-- darn right.
(LAUGHS)
RANCH: Well, commit that
to memory, Wally...
'cause he doesn't have
any more of those in him.
- An angel helped out on that one.
- Good.
- MEL: Unh!
- VERNE: Got it!
Strike!
- MEL: Unh!
- BRENT: Got it!
- Strike!
- (CHEERING)
Mel!
Way to go!
All right, Mel!
Unh!
Unh! Unh! Unh!
BRAD: Got it!
It's now the top of the ninth. There
are two outs. We've got a full count.
This could be the Tigers' last
chance to get back...
- in this ball game.
- One more! One more!
Unh!
- VERNE: Got it!
- ROGER: Yeah! Yeah!
I told you!
RANCH: That's the game! The Angels win
one-nothing in a miracle shutout...
pitched by the veteran Mel Clark.
(PLAYERS CHEERING)
- All right, Mel! - Good game!
- Yeah! Yeah!
It's unbelievable.
How in the world did
old noodle-arm pull that off?
And who gets the credit?
George Knox. George Knox.
And we're down in the Angels' clubhouse
for a talk with manager George Knox.
- What inspired you to start Mel?
- A feeling.
An instinct. A kind of faith.
A faith in what? Has Mel shown
this kind of power in practice?
Mel Clark has always shown himself
to be an extraordinary athlete.
The rest is about believing
in something or someone.
And when did you suddenly start
believing in Clark?
He's been sitting on
the bench all season.
- I look for signs.
- It's good to win.
GEORGE: And sometimes they come
from unexpected places.
Look, that's enough out of me for today.
Talk to the star of the game.
Excuse me.
Something's goin' on.
- Mel! You talk to us about the game.
- Yeah!
Well, it-- it feels great
to be a winner again.
- We won! - (CHUCKLES)
- Yeah. Three in a row.
- Oh, I feel good!
- Yeah. Me too.
- Me three.
- Ah, I owe you guys.
GEORGE: Okay. Anything you want.
You name it, you got it.
(JAZZ PLAYING)
- All right, let's play ball!
- BOYS: Yeah!
- I got third!
- Spread out, guys.
(EXCLAMING)
(BOYS CLAMORING)
Slow and easy.
Keep your elbows up.
Here it comes.
Great hit, JP!
Get it, Roger! Get it! Get it!
Yeah! All right!
-All right, J.P.
-All right! Who's next?
BOYS: Me! Me! Me!
Me! Me! Me!
Let's give the kid
over on the car a shot.
BOYS: Aww!
- What's your name?
- Marvin Vincent Archer.
You play any ball before, Marvin?
No, I never played any ball.
Well, this is a perfect time to learn.
Come on.
- GEORGE: Watch the ball...
- ROGER: Stay sharp, Zack.
and when I say "now," you swing.
GEORGE: Just do exactly what I say.
Get ready to swing.
- Now! Oh, oh!
- Yeah, Marvin!
Go, Marvin! Run to first base.
- Nice one. Go!
- Nice hit, nice hit.
You stay on base
and do just what I say.
Okay.
We got runners on first and second.
And look who's comin' to bat--
Babe Ruth.
(GROWLS)
- (GRUNTS)
- Whoa!
Go, Marvin! Run home!
- Run home?
- Run home!
Run home. Run home.
MARVIN: Run home. Run home.
GEORGE: Hey, Marvin,
where ya going?
MARVIN: Run home. Run home.
GEORGE: Hey. W-Where's he goin'?
- Eh, what happened?
- You told him to run home.
- I--
- He did.
(GEORGE LAUGHING)
WHIT: Unh!
(CHEERING)
(PLAYING "TAKE ME
OUT THE BALL GAME")
- Aaaaaah! Unhh!
- Verne: Oh, wow!
(LAUGHS)
(LAUGHING CONTiNUES)
GEORGE: You call that a call?
You call that a call?
In all my years of baseball,
I have never seen such a--
such an astute evaluation...
of a potentially
difficult decision.
Masterful call.
Oh, have a nice day.
Aah!
Fair ball!
Yeow!
TRISCUIT: Aaaaaaah!
- VERNE: Oh, wow!
- UMPIRE: Safe!
Yeah! Yeah!
Whooooo!
- Yeah!
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
Here you go, black man.
- Thanks!
- Thanks, Mel!
- Hey!
- (LAUGHS)
Oh! It's-
VERNE: Oh, wow!
- ALL: Aah!
- RANCH: Unbelievable!
- VERNE: Yes! Yes!
- GARY: Wow!
Get out of the way!
AUBREY: Yes!
VERNE: He's got a
man wide open!
ALL: Yeah!
(KISSES)
VERNE: He's got a
man wide open!
- You're outta there!
- Yeah! Hey?
No?
VERNE: Got it!
- VERNE: Got it!
- GARY: My, my!
(ALL CHEERING)
- (SNAP)
- VERNE: Got it!
- AUBREY: Oh, my god!
I got it!
RANCH: The Angels have closed out the
season with an incredible hot streak.
Who would have believed they could go
from last place at the All-Star break...
to just one win away
from clinching the division title?
Now it all comes down
to the last two games of the season...
and, ironically, they are with the
defending champion Chicago White Sox...
who are one game back
and closing fast...
in a determined effort
to deny the Angels the championship.
The first ofthose crucial games
takes place right here...
this afternoon.
- What's it say?
- Thanks. Bye.
ROGER: Van's gonna
pick us up at 12:00.
- Rog-- Stupid thing. Roger.
- (DIALS PHONE)
- ROGER: Huh?
- That was your social worker.
What does she want?
MAGGIE: Your hearing's
been changed to this afternoon.
- But I got a game this afternoon.
- I know.
I've just tried everything to get 'em
to reschedule. It's just not possible.
Maggie, I'm not going.
You don't have a choice,
sweetheart.
Well, what about George?
What about the Ang-
I'll call Mr Knox.
I know he thinks you guys
are his lucky charms...
but this is just something
you have to do.
JP can go to the game,
and we'll just try real hard...
to get you there before it's over.
It's all I can do.
ROGER: Aw, man!
And what about the game?
ANNOUNCER: Attention,
youngsters age 6 to 16...
be sure to join the
Junior Angel Fan Club.
For just five dollars,
you'll receive game tickets...
baseball cards, a free autograph--
RANCH: The Southern California
sun is shining, the field is ready...
the hot dogs are warm, and there's
not an empty seat in the house.
I know. I know.
Don't even say it. A large Coke,
two dogs, three Cracker Jacks.
And I was thinking of getting him a car.
And maybe a corporate jet.
- And maybe a--
- S-Still no Roger.
He'll be here any second.
Of all the days to haul
the kid off to court.
Why didn't Maggie say
he was sick or somethin'?
That'd be lying.
Maggie would never lie.
Well, Maggie's not
in a pennant race.
ANNOUNCER: Number 19,
third baseman Bruce Shea.
- Hey, you don't see anything, do you?
- Maybe.
Huh?
Sorry.
Well, it's not your fault.
You never seen angels before.
Why should you now?
Hey, it could happen.
(PEOPLE TALKING)
You understand that once
this hearing has established...
Roger's permanent
placement status...
his welfare will forever forward
be determined by this court.
- I understand.
- And you've consulted a lawyer?
Look, lady, I get what I'm doin'.
The kid's not mine any more.
I'm not proud of it.
It's not something I could
change my mind about either.
We're ready to see you now, Roger.
Dad?
ROGER: Dad, I didn't know
you were gonna be here!
You know the Angels are
only one game from the pennant?
Can you believe it?
It's just like you said!
- Sorry, boy.
- Dad?
Hey, Dad, wh--
Did you hear what I said?
Where ya goin'?
Daddy?
- Don't cry.
- Come back.
(CRYING)
(THUMPING)
- (CRYING) But, we lost!
- Don't cry. I-It's only a game.
Come on. You're getting snot all over
the place. It's nobody's fault.
I tried to see angels.
I really tried.
I guess without angels helping,
this team doesn't have what it takes.
Maybe I just don't
have what it takes.
JP: If we could still win
without the angels. It could happen.
Maybe. Eh, gimme a minute, kid,
and I'll be out to take you home.
But, don't cry.
MAN: No, we're not.
Hey, put out that cigarette.
Hey.
RANCH: I'm Ranch Wilder the
voice of the Angels.
I know who you are.
I heard you on the radio.
JP: You sure do
have a big chin.
Everybody's a critic.
- Well, what's your name?
- JP.
RANCH: Well, J.P., that was
a tough loss today, huh?
Knox took it pretty hard.
He was gettin' kinda crazy out there.
'Cause Roger couldn't come.
I get it. So Roger's sort of lucky.
Is that it?
He sees the angels, the ones
who help out. He prayed for 'em.
- Real angels?
- Yeah, but I don't see 'em.
And Knox-- he sees 'em?
No!
Roger has to tell him
when they're around.
Really?
MAGGIE: You know,
by releasing you legally...
it does make it possible for somebody
to take you permanently.
He did that 'cause he wants
the best for you.
Yeah. Givin' someone away is
a great way to show 'em you care.
- Hey, Roger!
- Took a little longer than you expected.
We waited three hours for his hearing.
That's quick for family court.
- What'd they decide?
- Oh, it's just a formality.
(CLOSES DOOR)
He belongs to the state
of California now.
Scoot over.
Roger, I'm sorry about today.
Why? 'Cause you lost
your stupid baseball game?
No. Because you're hurt.
(SCOFFS) You don't
know anything about it.
You know, Roger, when I was growin' up,
I never saw very much of my dad.
GEORGE: He couldn't
take care of himself...
so takin' care of me and my brothers
was outta the question.
I'm not sure the pain
that caused ever goes away.
But I am sure you can't
go through life...
thinkin' everyone you meet
will one day let you down.
Because if you do,
a very bad thing will happen.
You'll end up like me.
I'm goin' inside.
I thought you said you
had to be somewhere.
I do. Right here.
- Yuck!
- You both wash your hands?
- Yep.
- Okay, then, let's dig in.
GEORGE: Next time I'll try lasagna.
You guys like lasagna?
BOTH: No. What is it?
JP: Look. It's God's thumbnail.
That's just the moon, JP.
No God up there.
(BASEBALL THUMPING)
I can't believe you said that.
The kid who sees angels.
I don't believe
in angels any more.
JP: Roger, what are
you talking about?
That's okay, JP.
Roger's had a tough day.
(ROGER SIGHS)
"The source says there's
a boy known as Roger--
Even watches games on TV
when the team is out of town...
and reports to manager Knox
over the phone."
What's a source?
- The person who told.
- Oh.
"And when Mel Clark made his
amazing comeback in August...
it was Roger's--
it was Roger's idea to start him."
- That's me.
- Who do you think told?
I don't know. Maybe David found out.
I don't see how.
- JP: Are we in trouble?
- Knox is in trouble, that's for sure.
This is bad, right?
I'm gonna have to tell Maggie.
(JP SIGHS)
WOMAN: Right this
way, Mr Knox.
You stood me up last night.
HANK: What in the Sam Hill is
all this about real angels?
- It's nothing.
- Start talkin'.
Okay. I-- I got these two kids.
And I-I think of them as mascots.
And the angels-- Uh, well--
It's just something that's
going on between me and them.
HANK: You're tellin' me there's
real angels in the ball park?
Sometimes.
But they're not in on all the plays.
(CHUCKLES)
- You've lost it, partner.
- Look, if I lied to you...
then the angels wouldn't like it,
and they might not come back.
They're very temperamental.
Mental is the key word here.
I'm sorry, George, but I'm relieving you
ofyour management responsibilities.
You can't do that.
We're only one game away.
I tell you what. I'll give you 24 hours
to get your head on straight.
Then I'll call a press conference.
And you can publicly
renounce this hogwash.
HANK: George, you repeat any of
the baloney I've heard here...
we're talkin' the end of
your career in baseball.
HANK: Have I made myself clear?
Yes.
MAN: What's goin' on, Knox?
Good morning, ladies and gentlemen.
We're gonna make this short and sweet.
My manager, George Knox here,
has something he'd like to say to ya.
- George.
- I have a statement I'd like to read.
There have been reports...
that I've been using angels
to help the team win.
MAGGIE: Go on. Go in.
(ALL CLAMORING)
I was gonna read a statement...
but instead,
I'm gonna shoot from the hip.
You know, there are
a lot of times in sports...
when there's no logical explanation
why things happen.
GEORGE: Sometimes a
player gets hot and...
goes beyond their physical ability.
Is it just adrenaline?
I don't know.
But I do believe
there are times in life...
where something stronger, higher...
or maybe spiritual is with us.
GEORGE: I can't explain it, but something has
happened to my players this year...
something that's changed
the way they play...
and the way I manage.
You can call it faith.
You can call it angels.
You can call it whateveryou want.
That's all I have to say.
RANCH: George, does this mean
you really think...
that a kid sees angels
at your games?
(CLEARS THROAT)
Excuse me.
I'd, uh-- I'd like to say something
on behalf of George Knox.
Uh, what's your name?
What's your business here?
My name is Maggie Nelson.
I take care of foster kids.
MAGGIE: One of these boys is, uh,
the child who can see angels.
He could stand up right now
and tell you exactly what's happened...
and I know you'd just laugh at him.
But, when a professional football player
drops to one knee to thank God...
after making a touchdown,
nobody laughs at that.
Or when a pitcher crosses himself
before going to the mound?
Nobody laughs at that either.
Seems like you're saying
it's okay to believe in God...
but it's not okay
to believe in angels.
Uh, I thought they were
on the same team.
Is it your belief, ma'am,
that, uh, angels play baseball?
Since the All-Star break, yes.
(ALL LAUGHING)
We all need somebody
to watch out for us.
Every kid I have
ever taken care of...
has been looking for
someone to love-- an angel.
You gotta have faith.
MAGGIE: You gotta believe.
You gotta look inside yourself.
The footprints
of an angel are love.
And where there is love,
miraculous things can happen.
I've seen it.
I'd also like
to say something.
MEL: I don't know if there
are angels out there...
other than the 25 of us
in uniform...
but I know there is
one thing I won't do.
I won't play for anyone
but George Knox. I believe in him.
That goes for me too.
(ALL CLAMORING)
Thank you. All of you.
Print what you want. George Knox
is the manager of the ball club.
- (ALL CHEERING)
- And if there are any angels out there...
sure hope they're on our side.
(CHEERING CONTINUES)
DAVID: Oh, yeah!
Yeah! Yes!
RANCH: Good evening, everyone,
and welcome to downtown Anaheim...
where there are no seats
left in sports heaven...
as a sell-out crowd fills the ball park
for the final game of the season.
Tonight, George Knox will send
his Angels, real or imagined...
out against
a tough White Sox team...
to determine who will be
the Western Division champion.
GEORGE: When I came here this season,
I didn't believe in you guys.
I didn't believe in anything.
But when you stood up this morning...
you gave me back
my reason to believe.
I'm more proud of bein' a part of
this team than any team I've been on.
You're all winners,
and I believe in you!
So let's go out there
and show them what winners can do!
- Let's take that championship!
- Yeah! Yeah!
- All right! You're so fantastic!
- MEL: Okay, you heard him. Let's go!
ANNOUNCER: Ladies and gentlemen,
your California Angels.
(ALL CHEERING)
RANCH: Starting pitcher
for this crucial game...
is the veteran Mel Clark.
- Yeah!
- All right!
He's been their hottest pitcher since
he returned to the line-up in July.
RANCH: So, Clark's have a rocky
start here in the first.
He's got runner's a second and third
with two outs,
And Darren at bat.
Darren tries the ball to left.
It's fair!
One run will score, and
here comes Cooper.
Norton get's to it.
It's gonna be close.
Here come the ball...
- Copper slides, he's safe!
- AUBREY: No!
RANCH: The fans don't like the call.
But the Sox go up 2 to nothing,
And we're still in the top in the verse.
- You got 'em, Mel!
- (SIGHS)
Clark pitches to Young.
He loops one over second base
and here comes Garcia!
- VERNE: Oh, wow!
- RANCH: Whoa! Garcia makes a...
spectacular save
to end the inning!
Yeah! Yeah!
RANCH: With the Angels
behind 2 to nothing...
Clark's really struggling with
one out in the top of the fifth...
And a man on first and second
Beasley comes to bat.
Anybody got any uh-No?
RANCH: No question he's tiring, Wally.
And Knox knows it. Ball one.
That expected this there
getting Teller up now...
In the ballpen.
RANCH: Whoa! Mitchell makes a great
play makes the force at third.
GEORGE: All right, all right, all right
all right, all right.
All right.
RANCH: Here in the sixth...
Garcia's on first with the
single as the Angels trying...
To battle away back
into the ball game.
That brings up Ray Mitchell.
Ray's been hot as wild far
this second half of this...
- miraculous season.
- But as many you've known...
In the past, Mitchell is choked.
When it came from
real pressure situation.
(SHOUTING) You got the one, Ray?
GEORGE: You hear me?
You can do it!
RANCH: Mitchell connects...
It's hit deep...
Go, go, go, go, go!
- And It's gone!
- VERNE: Got it!
- AUBREY: Oh, my god!! I got it!
- RANCH: Ray Mitchell has just hit...
a monster home run with the man on
to tie the game here in the sixth.
VERNE: Oh, my gosh! Holy cow.
Are you kidding me?
(ALL CHEERING)
RANCH: Clark has it's back to
the wall here in the seventh...
As the Sox was threading again
with two man on base.
Okay. Holding on, holding on.
Holding on. Huh!
Hang it in there.
Clark definitely could use an angel now,
as he's tiring...
late in the game.
BRENT: Intercepted!
Yeah! Yeah!
WALLY: There seems to be some sort
of magic in the way his team
is supporting him, Ranch.
- Hey, kid. How you doin'?
- Fine. Al!
Hey, kiddo, sharp outfit.
I wish I had one.
Thanks. Gee, I am
glad to see you.
You know, I was afraid you guys
wouldn't show up today since...
you know, a lot of people
know about the angels now.
No one's coming. Championships have
to be won on their own. It's a rule.
Oh. Well, then,
what are you doing here?
I came here to check on Mel.
He's comin' up soon.
- He's gonna be one of us.
- Y-You mean he's--
Ah, he smoked for  years.
It's always a mistake.
AL: He's got six months left.
He doesn't know anything's wrong yet.
- No.
- Don't you worry.
He's well taken care of.
You concentrate on your own life now.
We expect great things from you, kid.
We'll all be watching.
Remember that. Even though you can't
see us, we're always watching.
(SIGHS)
RANCH: With the man on and
one out in the eighth.
Clark is showing definite
science of photic.
As he pitches to Marge.
Ball three.
Take your time, Clark.
BOY: We're ready to go, guys!
RANCH: Here's the pitch.
And Marge grounds to Martinez
they get Darren in second.
- Garcia throws, Double play!
- AUBREY: Yes!
- Yeah!
- And once again sulled defense...
barrels Clark out of the jam!
RANCH: It's still tied up here
in the bottom of the eighth.
but the Angels have Garcia at bat
and Martinez on third...
with the go ahead run.
Martinez goes on the pitch!
Garcia bunts!
There's a screen's play.
Here's the throw.
- VERNE: Oh, wow!
- Martinez scores!
And the Angels take the lead!
Yeah!
Unh!
RANCH: Messmer pops out to
Gaboyan to end the inning.
So as were in the ninth
the Angels are only three outs
away from the pennant...
if they can just hold on
to this 3 to 2 lead.
Hey, Mel.
- Let's finish this.
- We got 'em.
All right. All right,
three outs, boys.
Let's do it!
RANCH: So the championship
on the line...
manager George Knox elects
to send a tired Mel Clark...
out to face the heart of
the White Sox's lineup.
(SCOFFS) He's all alone.
Let's go.
Come on, Angels.
Don't worry. He'll get an angel.
Mel always gets an angel.
RANCH: Clark takes the sign
for his first pitch to Gasper.
Let's see if he has
anything left.
Gasper gets a piece of it.
And it balls in
for the single.
The tying run is
now on first.
RANCH: They're getting Sanford
up in the bullpen.
(COUGHING)
Bee, bunt!
Clark feels it cleanly
and gets the runner at first.
But Gasper advances at second
on the sarifice.
One down.
The White Sox now have
the tying run and scoring...
position with Darren at bat.
It's in the hole.
Garcia dives.
- He gets it!
- AUBREY: Yes!
The grow is off-balance.
- Safe!
- Not in time!
Are you sure?
RANCH: But the go
ahead run is now on first.
With only one away.
RANCH: Clark looks very tired.
Gaboyan swings and smashes it
deep left center!
This is trouble! Williams
got a good jump on the ball!
Somebody better take charge!
VERNE: Oh, wow!
RANCH: And Ben Williams saves the game
for now with a spectacular catch.
WALLY: Had a great throw,
to hold the runner at third.
- Aah!
- Oh!
And he hits Birch
in the back on the first pitch.
That loads the bases.
and Kesey, the lead guard
beyond leader is up next.
ANNOUNCER: Number 32,
Kit "Hit or Die" Kesey.
(SPITS)
RANCH: I can't believe
he's leaving Clark in the game.
Any hit scores a run.
- There's an angel there now, right?
- No.
And the runners take their leads.
And Kesey got a good piece
of that one, but it's foul.
We've got one strike.
Sanford is ready
in the bullpen.
Ball one!
WALLY: His arm has to be tired.
He's thrown 156 pitches.
- Ball two!
- There's one comin', right, Roger?
I don't know, JP.
I-- I don't think so.
And Clark just misses nicking Kesey,
and the count goes to 3 and 1.
He's way behind
the batter now.
(GEORGE SIGHS)
Any angels?
No.
RANCH: And Kesey jumps on it!
This could be the game!
AUBREY: No!
It's deep! It's down the line!
If it stays fair, it's outta here!
- Foul! Foul! Foul!
- It's gonna be close.
- RANCH: But it's foul.
- AUBREY: Yeah, my god!
So it comes down to a full count.
Two outs, the top of the ninth.
The Angels lead by one run,
and for Mel Clark...
this is
the pressure cooker!
I gotta take him out.
(SIGHS) No. Please,
just let him try.
He's all used up.
He can't do it by himself.
Yes, he can.
All he has to do
is believe.
(GEORGE WHISPERING)
RANCH: And Knox
will pull Mel Clark.
All I can say is,
it's about time.
I got nothing left.
Yeah, you do.
You got one strike left.
(SIGHS)
You got an angel with you right now.
Just got here, and he's gonna help.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
- Kid sees an angel?
- Yeah, he must. That's the signal.
(THEME PLAYING)
Could happen.
- Okay.
- (LAUGHING)
Go get him
for the championship.
All right!
- All right! Come on, Mel!
- I'm so happy!
RANCH: Ladies and gentlemen,
I don't believe it...
Knox will let Clark stay in
to pitch to Kesey.
This is not smart baseball.
This is ridiculous.
Let's go, my brother.
Come on.
- (GRUNTS)
- AUBREY: Yes!
VERNE: Oh, my gosh!
Oh, my gosh! Oh, no!
GEORGE: Aaaaah!
RANCH: He's got it, and it's over!
He's got it!
- I can't believe it!
- WALLY: The Angels win the pennant!
We won!
All right, JP! We won, we won!
- JP: Yea! Yeah!
- AUBREY: Oh, my god!
- ROGER: Aaaah! Hoo-hoo!
- AUBREY: I got it!
- There are angels!
- Not this time, Mel.
You did it yourself.
Ha-ha! Aaaah!
- We won! We won!
- (CROWD CHEERING)
GEORGE: Whoo!
Aaaah!
- (THUD)
- (LAUGHING)
Yeah! Yeah!
- All right!
- Yeah! Yeah!
- Yes! (LAUGHING)
- I can't believe it!
Ranch.
- (CHEERING)
- You're fired.
You can't fire me!
I got a contract!
I'm Ranch Wilder!
Easy, Ranch. Less is more.
And the Angels have won it!
(CHEERING RESUMES)
- ROGER: Maggie! Maggie! We won!
- JP: Maggie!
- BOTH: We won! We won!
- I know. I heard. Oh, congratulations.
- The Angels won the pennant.
- It's great.
Well done. (KISSES)
Oh, Roger,
your social worker called.
She did?
- What'd they want?
- Was it about my father?
MAGGIE: No. But it is about
finding you a permanent home.
(CRIES)
Oh, JP. Come back.
JP! Come back.
(SLAMS DOOR)
You know, nothin' is probably
ever as good as your real parents.
But there's some people
who could care foryou...
and love you and
take care of you.
Yeah.
I guess so.
Roger, the person who
called Social Service--
that was me.
I wanna try to be a dad.
I want you to come
and live at my house.
You want-- You want--
Ahh.
- (CRIES)
- Okay, honey?
No way. I-I can't. I--
You know, I-I can't leave JP.
I-I could never leave JP.
He's comin' too.
- He is?
- I heard that.
- (GEORGE LAUGHING)
- (CROWD CHEERING)
- JP: Yeah!
- GEORGE: Aww!
- Wait. What about Maggie?
- No. My work is here.
Don't worry. There are plenty
of little angels looking for a home.
So-- So--
So we're gonna be a family.
Yeah.
JP: I'm gonna have a daddy.
- (AL SPARKLES)
- (GASPS)
I knew it could happen.
- (ALL LAUGHING)
- (THEME PLAYING)
We're always watching.
(PLAYING "TAKE ME
OUT TO THE BALLGAME")
(CROWD CHEERING)