Where are you?
Oh. Hello, beautiful.
[Kissing Sound]
Did you miss me?
Dad, I've given this
some thought...
and I've decided that since Damien
and Ralph have their own rooms,
well, there's no reason why they should
be bringing their junk into my room.
Well, how does that
sound, Helen?
- [Gulping]
- [Door Opening]
- Out of the way, stick boy!
- Hand & Foot is here to stay.
- Oops, kicked your baby monkey.
- Get out of here, Ralph!
- Here, take this.
- Go away, Damien. This is my room.
Was. Now it's also the world
headquarters of Hand & Foot, Incorporated.
- Hand & Foot all the way!
- Hand & Foot, Hand & Foot, Hand & Foot!
- Hand & Foot? You guys aren't gonna make a dime.
- Okay, we'll use this.
- Yeah!
- Hey, that's my life savings!
- Consider yourself our silent partner.
- Yeah, say something and you're dead.
- Yeah.
- How's the big move going?
- Great.
- Good.
Come on, Ralph.
Gotta get to work.
Dad?
[Clears Throat]
Dad...
well, I've given this
a lot of thought,
and I've decided that...
- s-s-since Damien and Ralph have their own room...
- Preston,
they need the space
for their business.
- Not my space.
- Young man, in this family, industry gets rewarded.
While you're in here playing,
your brothers are hard at work.
- Yeah, kissin' butt for money.
- [Ralph] Well, you know the golden rule.
- He who has the gold makes the rules.
- One day you'll have a job.
- When I was your age, I had my own business cleaning wheels.
- [Mimicking Dad]
I was pulling down 100 bucks a week
polishing cars.
- You used to say 75.
- Well, you gotta think big, Preston.
- Surprise.
- [Brothers] Whoa, check it out.
Yeah, it's for your business.
We had a spare at the office.
- Damien, the speakers are out in the hall.
- How does it work?
It imitates human intelligence,
like you guys.
- Preston, maybe you could teach your brothers how to use it.
- Not possible.
[Dad] The software will teach you how to
do everything but make love to a woman.
- Now I know what programme to get your father for Christmas.
- Mom!
- Oops! Uh, here. Let me help you with that.
- Preston, you're gonna be late...
- for Butch's birthday party.
- Who wants to celebrate Butch's birth?
- [Dad] It's important to get out of your room more.
- [Brothers] Our room.
Well, good luck, guys.
[Computer Beeps, Talks]
Damien and Ralph sleep...
butt to face, butt to face,
- butt to face,
- Huh? - Who said that?
- Butt to face, butt to face,
- Type "Quit." Hit "Delete."
- Butt to face, butt to face, butt to face...
- Turn it off! Pull the plug!
- Ow!
- Don't rub it. Be a man.
- [Moaning] Ouch!
- Little wimp.
[Dad] Come on, Preston. You don't want
to be late for Butch's birthday party.
- Are you gonna have fun today?
- [Preston] How can I, Dad?
- I don't have any money.
- Now, look. Here's a couple of bucks.
Ah, heck, you can have fun
all day on that.
You don't get out much,
do you, Dad?
[P.A.] Welcome to Fun Land.
Fun, fun, fun for everyone.
Welcome to Fun Land.
- Hey. Hey, man.
- Hey, Butch.
Hey, man. Yeah!
Hey, what's up?
Oh, look.
It's Presto the Pesto.
- Hello, Butch.
- [Kids Laughing]
Oh!
- Tokens!
- [Kids Cheering]
- Give me 50. It's my birthday.
- Fifty.
- Twenty-five, please.
- Twenty-five.
- Twenty-seven.
- Six, please.
- Six.
Six.
- Coming?
- I don't know.
[Screaming]
- [Shouting]
- It's gonna be awesome!
- Yeah, let's go over here!
- This one! - Hurry!
[Butch]
Hey, Preston! Hey, over here!
- Hey, Preston, how's your ostrich?
- Watch out!
Preston has an ostrich!
Hey, Preston,
come with us!
- Just kidding!
- [Laughing]
[Groaning]
[Dad] Did you have fun
at Butch's birthday party?
I have a question.
Are we broke?
- No, we just have to watch our spending habits.
- That's right.
Like when your mother calls her sister
back East and talks for 97 minutes.
So if we're not
poverty-stricken,
there must be some other
reason I'm so deprived.
- We're outta here! Whoo!
- Goin' to the ball game.
- Can I go?
- We bought tickets, toad.
- [Mother] Damien!
- You need some cash?
- Nah, we got a bunch of change.
- Later, Preston.
It's not fair.
Why can't I have anything?
Well, Preston, they have jobs,
and they've learned to save.
How can I save money
if I don't have any?
A penny saved
is a penny earned.
- What do you want for your birthday?
- Money...
so I can pay to have Ralph
and Damien knocked off.
Anything else?
Well, maybe we'll give him
one of his birthday presents early.
A gift came
from Grandma today.
Hmm. What a rip-off!
It's a cheque for nothing!
I'm having a bad day.
Oh, your grandma just forgot
to fill in how much it was for,
but she signed it
at the bottom, see?
It's a blank cheque.
- We'll just fill in the amount.
- How much did you get last year, honey?
A thousand.
- Ten dollars.
- Wait, Dad. What about inflation?
- Oh, make it 11.
- [Muttering]
You'd be surprised how fast...
eleven dollars can grow
with interest.
Preston?
[Preston]
Eleven dollars...
at 3.45 interest.
[Computer]
Your account will reach...
one million dollars...
in 342,506 years.
I'm stuck here forever.
- [Dad] Lights out up there.
- Why?
My house, my rules.
"My house, my rules."
My own house.
[Yawning]
[Engine Stops, Car Door Shutting]
[Man]
Dave, who needs assets? I'm your asset.
- I'm a big asset. Oh, c...
- [Man On Phone] I can't believe you.
Dave, Dave. Come on, come on.
Why only borrow 150,000?
Our money is your money.
Round it off to two.
- Do I qualify?
- Of course you qualify for the loan, Dave.
We're golf partners.
- You don't look happy to see me.
- Quig...
- Quigley.
That's funny. I don't remember you
stuttering on the witness stand.
- You just sang like a bird, didn't you?
- I had no choice, Carl.
- I mean, lying in court...
- You also pointed at me.
- That hurt.
- Well, I was under oath.
- I mean...
- Come here.
The only reason
you're alive, Biderman,
is I knew I might need you
again someday... like today.
Oh, sure. You need a loan?
The rates are great now.
- And you get a toaster.
- I don't need a toaster.
Before I went away, I put
aside a little nest egg.
[Gasping] These bills,
they're marked consecutively.
- They'd trace these in a minute.
- That's right.
- [Coughing]
- That's where you come in, old buddy. I want new bills.
- We're back in the S&L business, Biderman.
- Ah, money laundering...
- is very difficult these days, Carl.
- You still do it though, don't you?
That's a good-looking family
right there.
You're not gonna
hurt them, are you?
- Hate to have to.
- All right.
How do you want
to do this?
- I'll send my guy in tomorrow with a cheque for a million.
- Tomorrow?
Yep, just like the old days. You give him
the cash, unmarked, send him on his way.
- Whom should I expect?
- Whom should...
Whom should you expect?
His name is Juice.
- Juice?
- Mmm, he'll be here in exactly 24 hours.
Let's call it 1:00.
Come on. Walk me out.
Show a little respect.
Whoa.
I know how you feel.
- Hi.
- Hi. Can you see okay?
Oh, yeah.
Oh, yeah, sure.
I would like to open
an account, please.
Eleven dollars.
Do you have any other money
you'd like to deposit, Mr Waters?
Oh, uh, I could,
but it's sort of hard to save
around my house; that's why I'm here.
I'm afraid we have
a minimum balance. It's $200.
Two hundred dollars?
That could take
a million years.
Well, whenever you're ready,
please come back and see me.
My name's Shay Stanley.
- Ask for me.
- Okay, I'll do that.
- Thanks.
- Bye-bye.
- I-I'll see you next time.
- I hope it's not in a million years.
B-Bye-bye.
[Biderman]
Excuse me. Carl, Carl!
Here. You can use these cheques.
They're temporary.
- Thank you, Edward.
- Like our relationship.
- Sucker!
- Give me that!
- [Laughing]
- Give it to me!
Butch, give it to me!
- Preston, come on!
- Butch!
- Give it back! Whoa!
- If you can catch me!
Come on, Butch!
[Control Panel Dings, Engine Revs]
[Preston Screams]
- [Screaming]
- [Tyres Screeching]
Perfect.
What the hell do you
think you're doing?
L... l...
- Huh?
- [Butch] I saw the whole thing.
- I can be a witness if the price is decent.
- Get outta here.
He's perfectly all right,
aren't you? Aren't you?
- Yes.
- Good. Get that thing out from underneath my car.
What about my bike?
- Kid, was I the one that parked there...
- Oh, my word!
- Are you all right?
- He's fine. It was just a little accident. He's okay.
- I think this guy's been drinking vodka.
- I have not been drink...
[Laughs] I don't drink at all.
Seriously, seriously.
Kid, talk to me.
How much you want for the bike?
- A thousand bucks.
- I'm not talking to you!
Bye, kid.
Go on. Walk away.
What do you want, kid?
Name a figure, we'll discuss it.
Give this to your dad. He'll know
what to do with it. I gotta go.
[Tyres Screeching]
[Tyre Squeaking]
Oh, man.
I thought we understood about
taking care of our valuables.
Valuable?
It was a piece of junk.
If that's how you feel
about a gift from your parents,
I don't see giving you
a new one for your birthday.
I don't want a new bike.
I want my own room.
I'm warning you. You're on thin ice
as it is about the bike.
You know what I want?
What I want
is my own house.
My rules, my money.
Listen, young man,
until further notice, you're grounded.
What'd I do wrong?
[Sighs]
Fred.
Hmm.
It's a blank cheque.
"[Computer Start-Up Tone]
Preston Waters.
Two hundred.
Hmm.
A thousand.
One million dollars.
Cash.
Whoa!
One million dollars.
[Electronic Zooming]
Hey, sonny.
Cashin' a big one today?
Uh, sort of.
Yoo-hoo.
Over here, young man.
- Well?
- I-I-I'd like to...
cash this cheque, please.
Oh, a comedian.
[Laughing]
- N-No, ma'am.
- Okay, then we better take it to Mr Biderman. Come on!
- [Ticking]
- [Door Opening]
Excuse me, Mr Biderman.
We have a little problem here.
What is it, Mrs Udowitz?
- Someone thinks this is some kind of game.
- What?
Let me see that.
I see.
Is there much of a line
out there, Mrs Udowitz?
- Yes, we're swamped.
- Then what are you doing here?
Please.
[Door Closes]
- Juice?
- No, thanks, I'm not thirsty.
Not thirsty.
Mr Quigley give you
this cheque?
He did.
How did you
run into Mr Quigley?
I didn't.
He ran into me.
Aha.
[Snickering]
[Laughing]
Brilliant. Brilliant!
- [Groans]
- I suppose you want big bills.
Actually, regular size
would be okay.
Regular.
Hmm.
That's cute.
Put your backpack
on the table.
Hey, hey.
I assume you know
what to do with this.
- Uh-huh. Yeah.
- Uh-huh.
Next!
Look here, sweetheart.
Mmm, you're lookin' kind of good there.
You got your pearls
and everything on.
Hate for something
to have to happen to 'em.
Look here,
my name is Juice...
and I got something right here,
and I wondered...
if you'd be so kind enough
as to cash it for me.
What do you want?
A million bucks?
Well, as a matter of fact,
I do.
[Sighs]
Go see Biderman.
Mm-mm.
Oh, my goodness gracious.
Here we go.
You tell Mr Quigley that
he hasn't lost his touch.
- Uh-huh.
- All right. You can go now.
Hey, kid!
- Stay away from the racetrack.
- Yes, sir.
Good one, man.
Looking good.
Mmm. Oh!
Excuse me, sweetie.
[Gasps]
- What's wrong with you, little boy?
- [Preston] I'm sorry.
Don't be messin' up a view
as good as all that.
- I-I'm sorry.
- What you doin' out of school anyway, huh?
You know you oughta
be in school.
Go on and get up outta here
before I start to get upset.
Hurry up.
How, uh...
How may I help you, sir?
I'm big Juice, man.
Quigley sent me.
Everything is fine.
- Not to worry.
- Uh-huh.
Yeah!
- The Eagle has landed.
- Hmm?
The horse is in the barn.
The chicken...
is in the pot.
Look here, man, I don't know nothin'
about no eagles landin' and all of that.
I don't know nothin'
about no horse runnin' through the barn.
And I certainly don't know nothin'
about no... chickens bein' in the pot.
You understand?
But if you do me a favour...
as to be so kind as to cash
this cheque right there,
- I could be on my way.
- Wait.
- Quigley sent you?
- That's right.
- What about the kid?
- What kid? Man...
The kid! The kid
with the backpack!
Look here, man.
I'm tired of tellin' you this.
But if you don't give me
the money for that cheque,
I guarantee there's a bullet
with your name on it in this chamber.
[Moaning]
The kid with the backpack.
The kid with the backpack!
The backpack!
Shit! Oh, my god!
[Quigley]
150 grand, cash.
- It's my last offer, guys.
- [Woman] You're our Realtor.
You tell us. This offer is so
much less than our asking price.
Well, Mrs Appleton,
it really is a buyer's market.
Do you mind if we take a minute
to think about it?
Listen, I got all the time
in the world, sweetheart.
Too bad I can't say
the same for you two.
Applesauce, what's
with the long face, my man?
I bought your pad. You've got some cash.
It's a beautiful thing.
Su casa is soon to be mi casa.
You know what I'm saying?
- Groovin' thing, man.
- Yeah, well...
[Dial Tone]
- " [Start-Up Tone]
- [Sighs]
[Phone Ringing]
- Hello.
- [Computer] Good afternoon.
...your house.
- [Computer Beeps]
I'd like to make
a cash offer on your house.
Someone else
wants to make an offer.
What?
On this dump?
- Uh, hello, sir. Can you hear me?
- Who is this yo-yo?
[Typing]
- [Computer] One-sixty.
- What kind of hustle is this?
And what's with
your voice, pal?
Sore throat-itis.
[Computer Coughs]
Yeah. I'll tell you what. One-seventy
right now, cash, and I walk away.
- You take it or leave it right now.
- Ask the box.
One-eighty,
plus closing costs.
- One-eighty,
- [Preston] Top that, sucker.
Plus closing costs.
- One-ninety, darlin'. Top that.
- Preston, honey?
I have a few errands to run.
I'll be back by 2:00.
Okay. Bye, Mom.
- [Computer] Two hundred.
- Two-ten.
- Just to be safe, make that 3:00.
- [Laughs]
- Three hundred?
- Ma, you're killin' me on this deal.
Come on. Are you tellin' me
we're gonna sit here and listen...
to some talking box
with a robot voice? What is this?
Uh, 300 it is. Are you
prepared to top 300?
No, I don't think I'm prepared
to top 300! Are you out of your mind?
We had a deal here! Are you Realtors
just a bunch of crooks? Is that it?
What's going on
with you people?
Well, I am sorry
you feel that way,
but I have an offer
on the table of 300.
- [Computer] Thousand.
- Uh, we'll take it.
- Sold.
- Yeah.
You probably won't live
to enjoy the cash.
[Realtor] Just one thing, sir.
What is your name?
My name is Preston...
Bingo.
Macintosh.
My name is Macintosh.
Well, congratulations,
Mr Macintosh.
- You have a house.
- Yes!
I'm rich!
Yeah!
Whoo, yes!
Money!
- You did what with my money?
- [Juice] You're not gonna believe this.
He gave all your money
to a little old bitty boy.
That was my nest egg.
That's all I had to start a new life.
I worked hard to steal
that money, Biderman!
You gave it to some
zit-faced little kid?
Now wait a minute.
I seen the kid.
- His skin looked pretty smooth.
- The boy had a cheque signed by you.
I didn't write a cheque to anybody
except for this genius here.
Now hold on a minute.
I'm not the one who cashed
a cheque for a million dollars.
- That was this man right here.
- Had your signature.
I said I didn't write it!
You gave me the cheque-book,
I put it in my pocket,
I got in my car, l...
l... I can't
feel my legs.
Uh, l...
Oh, oh, oh.
Calm down. I've got
a surveillance photo of the boy.
[Stammering]
We'll find him in no time.
- Oh, yeah, that's him.
- I can't see a thing.
I recognize him.
I'd know him anywhere.
It's upside-down.
All right. So where are you
gonna find the kid, Mr Family Man?
- Newspapers.
- You want me to advertise, is that it?
No, no, no.
They have listings.
Uh, family activities where, where...
You know, things where kids go. See?
Fine. You're gonna
help me find him.
- You understand? Dead or alive.
- Uh-huh.
Let's get out of here.
- Oh, don't think you ain't comin' with us.
- [Gasping]
Somebody's in there
with Biderman now.
A couple of guys I've never seen before.
They've just left.
The money laundering
is definitely on again.
We've got to notify
the Bureau right away.
[Man]
Hello, Limousines Unlimited.
- You have the car keys?
- No, you have the car keys.
- Oh, yeah. You make sure you-know-who stays grounded.
- And he goes to bed early.
- You got it, Pops.
- Don't call me that.
Uh, excuse me.
Sorry, kid.
Nobody famous inside.
Do you want to take your mitts
off the car, please?
- I'm waitin' for a client here.
- But I'm your client.
Oh, right, yeah.
And I'm Madonna.
Sorry, kid. The boss doesn't like me
taking baseball cards as payment.
So if you want to ride in this,
you need some buckaroos, buckarinis,
some moola, some dinero,
some money, some frogskins,
much similar to the money
you've given me...
In fact, identical to the money
you've given me right now.
I was just kiddin'
about bein' Madonna.
- My name's Henry.
- Hi, Henry. I'm Preston.
- Preston, good to see ya.
- Preston Waters.
Yes, nice to meet ya.
Hop in.
Go ahead.
I didn't actually
mean hop in, but...
So, where to,
boss?
- Well, Harry, we're gonna go buy some stuff.
- Yes, sir.
[Tyres Screeching]
"Hey, yeah"
"Ow, whoo"
"The best things in life
are free"
"But you can keep them
for the birds and bees"
- "Now give me money"
- "That's what I want"
- "That's what I want, yeah"
- "That's what I want Yeah"
- "That's what I want"
"That's what I want"
"Baby, your lovin'
gives me a thrill"
"But your lovin'
never paid my bills"
- "Now give me money"
- "That's what I want"
- "That's"
"What I want"
"That's what I want"
"Give it to me, baby
Uh-huh"
- "Oh"
- "Money"
"I want m-m-m-m-money
Yeah"
"I got to have some money"
- " I want to have the money Uh-huh, hey, hey"
- "Money"
"Hey, yeah"
"Money don't get everything
it's true"
"What it don't get now
I can't use"
- "I want m-m-m-money, hey"
- "That's what I want"
"That's what I want
Hey, yeah"
- "I want some money"
- "That's what I want"
- "Hey, yeah"
"That's what I want"
- "Money"
- "That's what I want"
- "Ow, hey"
- Ice cream! Turn around, Henry.
- Oh, right on.
"I need some money, baby
I need some money"
"I just need a few"
- Hey, thanks a lot for the great watch.
- You're welcome.
- Hey, this guy, uh... What is it? Mclntyre?
- Macintosh.
Uh, Macintosh.
Yeah, yeah.
If you don't mind me askin',
where does he get his money?
Well, he doesn't get it,
he just has it.
Why does he get a kid like you to go out
and buy all this stuff for him?
He... He never
had a real childhood.
So now that he's
really, really rich,
he can have all the fun
that he couldn't have when he was a kid.
- Oh. Oh, I see.
- You know.
So he didn't have any
fun when he was a kid,
but now he's old
and he's got money.
You're a kid having
the fun for him now...
that he couldn't have
when he was a kid.
- Okay, sure.
- Stop! Pull over, Henry! It's Shay!
- Stop! Hey!
- [Shay Screams] You scared me!
- Sorry.
- Preston, right?
- You've got a good memory.
- Thanks.
- Great, kid. Very nice.
- Nice wheels.
Oh, this? Ah, it's my boss,
Mr Macintosh.
- Do you want a ride?
- No, thanks. I'm outta shape.
Not from where
I'm sittin' you aren't.
So, uh, I'm thinkin' about
comin' into the bank tomorrow...
- and opening my account.
- Wow, you got the $200 already?
- Just about.
- All right. Well, see you tomorrow.
- Bye.
Was that him?
Was that Biderman?
- No, some kid who came into the bank today.
- Nice wheels for a kid.
Yeah. Says it belongs to his boss,
a guy named Macintosh.
Macintosh.
When are we gonna see Biderman?
[Man]
It looks like a circus.
Hey. Hey, hey, move it.
I've got work to do too, you know.
Where am I supposed to go?
You see an opening? Huh?
Hey, what's
the holdup here?
- Yeah, same to you, buddy.
- Hey, move it!
What is all this?
What a mess.
This is absolute madness!
Yo, who's in charge here?
[Preston Over Speaker] You with
the race car, put it in the backyard.
Uh, the water slide
goes back by the pool.
You guys with the TVs,
put them in the living room.
Hey, you with the Cadillac,
out by the pool.
You in the green jumpsuits,
bring that around the back.
- Preston?
- Hi, Dad.
- What's going on here?
- Movin' in.
- Who is moving in?
- Macintosh.
- Who's Macintosh?
- I'll be right with you, Dad.
Come on, boys.
I don't have all day.
Okay, Mr Waters,
the security system is all in place.
Excuse me.
This is the remote.
Here are the instructions.
All right?
We appreciate Mr Macintosh's business.
Here you go, pal.
What's with
all the security?
Mr Macintosh says you can
never be too paranoid, Dad.
- Well, who is Macintosh?
- I work for him. He's paying me.
Yeah, but who is he?
I never met him.
- You mean you haven't met him?
- No, I haven't met him.
- He's heard about you.
- Really?
Yeah, about work and stuff.
Really good things.
- Well... His stuff is blocking our driveway.
- Dad.
Boys!
Could you clear a path,
please?
Get a move on it!
All set, Dad.
"I knew a guy who was tough
but sweet"
[Henry]
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
"He's the one
He can't be beat"
"He's got everything
that I desire"
- "Sets the summer sun on fire"
- Brake, brake!
"I want candy"
- "I want candy"
- Flip, flip, flip, flip, flip!
- "Yeah"
- [Game] Body blow. Uppercut.
- Body blow. Left hook. Uppercut. Body blow.
- Ow.
- Uppercut.
- Come on, come on, come on, come on, come on!
Body blow.
Ten, nine...
- "I want candy"
- Yeah! Yes!
"I want candy"
"Go to see him
when the sun goes down"
- Come on, Henry! Come on!
- "Ain't no finer boy in town"
- Hey! Whoa!
- "I want candy"
- Oh, Henry!
- The blood rushed to my head.
- "Hey"
"Hey"
"Hey, hey"
[Woman]
Is something wrong?
No. I was wondering who could spend
cash like that these days.
Oh, yeah.
The man's name is Macintosh.
- Macintosh?
- Mm-hmm. He just moved here.
- Apparently loaded.
- Apparently.
I don't feel good about being here.
People may get the wrong idea.
Really?
You don't feel good?
How do you think I felt when you
gave away my million dollars, huh?
Juice. See anybody
that looks like him?
Oh, yeah. He looks like him.
Uh, she looks like him right there.
Way back over there,
uh, there goes his little twin brother.
You give me one picture and expect me
to find him out of all these kids?
You must be crazy. I'm gonna get on
the water slide. I'm startin' to sweat.
Hey, mister, you know
where the refreshment stands are?
- [Pops Balloon]
- No.
[Girl Crying]
Boom, boom, boom!
I got you!
Boom, boom,
boom, boom!
[Electronic Gunfire]
- [Butch Whimpering]
- He says he knows you, boss.
Oh, well, just throw him out.
[Screaming]
Ow! Ow!
- Banzai!
- "I want candy"
- [Preston Screaming]
"Hey"
- "Hey"
- Hiya.
I didn't expect
to see you here.
- Oh, what you doin' here?
- I came by to see Mr Macintosh.
- Oh, no, he's in a meeting.
- That's okay, I'll wait. I just really need to see him.
- He's in meetings all day.
- All day?
- Swamped.
- Hey, I missed you at the bank.
I thought you were gonna come by
and see me about opening up an account.
- Oh, I had to work.
- Wow. This is where you work?
- Not too shabby.
- Comfortable. - I brought an application.
- Do you still want to open up an account with me?
- Yeah.
- Okay. Do you have your deposit?
- I'll go get it.
Okay. Great.
[Preston Screaming]
- Whoa!
- That's amazing!
Sorry, just printed it.
Two hundred dollars. Looks like
you fell into some money, huh?
- I make a living.
- Yeah, well, I guess Mr Macintosh...
He knows a good man
when he sees one.
- Will he be opening up an account with us?
- Uh, maybe.
Yeah? Great. You know, I'd love
to meet him. How's tonight?
- Uh, tonight. What's tonight?
- Tonight's Wednesday.
Wednesday.
I'm sorry, he's busy.
- Too bad.
- Uh, but I'm not.
Oh, I handle
all his financial affairs.
- You do?
- Not all of them,
but I can tell you a lot about him,
sort of like a pre-meeting.
- And he wouldn't mind?
- Hasn't complained yet.
Okay. I'll come by
around 8:00.
Okay. Wait, I could
send a car for you.
Okay. Cool.
It's a date then. Bye-bye.
A date?
I've never been on a date.
You know what they call me
downtown? The Babe-Meister.
Think about it.
Okay, I'm gonna tell you about
the real deal on dating, which I know.
First of all, women love a great body.
They love... Look at this bod.
- Whoa. See?
- Yeah, yeah.
Of course, you've got a bod now that's
of a Greek god. Really. Think about it.
Women like you to have a good bod because
they want to feel they're protected.
You might have to fight some guy,
you know? But not with those arms.
You don't want to hit a guy with those arms
'cause those pythons would take a guy's head off.
Seriously. You're buff, but we're
gonna get you chiseled.
Okay? Oh, wait.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
I'm having a vision
here of a date.
- The perfect date for you guys.
- Uh, Steak Heaven!
Ho, ho! My little friend, you really
have the hots for this one, huh?
You know, if you really
want to go upscale,
that all-you-can-eat salad bar...
women love that.
And take some with you. You know,
line your pockets with plastic bags.
Put the food in there. 'Cause
it doesn't say "All you can eat here."
Does it say "here" on the sign?
I don't think so.
So you take something back for later.
A little snackaroo.
Oh, women love that. You get home
and you got a pocketful of hot wings.
There's nothing more
that impresses a woman.
Get yourself some flowers.
Get yourself a great body,
some nice hair,
some good clothes, a car,
and learn to say words
like "noncommittal."
You are a date
and a half, pal.
"There he is
Some Tiny Tim"
Six foot and risin'"
"Ooh, there he is
He's a knockout machine"
- "He's number one He's double cool"
- Yeah!
"He's the naked truth
in magazines"
- "I believe in him"
- "Wonderman"
- "He is a Mr Wonderman"
"He is a Mr Wonderman"
"Ah, yes"
- "Wonderman"
- Ew.
- One more! Yes, yes, yes!
Ah!
[Preston]
Hey, I'm gonna get you!
[Henry] You are little sushi man.
Sushi man down. Big boy throw.
Then they chase around. Come around
other way, fall down. Splat.
- [Preston Screaming]
- " Here comes the wonderman He'd like to say bye-bye"
- Why are you dressed like a game show host?
- I'm going out tonight.
Just a minute, young man.
You're still grounded.
- But it's for Mr Macintosh.
- I don't care.
Macintosh may have a pile of
money, but he doesn't decide...
when my son
is or isn't grounded.
- But it's for my job.
- Your job is to be grounded.
- [Both] Grounded.
- So much for Plan 442.
What do you know
about Plan 442?
Well, it's the investment plan you've
been working on, your "prespectus."
Prospectus. What are you doing
going through my work?
Well, I didn't want to say it,
but I told Mr Macintosh...
about your Plan 442, and he was
very, very interested.
Yep, I promised him I'd bring a copy
of it tonight and show it to him.
But I didn't want to tell you just
in case you got your hopes all up and...
No, no, no, no, no,
of course not.
Let me get you a fresh copy
of the "prespectus."
- I'll get a copy of it, sweetheart.
- Prospectus.
Yeah.
- Here. You're welcome.
- Oh, thank you.
Hurry up. Go. Go!
You want the car keys?
Nah, that's okay, Dad.
I don't drive yet.
- [Dad] You want me to drive you?
- [Preston] No, it's okay.
You know, I still haven't met Macintosh.
Maybe I should go over and...
- No! You'll ruin everything.
- Why not?
He has a date tonight
and he's very nervous about it.
- I guess I can see him first thing in the morning.
- Oh, I don't know, Dad.
I mean, he might be up
pretty late with this woman.
[Chuckles]
Lucky dog.
Later, toads.
- [Groaning]
- Thank you. That's enough.
- Oh!
- Sorry.
I can't believe Mr Macintosh went
to all this trouble.
- This place is great.
- Mr Macintosh has been eating here for years.
Oh, yeah? I thought
he just moved here.
There was a Tangerino
where I used to live.
Oh.
[Gargling]
Compliments of the chef
for Mr Waters...
and his lovely guest.
Th-They look
like lobsters,
only weenie.
Oh.
Mr Macintosh wanted you
to have this too.
Oh, thanks.
Oh, wow.
This is beautiful. Oh.
But I can't
accept this from you.
But it's from Mr Macintosh.
- Why?
- Just a little business gift.
I mean, it's deductible,
isn't it?
I'm not really sure,
but it's way too expensive.
Mr Macintosh has
a million dollars.
A million dollars doesn't buy
all that much these days.
Do you think he should have
asked for more?
What exactly
does he do anyway?
Oh, a little of this,
a little of that.
- You know.
- No, I'm afraid I don't.
- Oh, well...
- Is he an entrepreneur?
No, he's American.
Very secretive.
He has some questions
for you too.
Okay.
Shoot.
- "Are you married?"
- No.
"What's the shortest guy
you ever dated?"
Mmm. I'm not really sure.
- "The youngest?"
- You know,
these are pretty
personal questions.
Well, Mr Macintosh
is very interested in you.
- He is?
- He's, uh, never met anybody like you before.
He's never met me before,
period.
Technically no, but he's been thinking
a lot about you lately.
- He has?
- Yep. Whoa!
Preston!
Are you okay?
- [Screaming]
- [Gasps]
Do you like hamburgers?
I love hamburgers.
Never saw this kid
before in my life.
This is a waste of time.
Come on.
What's so special
about this place?
- You'll see.
- Mmm, come on. Tell me.
- Okay.
- You gonna tell me?
- Come with me.
- All right.
- Where are you taking me?
- You'll see.
- See what?
- Okay, get in the middle.
- Okay, ready? Five, four, three,
- Here?
Two, one.
[Shay Laughing]
Holy smokes!
Okay! Okay, now,
come here, Shay!
- Okay, okay, now!
- Preston, I don't believe this!
Okay, now,
let's run around!
- Don't get wet!
- Get us out!
Run!
[Screams]
- Okay, okay, okay!
- Watch out!
- No, we're gonna get soaked!
- No, no, no. Now come...
Come around here!
Come around here! Come on!
- Okay, hold onto me.
- [Screaming] Hey, where are you?
[Screaming]
Yeah! Yes!
- Whoo, yeah!
- Preston!
[Clapping, Cheering]
This is a great idea, Biderman.
Where's all the kids, huh?
Carl, it's late at night.
All the little boys and girls
are tucked in bed. What do you expect?
What I expect is when I give someone a
million dollars, and I come back a day later,
I find the million dollars.
That's what I expect.
- Carl, I'm not a magician.
- You can make it disappear,
- you just can't get it back, right?
- I'm telling you...
If y'all want a kid so bad,
there go one over there.
[Biderman]
That's the little boy from the bank!
Shh.
- [Preston Screams]
- Go get him!
- Oh, I'll race ya to the limo! I'll race ya to the limo!
- What? Okay, I'll race ya!
[Shouting]
[Screaming]
- I got the door for ya!
- Open the door. It's freezing!
Go, Henry!
Go, Henry, go!
- [Henry] Here we go!
- [Groaning]
He got away again! I don't
believe this! He got away again!
[Screaming]
[Shay]
This was the most fun.
- I haven't done anything like this since I was a little kid.
- Me neither.
Thank you so much.
When can I see you again?
Well, I really have to spend
some time with my job right now.
Well, uh,
I'm having a party.
On Friday.
Can you come?
It's for Mr Macintosh.
Um, it could be
for your business, sort of.
Mr Macintosh will
really be there?
Uh-huh.
It's his birthday.
Okay.
Well, great.
It's a date then.
Oh, I'm getting out
up here.
It was really fun.
And, uh,
- I had such a good time.
- Me too.
- Good night, Preston.
- Good night, Shay.
- See you later.
- Bye-bye.
- Good night, ma'am. Bye now. It's been a pleasure.
- Thank you.
[Henry]
So you're having a party Friday?
[Preston] Oh, yeah,
it's Mr Macintosh's birthday.
Oh, I thought you said
it was your birthday Friday.
Well, we're gonna have
a joint party for the both of us.
Oh. Well, it's a good thing it worked out
your birthdays are around the same time.
Hey, you wanna move that horse? Come
on. What is this, Bonanza? Let's go!
Well, here we are.
Home at last.
- Thanks, Henry.
- My pleasure.
Hey! Preston Waters!
- Good night.
- You know what you got, pal?
- What?
- S-T-Y-L-E.
- Style. Good night, Henry.
- Style. Good night.
Take it easy, man.
Good night.
Macintosh and I are having
the biggest birthday party ever.
- Honey, where's Preston?
- He's working for Macintosh.
Oh. Where's
Damien and Ralph?
They're working
for Macintosh too.
Oh.
- Have you met Macintosh?
- No, I thought you met him.
- No, I haven't met him.
- Well, I haven't met him either.
[Machine Humming]
Keep 'em comin'. Mr Macintosh wants me
to get plenty of practise.
[Screams]
Watch where you're hittin' those!
Quit messin' around.
Macintosh is watching.
Where? We've still
never seen him.
Just get back to work.
He's watching.
- " [Loud Rock]
- [Man]... coming out of the garage.
Ruining the neighbourhood.
"[Continues]
[Shooting Noises]
[Henry]
Hey, Preston!
Your party planner's
here again.
[Woman]
Piston! Piston! Piston!
Turn off this contraption.
I have wonderful news.
Mr Macintosh's birthday is going
to be the event of the century.
We gonna make
the front page from coast to coast.
Oh, we are so lucky,
lucky, lucky!
Now what kind of food
does Mr Macintosh like?
- I don't know.
- And who are his friends?
- Do you have a guest list?
- Uh, I don't think so.
You know, dewdrop, I think
I should meet him because...
I'm gonna need
a little cash deposit.
Oh. Uh, here.
Let me get you some cash.
Ooh, yes, you do
have money, don't you?
- Wait, wait, wait.
- Careful walking around with this much money, darling.
Somebody could just
rip you right off.
Now, this first $10,000
is going to be the deposit.
Now, of course, I'll get
the balance at the party,
and Mr Macintosh
is good for it?
I am just so looking forward
to meeting him.
- Who isn't?
- Waiters, security,
- guest list, paparazzi...
- Oh, and Yvonne?
- Yes?
- Remember, it's Preston.
Whatever!
Hey, uh, hey, Henry.
[Grunting, Laughing] It's attack
of the 50-foot chauffeur from hell!
I was just wondering if you
wanted to play some video games.
Oh, man, I wish you'd
have said something.
I can't. I promised some friends
I was gonna meet 'em in a while.
Oh, okay.
No problem.
I'll tell you what. I'll drop you over
at one of your friend's place...
on the way over, and you
can have some fun there.
Nah. Maybe I'll go to the park.
All right. It's up to you.
Hey, Preston,
- is my tie straight?
- Well, it looks perfect.
All right.
Later.
- Over here.
- Over here!
There it is.
That's the park up ahead.
Where did all these kids
come from?
Keep driving and maybe
someday I'll tell you.
- How could you hit a kid?
- I didn't hit a kid. I ran over his bicycle.
I had a dog once
that got hit by a train.
- Thanks for sharing, Juice.
- Old King Cole we called him.
- He was a merry old soul.
- It's him.
- Boy with the backpack.
- Go! Go! Go!
- The sign says "No Cars Allowed"!
- Just drive!
Quigley!
- You're gonna pay for this!
- Just drive!
- Carl, this isn't a good idea.
- Shut up! Whoa!
Let go, man.
What's goin' on?
- Oooh!
- I'm gonna get him.
- We're gonna tear him up!
- Reach over there and get him!
- Your butt is mine, kid!
I've been wantin'
this little punk.
I own you!
I own you, kid!
Come here!
He's got my money!
Aaaah!
- Follow him on foot! Go!
- Follow him on foot?
- Do I look like a bloodhound, a professional tracker?
- Juicy, listen.
If we don't get that kid,
nobody gets paid.
[Groaning]
- I want cash benefits, dental, everything.
- Not a problem.
Insurance!
Here, kiddie, kiddie!
Oh, there you go. Come here, boy.
I'm gonna get you now.
I've been lookin' for you!
Huh? Oh, no.
There he goes.
Yes. Come here, boy!
I'm gonna get you now!
Aaaah!
Don't believe this! Kill that kid when I
find him. I'm not gettin' paid for this.
- Where are we going now? My hands are over my eyes.
- Shut up!
- Get out...
- [Screaming]
There he is!
Stick with it! I got ya!
[Juice]
I'll get you!
Hang on, hang on.
- Okay, there he is!
- Come here! Come here!
- Juice! Run after him.
- You must be crazy. You run after him.
- Just ran through this whole entire park.
- Fine, get in the car.
- [Coughing]
- Don't blow chunks in my car. I just had it detailed.
- I'm cool!
- Are you sure? Are you sure?
- I'm not gonna mess up your priceless detail.
- Come on.
- [Retching]
- Hey!
[Boy]
Wow, what's this?
- Let's go!
- After him!
- Hey, dude!
- [Juice] Move outta the way.
Sorry!
- Get 'im!
- Your butt is mine!
I want this kid...
What are you doing?
- Yeah!
- No! Carl, watch out!
[Juice]
Oh, no!
Whoa!
- Aah! No!
- Oh, man!
Yes!
Now that's a display
of fine driving right there.
You know, Carl, it might be easier
just to steal another million dollars.
Hello, Mr Jackson.
Well, well, well, if it isn't the world's
youngest personal injury attorney.
You know, you're in a lot
of trouble today, little man.
Yeah, 'cause today
I have been drinking vodka.
- Take a hike, butt-brain.
- What?
- Take a...
- Never mind, never mind. Never mind, never mind!
[Chattering]
[Yvonne] Antoine, get that truck thing
off the stage. Thank you!
Get those golden gloves off!
Thank you!
Love, love, love, love!
What do you think?
Ta-da! Is this
to die, or what?
Uh, yeah, sure,
it's, uh, to die.
I can't wait to show it
to Mr Macintosh.
Come on, honey, let's see
what they did with that...
"Is it to die for or what?"
[Laughing]
Where did you find her?
Oh, man.
- What does this cost?
- I don't know.
- What do you think it should cost?
- Lots, lots.
Kid, why don't you just tell me what
I need to know. I'm a good guy.
Okay, how good are you
going to be to me?
In round numbers.
I don't think you get
the picture, sonny.
- Maybe you need a better view.
- [Screaming]
[Screaming] Preston Waters,
1508 Oak Street, Hillsdale, Indiana!
- Thank you.
- [Crying]
- You all right?
- Aaah! Aaah!
- Is something wrong?
- No, not at all.
- Is Mr Macintosh around?
- Uh, no.
- But he will be here tonight?
- Yeah.
- In person?
- In person.
- Okay. I'll see you tonight?
- Okay.
Okay. You're looking good.
Bye.
- I'll be calling.
- What a babe.
Baby brother
comes into his own.
For a little weasel, he sure knows
how to get a girlfriend.
- Too bad he picked a fortune hunter.
- Little love pilot...
shot down in flames
by a gold digger.
By a what?
Gold digger, someone
who is only after money. I know women,
and that one is after
Macintosh's cold, hard cash.
For your information,
me and Shay already went on a date...
and she had one
fantastic time, boys.
Oh, yes, every second
she was getting closer...
- and closer to Mr Macintosh.
- [Laughing]
- Shut up!
- Just answer me this.
Did she ever, ever just once,
come by without saying,
"Meanwhile, I wonder if
I could see Mr Macintosh?"
She's a gold digger, man.
She just wants Macintosh's money.
- Yeah! Ow!
- Don't rub it. Be a man.
- Don't rub it.
- I'll rub it if I want to.
- She wants a guy with money, not some little kid with an empty piggy bank.
- Yeah.
"Well, I'll wait by the windows
I'll wait by the door"
"To make sure
you don't come home"
- You ever known any gold diggers?
- Man, have I.
I hate 'em.
They're the worst.
Anybody who is your friend because you
have money is not your friend at all.
You know what
they say about gold?
"He who has the gold
makes the rules"?
No, no, no.
"A fool and his gold are soon parted."
What does that mean?
Those old sayings, man,
I don't get 'em. I don't even
know really what that means.
You ever heard:
"More than one way to skin a cat"?
Who skins cats?
Why would you skin a cat?
And there is not more than one way
to skin a cat. There is only one way.
You grab the cat,
you rip the skin off the cat.
What is the number two way?
You put a hose up the cat's butt?
He gets so bloated
that he skins himself?
Does he have a piece
of Velcro under his butt? No.
"Kill two birds with one stone."
You heard that one?
You know anyone who has even
killed one bird with one stone?
Kids try it all the time.
You can't hit a bird with a stone.
Unless you got a huge stone
and they're tiny baby birds.
Then... [lmitating Crash]
Beep, beep! Dead.
[Sighing]
"A fool and his gold are soon parted."
I guess it means
that if you're a fool,
your gold or your money
is soon gone.
Once it's gone, it is
outta there. It is history.
It is dust. It is vapour. It is no more.
You are living in Brokesville.
- Unless you have Macintosh's kind of money.
- What if you don't?
I guess then you find out
who your real friends are.
Man, we look good.
- Is everybody having a good time?
- [Woman Laughing]
- Good, you are.
- "Yes, we are, darling." Wow, look at the balloons.
- This is great. Look at the ice sculpture.
- Presents!
Hey, hey, hey, kid, no touching.
Those are Mr Macintosh's.
Go find your parents.
Go on, get outta here.
Go on!
- I just want to see Mr Macintosh.
- I just want to pig out.
[Chuckling]
Hey, look at that.
Excuse me.
- Sorry!
- Exactly who are you looking for, Preston?
- Have you seen Shay?
- I haven't seen her, but she'll be around.
Come on... Oh, man,
look at all this food!
Macintosh doesn't show,
we bring the kid in, agreed?
If Preston says Macintosh is gonna
be there, Macintosh will be there.
But you don't make a move, until
I give you the signal, understood?
We got eight men ready to go in
and nail him the second he shows up!
We close this deal tonight!
Where's the pizza and the ice cream?
What's going on here?
This could have been a pizza before
it got run over by a couple of trucks.
Oh, that looks tasty. Looks like
something you'd find between your toes.
Ah, ah, ah!
It's sucking the life outta me!
- Shut up! Everybody's looking.
- So what? Who cares?
Relax, have a good time. She'll show up.
Oh, there's Shay now. Ha!
Just kidding. I was kidding ya!
Would you just relax?
She'll be here. It's not at all
what you thought it'd be like?
Hate being rich, huh?
Preston? Preston?
Ice cream, ice cream.
Yoo-hoo, Preston!
Now, where is our mystery man? It's time
for Mr Macintosh to make his appearance.
I like to give my employers
their bills directly.
That way if they have any questions
or heart attacks or something...
- I'll give it to him.
- Fine.
Be quick about it.
$100,000?
Sweetheart, I know this seems like a whole
lot of money to normal people like me and you,
but to a man like Macintosh
this is just pennies.
- Now, you get up there and get me my money!
- Ow! I'll get your money.
[Computer Beeping]
Party: $100,000.
Not a problem.
You can leave it.
This is fine.
I'll be right back. Thank you.
[Computer]
Transaction not possible.
Insufficient funds.
Current balance: $332.17.
- Transaction not possible.
- Three hundred dollars?
- Insufficient funds. Transaction not possible.
- Oh, no!
- No, please, God.
- Insufficient funds.
This can't be right.
One, two, three, four...
[Chattering]
It's gone.
It's all gone.
[Knocking]
Mr Macintosh?
Oh, sorry to bother you.
It's Fred Waters,
Preston's dad.
I know you got a bash going on here,
so I'll make it brief.
But, uh,
I wanted to ask you
a favour.
You see, today is Preston's
birthday and if you see him,
if you could send him home
a little early.
Lately he's been
working so hard.
All of a sudden money's
become so important to him.
I guess that's
mostly my fault.
You don't have kids,
do you, Mr Macintosh?
I'll tell you, it's very easy
to make mistakes with them.
I haven't always paid enough
attention to my kids.
I pushed them
too hard... maybe.
Especially Preston.
I guess I expect
more from him.
He reminds me of myself at that age.
I couldn't wait to grow up.
I'm afraid he's missing out
on his childhood.
So am I.
Well, thanks. I won't take up
any more of your time.
And we appreciate you
sending Preston home early.
If... If he wants to come,
that is.
- [Whispering] I want to come home.
- Thanks.
Dad. Dad?
Dad?
Dad! Dad!
Dad!
Dad, wait!
Daddy! Henry?
Henry! Wait a minute,
where's Henry?
Your driver?
He left a little while ago.
H-He left?
You sure it was Henry?
Big guy, white limo.
He's gone.
Thanks.
Now I know
who my friends are.
Excuse me. Sorry.
- [Door Opening]
- [Shay] Preston?
Mr Macintosh?
- Mr Macintosh?
- It's just me.
- Which one of us did you want?
- I was looking for you.
- Oh, good.
- And Mr Macintosh.
Look, it's very, very important
that I find Mr Macintosh right now.
- Do you understand?
- He's nowhere.
- He's gone. I think you'd better leave too.
- Preston...
- you could be in danger.
- Just go, okay?
You got your necklace.
Just take it and leave.
"Give it back
There's no time to lose"
"So give it back
Give it back"
Riggs? Riggs?
Riggs?
Looks like
no one's home.
- Shut up, Wienerman.
- Biderman.
- Where is he?
- I don't know, but he might be down the street...
at Mr Macintosh's,
that's his boss.
- Macintosh. Come on!
- [Whimpering]
You know, I do like
what they have done with this colour.
There you are, puppy-butt.
Did you get me my money?
- Uh, Macintosh has disappeared.
- What?
Now, I am warning you, Tom Thumb,
don't you trifle with me.
If I don't get paid,
I will sue Mr Macintosh...
for every dime
he is worth!
Well, be sure and tell me
when you find him.
Okay, little Mr Man,
this party is over!
Quiet! Stop that playing! Stop that
music! Quiet! Attention! Attention!
Everybody,
this party is over!
Our host...
can't pay his bills!
- Mr Macintosh is a fraud!
- [Woman] What?
[Crowd Murmuring]
Who's that kid?
She's right.
Hate to tell you this,
but there's been
a terrible mistake.
Nobody s-should
have been invited.
Macintosh is... is gone.
And he's not coming back.
So I think you should
all leave too, so go. Go on.
Close down the bar!
Come on, let's get outta here.
Come on, Antoine.
Move it!
Come on, move it!
Come back with those glasses!
Give me that!
Oh! Oh! Oh!
[Knocking]
Henry?
Henry!
I knew you'd come back!
Henry...
[Gasping]
Happy birthday.
I'm here to blow out your candles.
- Oh! Let me go!
- What's your hurry, kid? Got a big cheque to cash?
- Let me go!
- I like this pad. What do you think, Juice?
Oh, yeah, I like the pad.
It looks real nice.
- Can you handle it? Got the TV, drums.
- Oh, I like this.
- TV, drums.
- All kinds of toys.
- He's got a little taste, a little flavour.
- What's this thing here?
- I don't think I've seen one of those before.
- How do you work this?
Well, you turn the knob...
You really shouldn't let him
in such a nice house as this.
All your stuff
could get broken.
Kid, where's Macintosh?
N-Nowhere.
He's nowhere.
I'm going to ask you one more time.
Where is he?
Huh!
There is no Macintosh.
- I made him up. It was me the whole time.
- Don't give me that.
- Who bought this house?
- I-I did.
You? You outbid me?
Wait a minute. You tryin' to tell me
that this little boy here...
outbid you
with your own money?
Be a fly on the wall,
okay, Juice?
Listen, kid, you know it's illegal
to take things that don't belong to you.
I know. I feel awful.
Take me to the police.
- Carl, don't do it. It's a trick.
- Get outta here.
Son, I don't want to take you
to the police. Just tell me, okay?
Where's my money?
I-I spent it.
- All of it?
- All of it.
How could you spend...
a million dollars
in six days?
You must not have been
shopping lately.
Carl, Carl,
wait a minute.
Maybe we're thinking about
this Macintosh thing in the wrong way.
- What are you talking about?
- You needed a new house, a new identity.
This kid,
he's done it for you.
I mean, Macintosh
could run for mayor here.
Yeah, I kind of like the idea of that...
Mayor Quigley.
No, no, Mayor Macintosh.
I like it.
Look, there's only one problem
with that. The... Aaah!
- Hey!
- Come back here!
- Wait for me! I'm coming!
- He's upstairs, man!
Break it down!
There he is!
- Where is he? Where is he?
- He went down there!
- Juice, go after him!
- I ain't goin' down there.
- Go on! Now!
- You're crazy. I ain't goin' down there.
- Watch your head.
- What is it, about 230... Whoa!
- Aaah!
- I'm not goin' in there.
- Oh, no, he didn't.
- Did you see him?
- Oh, no, you did just push me in the pool!
- Get out, we gotta find him!
What?
What happened?
Act like you got
a purpose in life. Go.
[Biderman]
I think I'm experiencing chest pains.
[Indistinct Noise]
Carl? Juice?
Huh? Oh.
Little boy?
Little boy from the bank?
Ha, ha.
Oh!
[Groaning, Grunting]
Where am I?
Oh-oh!
Ooh! Ooh!
[Sheep Bleating, Cow Mooing]
[Muttering]
[Rooster Crowing]
- Hey, hey!
- [Cow Mooing]
Got ya! Uh-huh!
- Hey!
- Got him.
It's time for
a little batting practise.
Here we go!
Hey! What's happening?
Whoa! Hey!
Just outside.
Let's try a sinker. A sinker!
Another! Another!
Let's try a screwball!
- Turn, turn, turn!
- Be cool! Ow!
Hey! Ho!
Come on, boy!
Screwball! Boom!
Whoa! Oooh!
- That must have hurt!
- My god!
Fastball, fastball!
Just inside!
- Oooh! Ow!
- What's next, Juice? How about tennis?
It's over, kid.
Ow! Ow!
Preston, come out, come out,
wherever you are.
None of this would have
happened, you know,
if you hadn't been
a bad boy!
Tell me something, did you think
you were going to get away with it?
Spending somebody else's
hard-earned money? Huh!
We need to have a chat.
Preston...
I'm not mad any more.
I know you're sorry.
Come on, buddy.
Pres?
Come on out now!
Banzai!
Quigley, I'll be back
in a minute.
Don't leave me here...
Oh, where am I goin'?
- Whoa! Kid!
- Don't you move.
Juice! Biderman!
Get your useless butt over here!
[Motor Revving,
Tyres Screeching]
Whoa! Oh! Oh!
Kid! Kid!
What are you doin'?
Oh! Oh!
Kid, kid, stop,
please, please! Stop!
Oh!
[Groaning]
Kid, please!
Don't do that!
Ooooh!
[Screaming]
Quigley?
Are you okay?
Aaah! I got you now!
Come get him!
I got him now. Come get him, you guys.
All right, hold him.
- Baseballs!
- You're not a very nice boy, you know that?
- Freeze!
- Preston, are you okay?
What's this all about?
What's happening here?
Stanley?
What are you doing here?
- Let go!
- As of this moment, you're fired from my bank!
F.B.I., Biderman. From this moment,
you're fired from your bank.
- What?
- You're with the F.B.I.?
- Yes, Preston, I am.
- Okay, kid, finally, at long last, who's Macintosh?
Uh, uh, uh, uh,
uh, uh,
uh, uh...
- I'm Macintosh.
- You're Macintosh?
I'm Macintosh! And I want you all
off my property now!
- He's Macintosh.
- You sure?
I tell ya, I'm Macintosh!
Please tell these guys I'm Macintosh.
- Oh, he's Macintosh. Don't you know Papa Macintosh?
- Mr Macintosh.
And Big Mama Macintosh
be hangin' out with the brothers.
Mr Macintosh, you're under arrest for
fraud, money laundering and grand theft.
- What are you talking about?
- Bring in Biderman too.
- I'm a banker!
- And take Mr Wise Guy too.
- Who? Me? I'm not wise.
- Get your hands off me.
- Man, I flunked recess.
- Take it easy, man.
- Take 'em out.
- I'm not even from here, man. - I'm a banker.
- I was roaming down the street. Cat said, Hey, there's a party.
- I own a bank!
Sir, stay behind the line there.
Everyone, just calm down, okay?
Honey, I'm gonna check this out,
make sure that Preston's okay.
- You take the boys home.
- [Chattering]
- What's going on?
- Something to do with Macintosh. The F.B.I. Is all over.
- Uh, have you seen my son, a little boy?
- He's inside with the F.B.I.
- Excuse me, excuse me, please. Officer...
- Whoa, whoa!
- Nobody gets in there without a badge, sir.
- I'm looking for my son.
Kind of neat.
Can I see your badge?
Shay Stanley,
F.B.I.
Cool.
Wait a minute.
So that means our date...
was just for your...
just for your job?
Well, it started out
like that.
I should have known.
Hey, you know, I wouldn't
have traded that night for anything.
So when can
I see you again, Shay?
Mmm, why don't you give me a call
in, say, about ten years?
- Five.
- Seven.
- Six.
- Okay, it's a date.
Good night, Preston.
[Dad]
Preston!
Preston?
Oh, my god, he's in shock.
Oh, oh, I'm fine, Dad. I'm fine now.
Oh, I'm glad to see you.
- What's going on here?
- It's a long story.
- Well, why don't we go on home, you tell me all about it?
- Okay.
I want to say goodbye
to a friend, okay, Dad?
Wow, this is just great. I can't
step out for a couple of seconds.
I miss all the action.
Thanks.
- Are you okay?
- I thought you left, man.
No, I didn't leave. What did we say
the party needed? Ice cream, right?
I just went to get ice cream.
I don't know if I got the exact recipe,
but I think I got it close.
- So?
- Hey, it's pretty close.
Well, I guess Macintosh
is no more, huh?
It's too bad, because, uh,
I really enjoyed working for him.
- I had a good time too...
- Do me a favour?
Next time you see him,
tell him, uh,
that I'm really gonna miss him.
I'll miss you too, Henry.
You're gonna do
just fine.
See ya.
- Hey, Henry.
- Huh?
- Know what you have?
- What?
- S-T-Y-L-E, style.
- Style.
Hey, Preston, you're not gonna
finish this ice cream, I guess, huh?
Well, no sense
lettin' this go to waste.
So, what happened?
Oh, well, uh,
Macintosh wasn't...
He... He wasn't
who he thought he was.
- How do you mean?
- Well, he shouldn't have done what he did.
He shouldn't have
fooled everybody.
I think you're right.
It's been a long night.
Better get on up to bed.
Yeah, I think I ought
to get some sleep too, Dad.
And tomorrow, I'll tell you
all about Mr Macintosh.
Sleep well, Preston.
[Group]
Ta-da!
"Happy birthday to you"
"Happy birthday
dear Preston"
"Happy birthday to you"
Make a wish.
You know what they say,
"Be careful what you wish for."
Oh.
What else do I want?
I mean, I got everything...
that I need right here.
On the other hand.