[ Bell Ringing ]
[ Alarm Clock Ringing ]
[ Ringing Continues ]
[ Moaning ]
OH ! OH.
I'M UP !
[ Woman's Voice ] PHILLIP, DID YOU SET YOUR CLOCK ?
ARE YOU AWAKE ?
UP... AND READY FOR A NEW DAY. [ Sighs ]
[ Woman's Voice ] ♪ OH, WHAT A BEAUTIFUL MORNING ♪
♪ OH, WHAT A BEAUTIFUL DAY ♪
[ Phillip ] I CAN'T FIND MY SOCKS. THEY'RE IN YOUR SHOES.
[ Phillip ] WHERE ARE MY SHOES ? THEY'RE ON YOUR FEET.
[ Phillip ] THANK YOU.
[ Low Electronic Tones ] THANK YOU, WEBER.
OH. MORNING, WEEBO.
[ Woman's Voice ] HI.
HAVE YOU SEEN THE PAPER THIS MORNING ? YES, I DID.
IF I COULD SOLVE THIS WHOLE METASTABLE COMPOUND BUSINESS,
I COULD SAVE THE COLLEGE.
A NEW ENERGY SOURCE WOULD BE WORTH A FORTUNE.
YOU BETTER HURRY UP.
THE LOAN'S DUE AT THE END OF THE SCHOOL YEAR.
NOT TO WORRY, WEEBO. I'M VERY CLOSE.
MAY I SEE MY SCHEDULE, PLEASE ? [ Tuning Fork ]
♪ AAA AFTER SCHOOL, THERE'S SOMETHING.
I KNOW THERE IS. WHAT IS IT ?
THIS IS YOUR COMPLETE SCHEDULE.
MMM, LET'S SEE.
UNLESS YOU DIDN'T TELL ME SOMETHING.
WHAT IS IT ? THERE'S SOMETHING.
THERE'S SOMETHING THERE.
IT'S SOMETHING TO DO WITH WHITE.
OH, WHAT IS IT ?
I KNOW IT'S SOMETHING IMPORTANT.
I KNEW IT. OH.
I DON'T KNOW. I'M SORRY.
I KNOW IT'S SO FRUSTRATING.
I WISH I COULD HELP YOU.
- BUT I CAN'T ! - HAIRCUT !
HA ! [ Chuckles ] ♪♪ [ Tuning Fork ]
[ Woman ] THEY CAN'T JUST CLOSE DOWN THE SCHOOL.
OUTSIDE OF THE IVY LEAGUE,
NAME ME ONE PRIVATE COLLEGE OR UNIVERSITY...
THAT ISN'T IN FINANCIAL TROUBLE.
OH, ALL RIGHT. NAME ANOTHER !
YOU DON'T THINK IT'S TOO MUCH ?
NO, IT'S ELEGANT !
AND IT'S A WONDERFUL IDEA TO GO WITH THE
BIG WEDDING THIS TIME.
IT DOES PUT THE PRESSURE ON THE PROFESSOR
TO SHOW UP.
IF HE FORGETS THIS TIME, THAT'S IT.
IN HIS CASE, ONCE IS JUSTIFIABLE.
AND TWICE IS UNDERSTANDABLE.
BUT THREE TIMES ! [ Horn Beeps ]
COMING THROUGH.
[ Horn Beeps ]
MORNING... OR AFTERNOON,
WHATEVER THE CASE MAY BE.
WE HAVE A LOT TO TALK ABOUT TODAY,
SO LET'S GET INTO IT WITHOUT DELAY.
OHH ! OH, THANK YOU,
WHOEVER GAVE ME THE PLATE OF FRUIT AND THE
DEAD PHEASANT.
THIS DOES NOT COUNT AS EXTRA CREDIT.
LAST TIME WE WERE TALKING ABOUT NEWTON'S LAW OF GRAVITATION.
TO REVIEW: YOU SEE, THIS "G" IS LIKE
THE "C" IN "EQUALS 'MC' SQUARED."
IT'S A CONSTANT, CONSTANT UNIVERSE AS MUCH AS
ANYTHING IS CONSTANT IN THE UNIVERSE.
IT'S SAYING THAT THE FORCE OF ATTRACTION BETWEEN TWO BODIES...
IS IN DIRECT PROPORTION TO THE PRODUCT OF THEIR MASSES,
AND IN INVERSE PROPORTION TO THE SQUARE OF
THE DISTANCE BETWEEN THEM.
AN EXAMPLE WOULD BE: LET'S MAKE, UH, NAKED MAN "M-1,"
NAKED LADY "M-2."
ACCORDING TO THIS FORMULA,
THEIR ATTRACTIVE FORCES WOULD WANT TO CLOSE THE DISTANCE TO ZERO.
WHY DON'T THEY ?
HMM ?
THE EARTH ! AAH !
SO, IN ESSENCE, THAT IS GRAVITY AND THIS...
IS "DR. RICHARDS LIFE DRAWING."
[ Chuckles ] IT'S NOT MY CLASS, IS IT ?
PHILLIP. OVER HERE.
SARA ! OOH ! VERY SORRY.
AND SO, MOMENTUM.
MAY I SIT HERE ? THANK YOU.
HELLO, SARA. WHAT A PLEASANT SURPRISE.
- HELLO, RUTHIE. - MARTHA.
MARTHA WHAT ?
- MARTHA. ME MARTHA. - YOU MARTHA. ME PROFESSOR.
YES, I KNOW.
I WAS JUST GONNA, YOU KNOW,
GRADE MY LUNCH, EAT A FEW TESTS AND HOPE FOR THE BEST.
- HOW DO YOU HOLD IT IN ?
- LIKE EVERYBODY ELSE, RUTHIE. I CROSS MY LEGS REAL TIGHT.
NO, I WAS TALKING ABOUT YOUR EXCITEMENT.
EXCITEMENT ? THE WEDDING.
CONGRATULATIONS !
THE WEDDING !
SARA AND I. OH, THE WEDDING.
I'M LOOKING FORWARD TO IT. AREN'T YOU, HONEY ?
- IT'S TODAY. - ARE YOU SURE ?
THE WEDDING IS TODAY. OKAY ? I BELIEVE YOU.
6:30, AT THE PRESBYTERIAN CHURCH ON BEACH STREET.
I'VE BEEN THERE.
WE HAD OUR REHEARSAL THERE LAST NIGHT.
THAT'S RIGHT, WE DID ! IT WENT WELL ?
YES, IT DID. BUT IT DOESN'T COUNT. NO ?
THE WEDDING COUNTS !
AND I WANT YOU TO PROMISE ME ON EVERYTHING BETWEEN US...
THAT YOU'LL BE THERE, OKAY ?
I'D RATHER DIE THAN DISAPPOINT YOU.
WELL, THIS IS GOING TO BE THE
VERY LAST TIME I TRY TO MARRY YOU.
I IMAGINE SO.
I KNOW THAT I LOVE YOU.
BUT... I'M NOT SURE THAT YOU CAN LOVE ME.
THAT'S RIDICULOUS. I LOVE YOU WITH ALL MY HEART.
WITH EVERY CELL, EVERY MOLECULE,
EVERY ATOM. I LOVE YOU ON A SUBATOMIC LEVEL.
HMM. PROVE IT TO ME TONIGHT AT 6:30.
PROVE WHAT, HONEY ?
THAT YOU LOVE ME. I LOVE YOU.
6:30.
- GOOD LUCK. - THANK YOU, BETTY.
I KNEW I SHOULDN'T HAVE COME, BUT I'M VERY CRAZY ABOUT HIM.
AND THIS IS THE GOD'S TRUTH,
I WANT HIM TO HAVE WHAT HE WANTS...
EVEN IF IT MEANS YOU INSTEAD OF ME.
NO, NO ! YOU LOVE HIM. DON'T GIVE HIM UP !
[ Vacuum Motor Whirring ] [ Low Electronic Tones ]
HEY, I'M WATCHING SOMETHING !
WEBER ! WHY DON'T YOU BE QUIET ?
I'M WATCHING TV ! DOWNLOAD SOME MANNERS ! OHHH !
BUT HE AIN'T IN LOVE WITH ME, MISS FRENCH.
OOH, TELL ME ABOUT IT.
♪♪ [ Whistling "I'm Getting Married in the Morning" ]
[ Phillip Muttering ] ONE SECOND. THERE WE GO.
♪♪ [ Whistling Continues ]
HELLO, PHIL.
WHAT ARE YOU WORKING ON ?
CAN'T REMEMBER ? [ Chuckles ]
I UNDERSTAND.
IT'S A DAMN SHAME THEY'RE SHUTTING YOUR COLLEGE DOWN.
- I READ ABOUT IT IN THE PAPER. - IT'S NOT OVER YET.
WE'RE DOING FINE AT RUTLAND. NO SUCH FINANCIAL PROBLEMS.
HEY ! ARE YOU STILL WORKING ON THAT LIGHTER-THAN-AIR COMPOUND ?
IT'S A, UH, PROPULSIVE POLYMER AND...
I DON'T MEAN TO BE RUDE, WILSON, BUT I HAVE TO GO.
YOU DON'T SEEM TOO HAPPY TO SEE ME, PHIL. I'M NOT.
ALL THE YEARS WE'VE KNOWN EACH OTHER,
STUDYING, WORKING TOGETHER.
WHAT HAPPENED BETWEEN US ?
I JUST GOT TIRED OF YOU STEALING MY IDEAS, WILSON.
[ Laughs ] AND WHAT WOULD YOU HAVE DONE WITH THEM ?
YOU WOULD HAVE MISPLACED THEM,
FORGOTTEN THEM, LOST THEM.
THERE'S NO DOUBT YOU'RE
THE BRIGHTER OF THE TWO OF US.
YOU HAVE A GENIUS FOR SCIENCE. I GRANT YOU THAT.
IT'S THE SCIENCE OF DAILY LIFE THAT ALLUDES YOU.
I'VE HEARD THAT BEFORE.
EXCUSE ME. THAT'S VERY VOLATILE.
I WON'T DENY THAT I HATE YOU FOR YOUR BRILLIANCE.
I'M PETTY, CORRUPT.
I PROBABLY WOULD'VE GONE MAD
TRYING TO COMPETE WITH YOU IN PURE THOUGHT.
BUT I'M NOT AN INNOVATOR LIKE YOU, PHIL.
I'M AN ADAPTER, AND TO THAT END,
I HAVE PROFITED FROM YOUR IDEAS.
WHY ARE YOU HERE ? TO BE HONEST,
I'M HERE THIS WEEKEND TO STEAL YOUR FIANCEE,
AND MAKE HER MY WIFE.
WELL, I THINK YOU'LL BE SADLY DISAPPOINTED.
I'LL SEE YOU AT THE WEDDING THEN.
[ Wilson Laughing ]
[ Weebo ] IT'S A LITTLE CROOKED.
YEAH, THERE YOU GO. WEEBO,
THE WEDDING WAS NOT ON MY SCHEDULE.
NO. WHY WAS THAT INFORMATION DELETED ?
HMM. I DON'T REALLY KNOW.
DO YOU HAVE ANOTHER VIRUS ? NOW THAT YOU MENTION IT,
I AM FEELING FEVERISH.
REALLY ? MM-HMM.
YOU ARE A LITTLE HOT. SAY "AHH."
AHH. [ Growls ]
[ Together ] AHH.
[ Phillip ] AHH-AHH-AHH.
OH... YES !
HOT, COLD. HOT. THAT'S IT.
THE HYDROCARBONS HAVE BEEN INHIBITING THE COOPER PAIRS.
BUT, IF YOU GO FROM HOT TO COLD VERY QUICKLY,
YOU GET A CONDUCTIVE POLYMER AND
YOU COMPLETE THE METASTABLE SPHERE.
BEHOLD ! THERE IT IS.
NOW IT'LL WORK. YES !
BUT, UH, WHAT ABOUT YOUR WEDDING ?
[ Weebo ] SORRY, SARA.
[ Laughing ]
SHOULD I CALL THE CHURCH AND TELL THEM YOU'LL BE LATE ?
VERY GOOD. ALL RIGHT.
[ Muttering ]
VERY GOOD. AHH.
FLOWING FROM THE CONDENSER TO THE PRESSURE REACTOR.
YES.
[ Clanking Noises ]
YES ! IT'S READY.
ORGANIC CATALYST.
THE POSITIVE...
AND THE NEGATIVE.
LITTLE TOUCH OF ELECTRICITY.
HMM. HMM. [ Bell Rings ]
[ Groans ]
WOW ! WHAT A BANG !
[ Weebo ] YEAH ! LITTLE TOUCH OF ELECTRICITY.
[ Laughing ] THAT'S NOT HELPFUL.
AHH.
OH... BOY ! THIS IS NOT GOOD. NO, SIR.
WEEBO ? WHAT ?
GET A BROOM. THAT'LL HELP.
[ Bell Chiming ]
♪♪ [ Organ ]
♪♪
TWO YEARS.
[ Gurgling Noise ]
WOW.
[ Purring ]
[ Squeals ]
[ Blowing Raspberry ]
[ Blows Raspberry ]
[ Whistles, Kissing Sounds ]
OHH. [ Sneezes ]
OH, BLESS YOU. YOU HAVE A COLD.
YOU SHOULD. IT'S 77 DEGREES KELVIN.
IT'S VERY COLD.
COME ON.
WHAT THE-- LET'S TRY AND DESCRIBE YOU.
YOU'RE AN ELASTOMER. YES.
UM, OOH ! YOU'RE HIGHLY VISCOUS.
BUT YET YOU CAN PHASE-SHIFT.
WELL, LET'S SEE.
YOU'RE MOLDABLE.
[ Giggles ] [ Laughing ]
IT'S A LITTLE TICKLISH. [ Laughing ] [ Giggling ]
OOH !
YOU'RE FOLDABLE. [ Yaps ]
YOU'RE GULLIBLE.
OH. ALL RIGHT. LET'S SEE.
OH, WAIT A MINUTE. OKAY. AND--
OOH, YOU'RE DUCTILE.
[ Making Noises ]
[ Laughing ] OH ! YOU'RE ELASTIC.
LET'S SEE HOW ELASTIC YOU ARE. OKAY.
I'M THE HACKEYSACK KING !
[ Grunting Rhythmically ]
[ Weebo Laughing ] BRAVO ! ENCORE !
OH, BOY !
WEEBO, TAKE A PICTURE. OKAY. LOOK THIS WAY.
SMILE !
[ Gasps ]
YEOW ! [ Gasps ]
- OWW ! - [ Grunting ]
WEEBO, IT'S AMAZING, IT'S MIRACULOUS,
IT'S-- PROFESSOR ! PROFESSOR !
IT'S GONE. [ Glass Shattering ]
IT IS ! OH ! OH !
PROFESSOR, I THINK YOU GAVE IT A LITTLE TOO MUCH FREE WILL.
OHH ! OH, NO.
THERE'S NOT A DARN THING TO BE AFRAID OF,
PAL. HOW CAN ANYTHING GET IN YOUR WINDOW ?
IT'S CLOSED, OKAY ? WHOA !
[ Cat Yowls ]
HUH ?
OH, NO !
WHOA !
WAAH ! YEE-HAH ! AAAAAH !
- [ Explosion ] - [ Grunting ]
HAH !
MMPH ! WOW, WEEBO !
I GOT IT ! GREAT ! NOW WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO WITH IT ?
- IT HAS INCREDIBLE INERTIA. - MMM,
MAYBE IT'S JUST GLAD TO SEE YOU.
[ Laughing ] WEEBO ? YES ?
OH. DO YOU KNOW WHAT THIS IS ?
FLYING RUBBER ?
YES. THAT'S WHAT IT IS !
IT'S FLYING RUBBER !
IT'S FLUBBER !
OUCH.
THANK YOU FOR WAITING SO LONG. YES, MA'AM.
I'M SORRY, SARA.
ARE YOU GOING TO TELL ME, "I TOLD YOU SO" ? NO, NO.
I'M GONNA GIVE YOU A RIDE HOME. THANK YOU.
THERE YOU ARE.
CAREFUL.
WATCH YOUR GOWN. I'VE GOT IT. THANK YOU.
[ Phillip ] IT'S PERFECTLY SAFE, WEEBO.
IT'S JUST AN ORDINARY RADIOACTIVE ISOTOPE...
THAT WEBER IS NOW REMOVING FROM THE LEAD CONTAINMENT UNIT.
VERY GOOD, WEBER.
YOU PLACE THE RADIOACTIVE ISOTOPE...
CAREFULLY BEHIND THE SLIDING SHUTTER.
YOU SEE, THE SLIDING SHUTTER WORKS JUST LIKE A CAMERA.
IT REGULATES THE FLOW OF GAMMA RADIATION.
INSTEAD OF BILLIONS OF RANDOM PARTICLES,
YOU HAVE A PRECISE STREAM OF ENERGY.
WE CAREFULLY PLACE THE SLIDING SHUTTER MECHANISM...
UNDERNEATH... THE FLUBBER.
AND I'M BURNING UP IN HERE !
WEEBO ? OVER HERE.
THE GAMMA RADIATION TRIGGERS
A METASTABLE DECAY IN THE FLUBBER ITSELF.
RIGHT. WHICH RELEASES ENORMOUS QUANTITIES OF ENERGY.
THAT'S WHAT PROPELS THE FLUBBER. OF COURSE.
DOING IT THIS WAY, I BELIEVE,
IS A LOT MORE SCIENTIFIC THAN DROPPING IT OR KICKING IT...
OR BOMBARDING IT WITH LIGHTBULB PHOTON FLASHES.
ABSOLUTELY ! I BELIEVE...
BY CONTROLLING THE GAMMA RADIATION FLUX,
WE CAN CONTROL THE MOVEMENT OF THE FLUBBER ITSELF.
CROSS YOUR FINGERS, WEEBO.
HERE'S HOPING ! GOOD LUCK.
OH ! [ Laughing ]
IT WORKS ! [ Laughing ]
[ Laughing ] AYUK, AYUK.
DESCENT GRADUALLY.
[ Laughing ] BACK UP AGAIN.
YEAH ! [ Watch Beeping ]
MY WEDDING !
I'VE GOTTA GO, WEEBO.
BUT YOU HAVEN'T FINISHED THE EXPERIMENT YET.
YOU'RE JUST GETTING STARTED.
YOU CAN'T JUST STOP IN THE MIDDLE.
THE WEDDING. OH, I CAN'T MISS THIS ONE, WEEBO.
I'M AWARE OF THE TIME. THANK YOU.
TODAY'S THE WRONG--
I'M GETTING MARRIED FRIDAY, 6:30 P.M.
NO ! NO, YOU'RE NOT.
WHY NOT ? BECAUSE YOU'RE NOT GETTING MARRIED,
PHILLIP.
YES, I AM. YOU MISSED THE WEDDING.
IT'S 6:30... IN THE MORNING.
NO. NO.
YES. I'M SORRY.
IT IS ? YEAH.
SARA.
SARA ?
YOU HAVE A LOT OF NERVE TO SHOW YOUR FACE AROUND HERE...
AFTER WHAT YOU DID TO ME LAST NIGHT.
WOULD YOU PLEASE LET ME EXPLAIN ?
NO.
THERE'S NOTHING TO EXPLAIN.
YOU WEREN'T THERE. FOR THE THIRD TIME,
YOU LEFT ME STANDING AT THE ALTAR.
I'M SORRY WITH ALL MY HEART.
BUT PLEASE LISTEN TO ME. PLEASE. YOU KNOW ME.
YOU KNOW HOW SOMETIMES I CAN GET
REALLY FIXATED ON AN IDEA ?
I DON'T WANT TO HEAR IT. SARA,
YOU'VE GOT TO HEAR IT. SARA ?
THIS IS THE REASON
I DIDN'T MAKE IT LAST NIGHT. [ Flubber Chittering ]
IT'S FLUBBER.
FLUBBER ! IT'S A METASTABLE COMPOUND.
IN LAYMAN'S TERMS,
IF YOU APPLY A SMALL AMOUNT OF ENERGY,
IT LIBERATES AN ENORMOUS QUANTITY OF ENERGY !
BUT THE TOTAL EFFECT IS TRANSIENT, SARA.
THE MOMENT YOU STOP APPLYING ENERGY,
IT RETURNS TO A QUASI-PLASMOID STATE.
ISN'T THAT REMARKABLE, SARA ?
WHAT'S REMARKABLE, PHILLIP,
IS THAT I EVER FELL IN LOVE WITH YOU.
YOU BROKE MY HEART SO THAT YOU COULD
STAY HOME AND MAKE SOME GREEN GOO !
SARA, IT'S MUCH MORE THAN THAT.
FLUBBER COULD SAVE THIS COLLEGE.
LET ME DEMONSTRATE.
NO, NO, NO. JUST GIVE ME ONE MINUTE. OKAY ?
THE FLUBBER IS PLACED IN MY BACK POCKET.
WHEN I EXIT THIS WINDOW, I WILL FALL TO THE GROUND.
WHEN I HIT THE GROUND,
THE FLUBBER WILL SEND ME BACK UP UNHARMED. WATCH.
TA-TA, MY LOVE.
ARE YOU NUTS ?
- I'LL BE RIGHT BACK. - PHILLIP !
- OUCH. - PHILLIP, ARE YOU HURT ?
JUST MY PRIDE.
IF YOU THINK THAT YOU ARE GOING TO GET MY SYMPATHY,
YOU ARE WASTING YOUR TIME !
OOH ! WE ARE FINISHED !
[ Whispering ] SARA.
[ Groaning ]
[ Glass Shattering, Shouting ]
JUNIOR'S HOME.
DAD ?
DAD !
SOMEBODY IN YOUR ORGANIZATION SCREWED UP BIG TIME.
I GOT THROWN OFF THE BASKETBALL TEAM.
I FLUNKED CHEMISTRY.
I'M ON, UH, ACADEMIC PROBATION.
HOW DID THIS HAPPEN ?
I'M SUPPOSED TO GET A'S. AT LEAST,
THAT'S WHAT I WAS TOLD.
THE ONLY REASON I LOANED THIS "JERKNUT"
COLLEGE MONEY...
WAS SO HE COULD GET STRAIGHT
A'S AND GO TO HARVARD BUSINESS SCHOOL.
THIS ISN'T SUPPOSED TO HAPPEN.
YES, SIR. WE TALKED TO THAT BRAINARD GUY,
THE CHEMISTRY PROFESSOR.
EITHER HE DID NOT UNDERSTAND US OR HE FORGOT.
THE BOY KNEW WE WERE HAVING PERSUASION PROBLEMS,
SIR.
I HAVE A SCIENCE REQUIREMENT, YOU MORONS !
QUIET.
WE'LL HAVE TO GET THE "F" CHANGED TO AN "A."
WON'T WORK.
THIS GUY, HE DOESN'T LIVE
IN THE REAL WORLD. HE HAS PRINCIPLES.
GET SOMETHING ON HIM THAT WE CAN USE...
TO FORCE HIM TO CHANGE THE KID'S GRADE.
WHEN A MAN SAYS HE HAS PRINCIPLES,
WHAT HE MEANS IS HE CAN'T BE BOUGHT CHEAP.
HMPH. HMM.
[ Sneezes ]
ADDING 500 MILLIGRAMS...
CRYSTALLIZED FLUBBER TO COMMON HAND CREAM.
STIRRING IN SOLUTION.
HMPH.
HMPH. I JUST NEED ONE SPHERICAL TEST SUBJECT.
PERFECT.
NOW, ABOUT TWO--
APPLYING FLUBBER IN A SOLUTION...
EXTERNALLY TO GOLF BALL.
ALL RIGHT. VERY GOOD.
EVENLY OVER THE ENTIRE SURFACE.
KINETIC TEST NUMBER ONE.
OH. OH ! OH !
[ Groans ]
[ Chuckles ] ARE YOU ALL RIGHT ?
ALL RIGHT.
APPLYING LIGHT COATING OF FLUBBER...
TO SURFACE OF BOWLING BALL.
ALL RIGHT.
OH. VERY GOOD.
[ Groaning ] OH. RIGHT IN THE HEAD.
THE GOLF BALL WAS REALLY MOVING.
HOW'D HE DO THAT ? I DON'T KNOW.
COMMENCING KINETIC ENERGY TEST NUMBER TWO.
CONTROLLING HORIZONTAL MOMENTUM.
COMMENCING NOW.
HIT THE DECK !
[ High-Pitched Voice ] THIS DEFINITELY HAS
APPLICATIONS IN THE FIELD OF SPORTS.
HO-HO, YES !
[ Laughing ]
[ Groans ] [ Cat Screeches ]
WHAT ?
[ Groans ] OH !
FLUID FLUBBER...
WITH A CONVENIENT SPRAY APPLICATOR.
IT'S CLOGGED. HMM.
YOU SEEN ENOUGH ? PLENTY.
ALL RIGHT, AFTER THE BOWLING BALL HITS,
WE BREAK FOR THE CAR.
OH, WAIT A MINUTE. YOU CAN ADJUST IT.
GO !
[ Both Yelling ]
[ Yelling ]
- [ Gasps ] - [ Both Groaning ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Pressurized Tool Revving ]
[ Phillip ] OH, DAMN ! OH !
YES ! WEEBO ? YES, SIR ?
IT'S GONNA WORK. I HOPE SO.
NOW, LET ME SHOW YOU HOW.
I CONNECTED THE ACCELERATOR TO A SLIDING SHUTTER.
IF I PRESS DOWN ON THE ACCELERATOR,
IT RELEASES THE GAMMA RAYS,
AND THAT INCREASES THE THRUST.
[ Flubber Chugging ] AHH, LISTEN TO THAT
BABY CHIRP.
NOW... THE STEERING WHEEL CONTROLS LATERAL MOTION.
MM-HMM.
IF YOU TURN RIGHT, IT'LL STEER RIGHT. AH.
TURNS RIGHT.
TURN THE WHEEL LEFT, IT STEERS LEFT.
SO, IT FUNCTIONS A LOT LIKE A
NORMAL AUTOMATIC SHIFT...
WITH DRIVE, PARK, NEUTRAL, REVERSE. YES.
IT'S THAT EASY.
SEE, WEEBO ? PROFESSOR ! HELP ! LET ME OUT !
OH, WEEBO. PROFESSOR !
OHH ! WHAT WERE YOU DOING IN THERE ?
FLIRTING WITH THE ALTERNATOR.
HOPE YOU DIDN'T TOUCH ANYTHING.
IT'S NOT THE TIME TO PLAY.
WE'RE ABOUT TO MAKE A MAJOR BREAKTHROUGH.
[ Weebo ] OKAY, HERE WE GO.
YEAH, I THINK WE'RE READY.
WEEBO ? YES ?
WHAT DO YOU SAY WE TAKE HER FOR A RIDE ?
FLY ME TO THE MOON ! THAT'S IT !
THAT'S THE SPIRIT !
WE'LL FLY OVER TO SARA'S HOUSE,
PARK THIS BABY ON THE ROOF.
THEN MAYBE SHE'S GONNA CHANGE HER TUNE.
- YOU KNOW, MAYBE YOU SHOULD JUST GO WITHOUT ME.
- WHY ?
BECAUSE I GET CAR SICK.
COME ON. YOU'RE NOT GONNA BLOW CHIPS. NO.
YOU DON'T HAVE A STOMACH. I HAVE A QUEASY GYRO.
NOW GET OVER IT. THIS IS NOT ABOUT CARS.
THIS IS ABOUT SARA.
NOW GET IN HERE.
NO !
NOW. ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE FINE NOW. [ Laughing ]
AHH, OUT INTO THE WORLD. OKAY, HERE WE GO.
LOOK AT THIS ! LET'S SEE WHAT THIS BABY WILL DO.
OH ! IT WORKS !
[ Weebo ] YES, IT DOES. I'M PSYCHED !
OH, BOY !
[ Phillip ] YOU KNOW WHAT THIS MEANS, WEEBO ? WHAT ?
I'LL NEVER HAVE TO BUY TIRES AGAIN. [ Laughing ]
LET'S SEE WHAT'S ON THE RADIO, WEEBO. HO ! LATIN !
♪♪ [ Radio: Mambo ] ♪ BAM, BA-BUM, BA-BUM BA-BOOM ♪
♪ BUM, BA-BUM, BA-BUM HEY ♪
♪ BAM, BA-BING, BOOM-BOOM
♪♪ [ Mambo Continues ]
RIGHT TURN.
WHOA ! YES !
HUH ? HUH ? [ Closes Car Door ]
YEAH, WE'RE FINE.
WHOA ! [ Sighs ] IT'S ALL RIGHT. I SAW IT.
[ Laughing ] I DON'T THINK SO.
WEEBO, THERE IS NOTHING TO WORRY ABOUT. [ Gasps ]
[ Phillip ] OH ! MAYDAY !
[ Phillip ] COME ON. EASY.
OH ! SORRY.
FIRST-TIME FLYER. SHH.
[ Screaming ]
[ Geese Honking ] [ Car Horn Honks ]
[ Honking ]
I'M VERY SORRY.
[ Honks ]
HANG ON, WEEBO ! AAH !
OH ! WHOA ! AAH, WEEBO !
OH, NOW WE'RE COOKIN' !
[ Phillip ] WHOA !
WHOA !
[ Laughing ]
[ Phillip ] OH... YES !
[ Sighs ] OH, WEEBO, COME ON UP.
PLEASE, YOU'VE GOTTA SEE THIS.
WOW ! IS THIS WHAT YOU CALL...
HEAVEN ?
ALMOST. LOOK AT IT.
[ Phillip Sighs ] THE WHOLE WORLD,
BELOW AND BEYOND.
IT'S BEAUTIFUL. THE SOLITUDE UP HERE,
THE STILLNESS.
[ Engine Off ]
THE SILENCE. UH-OH.
- [ Screaming ] - [ Screams ]
SILLY ME TURNED IT OFF. TURNS RIGHT BACK ON.
THE SHUTTER'S JAMMED PROBABLY, WEEBO. WE'RE OKAY.
[ Screaming ]
START RIGHT UP !
OH, PLEASE TURN ON !
[ Phillip ] FOR THE LOVE OF NEWTON, TURN OVER !
[ Engine Cranking ]
- [ Alarm Ringing ] - ABANDON SHIP !
[ Screaming ]
OHH... YES ! [ Sighs ]
[ Phillip Laughs ]
IT'S SUCH A PLEASURE TO SPEND TIME WITH YOU...
WITHOUT HAVING BRAINARD HOVERING ABOVE US.
MMM.
MORE WINE ? NO, NO, THANK YOU.
I HAVE TO SAY GOOD NIGHT.
I HAVE A BUSY, BUSY DAY TOMORROW.
RUTLAND WOULD DIE TO HAVE YOU.
WE'D BE TOGETHER WITH NOTHING BUT TIME.
- SARA ? - HMM ?
MMMM.
I'M SORRY, WILSON.
FORGET IT. IT'S OKAY.
WE HAVE LOTS OF TIME.
LISTEN, I'M DRIVING UP ON
THURSDAY TO RUTLAND FOR THE GAME.
I'LL SEE YOU THERE.
SHOULD I MAKE DINNER RESERVATIONS ?
SINCE RUTLAND IS GOING TO LOSE, I'LL PAY.
ALL RIGHT. IF YOUR TEAM WINS,
YOU CAN BUY ME DINNER.
IF YOUR TEAM LOSES,
WE GO UP TO THE MOUNTAINS FOR THE WEEKEND.
MMM.
CAD !
DO WE HAVE A BET ?
I'LL THINK ABOUT IT.
I CAN'T LOSE ! SHE'S MINE !
SIR ISAAC.
OH !
O-O-O-O-O-OUT !
ALL RIGHT. ONE MORE TIME.
WHAT HAPPENED ?
HE TOOK A GOLF BALL. HE RUBBED THIS CREAM ON IT.
THEN THE GOLF BALL TOOK OFF AND...
POPPED SMITH IN THE HEAD.
SEVERAL TIMES.
MM-HMM.
- I GOT HIT WITH A BOWLING BALL.
- REPEATEDLY.
WERE YOU DRINKING ?
NO.
TWO BEERS AT DINNER. WESSON HAD A WHITE WINE.
WITH DINNER.
RIGHT.
IT'S THIS STUFF HE'S GOT, SIR. IT'S--
I DON'T KNOW WHAT IT IS.
I DON'T KNOW WHERE IT COMES FROM, BUT--
[ Sighs ]
IT WILL GIVE YOU ONE HECK OF A HEADACHE.
OH... GOODNESS.
[ Weebo ] OH, I WISH I COULD MAKE YOU FEEL BETTER.
HMM.
SO DO I.
MAYBE I'M OLD-FASHIONED,
BUT I BELIEVE A WOMAN SHOULD LOVE A MAN FOR WHAT HE IS,
AND NOT FOR WHAT SHE WANTS HIM TO BE.
THANKS FOR THE SENTIMENT, WEEBO,
BUT THIS IS REALLY NOT AN AREA
YOU'RE QUALIFIED TO OFFER PERSPECTIVE ON.
WELL, I DON'T HAVE MUCH OF A SMILE, BUT I DO HAVE A BRAIN.
I HAVE TO DEAL WITH THIS ALONE.
IT'S A HUMAN MATTER, NOT FOR COMPUTERS.
IT'S FOR PEOPLE.
GOOD NIGHT, WEEBO. GOOD NIGHT, PROFESSOR.
[ Beeping ]
MMM. [ Quiet Chuckle ]
- HMM ! - [ Weebo Gasps ]
[ Gasps ] I GOT IT !
I GOTTA TURN THIS THING OFF.
THIS IS SO EMBARRASSING.
WEEBO, I JUST HAD THIS AMAZING DREAM !
WEEBO. HURRY, HURRY, HURRY, HURRY.
WEEBO. WEEBO.
WEEBO, WAKE UP.
MMM. [ Yawns ]
- I'VE SOLVED ALL OUR PROBLEMS. - I'M ALL EARS.
FLUBBER IS GOING TO THE BASKETBALL GAME.
BASKETBALL ? YES !
TESTING, TESTING.
APPLYING THIN LAYER OF FLUID FLUBBER...
TO SYNTHETIC LEATHER SURFACE OF BASKETBALL.
APPLICATION COMPLETE.
WOW !
OOPS.
TWO POINTS.
IMPLEMENTING PLAN "B."
VERY TIGHT.
TIGHT.
AND... CAREFUL, CAREFUL, CAREFUL.
AHH.
SECONDARY FLUBBER EXPERIMENT.
CONTROL ELEMENTS, BUNGEE CORD.
THREE-TO-ONE ELASTICITY RATIO, FIFTY-POUND BALLAST.
COMMENCING NOW.
WISH ME LUCK.
OH ! WHOA.
OHHH !
OH, YES !
HA-HA.
WHOA !
I...
GOT IT !
OW !
OH, BUNGEE ! BUNGEE !
AH, HELP.
AH... YEOW !
[ Screaming ]
[ Spitting ]
IT WORKED !
[ Laughing ] YES !
END TEST.
[ Sighs ]
DID YOU FULLY FIX THE FLUBBER ON EACH TACK BEFORE WE PAINTED ?
EXCUSE ME, DARTH VADER, BUT WHAT DID YOU SAY ?
DID YOU FULLY FIX A 15%
FLUBBER SOLUTION TO EACH TACK BEFORE WEBER STARTED PAINTING ?
YES. I'M POSITIVE. [ Phillip ] EXCELLENT.
HOW LONG DOES IT TAKE THE PAINT TO WEAR OFF ?
THIRTY MINUTES.
THEY'LL BE A LITTLE SUSPICIOUS
IF THE FLUBBER STARTED WORKING IMMEDIATELY.
ISN'T THIS CHEATING ?
NO, IT'S NOT CHEATING. IT'S EQUALIZING.
YOU'VE SEEN THE TEAM. THEY SHOULD HAVE THEIR OWN TELETHON.
COME ON ! WE'VE GOT TO WIN THIS GAME.
I'VE GOT TO DO IT TO PROVE TO SARA THAT FLUBBER REALLY WORKS.
I'M GONNA DO IT RIGHT UNDER WILSON CROFT'S NOSE.
DON'T FAIL ME.
WEEBO ? YES ?
WHILE I'M OUT, YOU'RE IN CHARGE. OKAY ? OKAY.
NO PHONE CALLS TO RUSSIA AGAIN. I THINK THAT WAS WEBER.
OH ! MAKE SURE THE FLUBBER STAYS IN THE TANK. GOT IT.
UNDER NO CIRCUMSTANCES ARE YOU TO RELEASE IT. OF COURSE !
- BECAUSE YOU KNOW WHAT WOULD HAPPEN. - HO-HO-HO.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND ? YES, SIR, I UNDERSTAND.
- PROMISE ? - HAVE NO FEAR.
THAT'S MY GIRL.
GO, MEDFIELD ! [ Laughing ]
OKAY !
[ P.A. Announcer ] GOOD EVENING, EVERYBODY,
AND WELCOME TO RUTLAND ARENA...
FOR THE 86th MEETING OF THE RUTLAND RANGERS
AND THE MEDFIELD SQUIRRELS.
RUTLAND, IF THEY CAN STAY AWAKE,
SHOULD BE ABLE TO STEAMROLL THE SQUIRRELS TONIGHT.
ALL RIGHT, SQUIRRELS, LISTEN UP HERE NOW.
OKAY, RUTLAND MAY HAVE US IN HEIGHT AND REACH,
WEIGHT AND POWER,
AGILITY, SPEED AND TALENT.
THEY HAVE THE ADVANTAGE ON OFFENSE...
AND DEFENSE.
SURE, THEY'RE BETTER COACHED,
BETTER TRAINED.
AND THEIR WILL TO WIN IS UNMATCHED IN THE CONFERENCE.
THEY'RE UNDEFEATED IN THEIR LAST...
108 GAMES.
BUT THAT DOESN'T MEAN WE CAN'T WHIP THESE GUYS ! RIGHT ?
[ Whistle Blows ]
- YEAH ! - OHH !
RUTLAND... RANGERS ! RUTLAND... RANGERS !
YEAH ! COME ON !
[ Low Electronic Tones ]
OOH.
OKAY, FLUBBER, IT'S TIME THAT YOU AND I
GOT TO KNOW EACH OTHER.
[ Buzzer Buzzes, Crowd Cheering ]
[ P.A. Announcer ] ANOTHER EASY BASKET FOR THE RUTLAND RANGERS.
THEY HAVE BUILT UP A COMMANDING LEAD IN THE FIRST HALF.
EVENING, SARA. EXCUSE ME ?
WHAT A COINCIDENCE.
♪♪ [ Organ: "Charge" ]
COME ON, YOU GUYS, YOU GOTTA DO--
NOT NOW, ERNIE, NOT NOW !
GO, MEDFIELD !
[ Loud Horn Blast ] OW !
OH. SORRY. SORRY, WILSON.
SEE IF YOU CAN GET ME ANOTHER TEN GRAND ON RUTLAND.
YOU GOT A PROBLEM, BENNETT ?
YOU'RE BETTING AGAINST MY TEAM ? IT'S NOT YOUR TEAM.
THEY THREW YOU OFF. REMEMBER ?
OOF ! OH, BABY. THAT'S GOTTA HURT.
HE FOULED HIM ! HE THREW HIS HIP INTO THAT !
FLUBBER ? FLUBBER ! WHERE ARE YOU ?
[ Purring, Blubbering ]
[ Record Scratches ] [ Man ] ♪ MAA-AAMBO ♪
♪♪ [ Mambo ]
♪♪
MAMBO !
YEAH ! [ Giggling ]
HEY ! [ Singing, Blabbering ]
♪♪ [ Soprano ]
♪♪ [ Continues ]
[ Rattling ]
WHOO-HOO ! YEAH ! ♪♪ [ Ends ]
- [ Applause, Cheering ]
- [ Announcer ] WELCOME BACK FOR HALF NUMBER TWO.
THE MEDFIELD SQUIRRELS TONIGHT
ARE GETTING THEIR NUTS BURIED,
TRAILING BY 51 AT INTERMISSION.
IF COACH BARKER HAS ANY SENSE,
HE HAS TO BE THINKING FORFEITURE--
OHH ! OHH !
[ Announcer Continues ] ...FOR HALF NUMBER TWO.
COME ON, BOYS. EXPECT THE UNEXPECTED.
DALE. COME ON, SON, YOU CAN DO IT. COME ON, BRUCE.
BE A FLYING SQUIRREL.
BART. THE IMPOSSIBLE'S POSSIBLE. COME ON, LAWRENCE.
RODENTS RULE ! AAAH ! LOSER !
[ Cheering Continues ]
♪♪ [ Organ: "Charge" ]
[ Whispers ] SHOW TIME.
♪♪ [ Continues ] [ Man ] GO ! KEEP GOIN' !
- [ Giggles ] IT'S-- - OHH.
[ Young Man ] YEAH ! ALL RIGHT !
GET 'EM, MEDFIELD !
[ Players Shouting ]
COME ON !
THAT'S PRETTY GOOD.
[ Cheerleaders ] OKAY, GO !
BEAT 'EM ! LET'S GO !
[ Groaning ]
WHOA !
- OHH ! - [ Grunts ]
[ All Gasping ]
- [ Crowd Cheering ] - YES !
- GOSH ! WE'VE NEVER-- - YEAH !
DID YOU SEE THAT ? DID YOU SEE THAT, DAD ? YES !
- [ All Yelling ] - WHAT THE--
[ Yelling Continues ]
WHOA !
- [ Sara ] WE DID IT ! - [ Groaning ]
WOW ! WOW !
HEY ! ARE YOU BLIND ?
THEY'RE DOING SOMETHING ILLEGAL OUT HERE.
NOWHERE IN THE RULE BOOK DOES IT SAY
ANYTHING ABOUT JUMPING TOO HIGH.
NOW SIT DOWN. I DON'T KNOW.
LOOKS LIKE A LONELY WEEKEND IN THE MOUNTAINS FOR YOU,
CROFT.
[ Boy ] COME ON, SQUIRRELS ! [ Whistle Blows ]
[ Crowd Gasping ]
YEAH !
DID YOU SEE THAT, CROFT ?
[ Grunts ]
[ Horn Blows ]
[ Players Shouting ] ♪♪ [ Organ: "Charge" ]
HERE ! DALE ! DALE !
- YES ! - [ Crowd Cheering ]
[ Shouting, Laughing ]
[ Laughing ]
WHAT--
OHH.
DALE. NO !
WHATEVER YOU'RE DOING, KEEP DOING IT.
DALE !
NOT THE TACKS !
I DON'T KNOW. OKAY, NOW,
THIS GAME IS NOT OVER YET.
JUST STEAL THE BALL AND SCORE !
PARDON ME, BOYS. EDUCATOR COMING THROUGH.
COACH, I KNOW VERY LITTLE ABOUT BASKETBALL,
BUT I DO KNOW CHEMISTRY.
I BELIEVE DALE IS HAVING A PROBLEM--
NOT WITH MOTIVATION BUT WITH SOME SORT OF ADHESIVE
BUILDUP ON THE BOTTOM OF HIS SHOES.
DO YOU HAVE ANY ETHYL ALCOHOL ? WHAT ?
EXCUSE ME. HELLO, DALE.
OH, HELLO, PROFESSOR BRAINARD. MAY I SEE YOUR "SOLE" ?
WH-- I MEAN, THE BOTTOM OF YOUR SHOE.
OHH ! OH.
NO. GAME'S NOT OVER YET.
KEEP YOUR CHIN UP AND YOUR POTENTIAL ENERGY HIGH.
YOU KNOW WHY, DALE ?
SON OF A--
GET THE BALL. JUMP WITH ALL YOUR "SOUL."
UH, B-BUT I'M ON THIS END, SIR.
JUMP, OR I'LL FLUNK YOU. UH--
W-WHAT ? YOU HEARD ME.
JUMP, OR I'LL FLUNK YOU OUT OF MY DEPARTMENT FOR GOOD.
[ Sighs ] OKAY.
[ Cheerleaders Chanting ] A-T-T-A-C-K ! MEDFIELD IS BACK !
THINK THAT'S A LITTLE HARSH, BUT--
JUMP !
[ Cheerleaders ] A-T-T-A-C-K ! MEDFIELD IS BACK !
[ Announcer ] THE MEDFIELD SQUIRRELS ARE TRYING TO
COMPLETE THIS ASTONISHING COMEBACK.
NICE AND PATIENT, RUTLAND. PLENTY OF TIME, BABY.
[ Announcer ] RUTLAND HAS THE LEAD,
WITH THE CLOCK WINDING DOWN.
THESE RODENTS HAVE FOUGHT THEIR LITTLE HEARTS OUT TONIGHT,
BUT IT LOOKS LIKE THE SQUIRRELS ARE GONNA COME UP
A COUPLE OF NUTS SHORT OF A BUSHEL.
PLAYING KEEP-AWAY ARE THE RANGERS.
HERE'S A WIDE-OPEN "J" BY HATCH.
JUMP, DALE ! JUMP !
[ Announcer ] JEPNER IS SOARING INTO THE AIR,
MAKES THE STEAL.
LOOK AT HIM GO ! JEPNER WITH WINGS ON HIS SHOES,
SOARING TO THE OTHER END.
- HE'S ALL OVER IT ! HE DIVES ! HE'S THROUGH !
- [ Whistle Blows ]
- MEDFIELD UPSETS RUTLAND ON
AN INCREDIBLE PLAY BY JEPNER ! - YEAH !
- NO ! - [ Announcer ] THE SQUIRRELS ARE GOING NUTS !
- YEAH ! - WE WON !
WE DID IT ! WE DID IT !
[ Wilson ] FOUL ! FOUL !
SINCE WHEN IS IT WITHIN THE RULES...
FOR A PLAYER TO ACCOMPANY THE BALL THROUGH THE HOOP ?
OH, I DON'T KNOW. COME ON. I OWE YOU DINNER.
SARA ?
GOOD NIGHT, PHILLIP. GOOD NIGHT.
BRAINARD HAS SOMETHING TO DO WITH THIS.
IT'S THE SAME STUFF WE SAW THE OTHER NIGHT,
OVER AT HIS HOUSE.
RIGHT.
I DON'T KNOW HOW,
BUT I'M ABSOLUTELY CERTAIN YOUR TEAM CHEATED.
OH, YOU'RE JUST BEING A SORE LOSER.
SARA, M-M-MAY I SPEAK TO YOU FOR A MOMENT... ALONE ?
WHAT YOU HAVE TO SAY TO HER
YOU CAN SAY TO BOTH OF US... IF YOU CAN REMEMBER.
SARA ?
FLUBBER.
FLUBBER ? SOUNDS LIKE BABY SHAMPOO.
[ Whispers ] SARA.
FLUBBER IS WHAT WON THE GAME.
THAT AMAZING AERIAL BALLET ?
THAT'S BECAUSE I FLUBBERIZED THE BOYS' SHOES.
A LITTLE ON THE BOTTOM-- WHOO !
YOU'RE REMARKABLE.
[ Phillip ] SARA ?
GOOD NIGHT, PHILLIP.
WATCH YOURSELF.
WHAT DO WE HAVE TO DO TO GET YOU TO TAKE A HINT ?
IT'S OVER, PHILLIP. YOU LOST.
GO HOME. PLAY WITH YOUR RUBBER.
[ Door Closes, Engine Starts ]
WHAT KIND OF CAR DOES THAT BRAINARD FELLOW DRIVE ?
OLD T-BIRD. WHY ?
I JUST SAW IT.
- SO ? - IT WAS FLYING.
YOU HEARD ME. FLYING.
[ Weebo ] HEY, WHO WON ? WE DID.
UM, PROFESSOR ?
WHY THE LONG FACE ?
I THINK YOU KNOW WHY.
MAYBE...
A SARA ISSUE ?
WISH I UNDERSTOOD HUMAN BEINGS.
WISH I UNDERSTOOD WOMEN. [ Chuckles ]
WISH I UNDERSTOOD EMOTIONS AND PASSIONS.
WISH I UNDERSTOOD ANY OF THAT.
IF I DID,
I WOULDN'T HAVE HAD TO SPEND MY ENTIRE LIFE IN A LABORATORY...
TRYING TO FIGURE OUT HOW THE WORLD WORKS.
I WOULD'VE BEEN OUT IN THE WORLD
TRYING TO FIGURE OUT WHY IT WORKS.
I KNOW I LOVE HER, WEEBO.
EVERY NEURON IN MY LIMBIC SYSTEM...
IS SATURATED WITH PHENYLETHYLAMINE.
THAT TRIGGERS EUPHORIA, ELATION, EXHILARATION.
TRUTH IS, WEEBO,
I'M NOT ABSENT-MINDED BECAUSE I'M SELFISH,
CRAZY OR--
OR INCONSIDERATE.
I'M ABSENT-MINDED BECAUSE I'M IN LOVE WITH SARA.
OH, PROFESSOR.
THAT DOESN'T MATTER ANYMORE,
'CAUSE I DON'T GET ANY MORE CHANCES WITH HER.
OH, THAT'S NOT TRUE.
THERE'S ALWAYS ANOTHER CHANCE.
I MEAN, YOU NEVER KNOW, RIGHT ?
PROBABLY JUST AS WELL THAT IT'S OVER. WHY ?
SHE HAS TO MOVE ON. OH.
I'M NOT RIGHT FOR HER.
BUT YOU KNEW THAT, DIDN'T YOU, WEEBO ?
HUH ? YOU NEVER WANTED ME TO MARRY HER.
MMM.
WELL, YOU WERE RIGHT. I WASN'T RIGHT FOR HER.
YOU'RE THE ONE FOR ME, WEEBO.
JUST THE TWO OF US.
AND FLUBBER MAKES THREE.
GOOD NIGHT, WEEB. GOOD NIGHT.
[ Sighs ] UH, PROFESSOR--
AND THIS IS THE GOD'S TRUTH--
I WANT HIM TO HAVE WHAT HE WANTS,
EVEN IF IT MEANS YOU INSTEAD OF ME.
[ Dog Barking ]
OOOH !
[ Sighs ]
SARA ? SARA ? IT'S ME.
WEEBO ? MAY I COME IN ?
OH, I'M SORRY TO WAKE YOU LIKE THIS,
BUT I CAN'T RING THE DOORBELL.
IS EVERYTHING OKAY WITH PHILLIP ?
OH, YEAH. IT'S NOT A CONVENTIONAL EMERGENCY.
OH, PHILLIP WOULD BE VERY ANGRY IF HE KNEW I LEFT,
BUT I HAVE TO SHOW YOU SOMETHING.
DO YOU HAVE A MINUTE ?
[ Beeping ] LISTEN.
I KNOW I LOVE HER, WEEBO.
EVERY NEURON IN MY LIMBIC SYSTEM...
IS SATURATED WITH PHENYLETHYLAMINE.
THAT TRIGGERS EUPHORIA, ELATION, EXHILARATION.
TRUTH IS, WEEBO, I'M NOT ABSENT-MINDED
BECAUSE I'M SELFISH, CRAZY OR--
OR INCONSIDERATE.
I'M ABSENT-MINDED BECAUSE I'M IN LOVE WITH SARA.
[ Weebo Sighs ]
THIS WILL BE OUR LITTLE SECRET.
PHILLIP.
OHH.
SARA ?
UH-HUH.
[ Sara ] THIS IS IT.
THIS IS THE SOLUTION.
THIS IS HOW WE SAVE THE SCHOOL.
THAT'S WHAT I'VE BEEN SAYING.
FLUBBER. YOU SAW WHAT IT DID AT THE GAME. YES.
IMAGINE THE LINE OF SHOES WE COULD DEVELOP.
OH, NO, PHILLIP, NOT SHOES.
NO. LOOK.
THIS. FLIGHT.
FLIGHT ? YES.
OH ! OF COURSE. AIR TRAVEL.
OH, SARA. AIR TRAVEL.
YES. OHH.
WE'D BETTER SELL THIS TO A CAR COMPANY. OH, PHILLIP.
HEY ! [ Gasps ]
DR. REYNOLDS. PROFESSOR.
IT'S A PLEASURE TO FINALLY MEET YOU.
I BELIEVE YOU KNOW MY SON.
HE USED TO PLAY BASKETBALL FOR MEDFIELD.
LOVELY OLD CAR.
MIND IF I TAKE A LOOK UNDER THE HOOD ?
YES, I DO.
AND I DON'T APPRECIATE YOU GENTLEMEN...
LETTING YOURSELVES ONTO MY PROPERTY.
I EXPECTED SOMETHING MORE COMPLEX.
THERE'S A LOT OF MONEY IN YOUR DISCOVERY.
PERHAPS WE COULD MAKE A DEAL.
ANY DISCOVERY I MAKE WILL BELONG TO MEDFIELD COLLEGE.
AT THE END OF THE TERM
THERE ISN'T GOING TO BE A MEDFIELD COLLEGE.
WE'LL SEE ABOUT THAT.
YOU COULD MAKE A LOT OF MONEY.
IF WE WERE INTERESTED IN MAKING MONEY,
WE WOULDN'T HAVE BECOME TEACHERS.
YOU THINK YOU'LL BE ABLE TO SELL IT FOR
WHAT YOU OWE ME BY THE END OF THE TERM ?
WE WILL.
I'LL FORGET THE DEBT RIGHT NOW.
NO. I'M NOT SELLING.
WHEN I LEAVE,
I TAKE MY OFFER WITH ME.
WE UNDERSTAND.
GOOD LUCK.
COME ON.
WATCH YOUR BACK, SMART GUY.
BAD MOVE, PROFESSOR.
[ Phillip ] GOOD MORNING !
PARDON ME, MR. SELDON.
ARE YOU INTERESTED IN SEEING A PHILLIP BRAINARD ?
WHO ?
HE'S THE COLLEGE PROFESSOR YOU SPOKE TO ON THE SIXTH...
ABOUT A BRAND-NEW CAR DESIGN.
TELL HIM I'M BUSY, THANK HIM FOR THE INTEREST...
AND SEND HIM A HAT.
WELL, HE'S HERE. HE'S RIGHT OUTSIDE. [ Horn Honks ]
[ Flubber Chugging ]
[ Pedestrians Shouting ]
[ Man ] IT'S ONE OF THE RAREST LOOKS IN WATCHES YOU CAN ACTUALLY OWN.
THIS WATCH WE HAVE HERE IS CALLED THE SCARAB.
[ Yawns ]
GOOD NIGHT, WEBER.
[ Low Electronic Tones ]
[ Gasps ] WHAT ?
- [ Barking ] - [ Crash ]
[ Barking Continues ]
[ Flubber Growling ]
ONE GOON.
TWO GOONS.
[ Flubber Purrs ]
[ Tapping ]
- HEY. - WHAT ?
THINK I FOUND IT.
YOU FOUND IT, ALL RIGHT !
- [ Weebo Laughing ] - [ Groans ]
WHAT WAS THAT ?
[ Weebo ] TAKE TWO.
[ Grunting, Panting ]
[ Weebo ] KNOCK, KNOCK ! WHOOPS ! OHH !
[ Gasps ]
♪♪ [ Bugle ] [ Whooping, Shouting ]
KISS ME, BIG BOY !
- [ Grunts ] - [ Beeping ]
[ Electricity Crackling ]
[ Beeping Weakly ]
DID YOU GET IT ?
YEAH.
[ Flubber Whimpering ]
[ Phillip ] I-I'VE NEVER SEEN SO MANY ZEROES.
[ Phillip Laughing ]
WHEN THEY SAW US FLYING,
THEY COULDN'T WAIT TO WRITE THE CHECK.
THIS WILL SAVE THE SCHOOL, PHILLIP. [ Both Laughing ]
YES-- [ Gasps ]
[ Low Electronic Tones ]
WEEBO ?
THEY TOOK THE FLUBBER.
[ Electricity Crackles ]
- WEEB-- - [ Electricity Crackles ] - OHH.
UM, S-S-SHE'S LEAKING BATTERY FLUID.
WEEBO, IT'S ME.
DO YOU HAVE SIGNAL ?
DO YOU HAVE AUDIO SIGNAL ?
TRACKING ? IT'S ME. PROFESSOR BRAINARD.
FOCUS ? WEEBO ?
CAN YOU SEE ME ?
[ Whispers ] SHE SEES ME.
OH.
WEEBO.
IT'S ALL RIGHT. I'VE-- I'VE--
I NEED TO GET SOME SORT OF EXTENSION CORD,
SOMETHING, SO I CAN RECHARGE HER.
I'VE GOTTA-- I'VE GOTTA DOWNLOAD HER, QUICK.
WEEBO ?
IT'S ALL RIGHT. IT'S OKAY.
WEEBO.
CAN YOU HEAR ME ?
IT'S GONNA BE ALL RIGHT.
IT'S LIKE THAT TIME
YOU RAN INTO THE WALL WHEN I FIRST MADE YOU. [ Chuckles ]
WE'LL GET YOU UPSTAIRS, ONTO A.C., AND--
[ Whispering ] SHE-- SHE'S LOSING--
SHE'S LOSING POWER.
IT'S OKAY. IT'S ALL RIGHT.
JUST GOTTA GET YOU TO THE DOCKING STATION
TILL I CAN MAKE REPAIRS.
[ Weak Static Response ]
WEEBO ?
GOOD-BYE, MY FRIEND.
[ Whispers ] SHE'S GONE.
I HAVE NO IDEA WHAT--
GOOD-BYE.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO DO WITH HER.
WHAT HAPPENS TO THE SOUL OF A MACHINE, SARA ?
CAN YOU FIX HER ?
I CAN MAKE REPAIRS,
BUT I CAN NEVER BRING BACK THE LIFE IT
WAS SHE HAD.
THAT'S GONE.
I NEVER KNEW WHAT IT WAS TO BEGIN WITH.
IT WAS SOME SORT OF GLORIOUS ACCIDENT.
I KEPT TRYING TO
RECREATE IT AND ISOLATE IT AND FIND OUT WHAT IT WAS.
I NEVER COULD.
WHAT WAS THAT WORD
SHE WAS DISPLAYING ON HER SCREEN AT THE END ?
PROBABLY A FILENAME.
WHY WAS SHE DISPLAYING IT ?
SHE WAS DAMAGED. DOWNLOAD
A RANDOM PIECE OF INFORMATION.
I DON'T KNOW. WHAT WAS THAT WORD ?
OH, CAN YOU REMEMBER ?
NO, I-- [ Sighs ]
TRY. I AM.
IT BEGAN WITH "S."
HELLO, PHILLIP. IT'S ME.
WEEBO.
IF I WAS HUMAN, THAT IS.
I-IF YOU'RE WATCHING THIS, I'M NO LONGER HERE.
I HOPE MY DEMISE DIDN'T CAUSE
YOU ANY UNDUE DISTRESS.
PHILLIP,
A FULL AND COMPLETE DESIGN OF ME IS IN THIS FILE.
YOU DIDN'T FORGET IT. I NEVER SHOWED IT TO YOU.
I'VE MADE A FEW CHANGES.
I'VE REMOVED A FEW OF MY FLAWS...
AND ADDED A LITTLE OF YOU.
I HOPE THAT YOU CAN LOVE MY DAUGHTER...
AS MUCH AS I LOVED YOU.
[ Beeping ]
OOH.
[ Wesson ] SURPRISE, SURPRISE.
PROFESSOR BRAINARD. DR. REYNOLDS.
GOOD EVENING. SIT DOWN.
YOU LOOK, UH--
WEARY. YES.
WEARY.
YOU CAME TO REPAY YOUR LOAN ?
NO. I KNOW YOU DIDN'T.
I WAS JUST HAVING A LITTLE FUN.
I'M HERE TO SELL YOU THE FLUBBER.
YOU BEEN TO YOUR HOUSE RECENTLY ?
YES.
DO I REALLY NEED TO BUY IT ?
FLUBBER IS A VERY QUIXOTIC SUBSTANCE.
IT'S, UH, VERY DIFFICULT TO HANDLE.
HAVE YOU TRIED TO DO ANYTHING WITH IT ?
MY MAN IS WORKING ON IT.
- IT WON'T BE A PROBLEM. - WELL,
I COULD MAKE IT A LOT EASIER FOR YOU.
IF YOU GIVE US A 30-DAY EXTENSION ON THE LOAN,
I'LL TELL YOU EVERYTHING I KNOW...
AND MAKE YOU A GREAT DEAL OF FLUBBER.
I'LL GIVE YOU THE 30 DAYS,
AND AFTER THAT YOU GIVE ME TWO YEARS.
WHATEVER YOU
COME UP WITH OVER THE NEXT TWO YEARS IS MINE.
THAT'S NOT FAIR ! [ Bouncing Noise ]
SHOP SOMEWHERE ELSE, LADY.
SARA. SARA.
I'LL DO IT.
MAY I SEE THE FLUBBER ?
WOULD YOU LIKE TO SHOW THESE GOOD PEOPLE
TO THE LIBRARY ?
[ Beep ]
[ Engine Starts, Flubber Chugging ]
YOU'RE GOING TO ENJOY THIS.
PROFESSOR ?
I GOT YOU A LITTLE HELP.
[ Gasps ] THE LOVEBIRDS.
WILSON.
SHAME ON YOU.
WELCOME.
SO YOU FINALLY GAVE UP TEACHING.
HOW COULD I PASS UP
THE OPPORTUNITY TO TRANSFORM THE ENERGY INDUSTRY ?
FLUBBER. VERY INTERESTING, PHIL.
TOO BAD IT'S SO UNSTABLE.
I WAS JUST LOOKING OVER THE FORMULA.
DANGEROUS MIX.
YOU JUST HAVE TO KNOW HOW TO DEAL WITH IT,
REALLY. IT JUST TAKES A FEW SIMPLE--
HEY, HEY. HANG ON, "EINSTEEN."
STEIN. WHATEVER.
WHAT'S THIS ?
WELL, I
-IT'S A HAND CREAM THAT ACTS AS A SEPARATING AGENT.
RIGHT.
IT'S SO I CAN HANDLE THE FLUBBER.
IT'S OKAY.
THANK YOU. SHE NEEDS TO ASSIST ME.
RUB IT ON YOUR HANDS. [ Sighs ]
UHH ! WHOA.
IT'S A, UH,
SQUIRT GUN.
WHAT'S IT FOR ?
I USE THAT TO LOWER
THE TEMPERATURE OF THE TANK.
LET HIM HAVE IT.
NO, NO. GIVE IT TO HIM.
N-NO, NO. GIVE IT TO HIM.
STOP THAT AND GIVE IT TO HIM.
P-PUT IT IN HIS HAND AND GIVE IT TO HIM.
NO, NO, NO, NO. GIVE THE GUN TO HIM !
OH.
THANK YOU. YOU'RE WELCOME.
[ Canister Ticking, Clicking ]
[ Flubber Purring ]
YOU OKAY ? [ Purring Continues ]
- IT'S ME. - [ Sighs ]
[ Purring ]
THERE YOU GO.
- OH ! - NYAAAH !
DO IT FOR WEEBO. [ Growls ]
- LOOK OUT ! - [ Beeps ]
- [ Flubber Shrieking ] - OHH !
[ Hoenicker ] GET HIM !
- WHOA ! - OH, DEAR.
AAAH ! SARA. GOING SOMEWHERE ?
WILSON ?
- [ Groaning ] - OH.
[ Groaning Continues ]
- LEFT, LEFT, LEFT, RIGHT, LEFT.
- AND CROSS !
- [ Whimpering ] - SARA !
- HUH ? - GRAB HER.
WHAT ? JUMP !
I'M COMING, SARA !
YO !
WHOO-OO-AAAH !
- AAAAH ! - [ Karate Yell ]
OHHH ! OOH !
HEY, LUMPY. HMM ?
- COME ON. - LET'S GO, SMART GUY.
[ Yelling ]
[ Grunts ] OW.
[ Sara ] PHILLIP, LOOK OUT !
AAAH !
WHOA !
- SARA ! - WHOA !
- [ Phillip ] GET HIM. -
THIS ONE'S FOR WEEBO.
AAAH !
[ Flubber Chittering ]
AAAAH !
- [ Loud Gurgling ] - OOOH.
[ Gurgling Continues ]
OHH-HO ! [ Giggling, Gasping ]
OHHH-AAAH ! AAAH !
[ Gurgling Continues ] [ Laughing ]
[ Groaning, Yelling ]
AAAAAH--
OH, MOMMY--
[ Whimpers, Inhales ]
- OHH ! - [ Hisses ]
[ Whimpers, Gasps ]
[ Sighs ]
WOW.
♪♪ [ Whistles ] [ Sighs ]
[ Bicycle Spokes Whizzing, Bell Ringing ]
[ Liquid Bubbling ] HMM.
BEAUTIFUL.
[ Minister ] FOR AS MUCH AS THESE
TWO PEOPLE HAVE FINALLY...
CONSENTED TOGETHER IN HOLY WEDLOCK,
AND HAVE WITNESSED
THE SAME BEFORE GOD AND THIS COMPANY,
I PRONOUNCE, BELIEVE IT OR NOT,
THAT THEY BE HUSBAND AND WIFE TOGETHER.
YOU MAY NOW KISS THE... VIDEO SCREEN.
- OH. - [ Low Electronic Tones ]
[ Kissing Sounds ]
MMM. ♪♪ [ Organ: Wedding Recessional ]
LOVE YOU, SARA.
♪♪ [ Continues ] I LOVE YOU.
I'LL MEET YOU AT THE RECEPTION.
I'M ALMOST DONE. [ Test Tubes Clattering ]
IT'S GONNA BE REMARKABLE.
PHILLIP, PLEASE BE CAREFUL.
DON'T WORRY.
THESE CHEMICALS ARE COMPLETELY COMPATIBLE.
THERE'S NO CHANCE THAT ANYTHING...
COULD GO WRONG !
HEY, PAL.
WE'RE 30,000 FEET UP IN THE AIR.
THERE'S NO MONSTERS OR
BAD GUYS WAY UP HERE. OKAY ?
YOU CAN LOOK OUT THE WINDOW.
[ Flubber Chugging ]
[ Giggles ]
[ Chittering ]
MOM. MOM. FLUBBER'S GONE.
GET BACK HERE !
[ Weebette ] WHEN WE GET TO THE HOTEL,
I DON'T CARE WHAT YOU SAY.
I'M NOT SHARING A ROOM WITH HIM.
LOOK AT HIM. HE'S GROSS.
HE BOUNCES ALL THE TIME.
HE SQUEAKS. HE PHASE-SHIFTS.
I MEAN, HE'S A QUASI-PLASMOID.
IF IT'S HOT IN HAWAII, I HOPE HE MELTS.
[ Man ] OW-W-W-W !