[Dogs Barking]
[Man] Come on, boys!
Let's go. Hike!
Hike! Hike!
Let's go! Hike!
Let's go, Curly.
Atta boy!
That's it, Curly. Hike!
Yeah!
- That's a good boy.
- [Train Whistle Blowing]
Yeah! Yeah!
Okay, let's go, boy!
Come on, now!
We gotta race now!
We gotta race!
Let's catch 'em. Let's catch 'em.
Come on, boys! Yeah!
That's it.
Come on, Curly!
Let's get there first.
Let's beat 'em!
Let's go!
Come on, boys!
Come on! Let's move!
Come on! Come on!
We've gotta beat this train!
All right, all right, all right,
we got 'im, now!
Come on! Come on!
Almost there! Come on!
Yeah! All right!
Here you go.
- Whoa! Whoa!
- Watch it! Look out!
Curly, gee! Gee!
- Will, that was incredible!
- Incredibly foolish.
You could have been killed,
Will Stoneman.
How many times is there
an army truck in the
middle of the street?
I've been coming around
this corner my whole life.
Has there ever been
an army truck
in the middle of the street?
Nice piece of running there.
- So, how old are you, pal?
- Seventeen.
- Think you'll be ready to
fight a war in a year?
- No, I'm ready now.
- War with who?
- [Laughing]
Stay alive, buddy.
Your country might need ya.
- Coming on the run tomorrow?
- I ain't coming.
- We planned it. You gotta come.
- I can't.
- You know my father.
- Yeah.
Ward, you gonna do something
besides work for your father
your whole life?
Please, Will. Just 'cause
you want something doesn't
mean it's gonna happen.
- I know, but you can try, can't you?
- Ward!
Get back to the dock.
The train is on time,
Mr. Stoneman, and you are
once again late.
- Yeah, I got...
- If you're late again...
you're fired.
What are you so riled about?
Old man Burton. He's always
got something to say.
Next time he opens his mouth,
I swear, I'll knock his teeth in.
Don't waste time worrying about
the Burtons in this world, son.
They're too scared of living
to see past their own faces.
Besides, there's too damn
many of them anyway.
- One day you'll make him
eat his own words.
- You think?
Not a doubt in my mind.
There we go.
Come on. I'll help you
sort the mail.
Let's see:
Milkson, Sorrenson...
Jensen, Wilkerson
and Zeider.
That's it for...
- What have you got there?
- Just a letter.
[Sighs]
Hey!
[Whistles]
Is that from the college?
- Well, did you get in?
- Yes, sir.
You got in!
I'm so proud of you!
- I'm not going, Dad.
- What? Wha...
- I'm not going.
- What are you talking about?
I know how bad you
and Mom want this for me,
but it's just dreams.
- My place is here.
- Son, listen to me.
Your place is where your dreams are.
Now, you never forget that.
- Dad, what about the money?
- Don't worry about the money!
Look. When you need it, it'll
be there. That's a promise.
[Sighs] Come on.
Let's go tell your mom.
All right.
[Music][music] [Jack Whistles Tune To Dogs]
[Music][music][Whistling Continues]
- Come on, Will.
- I'm here.
Let's go, boy!
Come on, Will.
Whoa, boy.
- Zee-now, Tika.
- Easy, now.
Slow up, now.
Slow up.
- Good boy.
- [Laughing] Good dog!
Hey, Ned.
Good dog, yes.
Come here, Gus.
How ya doin'?
You're my dog, aren't ya?
You're my dog.
- Hey, Gus, good dog.
- [Laughing]
What? What is so funny?
- He bit me!
- Bite him back.
- Bite him back?
- He knows one master.
When he respects you
as he does your father,
then he'll like you.
Good dog, Curly.
Good dog.
Such a good dog.
- Mmm, yes, you are.
- [Barks]
That's a good dog.
[Jack] "Winnipeg to St. Paul
Carnival Dog Derby."
Listen to this, Ned.
"J.W. Harper announces...
"the longest, toughest,
richest race...
"in the history
of dogsledding...
- with a first prize of $10,000."
- Ten thousand dollars?
"The race will run from
Winnipeg, Canada...
to St. Paul, Minnesota,
500 miles."
Ten thousand dollars
for 500 miles!
- Not thinking of doing that,
are you, Jack?
- No, of course not.
- You should do it, Dad.
- He'd never make it.
- Why do you say that?
- He's too old.
He smokes too much.
[Jack] No, Ned. It's just because
I don't want it bad enough.
Besides, everything I want
is right here.
- Dad?
- Huh.
That's the way I feel too.
Look, son...
if you want something
real bad...
and you really want it...
you gotta go out where you
can find it and grab it.
Everybody's probably thinking
I'm just a big talker anyway.
- You know, wouldn't last
ten minutes away from the farm.
- [Mother] Actually...
we were wondering how the farm
would last without you.
Don't let fear stand in
the way of your dream, son.
Atta boy! Come on.
- Go! Pull, Gus! Pull!
- That's it, Curly.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Hey! Whoa!
Pull, Gus! Will!
Will, I'm caught!
Pull, Gus! Pull!
[Groaning]
Dad! Dad!
No, Dad! Don't let go!
Dad, no! I'm here!
- Dad, don't let go!
- Will, get back!
- Gus, pull!
- You're being pulled in!
Ah, no! Dad, hold on!
- Get back! You're coming in!
- No, no! Don't cut it, Dad!
No! Dad!
No-o-o! No, no!
[Gus Softly Growling]
He's not coming back, Gus.
He left us both.
Damn you, Dad.
[Whimpering]
I guess it's
you and me now, Gus.
- [Snarling, Barking]
- What? What?
Why didn't you pull
him out? Why?
You're his dog.
There was a whole team of you.
You wanna fight, huh?
You think I'm scared?
Don't!
[Speaking In Native Dialect]
It's not his fault.
It's not your fault either.
The river called his name.
No other reason.
- The river called his name.
- [Sobbing]
- He's gone, Ned.
- No.
No, he's with you forever.
[Music][music] [Whistling Jack's Whistle]
I've contacted most
of the customers.
- His dogs?
- Yeah.
[Man] I'll help you work out a plan,
but, Mrs. Stoneman...
you're going to have to
think about the farm.
[Music][music] [Jack's Whistle]
What you whistling?
I wasn't whistling anything.
It was your father's tune.
'Cept I can't do it
like he did.
Maybe you'll find
your own way.
I'm sorry, Will.
I've watched him, Mom.
I've worked with him.
I can fill these orders.
It's furniture, Mom.
It's tables and chairs and couches.
It wasn't only that.
It was your father's touch.
Ned can help.
He watches everything.
He knows Dad's work.
Will...
I'm arranging to sell the dogs.
We'll be able to pay off
most of our debts...
- the immediate ones anyway.
- You can't do that, Mom.
- The money we could get
for Gus alone...
- Gus?
- Gus is Dad's dog!
- And you're his son!
And he wanted to pay
for college because it
was important to you.
Maybe it's not so important
anymore. Maybe it never
should have been important.
Maybe I wasn't meant to go.
[Ned Chanting
In Native Dialect]
[Chanting]
[Panting]
[Dog Barking, Howling]
Down, Gus.
[Barking, Howling]
Mom! Mom!
- Mom, he was gonna enter the race.
- What?
"Winnipeg to St. Paul,
500 miles."
He was thinking of entering the race.
There's a difference.
But this was his solution,
and it still can be.
$10,000! That pays
for the farm, college...
Those men entering the race,
they're younger than your
father was and stronger.
- He couldn't possibly have
won and neither can you.
- But I can, Mom, I can!
I've just lost a husband.
I won't lose a son!
But, who said anything
about losing, Mom?
Ned, you've seen me race.
Tell her I can do it.
I taught Jack for years.
Even he couldn't run this race.
- You heard him say it.
- He didn't want it bad enough!
Since Dad died, I felt
my whole life was finished,
no more dreams.
We're barely making enough
to survive, with no hope
for anything better.
I couldn't dream anymore
about school.
When I saw this flier, I felt
life getting back into me.
- The race is in a month.
You're not ready.
- But you can get me ready!
- Not in a month.
- Mom?
Mom? Mom?
I want to feel alive.
I want to feel like Dad's alive...
right here.
And I don't.
I don't.
Mom, he was gonna
do this for me.
Now, let me do it for him.
Just tell me one thing:
Is it possible?
- Let's go, Will?
- W-What?
What are you doing? Ned!
Ned, what are you do...
Ned! Ned!
What are you doing?
Ned!
- Training begins now.
- Ned?
Ned? Ned, it's cold!
Ned! Ned!
Mom! Mom!
Mom, please, it's cold!
Mom, it's cold! Mom!
[Shivering]
Hi, guys.
Fellas.
[Whimpering]
- Hmm.
- The first few days
you sleep five hours.
Then four, then three, then two.
The last day you don't sleep.
You just run.
- Run 'til the end.
- [Drums, Native Chanting]
You have to be strong.
You have to learn focus,
stamina... and balance.
Only the smart ones will finish.
You have to run longer and sleep less.
- It's your only chance.
- Run longer, sleep less.
You'll make friends who aren't friends,
enemies who want to hurt you.
- Be careful who you trust.
- How do I know who to trust?
- Trust the dogs.
- Get...
- [Ned Laughing]
- Can't I just use Curly?
- Gus is a champion.
Yeah, but Gus
doesn't respect me.
[Chanting Continues]
You have one chance.
You must run at night
when the others have stopped.
Run with the moon.
Embrace the darkness.
Grow hard with the cold.
Put pain from your mind.
And on the last day,
when all will run at night...
you alone will be
friendly with the dark.
[Ned] You will need
these medicines.
If you are ill,
this will give you strength.
If you are hurt...
this... will heal you.
[Drums, Spirit Guide
Chanting]
[Whistle Blowing]
[Dogs Barking]
[Chanting]
[Train Bell Clanging]
Ten thousand dollars, Will.
You don't have to die for it.
If we lose the farm...
We'll lose it fighting.
But we're not gonna lose it.
Just come back alive.
[Ward] Will!
Here.
It's supposed to be from me.
I think you're both crazy.
Will, I'm your best friend.
Don't matter what
crazy things you do.
I just wish you could win.
I'll win. You can bet
all your money on that.
[Whistle Blowing]
What's this?
[Music][music] [Jack's Whistle]
[Chuckling]
- What?
- It's just...
being alone out there.
- Do you think I can do this?
- Matters most what you think.
I think you should come,
is what I think.
Be strong, boy.
Be brave.
Your father will be with you always.
He lives in your dreams.
Trust the dogs.
Trust yourself.
I will.
When you come to face
the thing you fear...
let the Creator guide you.
Ned...
take care of my mom.
Run longer.
Sleep less.
[Train Bell Clanging,
Whistle Blowing]
[Door Sliding]
[Brakeman] Wake up, son.
You're in Winnipeg.
Come on out of there.
I'll show you where
you can put up your dogs.
Thanks, mister.
[Brakeman]
Somethin', ain't it?
Belongs to Mr.J. W. Harper...
sponsor of the dog derby.
His personal steam locomotive.
[Men Chatting]
Well, that's what
I hear. Now...
[music][music][Ballroom]
[Cheering, Applauding]
Ladies and gentlemen...
from the great Clyde shipyards...
Angus McTeague.
Since the bankers control
all the money...
I think it right and proper
that Louis De Fountaine...
introduce his teams first.
My team consists of two racers
from our mother Canada:
From Quebec City,
Jacques Devereaux;
and from Montreal,
Jean Paul Remy.
[De Fountaine]
Angus, your teams...
- if you please.
- Ladies and gentlemen...
I'd like to present
Hyurtur Groven...
and Thordur Thorenson
from far-off Iceland.
And the great
Norwegian champion...
Gunnar Tveit.
And racing independently...
Joe McPherson
from Butte, Montana.
The only American
in the race.
And from Sweden...
the old Scandinavian champion...
Borg Guillarson.
And now, ladies
and gentlemen, the president...
of the Great Northern Railroad
and sponsor of this derby...
J. W. Harper!
Thank you, Louis.
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
Racing for the
Great Northern Railroad...
I'm proud to introduce
Mike Riley from Calgary.
- Take a bow, Mike.
- [Man] Take it to 'em, Mike!
And the Canadian champion
Indian sledders, Gabriel and Albert.
The legendary Carey Brothers.
Ladies and gentlemen...
we are here about a race!
Yeah!
[Glass Clinking]
The race will commence
tomorrow noon...
from the great clock tower
in the heart of Winnipeg.
It will cover 522 miles.
Starting order for all teams
will be luck of the draw.
It will cover
the following route.
The first man to arrive at
Como Park Depot in St. Paul...
will be the winner.
- Any questions ab...
- Mr. Harper! Sir. Mr. Harper.
- Sir, I'm Will Stoneman
from South Dakota.
- Let me through here.
- I'm here to enter the race.
- All right, lad. Let's go.
Let him alone.
Let him talk.
You say you're
registered to race?
You're Will Stoneman?
You're a boy!
I sent in my entrance form
and my $50.
- So, I want to run the race.
- [Harper] You do, do you?
Might I ask, what for?
- What for? For $10,000,
that's what for.
- [Laughing]
[Man] That sounds good to me!
- How much money you got, son?
- Two dollars. Why?
I'm afraid the penalty
for late registration is $10.
[Audience] Ooh!
I'll give you
the $2 I've got now...
and the rest I'll pay
from my winnings.
I know what you're doing
and I don't like it.
It's just 'cause I'm a kid.
Wait!
The Kane Newspaper Syndicate will
cover the boy's registration fee.
Now, Mr. Kingsley...
Sir, if this young man
is not allowed to compete...
twenty million Americans
who daily read Kane papers...
- will loudly cry, "Foul!"
- Here, here!
You're prepared to risk
this young man's life to
sell some newspapers?
[Whispering] If it gets me back to
a warm office in Chicago I am.
- Son, how old are you?
- Almost eighteen.
This young man may be fighting
Germans in a trench soon, Harper.
A lot farther from home
than he is right now.
And you're saying he's not
man enough to run a dog race!
- Let the kid race.
- Let him race. He won't last
through the first day.
I'll last as long as
any man here, including you.
[Kingsley]
What's it gonna be, Mr. Harper?
One more racer...
- or 20 million angry readers?
- [Crowd] Let him race!
[Crowd Jeering]
- Let him race!
Take a seat, lad.
Someone get him a packet.
- Get the kid a cigar too.
- Music!
[Music] My name is Kaiser Bill
I'm the fella you want to kill [music]
Hey, kid.
Son, look, have a cigar.
- [Music]But I hear a voice
of freedom calling [music]
- [Laughing]
[Music] Far across the sea [music]
- [Music]And this is what they say [music]
- Hi. Hi.
- [Music] To me [music]
- Whoa!
[Music] Go home, Kaiser Bill
Pack up your guns and beer [music]
[Music] Pack up your guns and beer
Get yourself on out of here [music]
[Music] Go home, Kaiser Bill
Better not test our will [music]
[Music] We've almost had our fill
Go home, Kaiser Bill [music]
[Music] Go home, Kaiser Bill
Pack up your guns and beer [music][music]
[Music][music] [Singing]
Not another word to
these parasites, kid.
You're Kane property now.
- I'm nobody's property.
- It's just a figure
of speech, that's all.
Just make sure you talk
to me before them.
Harry Kingsley, at your service.
Sorry, I gave 'em away
to all the ladies.
You sure you want to sell
your soul to this devil?
All I know is
he put up my fee.
- I'm not here to sell anything.
- Of course you're not.
- Boy's got integrity.
- You'll cure him of that in no time.
That's cute.
Drink it. Can't trust
a man that doesn't drink.
To the best eight dollar
investment I ever made.
- [Coughing]
- Can't die on me now, kid.
- I never drank before.
- You never raced before, either.
Uh, can I ask you something?
- Why'd you help me?
- Helping you is helping myself.
Having you in the race gives me
something to write about.
- Gotta sell newspapers, kid.
- [Music][music] [Singing]
Oh, I see it's the first time
for a lot of things, huh?
Get an eyeful, 'cause you
won't be seeing anything...
- but the butts on your dogs
for some time.
- Oh, my dogs!
[Barking]
[Indistinct Shouting]
[Snarling]
- Ah, back off!
- Hey, don't kick my dog, mister!
Then you shut your dog up!
Your dog started the trouble.
- You okay, Gus?
- So...
you think you gonna last
as long as me, huh?
Boyca!
You ever had frostbite?
You will,
you run this race.
Yeah, the mercury drop
to 30 below.
Forty below sometime.
Your fingers and toes,
they gonna look like this.
Yeah.
This race, boy...
this is the meanest stretch
of land God ever put together.
Good men have died out there.
When you get the frostbite,
you call me.
I cut off anything you want.
No charge.
[McPherson]
Don't give me an excuse, Borg.
You got a little frostbite
on the brain, don't you?
What you say to me?
I said, don't let me catch you
irritating my countryman again.
Now, get!
Come on, Joe.
I was just having fun
with the boy.
Remember to call me
if you need anything cut off.
[Chuckling]
Stay away from him. Mean.
Got a little timber wolf
not far down the family tree.
You all right?
Yeah, we're okay.
All right. Take care.
Thanks.
[Harper] I require
a gentleman's promise
from each of you.
You will not try to steal
my chef. He is world class.
Although, at the end
of the journey...
since I've laid in
some excellent vintages...
Thank you, Abdul.
I'll make a gift of them to you
if we have any left over.
In the meantime,
you'll find this cognac
more than satisfactory.
Elevated only by the taste
of my imported Havana cigars.
You should not have let him
enter,J.W., reporter or not.
I was not about to let Kingsley
ruin the reputation of the race!
Whatever he might have done,
it'll be nothing compared to...
what you'll face if that boy
gets himself killed.
We'll let the boy race
for a day, then find some
reason to disqualify him.
Didn't you want to take on
the world at that age?
Let the boy have a day!
- If he lasts that long.
- I'll bet $500 he does.
You two have already bet
over $5,000, Jonah.
- Then you're not gonna miss
another $500, are you?
- Right!
- Oh!
- It's $ 1,000...
- says he won't make Heartbreak Hill.
- No.
Yes. You're on.
Ahh. I couldn't
have dreamed all this.
Can't wait to tell Ward.
Tell you something,
though, Gus.
Ned's right. Got to stay away
from those racers.
How 'bout acting like
I'm the boss tomorrow, huh?
Not embarrass me
in front of a thousand people?
[Music][music] [Jack's Whistle]
I noticed your article, Harry.
- All the way on page 14.
- Yeah, that's cute.
And so we send you
brave men off in competition...
with the pride of many nations
at your shoulders.
Good luck and Godspeed.
Racing teams, are you ready?
[Cheering]
[Gunshot]
Come on, dog team.
Come on!
[Yells Command]
Thor!
Hut, hut, hut!
Come on, boy! Come on!
Let's go! Let's go!
Good boy.
Come on, Gus. Let's go!
Go, Will!
Let's go! Come on, now.
[Whistles]
[Music][music] [Jack's Whistle]
Let's go! Come on, Gus!
Come on, boy!
Let's move it!
Let's go, Gus! Come on!
Keep up that pace,
you'll be burying them dogs
in Canadian ground.
Hey, kid, where you goin'
in such a hurry?
St. Paul, Minnesota.
Come on, let's go!
We got 'em!
We're coming up
on the racers, sir!
Well, slow the train down,
then, man.
- Jonah!
- Thank you.
Wonder how that
young man's faring.
He's probably dropped
out of the race already.
If I was you, Jonah,
I'd get my $1,000 out now...
because there's my boys
coming up according to plan.
One, two and three!
[Laughing]
Make that nine, ten and eleven,
Angus. Look up there.
What? Oh!
Where are Remy
and Devereaux?
Good Lord! That young man's
in the lead!
Hey, the kid's in the lead.
- You think your boy's
got a chance?
- Doesn't matter what I think.
If I convince 20 million
Americans he can...
I may be back in the
good graces of my editor.
Heartbreak Hill's comin' up.
If he can make it through
that and Devil's Run...
you might get that desk
after all.
Atta boy, Gus!
We'll give 'em something
to talk about back home!
Whoo-hoo!
Come on, boys.
Come on!
Hut, hut, hut, hut!
Hut!
Hut, hut!
Wanna thank ya!
Hut, hut, hut, hut!
Lads, hut, hut!
Hey, you cut a good trail, boy!
He's a trailblazer.
I cut the trail for them!
Adrian, move up!
Hey, Will! Let's go!
On, Adrian. Let's go, move.
Okay... okay.
Okay, let's go,
let's go, let's go!
[Music][music] [Jack's Whistle]
[Speaking Swedish]
Beautiful, no?
This is as far as you go, kid.
Leave him alone, Borg.
How 'bout $25 to the man
who reaches bottom first?
You're out of your mind.
You scared, Riley?
Maybe you should
slide down on your rump
along with the boyca here.
[Laughing]
Better yet, make it good.
One hundred dollars, huh?
One hundred dollars!
[Laughing]
[Swedish]
Whoo-hoo!
Faster! Yah!
Allez!
Whoa... whoa!
Come on, Gus!
Allez, allez!
[Screaming]
Hey, Borg!
Come on!
Come on, Adrian!
Comin' by.
Let me through!
Hey, what are you doin'?
Borg!
Adrian, whoa!
Joe!
Go on! I'm all right.
Joe?
Gus, gee, gee!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Gus, whoa!
No, no, Gus!
Hey, Gus, whoa!
Hey, we wanna finish
this race, we gotta make
some kind of peace. Hear?
Gus!
Agh!
[Chattering]
Wire just came.
The Icelanders are in Morris.
McTeague's boys.
[Swenson]
Twelve miles ahead.
Ahead of the Carey brothers.
Harper's gonna be fuming
when he hears that.
Don't look so concerned.
Your boy's out there somewhere.
- No news is good news.
- No news is unemployment.
Wait. Groven's lost two dogs.
Devereaux, the Frenchman, is out,
and one of the Americans.
Not your American.
Seems a man who really
wanted to win this race
would keep goin'...
instead of pullin' up
every night to have supper
with his competitors.
Smart fella, huh?
You go out there, why don't ya?
Go on out there.
Take a leak while you're at it.
Watch it freeze
before it hits the ground.
[Muttering]
He wants us
to race at night. [Swedish]
to race at night!
Well, look who's here.
That little lost Yankee.
- I think for sure
I'd never see you again.
- We made it, didn't we?
You be careful now.
The cowboy ain't here
to protect you no more.
Good boy.
Leavin' awful early,
aren't you, kid?
Yeah, ah...
bad weather's comin'.
I'd like to get out in front
if I can.
What's that?
Fruitcake.
You're gonna run 40 miles
on fruitcake?
It's a special fruitcake,
Mr. Kingsley.
I wouldn't talk about it.
People think you're crazy
enough as it is.
They can think what they want.
It saves time not havin'
to build fires or cook.
It cuts down on the weight
I gotta carry.
Okay, let's go!
[Music][music] [Jack's Whistle]
Fruitcake?
Geez, this kid's
a gift from God.
[Kingsley] "Dateline:
The Canadian Wilderness.
"'At a time when the hearts of
this nation cry out for heroes...
"remember that there's a boy
out there, an American boy...
"racing against man,
against nature, against time...
"with his mother's fruitcake
and a homemade whistle...
"and a spirit that speaks
of the truest American ideals.
"So when you read this name,
remember it.
Remember the name...
Will Stoneman."
Gus! Gus, whoa!
[Remembering]
Dad! Dad, no. Dad, no!
Gus, get back up here.
Get up here now!
[Barking]
We're not crossing the lake, Gus.
Come on!
[Kingsley] Page nine.
I need something else.
[Kingsley]
Can you hear me?
It's Kingsley. Listen.
Get ahold of Potter.
Send him right away to
Birch Ridge, South Dakota.
South Dakota!
Tell him to get everything he can
on Will Stoneman and his family.
Find out where it is.
I don't care if you have
to drop him from a balloon.
Just get me that story!
Come on, boys.
I just...
I just need a rest.
[Barks]
[Barking]
We'll be comin'up
on Pembina in 30 minutes.
Thirty minutes, Pembina.
Thirty minutes.
What if something happens
to him, Harry?
- What do you mean?
- Don't you feel
somewhat responsible?
- [Lambert] He's missing.
- What for? For tryin' to
get him on the front page?
This kid'll have bigger
headlines than the war
when I get through with him.
- All of America
will hear about him.
- You got it wrong, Harry.
He'll make you.
If it wasn't for him...
you'd still be on the back page,
the canine section.
I just hope he lasts long enough
for me to get that big promotion.
- And if he dies?
- Then he'll die a hero, a somebody.
And I'll write one hell
of an obituary for him,
lauding his courage, idealism.
You know enough about such
things to write about them?
I know plenty, Lambert.
Plenty.
[Man] There's one comin'in.
I need some help over here.
Come on.
It's Remy! Remy!
He's frozen to the sled.
Cut him loose!
Hurry up.
Get him inside, quickly!
Hurry.
Come on.
Hah!
You're crazy, Groven!
You'll never make it
to the next checkpoint.
You'll die out there!
[Snoring]
[Whimpering]
Gus?
Oh, I fell asleep, didn't I?
I would've died
if it wasn't for you.
[Barks]
[Barking]
Holy Chicago!
Wha... Come on, wake up!
- What's goin' on?
- He's here!
Get the door!
Get the flash!
Let's go.
He's out there.
Step aside.
Let a man through.
Hiya, kid!
What? What was that?
That was me lighting the way for you.
Get this out yesterday!
- How ya doin', kid?
- A little tired.
- Come on, let him through.
- Take care of my dogs, please.
The boy's been through enough.
Will, do you plan
to continue with the race?
- Not tonight.
- [Native Indian]
My brother says you run
too hard. You must rest.
You owe me $100, Riley.
I'll pay ya
out of my winnings.
You will pay...
when it's time.
Yeah.
[Swedish]
It's cold out there, huh?
Your mama, she must
worry for you, eh, boy?
You miss your mama...
and your papa?
Leave me alone.
Go home, boy.
Before when it's too late,
you go home.
Hmm?
[Music][music] [Singing In Swedish]
[Music][music]
[Music][music] [Humming]
[Indistinct Scraping]
[Barking]
[Chattering]
Why don't you
have some coffee?
Buried again.
[Music][music] [Jack's Whistle]
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Easy, easy, easy, whoa.
One of the Icelanders.
We're closin' the gap.
Let's go. Hup, hup!
Groven?
Groven!
[Shivering]
Gunther... he not old.
- Good dog.
- No, l...
- My good dogs.
- You're burning up.
[Indistinct]
Go.
Go!
Okay, hup, hup!
Hup!
Hup, hup, hup.
Yah!
Come on, boy! Yah! Yah!
Borg! Come on, boys!
Hup! Come on!
Hey! Come on!
See you in St. Paul, Riley!
[Laughing]
See you in St. Paul someday.
[Train Whistle Blowing]
Excuse me. Watch it.
[Mc Teague]
Influenza. It's bad.
You're lucky
somebody found ya!
Boy.
Boy? What boy?
- Amerikansk.
- The American?
- Stoneman?
- Yes.
Stoneman.
- Stoneman?
- Stoneman.
Well, Angus...
this boy cost you
a thousand dollars, but
he did save your man's life.
And if he's kept going,
he's ahead of them all.
The boy has the heart
of a bear.
He lost a lot of strength
saving your man like that.
He could've died himself.
I'll wager $5,000
he doesn't reach St. Paul.
I'll take that bet.
Okay, let's go.
Let's go!
[Clicking Sound]
Come on.
[Music][music] [Jack's Whistle]
Heroic! Unbelievable!
Over the last four days and nights...
in a dogsled race running
between Winnipeg and St. Paul...
Selfless, courageous.
Racked by influenza...
Will Stoneman, a plucky
17 year old from South Dakota...
He saved someone's life.
He's the last American hope
in this race.
Racing through the night,
driven by his own iron will
with a courageous...
Wait a minute.
Hold it.
Iron Will.
That's great!
Kingsley, you're a genius.
- Iron Will Stoneman,
American hero...
- Iron Will Stoneman...
[Kingsley] Homegrown hero
left Birch Ridge a boy,
but he'll return a man.
He's in the lead.
He saved someone's life.
He's the last American hope
in this race.
The nation holds its breath
in awe...
as its newest champion,
Iron Will Stoneman,
forges on with little rest...
barely holding his lead
as the dog derby continues.
So, as war
looms over Europe...
the nation roots for a new symbol
of hope and determination.
This heroic tale of
a young man's bravery
spreads across the land...
and America rallies
behind Iron Will Stoneman.
A little right, little right.
That's great, Harry.
Here we go.
One, two, three, cheese!
Watch your step.
There you are.
Can I help you, sir?
Excuse me.
Could you tell me where I might find
the kin of Will Stoneman?
Where's the box?
- Box of what?
- The boy's remains.
The boy's...
Mister, don't you people
get the papers out here?
[Maggie] "Nourished only by
his mother's fruitcake...
"he carries a
hand-carved whistle...
"from which emanates a melody
people have taken to calling...
Will's tune."
What is the significance
of this whistling?
It must be some magic tune...
It's his father's tune.
I see. Charming.
How does Mr. Stoneman feel
about young Will racing?
His father's very proud of him.
[Potter] Tell Kingsley
I've got an angle for him.
Iron Will races to save
mother's farm and go to college.
I'm not making it up.
His father's dead.
I'm putting the mother
and the Indian on a train to St. Paul.
They'll be there for
the finish. Don't tell the kid.
Anyone know where the kid is?
[Swenson] The kid's been
runnin' for a week
and we still can't track him.
I know he's running!
But how far did he get?
Where did he stop?
He didn't stop. He's still
out there... somewhere.
Angus.
That $10,000 we bet maybe...
maybe we should send
some of it to the boy's mother.
Do what you like with
your money. Don't tell
me what to do with mine.
Jonah! Jonah.
I still can't understand
why you allow that boy
to stay in the race.
I'll tell you why.
Because when I looked
in that boy's eyes...
I saw myself 35 years ago.
Have we come so far...
that we've forgotten
what it's like...
to start out with nothing but
a dim chance and a bright hope?
I will not be...
the one to snuff out
that hope... gentlemen.
Not I.
- There's no sign of Stoneman.
- That doesn't matter.
He's crazy out of his mind.
You never sleep, you go crazy.
So crazy he's beatin'
the lot of you.
He'll never make
the finish line.
Nobody can last at his pace.
That's what you said
on the first day...
and he's still runnin'!
Can you catch 'im?
You know I've personally wagered
$ 10,000 my men would beat him.
Ten thousand?
Catch him.
Stop him.
And you might find yourself
the beneficiary of a handsome sum.
Half.
[Barking]
No, no!
[Snarling]
Gus! No!
No, no! Gus! Gus!
Gus!
[Whimpering]
Boil water.
Mix herbs.
Cook down.
Make a paste.
Don't die on me now, boy.
We were just startin'
to get along.
Now's when we need
each other most.
[Whimpers]
It's okay, Gus.
[Music][music] [Jack's Whistle]
You tried to kill my dog!
[Indistinct Shouting]
You want to fight, huh, kid?
You want to fight, huh?
So you want to fight!
What's the matter, kid,
you scared?
I'm beyond being scared
of you, mister.
Will.
No matter what he's done,
you tell us about it.
We'll take care of it.
I oughta kill you.
If you ever come near me
or my team again,
I'll kill you outright.
So help me God, I will.
[Will Panting]
Will, it's good to see you.
I was gettin' worried...
That's for using
me and my family to sell
your damn newspapers...
and printing pictures that
are gonna make my mother worry.
You okay?
You all right?
Never figured him to threaten
a man with a gun.
What's tomorrow's headline...
Mr. Kingsley?
Ah, I should have never
made you do this, Gus.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
[Growling]
How are you, Will?
Oh, it's a fine, fine race
you're runnin'.
Angus McTeague,
official sponsor of the race.
I know who you are, sir.
Where are the others?
The others? Oh, no, no, no, no.
I came alone.
I wanted to thank ya
for savin' the life of my driver.
It was very noble of ya.
You came all the way here
to thank me, Mr. McTeague?
I may be young,
but I'm not dumb.
I was compelled to come...
when I saw the terrible
condition of you and your team.
You've put up
a brave fight, lad.
And there's not a man amongst us
that doesn't admire your effort.
But I do feel very strongly...
that for you to continue
would be risking your life.
I'm not quitting... if that's
what you're driving at.
Withdrawing...
with $3,000 in your pocket
isn't exactly quitting.
What $3,000?
I am prepared to offer you
a reward...
of $3,000.
That's a lot of money,
Mr. McTeague.
Oh, it is, son. It is.
Well, you sleep on it.
And ask yourself...
if you haven't already achieved
the goals you had starting out.
How do I know you'll pay?
I'm not saying I'm gonna do it.
- I just...
- Well, when you say...
you are gonna do it...
I'll personally
hand ya $3,000.
Now... you take care
of that wee doggy there.
He'd be a real beaut to lose.
What?
I didn't take it, did I?
Will?
Come on. This is crazy.
You need more sleep.
You oughta be happy, Mr. Kingsley.
It'll give you another headline.
You'd probably love
to see me die, wouldn't you?
- You've got my obituary
written up already, I bet.
- Will.
I wouldn't spend another
minute with you no-good,
bunch of back-stabbing liars!
Get outta my way!
Let's go.
[Music][music] [Jack's Whistle]
Easy, easy.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Gus, you hear something?
You hear something, Gus?
What is that?
Okay, let's go, Curly.
Come on!
[Music][music][Band]
- Hi.
- Son, the whole town's
waitin' on ya!
- There he is!
- It's Will!
[Cheering]
Iron Will! Iron Will, my father
said to give these to you.
Said there's a few
hundred miles left in 'em.
Thanks. Uh, my name's Will Stoneman.
You might be confusing me...
To us, you're Iron Will,
American hero.
- That's what the papers call you.
- You're on the front page.
Every paper from here
to New York City.
Wait 'til you see!
The whole country's
rooting for you!
Look at this, "Iron Will saves
the Icelander and takes the lead."
"Iron Will races
to save mother's farm."
"Iron Will vows to realize
father's dream."
"Iron Will...
America's hope."
- America's hope!
- [Cheering]
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you all for everything.
Okay, let's go. Let's go.
God be with you!
Gus, they're sayin'
we're heroes. We better
start racing like heroes, huh?
Iron Will,
can we run with ya?
We know a shortcut.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
[Barking]
Come on, she's frozen, okay?
Is there a bridge around?
The train bridge.
But it'll take us
two miles out of the way.
- That's where we'll cross.
- That's an awful waste of time.
That's where we'll cross,
all right?
[Whimpering]
Will! Train's coming!
[Train Whistle Blowing]
Unhook the dogs!
No, there's not enough time.
Let's go!
Hurry!
No! No, no, no, Gus.
Whoa!
It's okay, it's okay!
Okay, let's move it!
[Boy] Run, Will, run!
[Laughter, Chatter]
- Will!
- You look like death, boy.
- Grab a chair, kid.
I'll get you a drink.
- No.
I need a blacksmith.
My... my sled's busted.
[Men Muttering]
- Now, tell me if this is too hot.
- Thank you.
- That's fine? All right.
- Yeah.
Ya see how rested they were?
I should have listened to those
boys and crossed the river.
Oh, my god.
Good evening.
If it's not
too much bother...
I'd like to talk
to the lad alone.
I'm prepared to raise the sum
considerably, Will.
- Let's say $5,000.
- Keep your money, Mc Teague.
I'm finishing this race
no matter how sick I am.
Son...
I don't think
you realize who I am.
But I do, Mc Teague.
In fact, I'd recognize you
from a pretty good distance.
- Kingsley! How long
have you been hidin' there?
- Long enough.
Now, I suggest you get out
of here before I make you
tomorrow's headline.
- We should talk about this.
- Maybe I'm not
making myself clear.
If you bother
the boy again, trust me,
the world will know it.
That felt good.
[Moaning]
Can you wake me
in three hours?
Listen, kid, this is crazy.
You're gonna kill yourself.
You've gotta
sleep longer than that.
Make it two hours. Okay?
Two hours.
You got it, kid.
Mr. Kingsley? Thanks.
You're not so bad after all.
Don't get soft
on me now, kid.
[Knocking On Door]
[Whispering]
Relax. The boy sleeps.
On the last day...
when one leads
the rest must follow.
Which fool will start the day?
[Kingsley] Will.
- [Gasps]
- Come on.
It's time.
[Grunting]
- Oh, G...
- What is it?
- I can't get up.
I can't move my arms and legs.
- That's it.
- I'm getting a doctor.
- No, no, no. I just gotta
get my blood going. Just...
Just help me.
- Aw, no!
- Will, you can't go on.
- Enough is enough!
I'm gonna get a doctor.
- No.
I am one day short of the
finish line. Not you or
anyone else is gonna stop me.
So, help me
or leave me alone.
It's not about me anymore.
[Grunting]
It's about all those people,
all the people pulling for me.
[Grunting]
It's about those boys.
They came out and cut trails.
- You, Will, huh?
- Ow! Ow!
- What about you?
- Just help me.
[Grunts]
Hey, Gus. Hey.
Now, you gotta stay here if I'm
gonna have a chance at this thing.
[Barking]
You want to wake somebody,
mess everything up? Shh.
[Snorts]
[Gus Whimpering]
[Barks]
Okay. Okay.
We started this together.
We'll finish it together.
That's the way it oughta be.
You stay down.
Okay, we're gonna get goin'.
Stay there, Gus.
Let's go.
[Music][music] [Jack's Whistle]
[Knocking]
What?
The boy's gone!
Wake up!
Get off the train!
The boy's gone!
[Mc Teague] The boy just left!
Wake Thorenson!
- Get up!
- [Shouting]
[Mc Teague] Get up! Get up!
Hook up the teams!
[Harper] Angus! Angus,
have you lost your mind?
A thousand dollars to the man
that beats that boy!
Come on! I wanna get
this shot! Quick, let's go!
[Mc Teague]
Open up the gate!
Open the gate!
Get my teams out!
Go, laddies!
[Mc Teague]
A thousand dollars! Do you
hear me? A thousand dollars...
to the man
that catches that boy!
[Shouting]
Hut! Hut, hut!
[Grunting]
Aah! Agh!
[Moaning]
[Lambert]
"Once in a generation...
"an athlete pits himself against
such overwhelming odds...
that even the most jaded
spectator finds himself
cheering breathlessly."
Harry, you're writing
from the heart.
I didn't know you had one.
This kid's the genuine article,
Lambert. He's A-1.
He sure gained your respect
with one solid hook.
You know something, Lambert?
Last night...
for the first time since I've
been in the newspaper business...
I actually felt excited
by what I do for a living.
Hut, hut!
[Barking]
Hut!
That's the finish line
right there.
- Are you Mrs. Stoneman?
- Yes.
Mrs. Stoneman, Harry Kingsley,
Kane Newspaper Syndicate.
I've been covering the race.
Mrs. Stoneman, this is one
of the few times in my life...
that I mean it when I say
it's truly an honor.
- Do you know where Will is?
- That's hard to say exactly.
- Is he all right?
- Mrs. Stoneman, if I know
anything about your son...
I'll guarantee you
he's all right.
[Gasps]
Now it's down
to you and me, boyca.
And there's only one chance
left if you want to win.
There's a shorter trail
down there to St. Paul.
It's the only way you
get there before the others.
Why didn't they go that way?
You follow me and you'll
find out. Hut! Hut!
I didn't think
you was man enough!
[Shouting]
Get!
[Barking]
Hut! Hut, hut!
[Shouting]
[Ned's Voice]
When you come to face
the thing you fear...
let the Creator guide you.
[Barks]
[Ned] Trust the dogs.
Trust yourself.
Damn you, river.
I'll beat you.
You took my father.
Come on!
Hup, hup, hup, hup!
Yah ha ha!
[Swedish]
Hah!
Hut, hut!
Why you stop?
Come on!
[Barking, Whimpering]
[Swedish]
- [Whimpering]
- [Swedish]
- [Growling]
- [Screaming]
- [Swedish]
[Screaming]
[Barking, Snarling]
[Borg]
Buster, come back!
Hut, hut!
First man out
is Albert Carey.
It's Albert Carey.
[Whistling, Applause]
[Chuckling]
Wait a minute.
It's Stoneman!
It's Stoneman. He's coming
out of the woods a half a mile
ahead of the Careys.
It's Stoneman!
- It's not possible!
I don't believe it!
- Get out your checkbook!
- Is that my Will?
- The one and only... Iron Will.
[Applause]
[Cheering]
Come on, Will!
Will, go!
Will.
[Barks]
- Oh, God.
- Will.
Get up.
- [Music][music] [Jack's Whistle]
- [Barks]
[Music][music] [Jack's Whistle]
[Music][music] [Crowd Whistling
Jack's Whistle]
[Man] Come on, boy!
You're almost home!
- Come on, Will!
[Music][music] [Crowd Whistling Louder]
[Barks]
[Barking]
- [Cheering]
- [Man] Come on, boy, go!
- Come on, Will! Go!
- Come on!
Iron Will!