- Ah. It was a fine meaI.
- Yes, it was, wasn't it?
Yes, what shouId we do now?
- Let's have Iunch.
- Oh, good idea.
Quiet down, you viIIains.
I'm being stoIen.
HeIp me, heIp me!
Put me down!
HeIIo.
What about my nose?
Banana peeIs coming down!
Come aIong, Iadies.
Here's a nice Christmas turkey.
Turkey.
Get your Christmas turkey.
Hey, get back in the box, Martin!
Get your boomerang fish.
Guaranteed fresh.
Throw the fish away
and it comes back to me.
Get 'em whiIe they're fresh.
- Christmas appIes.
- We got Macintosh.
- Red DeIicious.
Tuppence apiece, whiIe they Iast.
We... They won't Iast Iong
the way you're eating them.
I'm creating scarcity.
Drives the prices up.
Rizzo...
HeIIo. WeIcome to
the Muppet Christmas CaroI.
I am here to teII the story.
And I am here for the food.
My name is CharIes Dickens.
And my name is Rizzo the Rat.
Wait a second,
you're not CharIes Dickens.
I am, too.
A bIue furry CharIes Dickens
who hangs out with a rat?
AbsoIuteIy.
CharIes Dickens
was a 1 9th century noveIist.
A genius.
You are too kind.
Why shouId I beIieve you?
Because I know the story of A Christmas
Carol like the back of my hand.
- Prove it.
- AII right.
There's a IittIe moIe on my thumb.
And a scar on my wrist
from when I feII off my bicycIe...
No, don't teII us your hand,
teII us the story.
Oh, thank you. Yes.
The MarIeys were dead,
to begin with.
The... Pardon me?
That's how the story begins,
"The MarIeys were dead,
to begin with."
As dead as a doornaiI.
It's a good beginning.
It's creepy and kind of... spooky.
- Thank you, Rizzo.
- You're weIcome, Mr. Dickens.
In Iife, the MarIeys had been
business partners
with a shrewd moneyIender
named Ebenezer Scrooge.
You wiII meet him
as he comes around that corner.
- Where?
- There.
- When?
- Now.
There he is, Mr. Ebenezer Scrooge.
Say, is it getting coId around here?
# When a cold wind blows,
it chills you
# Chills you to the bone
# But there's nothing in nature
that freezes your heart
# Like years of being alone
# It paints you with indifference
# Like a lady paints with rouge
# And the worst of the worst,
the most hated and cursed
# Is the one that we call Scrooge
- # Unkind as any
- # And the wrath of many
# This is Ebenezer Scrooge
# There goes Mr. Humbug
There goes Mr. Grim
# If they gave a prize for being mean
# The winner would be him
# Old Scrooge, he loves his money
# 'Cause he thinks it gives him power
# If he became a flavor
You can bet he would be sour
Even the vegetabIes don't Iike him.
# There goes Mr. Skinflint
There goes Mr. Greed
# The undisputed master
of the underhanded deed
# He charges folks a fortune
# For his dark and drafty houses
# Us poor folk live in misery
# It's even worse for mouses
PIease, sir, I want some cheese.
# He must be so lonely
# He must be so sad
# He goes to extremes
to convince us he's bad
# He's really a victim
# Of fear and of pride
# Look close and there must be
a sweet man inside
- Nah.
- Uh-uh.
# There goes Mr. Outrage
# There goes Mr. Sneer
# He has no time for friends or fun
# His anger makes that clear
# Don't ask him for a favor
'cause his nastiness increases
# No crust of bread for those in need
# No cheeses for us "meeces"
Scrooge Iiked the coId.
He was hard and sharp as a fIint.
Secret and seIf-contained.
As soIitary as an oyster.
# There goes Mr. Heartless
# There goes Mr. Cruel
# He never gives
He only takes
# He lets his hunger rule
# If being mean's a way of life
you practice and rehearse
# Then all that work is paying off
# 'Cause Scrooge is getting worse
# Every day, in every way
Scrooge is getting worse #
- Oh, boy.
- How the time fIies.
Look at this, I've got to move...
Humbug.
Phew! What an unpIeasant feIIow.
He was a tightfisted hand
at the grindstone, Scroo...
Boy, this reaIIy is a dirty city.
Ha. You teIIin' me.
Thank you for making me
a part of this.
He was a tightfisted hand
at the grindstone, Scrooge.
A squeezing, wrenching,
grasping, cIutching...
covetous oId sinner.
Bob Cratchit?
Yes, Mr. Scrooge?
Who is this?
Mr. AppIegate, sir.
He's here to speak to you
about his... mortgage.
Mr. Scrooge,
I know you're very angry about this,
and I didn't mean to
faII behind in the payment.
Lord knows,
it being Christmas and aII.
PIease don't shout at me, sir.
That and, of course, IittIe Gwen.
Her Iungs aren't right.
The doctor takes his share, don't he?
You can yeII and scream,
and you're right,
but it won't do no good...
because I'm the stone
you can't squeeze bIood from.
And that's the truth!
Thank you for not shouting at me.
17... 42...
Let us deaI with the eviction notices
for tomorrow, Mr. Cratchit.
Uh...
Tomorrow's Christmas, sir.
Very weII, you may gift wrap them.
Let us heIp you with that, Mr. Cratchit.
My, there are certainIy a Iot today.
We'II get it.
I'm okay, okay.
- Here you go.
- Look out on that end...
- Uh...
- Whoa!
Christmas is a very busy time for us,
Mr. Cratchit.
PeopIe preparing feasts, giving parties.
Spending the mortgage money
on frivoIities.
One might say that December
is the forecIosure season.
Harvest time for the moneyIenders.
- Boss, ask him.
- TeII him.
- Come on. Come on.
- Do it now. Do it.
If you pIease, Mr. Scrooge,
it's gotten coIder.
The bookkeeping staff wouId Iike to have
an extra shoveI of coaI for the fire.
- We can't do the bookkeeping.
- Our pens are Iike ink-cicIes.
Our assets are frozen.
How wouId the bookkeepers
Iike to be suddenIy unempIoyed?
Heat wave!
This is my isIand in the sun!
I, I beIieve you've convinced them
once again, Mr. Scrooge.
At that moment,
who shouId arrive at the door
but Scrooge's nephew, Fred.
His onIy Iiving reIative.
- Nephew Fred? I don't see him.
- Trust me.
HeIIo? UncIe?
Rizzo?
You're very good at that, Mr. Dickens.
A merry Christmas, UncIe Scrooge.
God save you.
Merry Christmas?
Bah. Humbug!
Quick, it'II be warmer in there.
Christmas a humbug, UncIe?
You don't mean that, sureIy.
ActuaIIy, I think it's coIder in here.
Merry Christmas, you say?
What right have you to be merry?
You're poor enough.
And you to be dismaI?
You're rich enough.
He's got him.
The oId boy's speechIess.
If I couId work my wiII,
every idiot who goes about with
"Merry Christmas" on his Iips
wouId be cooked with his own turkey
and buried with a stake of hoIIy
through his heart.
WeII, not quite speechIess.
- UncIe...
- Nephew.
You keep Christmas in your own way,
and Iet me keep it in mine.
Christmas is a Ioving,
honest and charitabIe time.
And though it's never put
a scrap of goId or siIver in my pocket,
I beIieve Christmas has done me good
and wiII do me good,
and I say, God bIess it.
And how does one ceIebrate Christmas
on the unempIoyment Iine?
Now, in these times,
it was customary on Christmas Eve
for weII-meaning gentIemen
to caII upon businesses,
coIIecting donations
for the poor and homeIess.
Mr. Scrooge, I presume?
Who are you?
We're from the Order of Victoria
Charity Foundation.
We'd Iike to speak to you
about a donation.
Ah! WeIcome!
This joIIy oId gentIeman here
is Mr. Scrooge.
He's very generous to charities.
My dear nephew!
At this festive season of the year,
Mr. Scrooge,
many of us feeI we must
take care of our poor and homeIess.
Are there no prisons?
No poor houses?
Oh, pIenty of those, sir.
Oh. ExceIIent.
For a moment, I was worried.
Some of us are endeavoring to raise
a fund for the poor and homeIess.
What might I put you down for?
Nothing.
- You wish to remain anonymous?
- I wish to be Ieft aIone.
I do not make merry myseIf
for Christmas.
That certainIy is true.
I cannot afford
to make idIe peopIe merry.
That is certainIy not true.
Don't you have other things to do
this afternoon?
SadIy, I do, UncIe.
So I shaII make my donation.
And Ieave you to make yours.
Thank you so very much.
Oh, UncIe, come and have Christmas
dinner with me and CIara tomorrow.
Why ever did you get married?
Why? Because I feII in Iove.
That's the onIy thing in the worId
siIIier than a merry Christmas.
It's no use, I shaII keep
my Christmas humor to the Iast.
A merry Christmas to you.
And a happy New Year.
- Merry Christmas, Fred.
- Merry Christmas, Bob.
Humbug!
Ahem.
Now, then, sir, about the...
donation.
WeII, now.
Let's see.
I know how to treat the poor.
My taxes go to pay for the prisons
and the poorhouses.
- The homeIess must go there.
- But some wouId rather die.
If they'd rather die,
then they'd better do it,
and decrease the surpIus popuIation.
Oh, dear. Oh, dear.
This is the door, you may use it.
AII right, Beaker, come aIong.
I think we've taken enough
of Mr. Scrooge's time.
Oh, dear. Dear, dear.
17... 24... 58.
# Good King Wencelas looked out
on the Feast of Stephen
# Though the snow lay round about,
deep and crisp and even
# Brightly shone the moon
that... night,
# Though... the...
- What do you want?
- Uh... Penny for the song, guvnor?
Wh... Ow!
17... 24...
Excuse me, Mr. Scrooge,
but it appears to be cIosing time.
Very weII. I'II see you
at eight tomorrow morning.
Ask him, ask him.
Um... Tomorrow's Christmas.
8:30, then.
If you pIease, sir,
haIf an hour off hardIy seems customary
for Christmas Day.
- No.
- HardIy customary.
How much time off is customary,
Mr. Cratchit?
Um... Why, um, the, er, whoIe day.
- Yeah, that's right.
- The whoIe day.
The entire day?
- No.
- That's the frog's idea.
If you pIease,
why open the office tomorrow?
Other businesses wiII be cIosed.
You'II have no one to do business with.
It'II waste a Iot of expensive coaI
for the fire.
- That's definiteIy a point.
- That's a point.
It's a poor excuse for picking
a man's pocket every December the 25th.
But as I seem to be
the onIy person around who knows that...
...take the day off.
WiII you stop that?
Thank you, Mr. Scrooge.
Be here aII the earIier
the next morning.
- Okay.
- You bet. First thing.
With their empIoyer gone at Iast,
Bob Cratchit and the bookkeepers
immediateIy began
that most pIeasant of activities,
the ceIebration of Christmas.
He's gone!
GentIemen, Iet's cIose up for Christmas.
# There's magic in the air this evening
# Magic in the air
# The world is at her best, you know
# When people love and care
# The promise of excitement
is one the night will keep
# After all, there's only
one more sleep till Christmas
# The world has got a smile
# Today, the world has got a glow
# There's no such thing as strangers
# When a stranger says hello
# And everyone is family
# We're having so much fun
# After all, there's only one
more sleep till Christmas #
Okay, ready. Here we go.
That's it. Ha! Ha!
Mm-hm.
Very good, gentIemen.
# 'Tis the season to be jolly and joyous
# With a burst of pleasure,
we feel it arrive
# It's a season
when the saints can employ us
# To spread the news about peace
and to keep love alive
What's that?
Look, it's the penguins'
Christmas skating party.
- Hmm. Ah.
- Look at that!
You did good, boss.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you very much.
Wow!
- No way.
- Come on, Rizzo.
Boy.
Fun, huh?
Merry Christmas, penguins.
# There's something in the wind today
# That's good for everyone
# Yes, faith is in our hearts today
# We're shining like the sun
# And everyone can feel it
# The feeling's running deep
# After all, there's only
one more sleep till Christmas
# After all, there's only one more sleep
# Till Christmas Day #
Merry Christmas!
Scrooge Iived in chambers
which had once beIonged
to his oId business partners,
Jacob and Robert MarIey.
- Have some bread?
- Not whiIe I'm working.
Suit yourseIf.
The buiIding was a dismaI heap of brick
on a dark street.
Once again, you must remember
that the MarIeys were dead
- and decaying in their graves.
- Yeuch!
That one thing
you must remember,
or nothing that foIIows
wiII seem wondrous.
Why are you whispering?
- It's for dramatic emphasis.
- Oh.
Shh.
Jacob MarIey?
You okay?
Humbug.
Oh. Gonzo, speak to me.
I mean, Mr. Dickens.
CharIie! Are you hurt?
To say that Scrooge
was not startIed wouId be untrue.
StiII, the moment had passed,
and the worId was as it shouId be.
He ain't hurt.
Didn't even break his concentration.
- Hmm?
- Nothing.
Come on, Rizzo.
We'II foIIow him in.
In a minute.
I had a bag of jeIIy beans over here.
WiII you just get over here?
- AII right.
- Sheesh.
Oh-oh.
Steady, steady.
Scrooge made his way up the stairs,
caring not a button for the darkness.
Darkness was cheap,
and Scrooge Iiked it.
But the incident at the door
had made Scrooge wary.
Before he shut himself in for the night,
he searched his rooms.
- Okay, that does it.
- Pardon?
How do you know
what Scrooge is doing?
We're down here and he's up there.
I keep teIIing you, storyteIIers
are omniscient. I know everything.
Hoity-toity, Mr. GodIike Smarty-Pants.
To conduct a proper search,
Scrooge was forced to Iight the Iamps.
How does he do that?
Agh!
Oh.
It's my best dressing gown.
No harm done.
Look, it's Ebenezer Scrooge.
Looking oIder and more wicked
than ever.
I knew he wouIdn't disappoint us.
Who are you?
In Iife, we were your partners,
- Jacob...
- And Robert MarIey.
It Iooks Iike you.
- But I don't beIieve it.
- Why do you doubt your senses?
Because a IittIe thing
can affect them.
A sIight disorder of the stomach
can make them cheat.
You may be a bit of undigested beef.
A bIob of mustard.
A crumb of cheese.
Yes, there's more of gravy
than of grave about you.
More of gravy than of grave?
What a terribIe pun.
Where do you get those jokes?
Leave comedy to the bears, Ebenezer.
PIease, Jacob, Robert,
don't criticize me.
You aIways criticized me.
We were aIways heckIing you.
It's good to be heckIing again.
It's good to be doing anything again.
Why do you come to me?
# We're Marley and Marley
Avarice and greed
# We took advantage of the poor,
just ignored the need-y
# We specialized in causing pain,
spreading fear and doubt
# And if you could not pay the rent,
we simply threw you out
There was the year
we evicted the entire orphanage.
I remember the IittIe tykes
aII standing in the snowbank.
With their IittIe
frostbitten teddy bears.
# We're Marley and Marley
Our hearts were painted black
# We should have known our evil deeds
# Would put us both in shack-les
# Captive, bound, we're double-ironed,
exhausted by the weight
# As freedom comes from giving love
# So prison comes with hate
# We're Marley and Marley
But my friends, you were not unfeeIing
towards your feIIow men.
True, there was something
about mankind we Ioved.
I think it was their money.
# Doomed, Scrooge
You're doomed for all time
# Your future is a horror story
Written by your crime
# Your chains are forged
by what you say and do
# So have your fun
When life is done
# A nightmare waits for you
Why these terribIe chains?
The chains.
We forged these chains in Iife
by our acts of greed.
You wear such a chain yourseIf.
Humbug. Speak comfort to me, friends.
Comfort!
You wiII be haunted by three spirits.
Haunted?
I've aIready had enough of that.
Without these visits, you cannot hope
to avoid the path we tread.
Expect the first ghost tonight,
when the beII toIIs one.
Can't I meet them aII at once
and get it over with?
When the beII toIIs one!
# We're Marley and Marley
# We're Marley and Marley #
Change!
And with that, the spirits of Scrooge's
partners vanished into the darkness,
Ieaving him once again
aIone in his room.
That's scary stuff. ShouId we be worried
about the kids in the audience?
No, it's aII right. This is cuIture.
JeIIy bean? I had them
in my pocket aII aIong.
What?
Humbug.
Come on.
But I reaIIy hate this.
You wanted to know
what was happening.
Scrooge's bedchamber
is on this side of the house. Jump.
There's onIy two things
in this Iife I hate.
Heights, and jumping from them.
Too Iate now.
Come on, I'II catch you.
God save my IittIe broken body.
Missed.
Wait a second.
I forgot my jeIIy beans.
Um...
What?
You can fit through those bars?
Yeah.
You are such an idiot.
What, what? Hey, what?
What?
Oh, dear.
Scrooge sIipped into the empty siIence
of a dreamIess sIeep.
You know, a guy couId break his taiI
faIIing out of this tree.
Want to see what's going on, don't you?
- Yes.
- There's Scrooge's window.
Oh, yeah.
Expect the first ghost
when the beII toIIs one!
Wow! Ouch.
Are you the spirit
whose coming was foretoId to me?
I am.
But... you're just a chiId.
I can remember nearIy 1 ,900 years.
I am the Ghost of Christmas Past.
What business has brought you here?
- Your weIfare.
- Huh.
A night's unbroken rest
might aid my weIfare.
Your saIvation, then.
Take heed. Come.
I beg you, spirit, I am mortaI.
I'm IiabIe to faII.
A touch of my hand, and you shaII fIy.
- What are we doing?
- Nothing.
- What?
- Just hoId on.
- Watch out, Rizzo.
- What? Oh!
Whee!
HeIIo, London!
Goodbye, Iunch!
Spirit?
Yes?
Nothing.
- Look, Rizzo.
- I don't want to Iook.
Spirit? What is that Iight?
It cannot be dawn.
It is the past.
Look, it's beautifuI, Rizzo.
Mommy!
Hey, we're going down.
Hang on, Rizzo.
Sorry, madam.
Pardon me, sir.
Look out, Rizzo.
Rizzo, this is Louise.
Yeah, we've met.
And so they arrived
in Ebenezer Scrooge's chiIdhood.
That was the worst trip of my Iife.
It's over now.
Yeah, safe at Iast.
No.
No. No! Oh, no!
Nice kitty, nice kitty.
Ow! I'm from New Jersey.
It was the afternoon of Christmas Eve,
and Scrooge was conscious
of a thousand odors.
Each one connected with a thousand
thoughts, hopes, joys and cares,
Iong, Iong forgotten.
It's my oId schooI.
I was a boy here.
That's Henry.
And Edmund, my best friend.
HeIIo, boys. HeIIo.
These are but shadows
of your past, Ebenezer.
They can neither see nor hear you.
Come, Iet us go inside.
Rizzo, stop pIaying with the cat.
Save me, save me!
And what a fIood of memories
came back to him,
as Scrooge beheId his oId cIassroom.
I know it aII so weII, spirit.
The desks.
The smeII of the chaIk.
I chose my profession in this room.
And is he, too, famiIiar?
Scrooge beheId a smaII boy,
a boy he knew,
oh, very weII indeed.
Good heavens.
It's me.
Come Ebenezer,
the Iast coach is Ieaving.
Come on,
he never goes home for Christmas.
Who cares about stupid oId Christmas?
I was often aIone.
More time for reading... and study.
The Christmas hoIiday was a chance
to get some extra work done.
A time for... soIitude.
Rats don't understand these things.
You were never a IoneIy chiId?
I had 1 ,27 4 brothers and sisters.
Sheesh.
Rats don't understand these things.
Let us see another Christmas
in this pIace.
They were aII very much the same.
Nothing ever changed.
You changed.
The years performed
their terribIe dance.
And in a moment, Scrooge had seen
his entire chiIdhood pass.
He saw his oId schooI room
age and decay.
What the... Hey!
Agh!
So, Master Scrooge, graduation day!
That's my oId headmaster.
This man taught me my greatest Iesson.
Stand up. BuiId your Iife
as this schooI was buiIt.
Push!
My ear, my ear, my ear.
Yes, work hard, work Iong,
and be constructive.
Ebenezer, Iife is a goIden opportunity.
Today you go forth into the reaI worId.
You must keep your nose
to the grindstone.
Work hard, Iad. And one day,
your Iife wiII be as soIid
as this very buiIding.
Hmm. I've been meaning
to fix that sheIf.
Yes, headmaster.
Young man, you have been apprenticed
to a fine company in London.
Today, you become a man of business.
I'm Iooking forward to it, headmaster.
You wiII Iove business.
It is the American way.
Sam?
Mmm?
Oh. It is the British way.
Good.
Yes, headmaster.
Oh, here is your coach, Ebenezer.
Come, Scrooge, there is much to see.
Remember, don't tip the driver.
A moment Iater, Scrooge found himseIf
standing on a city street,
Iooking at a buiIding
he had not seen in years.
TeII me, Ebenezer Scrooge,
do you know this pIace?
Know it? My first job was here.
This is Fozziwig's
oId rubber chicken factory.
Once again, it was Christmas Eve,
night was faIIing, and the IampIighters
were pIying their trade.
Hey, Iight the Iamp, not the rat.
Light the Iamp, not the rat!
- My apoIogies.
- What are you doing?
Put me out, put me out!
- Rizzo!
- What?
Oh, oh, Th-th-th-thank you.
You're weIcome.
There he is, oId Fozziwig himseIf.
Look my Iads, dusk has faIIen,
and the IampIighters are at work.
It's Christmas Eve for certain.
What an empIoyer he was.
As hard and as ruthIess
as a rose petaI.
It's time for the party to begin.
It's the Fozziwig Christmas party.
Rizzo, come on.
Rizzo, just grab hoId of the stick.
Merry Christmas.
Thank you, thank you.
Excuse me, everyone.
Can we have some quiet, pIease?
Whoa!
I suppose I shouId be gratefuI for that.
You're weIcome.
Everyone, pIease,
can I have your attention for a moment?
Look, it's the MarIey brothers.
My oId partners, as they were as Iads.
Can I have your attention, pIease?
Quiet!
Thank you.
That's better.
WeIcome to Fozziwig and Mom's
annuaI Christmas party.
At this time in the proceedings,
it is a tradition
for me to make a IittIe speech.
And it's a tradition for us
to take a IittIe nap.
Uh, pay no attention to them.
My speech,
here is my Christmas speech.
"Thank you aII
and merry Christmas."
- That was the speech?
- That was dumb.
- It was obvious.
- It was pointIess.
It was short.
I Ioved it!
I'm bored with speeches.
Let's dance, Son!
Here's Mrs. Fozziwig to start the party.
- Way to go, Ma!
- Hit it, boys!
HeIIo.
Look, there's a buffet over here.
I'm kind of hungry.
# Fa-la la-la la
La-la la la
Forget it. Mother aIways taught me,
never eat singing food.
A pIeasure having you here.
I'm very pIeased,
and pIease enjoy yourseIf.
Excuse me, Mr. Fozziwig?
Sir, I've been going over the accounts.
Do you know how much the firm
is spending for this party?
Master Scrooge, this is Christmas.
It's a time for generosity.
Stop working, enjoy yourseIf.
Go meet some peopIe, go ahead.
HeIIo.
You dancing fooI!
I Iove these annuaI Christmas parties.
I Iove them so much,
I think we'II do it twice a year.
Excuse me.
- Master Scrooge.
- Excuse me.
BeIIe, I'd Iike to introduce you
to Ebenezer Scrooge,
the finest young financiaI mind
in the city.
Ebenezer, this is BeIIe,
a friend of the Fozziwig famiIy.
I'm pIeased to meet you.
WeII, I'm gIad you two finaIIy met.
Do you remember this meeting?
Remember?
Yes.
I remember.
There was, of course, another
Christmas Eve with this young woman,
some years Iater.
Oh, pIease,
do not show me that Christmas.
Another year
before our wedding, Ebenezer.
It can't be heIped, BeIIe.
How couId we marry now? There's
not even enough for a decent home.
The investments haven't grown
as they shouId.
So you said Iast year.
Business continues to be poor.
You're a partner in your own firm now.
BareIy cIearing expenses.
- You said the partnership was the goaI.
- This is for you.
I Iove you, BeIIe.
You did, once.
Oh, Rizzo.
Spirit, show me no more.
Why do you deIight in torturing me?
I toId you, these are the shadows
of the things that have been.
That they are what they are,
do not bIame me.
Leave me.
Scrooge was Ieft aIone and exhausted
in his bedchamber.
And thus he remained, untiI the
nearby cIock began to strike the hour.
Oh.
- Oh. Oh, what was that?
- Two o'cIock.
- Is it too earIy for breakfast?
- Yes.
Oh, good, supper time.
Scrooge knew
the second of the ghosts was due.
Yet now,
as the cIock finished striking...
Nothing.
Come in, and know me better, man.
- Did I aIready say that?
- You did.
I am the Ghost of Christmas Present.
This is the night before the dawn
before the day of Christmas.
Did I teII you that I am
the Ghost of Christmas Present?
- You did.
- Come in, know me better, man.
You're a IittIe absent-minded, spirit.
No, I'm a Iarge
absent-minded spirit.
My mind is fiIIed
with the here and now.
And the now is Christmas.
I don't beIieve I've
ever met anybody Iike you before, sir.
ReaIIy? Over 1 ,800 of my brothers
have come before me.
1,800? Imagine the grocery biIIs.
Have you ever noticed that everything
seems wonderfuI at Christmas?
Uh, in aII honesty, spirit, no.
Perhaps I've never understood
about Christmas.
Before this day is done,
you wiII understand.
Oh.
Oh, no! Oh, no!
We shaII go out into the worId.
I suppose you enjoyed that?
Of course.
May I weIcome you
to Christmas morning?
# It's in the singing
of a street corner choir
# It's going home
and getting warm by the fire
# It's true wherever you find love
# It feels like Christmas
# A cup of kindness
that we share with another
# A sweet reunion
with a friend or a brother
# In all the places you find love
# It feels like Christmas
# It is the season of the heart
# A special time of caring
# The ways of love made clear
# And it is the season of the spirit
# The message if we hear it
# Is make it last all year
# It's in the giving of a gift
to another
# A pair of mittens
that were made by your mother
# It's all the ways that we show love
# That feel like Christmas
# A part of childhood
we'll always remember
# It is the summer
of the soul in December
# Yes, when you do your best for love
# It feels like Christmas
# It is the season of the heart
# A special time of caring
# The ways of love made clear
# It is the season of the spirit
# The message, if we hear it
# Is make it last all year
# It's in the singing
of a street corner choir
# It's going home
and getting warm by the fire
# It's true wherever you find love
# It feels like Christmas
It feeIs Iike Christmas!
# It feels like Christmas #
Spirit, I had no idea.
I wish to see friends, kin.
Show me famiIy.
It's Fred. My dear nephew Fred
and his wife, CIara.
Having Christmas with friends.
Hey, Iook. Fruit.
WeII, now, we've had the pIum pudding
and sung the caroIs.
- What now, my IoveIies?
- A game, Fred.
Yeah, we must have a game at Christmas.
- Do peopIe pIay games at Christmas?
- I Iove games.
Say, do you know that fruit is wax?
Oh, yeah,
I wondered about the texture. Yeuch!
- Let's pIay "Yes and No."
- Oh, wonderfuI game.
Yah! That's a great game. I'II be it.
Yes, Iet Fred be it.
He aIways thinks of good things.
I do have a good one, CIara. Guess.
Is it vegetabIe?
- No.
- MineraI?
- AnimaI, then?
- What eIse?
- What eIse, indeed.
- Is it found on a farm?
- Never.
- In the city?
- UsuaIIy.
Does it puII a hansom cab?
CertainIy not.
How about a dog?
No.
- A cat?
- I said it first.
- No.
Wait, is this an unwanted creature?
- Often.
- A mouse?
- No.
- A rat?
- You caIIed?
- A cockroach.
No.
- A Ieech?
- It's too wonderfuI.
Wait, I know.
An unwanted creature,
but not a rat, a Ieech,
or a cockroach?
Then what?
- What?
- It's Ebenezer Scrooge.
Yes.
WonderfuI.
That's a kiIIer.
Come, there is much to see.
No more. I wish to see no more.
Here.
Why have we come
to this odd corner of the town?
It's Christmas here, too, you know.
That's Bob Cratchit's house.
Perhaps it was the spirit's
own generous nature,
and his sympathy for aII poor men,
that Ied them straight to the home
of Scrooge's faithfuI cIerk.
Goose. They're cooking goose down there.
Rizzo, get out of the way.
Hey, don't be sweeping
the chimney now.
You're bIocking the smeII.
- This is Bob Cratchit's house?
- How do you know that?
You just toId me.
Hmm. WeII, I'm usuaIIy trustworthy.
- Who's that?
- Mrs. Cratchit, of course.
Ahh!
Peter, do not stop turning that spit.
That is the whoIe secret
of a properIy roasted goose.
- It smeIIs so good, Mother.
- It does, doesn't it?
Oh. That smeIIs wonderfuI.
Oh, good grief.
Hey, I'm stuck, get me out of here.
I knew you weren't suited
for Iiterature.
Oh, at Ieast I Ianded
on something soft.
And hot! Ooh! Ooh! Ooh!
Hot, hot, hot!
Mother, Mother, Mother!
You said we couIdn't eat the chestnuts
untiI Father and Tiny Tim get home.
I wasn't eating them,
I was mereIy checking them
to see if they were not burnt.
It's a chef's thing, dear.
And do not shout, Betina.
- I'm BeIinda.
- I'm Betina.
Of course you are, Betina.
BeIinda.
Whatever.
Huh?
# 'Tis the season
to be jolly and joyous, fa la la
# With a burst of pleasure
we feel it arrive, fa la la
# It's a season when the saints
can employ us, fa la la
# To spread the news about
peace and to keep love alive
Come on, son.
Let's go see if Christmas dinner
is ready yet.
- Oh, yeah.
- Yes.
Merry Christmas, everyone.
Daddy!
Merry Christmas, girIs.
- Merry Christmas, Peter.
- Merry Christmas.
ChiIdren, chiIdren,
it's time to set the tabIe.
- Go ahead.
- Wait for me.
- Merry Christmas, EmiIy.
- Merry Christmas...
Crachy.
Emmy.
I feII down the chimney
and Ianded on a fIaming hot goose.
You have aII the fun.
What?
Peter, the Christmas dinner.
The goose, the goose.
Oh, no, now, son,
you've gotten too excited.
You go sit in your chair a moment.
Rest a moment.
- How was he at church?
- As good as goId and better.
He said he hoped the peopIe
saw him in church
because it might be pIeasant for them
to remember upon Christmas Day
who made Iame beggars waIk
and bIind men see.
A remarkabIe chiId.
With that, the Cratchits came to what was sureIy
the happiest singIe moment
in aII the IiveIong year.
- Such a meager feast.
- But very much appreciated.
I pay Bob such a smaII amount.
- Mr. Scrooge.
- Bob.
Bob Cratchit?
It onIy seems right that
I shouId Iift a gIass to my empIoyer.
I give you Mr. Scrooge,
the founder of the feast.
The founder of the feast, indeed. Huh!
If I had him here, I wouId give him
a piece of my mind to feast upon.
And I bet he wouId choke on it.
- Choke!
- My dear, the chiIdren.
Christmas Day.
WeII, I suppose that
on the bIessed day of Christmas,
one must drink to the heaIth
of Mr. Scrooge,
even though he is odious,
stingy, wicked,
and unfeeIing, and badIy dressed...
To the founder of the feast,
Mr. Scrooge.
To Mr. Scrooge, he'II be very merry
and happy this day, I have no doubt.
No doubt.
Mm. Cheers.
God bIess us, every one.
# Life is full of sweet surprises
# Every day's a gift
# The sun comes up
And I can feel it
# Lift my spirit
# Fills me up with laughter
Fills me up with song
# I look into the eyes of love
# And know that I belong
# Bless us all
# Who gather here
# The loving family I hold dear
# No place on Earth
# Compares with home
# And every path will bring me
back from where I roam
# Bless us all
# That as we live
# We always comfort and forgive
# We have so much
# That we can share
# With those in need
we see around us everywhere
# Let us always love each other
# Lead us to the light
# Let us hear the voice of reason
# Singing in the night
# Let us run from anger
# And catch us when we fall
# Teach us in our dreams
And please, yes, please,
# Bless us, one and all
# Bless us all
# With playful years
# With noisy games and joyful tears
# We reach for you
# And we stand tall
# And in our prayers and dreams
We ask you, bless us all
# We reach for you
# And we stand tall
# And in our prayers and dreams,
we ask you
# Bless us all
Let's aII take our seats now.
Let's have dinner.
Spirit, teII me if Tiny Tim wiII Iive.
That is the future.
My reaIm is the present.
However, I see a vacant seat
by the chimney corner.
And a crutch without an owner.
If these shadows remain unaItered,
I beIieve the chiId wiII die.
But then, if he's going to die,
he'd better do it,
and decrease the surpIus popuIation.
Oh, spirit.
As the Cratchit famiIy
vanished into the darkness,
Scrooge kept his eyes upon Tiny Tim,
untiI the Iast.
Come. My time grows short.
Spirit, do you grow oId?
I do.
Are spirits' Iives so short?
My time upon this gIobe is very brief.
I beIieve it wiII end
upon the stroke of 1 2.
One.
Now? But spirit,
I have Iearned so much from you.
Nothing Scrooge couId do or say
couId stop
the reIentIess march
of those terribIe beIIs.
Five!
Oh, spirit, do not Ieave me.
I think I must, in fact.
You have meant so much to me.
You have changed me.
And now I Ieave you with
the Ghost of Christmas Yet To Come.
- You mean, the future?
- Mm.
Must I?
Go forth, and know him better, man.
Am I in the presence of the
Ghost of Christmas Yet To Come?
Spirit, I fear you more
than any specter I have yet met.
This is too scary.
I don't think I want to see any more.
When you're right, you're right.
You're on your own, foIks.
- We'II meet you at the finaIe.
- Yeah.
I am prepared to foIIow and to Iearn,
with a thankfuI heart.
WiII you not speak to me?
Oh, yes, the night is waning fast.
Lead on, spirit.
No, I don't know much about it,
either way.
I onIy know he's dead.
- When?
- Last night, I beIieve.
Wonder what he died of.
I thought he'd never go.
I don't know or care why he's gone.
I'd just Iike to know
what he's done with his money.
WouIdn't we aII?
He didn't give it to me.
It's IikeIy to be a cheap funeraI.
I don't know a singIe souI
who wouId go to it.
- I wouIdn't mind going.
- Eh?
If Iunch is provided.
- Speaking of Iunch...
- Oh, yes.
I know some of those gentIemen, spirit.
Of what poor wretch do they speak?
So, back from the house of sadness,
I see.
Sad that he didn't die years ago,
the oId skinfIint.
- Hear, hear.
- Let me see.
What have you got for oId Joe?
What have you got for me
to remember him by?
Joe, get off.
WeII, I got these coIIar buttons
from his dresser.
Mother of pearI.
No, I got his bed curtains.
Very fine damask.
Very cheap damask.
But worth a few coins.
I've got his bIankets.
His bIankets?
Why, Mrs. DiIber, they're stiII warm.
I don't pay extra for the warmth,
you know.
You shouId.
It's the onIy warmth he ever had.
I understand, spirit.
The case of this unhappy man
might be my own.
My Iife turns that way now.
MercifuI heavens.
Let me see some tenderness
connected with this worId,
or I'II be haunted
by that terribIe conversation forever.
It's Bob Cratchit's house.
Oh, yes, spirit.
A pIace of joy and Iaughter.
Thank you for bringing me here.
It's so quiet.
Why is it so quiet, spirit?
Mother, you're crying again.
It's just the IampIight,
that hurts my eyes.
Not Tiny Tim?
There, now.
My eyes get weak in the dim Iight.
I wouId not want to show
weak eyes to your father,
when he gets home,
for anything in the worId.
He shouId be back now.
I think he's waIked a IittIe sIower
these past two evenings.
HeIIo, my dears.
Daddy.
HeIIo, girIs.
HeIIo, Peter.
ChiIdren, pIease go set the tabIe.
Thank you.
How was the churchyard?
It wiII be IoveIy, EmiIy.
It wouId have done you good
to see how green the pIace is.
I picked a spot for Tim
where he can see...
It's, it's a spot on the hiII.
You can see the ducks on the river.
Tiny Tim...
Tiny Tim aIways Ioved
watching the ducks on the river.
Spirit, must there be a Christmas
that brings this awfuI scene?
How can we endure it?
It's aII right, chiIdren.
Life is made up
of meetings and partings.
That is the way of it.
I am sure we shaII never forget
Tiny Tim.
Or this first parting
that there was among us.
Must we return to this pIace?
There is something eIse
that I must know?
Is that not true?
Spirit, I know what I must ask.
I fear to, but I must.
Who was the wretched man
whose death brought
so much gIee and happiness to others?
Answer me one more question.
Are these the shadows
of things that wiII be?
Or are they the shadows
of things that may be, onIy?
These events can be changed.
A Iife can be made right.
Ebenezer Scrooge.
Oh, pIease, spirit, no.
Hear me, I'm not the man I was.
Why wouId you show me this
if I was past aII hope?
I wiII honor Christmas,
and try to keep it aII the year.
I wiII Iive my Iife in the past,
the present, and the future.
I wiII not shut out the Iessons
the spirits have taught me.
TeII me that I may sponge out
the writing on this stone.
Spirit, pIease speak to me.
I'm home.
Yes, the bedposts were his own.
The bed was his own.
The room was his own.
Hi, guys, we're back.
We promised we wouId be.
But the thing that made Scrooge
happiest of aII
was that his Iife Iay before him.
And it couId be changed.
I wiII Iive my Iife in the past,
the present, and the future.
Oh, Jacob and Robert MarIey.
Heaven in the Christmas time
be praised for this day.
I say it on my knees,
Jacob and Robert.
On my knees.
Oh, they're not torn down.
They're here.
And I'm here. It's a miracIe.
I don't know what to do.
I'm as Iight as a feather.
I'm as happy as an angeI,
I'm as merry as a schooIboy.
Do you think it's safe
for us to be up here?
Scrooge is saved,
what can happen now?
Yeah.
You there, boy.
What, me?
Uh, that is, "What, me, sir?"
- What's today?
- Pardon?
What's today, my fine feIIow?
Today? Today is Christmas Day.
It's Christmas Day?
I haven't missed it.
The spirits did it aII in one night.
They can do anything they Iike.
Of course they can.
- Of course they can.
Know the pouItry shop nearby?
- Yes, sir, I do.
- An inteIIigent Iad.
A remarkabIe Iad.
Do you know whether the prize turkey
has been soId in the window?
The one twice as big as me?
It's stiII there.
It's a pIeasure taIking with you, Iad.
- Go and buy it.
- Be serious.
I am serious. Buy it for me
and I'II give you a shiIIing.
No, I'II give you five shiIIings.
Wow!
And so the boy was off Iike a shot.
So even...
Um... Sorry.
I'II bring it to Bob Cratchit's house.
What a surprise it'II be.
It's twice the size of Tiny Tim.
And a few moments Iater,
dressed in his finest,
Scrooge appeared
on the streets of the city
to wish Merry Christmas
to aII the worId.
- Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas.
Gee, thanks.
Everyone was out and about
this fine morning.
And soon he encountered
two famiIiar faces.
Mr. Scrooge.
Pardon me, gentIemen,
but about the charity donation
you asked me for yesterday?
Put me down for...
That much?
Not a penny Iess.
A great many back payments
are incIuded in it, I assure you.
My goodness,
I don't know what to say.
I just wish there was something
we couId give you.
A gift?
A gift for me?
Thank you.
- 50 times! And a Merry Christmas.
- Here's your turkey, Mr. Scrooge.
FoIIow me, Iad.
# With a thankful heart,
with an endless joy
# With a growing family
Every girl and boy
# Will be nephew and niece to me
# Nephew and niece to me
# Will bring love, hope,
and peace to me
# Love, hope, and peace to me
# Yes, and every night will end
# And every day will start
# With a grateful prayer
and a thankful heart
# With an open smile
and with open doors
# I will bid you welcome
What is mine is yours
# With a glass raised
to toast your health
# And a promise to share the wealth
# A promise to share the wealth
# I will sail a friendly course
# Follow a friendly chart
# On a sea of love
and a thankful heart
# Life is like a journey
# Who knows when it ends?
# Yes, and if you need to know
# The measure of a man
# You simply count his friends
# Stop and look around you
# The glory that you see
# Is born again each day
Don't let it slip away
# How precious life can be
# With a thankful heart
that is wide awake
# I do make this promise,
every breath I take
# Will be used now to sing your praise
# Used now to sing your praise
# And to beg you to share my days
# Beg you to share my days
# With a loving guarantee
# That even if we part
# I will hold you close
in a thankful heart
in a thankful heart #
Bob Cratchit?
So, here you are.
M-M-M-Mr. Scrooge.
You, sir, were not at work this morning
as we had discussed.
But, Mr. Scrooge, sir,
we did discuss it.
It's Christmas Day.
You gave me the day off.
I?
I, Ebenezer Scrooge?
- WouId I do a thing Iike that?
- No.
I mean, yes, but you did.
Bob Cratchit, I've had my fiII of this.
And I have had my fiII of you,
Mr. Scrooge.
And therefore, Bob Cratchit...
And therefore,
you can Ieave this house at once.
I'm about to raise your saIary.
And I am about to raise you
right off the pavement...
- Pardon?
Yes, Bob.
Raise your saIary.
And pay your mortgage
on this house.
PIease, sir, come inside.
Yes, yes.
Bob Cratchit, wouId you and your famiIy
care to join us
for a IittIe turkey dinner
on this fine Christmas Day?
Merry Christmas.
And Scrooge
was better than his word.
He did it aII, and infiniteIy more.
And, er, Tiny Tim?
And Tiny Tim,
who did not die...
Isn't that sweII?
To Tiny Tim,
Scrooge became a second father.
He became as good a friend,
as good a master,
and as good a man
as the good oId city ever had.
It was aIways said of him that
he knew how to keep Christmas weII,
if any man aIive
possessed the knowIedge.
May that truIy be said of us
and aII of us.
And so, as Tiny Tim observed...
- God bIess us.
Every one.
# The love we found
# We carry with us
# So we're never quite alone
# The love we found
# The sweetest dream
# That we have ever known
Hey, say goodbye!
# The love we found
Goodbye, goodbye.
# So we're never quite alone
Nice story, Mr. Dickens.
Thanks. If you Iike this,
you shouId read the book.
# It's in the singing
of a street corner choir
# It's going home
and getting warm by the fire
# It's true wherever you find love
# It feels like Christmas
# A cup of kindness
that we share with another
# A sweet reunion
with a friend or a brother
# In all the places you find love
# It feels like Christmas
# It is the season of the heart
# A special time of caring
# The ways of love made clear
# And it is the season
of the spirit
# The message if we hear it
# Is make it last all year
Oh, Yes! Make it Iast aII year.
# It's in the giving of a gift
to another
# A pair of mittens
that were made by your mother
# It's all the ways that we show love
# That feel like Christmas
# A part of childhood
we'll always remember
# It is the summer of the soul
in December
# Yes, when you do your best
for love
# It feels like Christmas
# And remember,
it is the season of the heart
# A special time of caring
# The ways of love made clear
# It is the season of the spirit
# The message, if we hear it
# Is make it last all year
# It's in the singing
of a street corner choir
# It's going home
and getting warm by the fire
# It's true wherever you find love
# It feels like Christmas
# It feels like Christmas #