Hey, Rose.
Hey, Dorothy.
I'm gonna go over there.
We're waitin'.
Alvin.
Alvin Straight!
Rose left a couple of hours ago.
Did you hear me
hollerin' for Rose?
I wasn't lookin' for Rose.
-I haven't seen Alvin today.
-Did I ask?
Straight, you're late!
Alvin!
-Come in, Bud.
-What the hell, Alvin?
Where the hell are you?
I can't see a thing.
Over here, Bud.
Watch your step.
What the hell's going on here?
What on god's earth are you
doin' layin' on the floor?
You nuts?
Supposed to be down at
Davmar's one hour ago.
What's going on?
Oh, my God!
Al...
Hey, Dorothy.
Oh my god. Oh! Oh!
What's the number for 911?
-Put the phone down, Dorothy.
-What the hell are you doin'?
What? Oh!
I'm gonna have to call the bar
and tell 'em we're not comin'.
Bud Spenser, are you crazy? We have
a stricken man here.
Are you stricken, Alvin?
Dorothy, put the phone down!
Dad, what's all the yellin'?
Wh-what... uh, have
you done to my dad?
Oh, for cry eye!
Dad?
Are you okay, Dad?
I just need a little
help gettin' up, honey.
I'm goin' to Davmar's.
I'll be right back.
Okay, Bud.
I'm not goin'.
Dad.
Dad!
I'm not goin'.
You promised me, Dad.
Okay, Mr. Straight, you need
to take off al your clothes,
except your underwear
and put this robe on.
Just bring me the doctor.
You like birds.
I build...
uh, birdhouses...
uh, for bluebirds.
Oh, that's nice.
Yeah, it's Pete...
uh, Pete sells my...
uh, birdhouses...
at the Ace Hardware.
Oh?
-I'll look for them next time I'm in.
-Yeah?
No operation.
Well, this morning you fall
and can't get off the floor,
that's your hips, Alvin.
You're going to have to use
a walker now to get around.
No walker.
Fine, a second cane, then.
Now, you say you're having
trouble seeing.
That could be a
diabetes-related problem.
I would like to run
to run a few tests.
No tests and I'm not
paying, so no X-rays.
Well, I see and hear
that you smoke.
My guess is you're in the
early stages of emphysema.
And Alvin, you have
circulation problems
and I'm worried about your diet.
If you don't make
some changes quickly,
there will be some
serious consequences.
It... has a... a red roof.
Another pretty one, Rose.
I want to... uh, paint the...
uh, next one blue.
That's a good idea.
What... uh, did the doctor say?
He said I was gonna
live to be 100.
I think I'll go
and mow the lawn.
Uh, I can... uh, cut
it for you, Dad.
I got it, sweetheart.
God darn!
No, we'll... we won't
be mowin' today.
Storm's comin' in.
Yeah.
I love a lightnin' storm.
Uh, me too, Dad.
Hello?
This is... is Rose.
Yeah...
Uh-huh.
Oh, no...
When?
Okay...
I'll tell him.
Yeah... okay... bye.
Uh, that was... Bobby.
Uncle Lyle... had a...
a stroke.
Dad?
No, Bobby, he... he
didn't say much.
Uh, they've both...
uh, been so...
uh, stubborn.
No, no, it was
longer, I remember.
It was... uh, July, uh, 7th, 19...
88, uh, Bobby.
I always... remember the dates.
Yeah.
I don't know... uh,
what he'll do.
Rose, darlin'?
Rose?
I'm gonna go back on the road.
I've gotta go see Lyle.
But, Dad...
How are you?
Well, I... haven't quite
got that figured yet.
One, your eyes are bad.
That's why you don't...
uh, drive your car.
Uh, two, Uncle Lyle... uh, lives in...
uh, Wisconsin,
which is... uh, 317 miles away.
You would have to... uh, stay all night...
in Des Moines.
Then there's no... uh, bus...
to Zion.
Three, your... uh, hips are bad.
You can hardly... uh, stand...
for two minutes... and when you...
uh, do stand up...
this... is the sound you make...
when you... stand.
Uh, four, uh, you are...
uh, 73 years old...
You were... uh, born
when, uh, Calvin... uh, Coolidge
was president... of America.
Uh, you are... uh,
73 years old, Dad.
And... I cannot drive you there.
Rose, darlin', I'm not dead yet.
Uh, what are we...
uh, building, Dad?
Havin' a party?
Oh, jeez... I love...
uh, parties.
Oh, me too.
And so... where's it at?
Where's what at?
Your... uh, party.
I'm not havin' a party.
I thought you were
havin' a party.
I am?
Well, yeah. Look at all
that Braunschweiger.
Oh, yeah, it's a lot
of Braunschweiger.
It's... uh, for my dad, uh, for his...
his trip.
Uh, my dad... he's going to...
uh, Wisconsin.
I... asked him how he's...
uh, going to get there...
Uh... but he... uh,
won't say nothing.
Wisconsin? That is a
real party state.
Yeah.
I... uh, hate... uh, Braun...
uh... schweiger.
Yeah.
Alvin, you've got three
five-gallon cans there.
15 gallons of gas.
What do you need so
much gas for, Alvin?
Sig, you're one
nosey son of a gun.
You got that right.
-I wanna buy that.
-What?
What?
The grabber.
Oh, jeez, Alvin.
-That's my grabber, Alvin.
-Well?
Oh, jeez, Alvin. I don't...
I... I do have two of them...
I think five dollars
would be about right.
That's a darn good
grabber, Alvin.
-I... I...
-Well?
They're hard to come by, Alvin.
It's gonna take me two months
to get another one on order.
Jeez, Alvin, ten dollars.
Ring her up.
What do you need that
grabber for, Alvin?
Grabbin'.
Oh, jeez, Dad.
Listen to that old
grain elevator.
It's... uh, harvest time.
Uh, that... uh, trailer is
too h-heavy for... for that.
It's a lawn mower.
You're going to...
drive a... a lawn mower
to another state?
Rosie, I've... I've
gotta go see Lyle.
And I... I've gotta make
this trip on my own.
I know you understand.
I guess so.
Look up at the sky, Rosie.
The sky is sure full
of stars tonight.
Crimenetto, it's Alvin and
he's driving his lawn mower.
Alvin! What are you
settin' out to do here?
For cry eye, Alvin!
Alvin, you're gonna get
blown right off the road,
that's what I'm afraid!
He'll never make it
past The Grotto.
I'm havin' a little
engine trouble.
What the heck is that
you're driving there?
It's a Rehds.
Could you give me
a lift into town?
Yeah, I can get you
as far as the Grotto.
This is the Sun Ray Tour.
Climb on in.
-I'll get you help there.
-I'd appreciate that.
My Edward loved
his riding mower.
Hey, come here, hurry. Hurry up.
Poor Alvin.
So the man... in a... pick-up,
he brought my dad back.
Ohh... mm, I must've
been at the beauty shop.
What kinda pick-up?
A Ford.
But what's your dad
doin' with that gun?
I don't know.
I thought that you
have that old Rehds
that we had the last
time, didn't I?
That you did.
You tradin' in that Rehds today?
No, I don't believe I will.
Pete was tellin' me
told me you tried
using that rider in a
real interestin' way.
-You still plannin' to do that?
-Still planning to, Tom.
I know better than
to try and talk
Alvin Straight out of
somethin' he set his mind to,
but I got to tell you Alvin,
that you've always struck
me as a smart man.
Well, that's appreciated.
Until now.
What year?
'66.
has a Kohler engine.
We've used it for parts
but I always replace order and
replace them when they arrive.
The guts are good.
It's got the old transmission.
Nothing fancy.
-Is it a good machine?
-It's a good machine.
Well, Tom, I got $325.
That's a fact.
That sounds good to me, Alvin.
Let's go settle up with Alice.
One more thing,
sometime you can find out
a little about these
thirty year old machines,
if you know who run 'em.
-Do you know who owned it?
-You bet I do... me.
All right.
I couldn't get a ride.
Are you hungry?
Whaddaya got?
Weeners.
Weeners?
Wanna try one?
Here's a good stick for you.
What a hunk of junk.
Eat your dinner, Missy.
So...
how long you been
out on the road?
Well, I been travellin'
most of my life.
Where you from?
Laurens.
Got a wife back there?
Kids?
My wife, Francis
delivered 14 babies.
Seven of 'em made it.
My daughter, Rose lives with me.
Francis died in '81.
Where's your family?
Are you runnin' away?
How far along are ya?
Five months.
Well, I'm headin' to
see my brother Lyle.
Huh?
I said I'm goin' to see my
brother Lyle in Mount Zion.
-Where's that?
-Wisconsin.
-Oh...
-Just across the state line.
Cheddar Heads.
Aren't those the dumbest things
you ever seen somebody
stick on their head?
I hear that's a real
party place... Wisconsin.
Guess I'll never
get to find out.
There's a blanket
in the trailer.
Why don't you go get it?
My family hates me.
They'll really hate me
when they find out.
You didn't tell 'em?
No.
No one knows.
Not even my boyfriend.
Well, they may be mad,
but I don't think they're mad
enough to wanna lose you
or your little problem.
I don't know about that.
Well, of course, neither do
I, but a warm bed and a roof
sounds a might better than
eatin' a hot dog on a stick
with an old geezer that's
travellin' on a lawn mower.
My daughter Rose is...
Some people call her a little
bit slow but she's not.
She's got a mind like a
bear trap for facts.
She keeps everything
organised around the house.
She was a real good mom.
She had four kids.
One night, somebody else
was watchin' the kids
and there was a fire.
Her second boy got
burned real bad.
Rose had nothin' to
do with it but, ah...
on account of the way Rose
is, the State figured
she wasn't competent to
take care of them kids
and they took 'em
all away from her.
There isn't a day goes by that
she don't pine for them kids.
When my kids were real little, I
used to play a game with 'em.
I'd give each one of
'em a stick and...
one for each one of 'em...
then I'd say 'you break that.'
'Course they could, real easy.
Then I'd say 'tie them
sticks in a bundle
and try to break that'.
'Course they couldn't.
Then I'd say 'that bundle...'
that's family.'
Why don't you sleep
in the trailer?
This chair's just
fine for me tonight.
No.
I'll be fine sleepin' out here.
Lookin' at the stars
helps me think.
Well...
Thank you.
Woo!
What the?
What the hell?
Hey, how're you doin'?
Doin' good.
Hey, Irene.
You don't think about gettin'
old when you're young.
You shouldn't.
Must be something good
about gettin' old.
Well, I can't imagine
anything good about being
blind and lame at the
same time, but...
still at my age, I've
seen about all that
life has to dish out.
I know to separate the
wheat from the chaff
and let the small
stuff fall away.
Let's go, man.
So, ah... what's the worst
part about being old, Alvin?
The worst part of being old is
rememberin' when you was young.
Can I help you, lady?
No, you can't help me.
No one can help me.
I've tried driving
with my lights on.
I tried sounding my horn!
I scream out of the window,
I... I roll the window down
and bang on the side of the door
and play Public Enemy real loud!
I have prayed to St Francis of
Assisi, St Christopher too!
What the heck! I've tried
everything a person could do
and still every week I plough
into at least one deer!
I have hit 13 deer
in seven weeks
driving down this road, Mister!
And I have to drive
down this road
every day, 40 miles
to work and back.
I have to drive to work
and I have to drive home!
Where do they come from?
Oh... he's dead.
And I love deer.
Well, they sure picked the right
place to practise a burn on.
That Rumelthanger
place was an eyesore.
What do you suppose?
Is that a lawn mower?
Mister, you okay?
Jeez, mister, you're lucky
she didn't roll on you.
I guess the belt broke.
I wouldn't be surprised.
You don't have brakes
on that trailer, do you?
Mister, I worked for John
Deere for 30 years,
so I can tell you you
shouldn't be hauling
a rig like that behind
a riding mower.
At least not down
a hill like that.
I'm Danny Riordan.
Alvin Straight.
Well, Alvin, let's get you
and this rig off the road
and see what the damage is.
Let's get this off the road.
Sure you're okay?
Okay.
You okay?
Everything all right? I'm
going back to the exercise.
Thanks. Appreciate it.
Well...
let's take a look at this mower.
-This is what '65, '66?
-'66.
Well...
tell you right now, Alvin,
you won't be going
anywhere tonight.
Aside from your, ah,
drive belt being busted,
you got transmission problems.
-Where you headed?
-Mount Zion.
Mount Zion, Wisconsin?
Past Prairie Du Chien?
That's 60 more miles of hills.
That's across the Mississippi.
What's in Mount Zion, Alvin?
My brother lives there.
Why didn't you just
take your car?
I don't have a driving license.
Couldn't.. couldn't
he come visit you?
He's had a bad stroke.
Where are you coming from?
Back a piece.
West Union?
-Hawkeye?
-Nope.
Well, not New Hampton? You
haven't come that far.
You've come a long
ways, haven't you?
Yeah, I have.
Laurens, Iowa.
Laurens?
That's west of The Grotto.
How long have you
been on the road?
What's the date?
October eighth.
Five weeks.
I left Laurens on the
fifth of September.
You been bunkin' in that?
That's my rollin' home.
Where you been settin' up camp?
In the fields.
I pull off.
I don't travel at night.
Haven't you been
scared, being alone?
There are a lot weird
people everywhere now.
Well, ma'am, I fought in the
trenches in World War II.
Why should I be scared
of an Iowa cornfield?
Well, um...
till we get this mower fixed...
why don't you... ah,
bivouac in our yard here?
There's a bathroom in
the garage you can use.
Well,
that's awful generous
of you and I'm
sure my machine here is
agreeable to that too.
Sure wanna thank you folks
for helping me today.
Well...
there's a lot of rain forecast.
Sure don't want to get
stuck in that trailer.
I... I do a little woodwork.
I thought you might want
to sit under a shade...
My daughter does woodwork.
She makes birdhouses.
Oh, that's nice.
-You finished there?
-I believe I am.
Hello.
-I'm in need of a phone.
-Why, sure. Come on in.
I wanna call my
daughter and give her
an account of my recent travels.
Sure. Sure. Come on in.
If it's all the same with you,
do you happen to have one of
them phones without a cord?
-Well, door's wide open, come on in.
-I can call from out here.
Here you go.
You know, you're
more than welcome
to sit down at the
kitchen table.
Darla and I can leave the room,
if you're lookin' for
a little privacy.
Out here's fine.
Is the area code still 712 here?
No, Alvin. That hill
rolled you into 319.
So, you need to dial one and
your area code to get her.
712, thank you.
'Hello? '
Rose?
Dad? Dad...
Dad!
Uh, I'm... so glad to hear you.
It's gonna cost him a
bundle to fix that mower.
I don't think he's got
that kinda money.
I wouldn't drive that
thing to Excelsior.
It's a lawn mower,
for God's sake.
Uh, your social security cheque?
Ah... it's here, Dad.
Rose, can you send me my cheque?
Uh, yeah.
He's damn lucky he made it
to the bottom of that hill.
He could've been killed.
-Easily. He could've been killed.
-Yeah. Mm-hm.
He's none too strong.
Did you see how he has to
walk with the canes?
Yeah. Mm-hm.
Okay, Dad.
I... I...
Okay, okay, Dad,
okay. I... I have a pencil, Dad.
The hills just get worse
the closer you get
to the Mississippi.
Go ahead and drive him, honey.
Mount Zion can't be half a day.
It's fine.
You're a good man,
Danny Riordan.
And that's why I married you,
despite what my mother said.
Now, shoo!
Dad?
I miss you, Dad.
I love you, Rosie.
'I love you too, Dad.'
Uh, bye, Dad.
Bye... Dad.
Ahem.
What are you cookin'
there, Alvin?
Oh, I'm makin' my
Mexican coffee.
Ah. Mind if I join you?
Get you a chair...
that iron one there.
You'll be a guest in
your own back yard.
I talked to the Olsen twins,
and, ah...
they estimate it'll cost around
250 dollars to get
your mower fixed.
Well, that's twice
what it oughta be,
I guess it's cos
they're twins, huh?
You know... uh..
I'd be happy to drive you the
rest of the way to Mount Zion.
Be a nice Sunday drive
for me and Darla.
We enjoy crossin' the river,
especially now with
the trees in colour.
Well, I appreciate that, but...
I wanna finish this
one my own way.
Try this.
Thank you.
Well, you know, Alvin, there's a
lotta hills bigger than Clairmont's
between here and Zion.
Even if you get that
mower runnin' again,
I mean there is no guarantee
it won't break down.
Well, you're a kind man
talkin' to a stubborn man.
I still wanna finish
this the way I started.
No, no...
Hi, Verlyn.
-How the heck you doin'?
-Fine.
Wonderful.
He's there.
Well...
they gave you a plate
of her brownies.
Yeah.
How's that for timing?
Janet makes the best brownies...
in Lafayette county.
She won prizes every
year at the county fair.
-Mmm... help yourself.
-Thank you.
Mmm... I've been doin' errands
and I'm heading for a beer.
I thought you'd like to join me.
Well, I don't drink
any more, but...
I'm always up for a
change of scenery.
Well, come on.
Well, I'm ridin' a little higher
and going a little faster.
Except when you came
down that hill.
I picked up a mournful taste
for liquor in France.
When I came back, I couldn't
drink enough of it.
I wasn't worth a stick
of stove wood...
I was mean.
A preacher helped me
put some distance between
me and the bottle.
And he helped me see...
the reason I was drinkin', I
was seein' all them things
here, that I'd seen over there.
# Though things may look very
dark, your dream is not... #
Lots of men came
back drinkin' hard.
Well...
everyone tryin' to forget.
I can see it in a
man right away.
Yup.
# The rainbow, you
will suddenly... #
There was one time...
when we just...
were waiting
for the first warm
meal in ten days.
We... thought we'd
seen the worst.
We hadn't had much
trouble from the air.
I was on the rise...
with the quartermaster,
workin' on more coffee
for me and my buddies.
A stray Fokker came
over the treetops...
and dropped an incendiary
on the mess tent.
All my buddies...
The Kraut then banked right in
front of me on that hill...
and now I can... see the...
Swastika.
That is one thing that
I can't shake loose...
All my buddies faces
are still young.
And the thing is,
the more years I have,
the more they've lost.
And it's not always
buddies faces that I see,
sometime they're German faces.
Near the end we were
shootin' moon-faced boys.
I was a sniper.
Where I grew up,
you learned how to
shoot to hunt food.
They'd post me up front.
Darn near ahead of the lines.
And I'd sit... forever.
It's an amazing thing what you
can see while you're sittin'.
I'd look for the officers,
the radio guys or
artillery spotter.
Sometime I'd spot a
gun nest by the smoke
and I'd fire into it.
Sometime it was just a
movement in the woods.
We had a scout,
a little fella...
name of Kotz.
He was a Polish boy
from Milwaukee.
He'd always take recon and
he was darn good at it.
We went by his word and he
saved our skin many a time.
He was a little fella...
We'd broken out of
the hedgerows...
We were makin' a run
across the open
and we come upon a woods.
We started drawin' fire.
I took my usual position...
and I saw somethin'
movin', real slow like.
I waited ten minutes,
it moved again and I shot.
The movement stopped.
The next day we found Kotz...
head shot.
He'd been workin' his way
back toward our lines.
Everyone in the unit
thought a German sniper
had taken him...
Everyone, all these years.
Everyone but me.
Ha ha!
See, Harald... brainiac...
Got the mower assembly free with
this here little old wrench...
You said it wouldn't work.
I'd say it worked pretty good.
Wouldn't you?
So help me slide her out.
We can get settled up.
Uh... I got parts and labour
that add up to $247.80.
Well, I'd say that's
a little heavy for light work.
Don't you think?
I've got an old man's
eyes, but, ah...
I'm noticin' some new tyre here.
Well, now... ah,
we got those off a re-sell,
but the treads are good!
Well, friend, are you chargin'
me for good or for new?
Ahhhh... Thorvald?
Ahh... we can make
an adjustment there.
Well, I think the adjustment
should be about thirty dollars.
Is that what your
pencil's sayin'?
And, ah... about the labour...
I appreciate that you boys have
done some real time on this, but...
of course, a man's gotta ask
when he's workin' with twins...
especially a bickerin' pair...-
how much workin' was fightin'?
He got that right.
Shut up, Danny.
If I was to judge by this
joyous affair I saw today,
I would calculate maybe 20 per
cent taken off the labour.
Anything else, mister?
Well, I'm not from
these parts, but
where I come from,
I would say that
that was a little
rich for Iowa oil.
Take the oil, no charge.
Well, that's a splendid offer
and I do appreciate it.
What's the tally?
Ah... ahhh...
Hundred and eighty even?
Done.
Thanks to you boys, I'm gonna
get this rig back on the road.
I've drove it all the way
across Iowa and I'm hopin'
it holds on till I
get to Wisconsin.
My brother lives there.
I haven't seen him in ten years.
There's no one knows
your life better
than a brother that's
near your age.
He knows who and what you are
better than anyone on Earth.
My brother and I said some...
unforgivable things
the last time we met,
but, I'm tryin' to
put that behind me.
And this trip is a hard swallow...
of my pride,
I just hope I'm not too late.
A brother's a brother.
Well...
Guess I'll be turnin' in.
I'll, ah... see you in the
morning, then, before you go.
I'm gonna leave awful early.
I wanna thank you for your
kindness to a stranger.
It's been a genuine pleasure
havin' you here, Alvin.
Write to us, sometime.
I will.
I noticed your camp fire.
I brought you some dinner...
Mashed potatoes, meat loaf.
Well, thank you kindly.
I've had my dinner,
but would you join
me for a while?
Sure.
Thank you.
I hope you don't
mind me trespassin'.
Oh, no, not at all.
Made a fine choice.
You're camped next to
one of the oldest
cemeteries in the Midwest.
French Catholic trappers.
-The Marquette party.
-Two of his men.
I couldn't help but
notice the rather unusual
mode of transport.
Well, you're not the first
person to notice that, Padre.
My eyes are bad. I can't drive.
I don't like someone
else drivin' the bus,
and I've got to get out
to my brother's place.
Fair enough.
Where is he?
Well, he's so close, I can
practically feel him.
Mount Zion.
What's his name?
Lyle Straight.
Is he that fella that
came in with a stroke
some weeks ago?
That's right. Do you know him?
I do some work at the
hospital over in Boscobel.
I remember him comin' in.
Caught my attention because...
he lives in my parish.
Well, he's a Baptist.
Oh, I believe he told me that.
he told me a few things,
matter of fact,
but he didn't mention
having a brother.
Well, neither one of us has had
a brother for quite some time.
So, you saw him?
Is he all right?
I only saw him that once
and I haven't heard
anything more.
Well, Lyle and I grew up as
close as brothers could be.
We were raised on a farm
in Moorhead, Minnesota.
We worked hard.
My mom and dad darn
near killed themselves
tryin' to make that farm work.
And me and Lyle would
make games out of our chores.
We'd dream up somethin'
about racin' and wagerin'
do anything to keep our
mind off the cold.
Lord, it was cold.
He and I used to sleep
out in the yard
every summer night,
if it wasn't pourin'.
Nine months of winter, we
couldn't get enough summer.
We'd bunk down when
the sun went down.
We'd talk to each other
until we went to sleep.
We'd talk about the stars and
whether there might be somebody
else like us out in space,
places we wanted to go and...
it made our trials seem smaller.
Yeah, we pretty much talked
each other through growin' up.
Oh, whatever
happened between you two?
Story as old as the Bible.
Cain and Abel.
Anger,
vanity.
You mix that together
with liquor, and...
you've got two brothers who
haven't spoken in ten years.
Well, whatever it was that made
me and Lyle so mad...
don't matter any more.
I wanna make peace.
I wanna sit with him,
look up at the stars...
like we used to do...
so long ago.
Well, sir...
I say 'Amen' to that.
Howdy.
I haven't had a drink
in a lot of years.
But now I'm gonna
have me a cold beer.
What flavour?
What does a Miller's
Lite taste like?
There you go.
-How's it taste?
-It's good.
-Keep the change.
-Thank you.
It's an interesting rig
you got out there.
Make it up the hill okay?
That hill and 200
more just like it.
How far did ya come?
From Iowa.
I'm headed for Lyle
Straight's place.
Iowa!
My God, you must be thirsty.
Another beer?
This will do me fine.
I wonder could you point
me to Lyle's place?
I haven't seen him in
an awful long time.
Well, you just... ah,
cross 61 here, on 'W',
Take 'W' on down to
Weed Road and then
on to Remington Road.
On your right will
be Lyle's place.
If he's there that is.
How you doin' pard?
Not too good.
This thing's just tired.
Is there anything I
can do to help you?
Well, I don't know.
It just quit on me.
Why don't you try her again?
I'm headin' to Lyle
Straight's place.
Lyle!
Lyle?
Alvin?
Sit down, Alvin.
Did you ride that thing all
the way out here to see me?
I did, Lyle.