Hmm.
- Yeah!
- On the 1 5th of May...
in theJungle of Nool...
in the heat ofthe day,
in the cool ofa pool...
he was splashing,
enjoying thejungle's greatjoys...
when Horton the elephant
heard a small noise.
Hmm?
Hmm.
- Horton!
Good morning, class.
Are you ready?
- Yeah!
- Jump on board!
Look out below!
Tommy's on board.
Katie, you there?
- Ahh.
- Okay.
Shh. There it is.
This is one ofthejungle's
most amazing creatures― the leaf bug.
In order to protect itself
from predators...
it disguises itselfas a leaf.
Hmm.
This one's got quite a grip.
Come on, little buddy.
Don't be shy.
I guess I was mistaken, kids.
There are obviously
no leaf bugs in this area.
Even a prof― Aah! They're on me!
Get 'em off!
I think I swallowed one!
Help me!
- Pull it out!
- Uh, okay.
Whoo-whoo! Whee!
- Then humpfing a "Humpf!"
was a sour kangaroo...
- Humpf!
the type who's convinced
she knows better than you.
She made every law
and enforced every rule...
as self-proclaimed head of the Jungle of Nool.
- Humpf!
- Why can't I play with the other kids, Mom?
How many times have I told you...
that thejungle is no place
to act like a wild animal?
- Ooh.
- My, that Horton certainly is eccentric.
And the children are learning
so much from him.
Learning to be a bunch
of harebrained half-wits.
And that's why my Rudy
is pouch-schooled.
So while Kangaroo stood there sneering a sneer―
Horton, that was the best time I've ever had
in my life. What are you gonna show us next?
once again
the speck floated right by Horton's ear.
Help!
And he heard it again,just a very faint yelp...
as ifsome tiny person
were calling for help.
And you know what he thought?
Why, he thought that there must be
someone on top ofthat small speck ofdust.
Or even a family—
it just might be so―
a family with children
just starting to grow.
I wanna live!
Uh, I gotta go.
Katie, you're in charge.
- Ahh.
- Huh?
Wait! Come back!
- Watch it!
- Eh— Uh—
Ohh!
One more! One more!
Ooh! Ooh!
- I hear someone comin'.
- Gimme those.
Wait!
Sound the alarm!
Huh?
Excuse me. Pardon my stampede.
Sorry, Wickershams. I promise
I'm gonna clean all this up later.
Bring the ammo!
I love the smell of bananas
in the morning!
Banana in the hole!
Come on, guys.
We're all mammals.
Whoa!
I feel the diplomatic
process is beginning to break down.
Whoa!
There you are! I got ya!
- Hi, kids.
- Whoa!
- Aah!
There. Now you're safe.
I know I heard you say something.
I just know it.
Where are you?
Humpf!
- Horton!
- Oh. Sorry.
Uh—
I just—
There was this speck, and, uh...
it called out for help.
- And I was—
- The speck called out for help?
Well, not the speck.
I mean, that's... ridiculous.
Is that what you thought I meant? No.
The speck can't call out for help.
Come on. Get real.
No, there's a tiny person on that speck
that needs my help.
Absurd.
There aren't people that small.
Well, maybe they aren't small.
Maybe... we're big.
- Horton—
- No, really. Think about it.
What ifthere were someone
way out there...
looking down on our world right now?
And to them, we're the specks.
And then maybe someone else will come along
and say, "There can't be people that small."
And the first guy would say,
"Are you calling me a liar?"
And the second guy would say,
"Ifthe shoe fits, wear it!"
Now the fists are flying.
The first guy picks up a brick―
You might want to zip up the pouch
for this next part— "Fat boy, you want some?"
- Horton!
- What?
There is nothing on that speck.
- But I heard.
- Did you?
Really?
Oh, my.
Then how come / don't hear anything?
Well—
If you can't see,
hear or feel something...
it doesn't exist.
And believing in tiny, imaginary people
is just not something we do...
or tolerate here
in the Jungle of Nool.
Really? 'Cause I bet if I tried, I could find
somebody who'd believe what I was saying.
You will do nothing ofthe sort.
You will not breathe a word ofthis lie
to anyone else...
especially the children.
I do not want you poisoning their minds
with this nonsense.
Our community has standards, Horton.
Ifyou want to remain a part of it,
l recommend you follow them.
Mmm. Have a nice day.
All right then.
I'll, uh, take that under advisement.
Certainly appreciate your input.
I don't understand.
I know I heard you.
It was as plain as the nose on my face.
That's it.
Maybe you can't hear me.
Ofcourse.
Your ears must be tiny.
I need to speak up.
Hello!
Now, some people out there― I think  l know who―
may find they agree
with that sour kangaroo.
There can't really be people
as small as a mite.
Well, there can and there are,
because Horton was right.
Hello!
That single "hello"
traveled all the way down...
through the speck,
through the clouds...
till it found a small town.
A town known as Who-ville,
for there lived the Whos...
feeling happy and safe,
knowing only good news...
unaware that theirworld
was a speck on a clover...
unaware that the sweet life they knew
might be over.
- Over.
- Under.
Oi! Oi! Oi!
The Mayor of Who-ville, a man named McDodd...
was devoted and fair
and a little bit odd.
The mayor and his wife,
they had children to spare―
96 daughters,
some here and some there.
Ninety-six girls to love.
Ninety-six girls to teach.
But the mayor had only a few seconds for each.
Daddy, I got better than best
on my "Who-story" test.
Ah, Who-story.
I remember it well.
- That's one of my girls.
- Hildy's been using my hairbrush!
Holly's been using my hairbrush!
Look! Over there!
There. All better.
Can I please have a Who-phone, Dad?
Everyone else in my class has one.
Oh, really? Everyone?
Oh. I will think about it.
Daddy, look! Daddy, look!
Mm-hmm.
Toof!
It's a "T-H," sweetheart.
It's "tooth."
In Who-ville tradition, unlike yours or mine...
the mayor's oldest is next
in the mayoral line.
And who was the oldest,
to lead and stand tall?
It wasJoJo, his son,
the smallest Who ofall.
So,JoJo, what's, uh—
What's shakin'?
What's happenin'?
What's the word?
Now, to you or to me, it's abundantly clear...
that JoJo did not want
his father's career.
But the mayor pressed forward,
completely deluded...
Boom-badda, boom-badda,
bidda-bidda-boom!
whileJoJojust sat there
in silence and brooded.
Oh,JoJo.
- Why does he get more time?
- That's not fair.
Son. Hey.
And why didn't he speak?
Well, I think that the lad was afraid,
if he did, he might let down his dad.
You know what's awesome?
This is awesome.
Just look at the men and women
hanging on these walls.
You, my boy, are part
ofa family legacy...
that spans centuries.
You know what?
Your grandfather was mayor
of Who-ville. Mm-hmm.
And your great-grandmother.
That's right.
All the way down to your―
great-
great-great-great-
not-so-great-
great-great-
great-great-great-
great-great-great-great-
Someday, I hope to join them...
be one ofthe greats.
I tell you, JoJo,
there is nothing like being mayor.
I get to sign resolutions,
approve ordinances, submit budgets.
And in the Edible Parade, I'm the one
sitting on top ofthe giant meatball.
Someday, that can be you too,JoJo.
Someday, you'll be the one
wearing the mayoral crest.
You just—
You just need to—
You know what I mean?
Okay. Good chat.
I'm glad that we had this talk...
that l'm continuing now by myself.
Good.
Huh.
Ooh. There. That oughta be comfy.
Nothing wrong with this, Morton.
Nothin' wrong with this.
Just you and me and the speck shootin' the breeze.
- We're a club. We're a group.
- Hmm?
We can take a vote on the issues.
We can be a secret society that controls
the balance of power in the world.
- Horton—
- And no one else can join
unless they wear funny hats.
- Listen, Horton—
- The chair recognizes Brother Morton.
I am really happy
you found this speck and all...
but you might wanna think
about keeping it to yourself.
Hmm? What? Why?
You're talking to a clover.
That doesn't look good.
You know what doesn't look good?
You talking about the speck
like the speck isn't even there.
The speck never said
anything bad about you.
But, hey, good luck
with your illusion ofsuperiority.
You know, the speck can think anything
it wants about me. It's a speck.
Whoa!
I see what's going on here.
Morton, no matter how tight
the speck and I get...
the speck could never replace you.
I'm only sad that I would have
to explain that at this point.
Well, that's awesome, Horton.
That really helps.
Just try to keep this to yourself.
I'll see you later.
Try.
Hmm.
Hey, Horton. What you got there?
What? Nothing.
We're not doing anything.
We're totally alone.
- Who's "we"?
- We? What? We? Did I say that?
No, I would never say that, because that
would imply that I was with someone...
and not alone.
Okay, seriously, you can't tell anybody.
I mean it.
Ifanybody finds out about this,
it could be very, very bad.
I'm not sure why.
We won't tell anyone.
And ifwe do, we'll tell them
not to tell anyone.
Perfect.
Okay, I'm taking a bath, right?
'Cause my skin
gets kind ofdry and ashy―
While Horton came clean
about the speck that he'd found...
and how he saved it
when it nearly drowned...
the mayor set off
on his morning commute...
and noticed things weren't
quite the same on his route.
But please don't blame Horton,
for he didn't know...
that a small bump above―
And I dove into the water like this!
was a big bump below.
Hey,Joe. Don't work too hard.
Ah, these luxury condos,
they don't build themselves.
Hey, look at that!
I guess they do build themselves.
Okay, that happened.
Now, the mayor knew it was hisjob to convey...
the unusual things
that he'd noticed that day.
But there was one problem.
Though his will was strong—
- You're late.
- Thankyou, Miss Yelp.
nothing in Who-ville had ever gone wrong.
We have all that we need.
We need all that we've got.
We like it in Who-ville.
We like it a lot!
We're all very busy
with the Who-centennial coming up...
so let's bring this meeting to order.
Mr. Mayor, I presume
you have some good news for us.
Well, it's news.
I don't know ifwe need to go labeling it
good or bad or anything like that.
The thing is,
I have noticed some odd goings-on...
in Who-ville lately.
Good odd goings-on?
Well, you know, tremors,
clouds swirling in the sky.
It seems to me,just to be safe,
we might want to consider...
postponing the Who-centennial.
- Consider what?
- Postponing the Who-centennial.
What? Speak up, man!
Postponing the Who-centennial. All right?
Hmm.
We are about to celebrate 100 years
of Who-ville happiness and harmony...
and you want
to postpone the celebration?
Well, what ifWho-ville's not safe?
Nothing ever goes wrong
in Who-ville.
Never has and never will.
You blathering boob.
Boob?
The Who-centennial
will proceed as planned.
The mayor was merely being an idiot.
It will be all smiles from now on.
Ow. Ow.
Girl, I got 15,000 friends already.
What you mean it don't look like me?
That look just like me.
Ten years ago.
Wait a minute. Hold on for a second.
Treats me like an idiot.
I am not an idiot.
Do I look like an idiot?
- You don't want me to answer that.
- I am not an idiot.
Has the nerve to call me a boob? I would never
call somebody a boob. He's a boob.
Look at you. Yuck.
Look at your face.
And l bet you don't look so good
with a stapler in your head!
Whoa! Whoa!
Ow. Ow. Ow.
- Yaah! Thankyou, Miss Yelp.
- You're welcome.
Oh!
- Hello?
- Who said that?
I'll punch you!
Whoa!
Hmm?
Hello?
Hello.
- Who's there?
- Um, this is the mayor.
The mayor? The mayor?
I'm talking to the mayor!
I knew it, I knew it,  l knew it!
I knew there was life on this speck.
Speck? What speck?
Well, um, I don't exactly know
how to tell you this, but...
you're living on a speck.
Well, I hate to disagree with you,
O Voice from the Drainpipe...
but I live in Who-ville.
Well, then Who-ville's a speck.
Right. Okay.
Seriously, who is this?
Is this Burt from Accounting?
Uh, no. This is Horton.
I'm an elephant.
Okay, Horton— fake name—
where are you?
Well, from where you're standing...
I guess I'm in the sky.
Compared to you, I'm enormous, which is saying
something, because I've slimmed down a bit.
I swim.
Your whole world
fits on a flower in my world.
Oh, man, this is even
pushing it foryou, Burt.
Don't believe me? Watch what happens
when I put you in the shade.
This is absolutely impossibl—
Dark.
Light. Dark. Light.
Dark. Light. Dark. Light. Dark. Light.
Dark. Light. Dark. Light. Dark.
- Light.
- Whoo.
Don't you see? We're in the middle of
some kind ofamazing cosmic convergence.
Two vastly different worlds...
- miraculously crossing paths.
- Who— Who—
Mine colossal!
Yours minuscule.
Yet somehow
we've managed to make contact.
Ifyou think about it,
it's pretty amazing.
Is everything okay down there?
Uh, I-I don't know.
You tell me.
You're the one holding the speck.
I'm the one holding the speck.
Don't you worry, Mr. Mayor.
Um, hold, please.
Oh! Ohh!
What did all ofthis mean? The mayor hadn't a clue.
So he ran to the office of Dr. Larue...
the brainiest brain
on the staffat Who U.
Dr. Larue?
Oh, this is crazy.
Oh. Mr. Mayor.
Uh, how may I be ofassistance?
I don't know.
Hey, I wasjust wondering...
ifourworld were, say, a tiny speck, mmm,
floating through space...
how would we know?
Why would you ask
something like that?
Oh, no reason.
No reason at all.
I don't even remember.
Yes, I do. You know what?
Some guy was talking to me.
Not an elephant in the sky,
a guy on the ground.
There would be several ramifications.
Good ramifications?
A tiny speck.
Uh-huh, yeah. Tiny speck.
- Floating around.
- Whoa.
Well, we'd have
"unexplicable" tremors...
dramatic changes in the weather.
And ifwe didn't eventually achieve
some sort ofstability...
our world would be...
destroyed.
Destroyed? Destroyed.
Oh, destroyed.
The drama!
Aaaah!
- Horton.
- Uh, no, uh, this is, uh, Benny.
Horton is busy right now.
I'm joking.
That's me.
Oh, we're doomed.
Listen, Horton,
turns out l need your help a little bit.
Apparently, ifthat speck
keeps moving around...
our whole world could be obliterated.
So I need you to find us Whos
a safer, more stable home.
And fast.
No problem, Mr. Mayor.
Let's see.
Mmm. Wow!
That's a nice view.
Hello? Is everything okay?
Ooh!
What's going on up there?
Oh, no!
Aaah!
This entire jungle
is a house of death!
Oh, wait.
There's a good spot.
And it's then Horton saw,
at the top of Mount Nool...
a small cave that looked peaceful
and quiet and cool...
where a sunflower grew
proud and tall from the ground.
There he knew every Who
would be safe, would be sound.
I've found it, Mayor.
The perfect place.
Right up there.
On the top of Mount Nool.
- Mr. Mayor?
- I wish you could—
Oh, how shiny.
The Who-centennial committee
is waiting foryou...
to look over the giant meatball
for the Edible Parade.
Oh, and then you're due at the dentist
foryour Who-root canal.
You know, sticking "Who" in front
ofeverything doesn't make it hurt less.
Just wastes time!
I don't... wanna go.
Listen, Horton, I've gotta go.
Apparently there's a problem
with the giant meatball.
You just take care
ofthat meatball, sir...
and leave the freaking out to me.
So then Horton began his long, perilous trek...
determined to save
the small world on the speck.
Horton was faithful
and stalwart and kind.
I got ya. Don't worry.
He was a brave hero―
- I'll protect you.
- at least in his mind.
We must become invisible,
travel silently...
for there are forces
that would seek to destroy us.
Huh? So you think
you can sneak up on me, huh?
It is clear that you are no match
for my technique! Hey!
l see you have mastered
the Way ofthe Snapping Branch.
Watch me tumble!
Morton Mouse, go!
You are fast, Horton,
but the kangaroo has monkeys!
I will make monkeys ofthese monkeys!
lt is their destiny― Huh?
My clover!
Ooh!
Horton is the greatest hero
ofthem all! Ha!
- Horton! Go!
- Morton! Go!
- But Mount Nool is that way!
- Ha-ha-ha!
To the top of Mount Nool!
As fast as lightning! Away I go!
Oh. Sorry, little fella.
You'll be fine.
Just think healing thoughts.
- Horton! Horton! Look!
- Look, look, look!
- We've all got our own clovers
with worlds on them.
- Yeah.
Oh.
In my world, everyone's a pony...
and they all eat rainbows
and poop butterflies.
That's beautiful, Katie.
Ahh.
In a really weird way.
My world is called Jessica-land.
Everyone worships Queen Jessica
becauseJessica is so beautiful.
Jessica, that was awesome.
Hmm.
- Rudy!
- Mom, be careful!
- My best friend, Thidwick, lives on that.
- Rudy, no one lives on this.
It's not possible.
That Horton is a menace.
- M-Mom, you're so weird. Don't do this to me.
- Honey, go to your room.
Horton!
Whee!
- It's good!
- What do you thinkyou're doing?
Huh? You guys with worlds
are in trouble.
Have you forgotten
what we discussed?
Oh, no. l'm an elephant.
And elephants never forget.
It's a curse really.
I was on my head, and you said "Humpf!"
I looked up, you said "What are you doing?"
I said the thing about the speck. Then you
pulled my ears, poked me on the forehead—
- Horton!
- Well, you did.
Give me that clover, Horton. Now.
No.
No?
Yeah.
Are you sure you wanna
fight this fight, Horton?
Because I promise you
it will get very ugly very fast.
And you need to askyourself...
"Do I really want
to put myselfthrough all this...
for a clover?"
Take it from me, Horton—you don't.
So hand it over.
No! I can't give it to you.
There are people on this speck.
Granted, they're very small people...
but a person's a person,
no matter how small.
- Huh.
- How—
You just crossed the line, Horton...
and I'm gonna make you pay.
Uh— Uh— Ohh!
That Horton is a menace.
He has those kids using their imaginations.
It's sick!
All right, I gotta get this speck up to the top
of Mount Nool A.S.A.P.—
whatever that means.
Probably,
"Act swiftly, awesome pachyderm."
I mean, how hard can that be?
It'sjust a straight plummet to certain death.
This looks kind of... precarious.
Well, no need to worry.
Obviously, when they
build a bridge like this...
they take into account
that elephants will be crossing here.
All right. Feels good.
I'll just get...
the... feel of it!
Yike!
Oh, that's― that's true.
All right!
Hello. And how are we today,
Mr. Mayor?
Say "ahh."
Ahh.
Aaah!
Hmm.
Rinse, please.
Huh. I think a few
of these boards could stand to be replaced.
Ooh!
I just need to think light.
I'm light as a feather.
Heavy feather.
Okay.
This will just pinch a little.
l'm lighter than a feather.
What's lighter than a feather?
Air!
There's nothin' lighter.
So it stands to reason—
that the more air I have—
the lighter—
I'll be.
La-aah!
- Aah!
- Next, please.
All right,
that was absolutely terrifying.
If I just pull myself up—
Try not to panic.
Hmm.
Whew! That could have been a disaster.
Wow. I feel really good right now.
Maybe it's my new sense of purpose.
Whoa.
All right.
Hey! JoJo, I need your help.
Can you help me?
Okay. Great. Okay, first  l need you
to go to the girls' room.
Aah! Take down Hannah's
china doll collection and then—
Stop looking at my arm. Put away
Holly's lightbulb collection and then—
You know what?Just take care
ofanything that might break or shatter.
Okay. Take a good, long look.
Got it? Thanks,JoJo.
Oww! Oh!
Whew!
Here. And I'll take that.
And— Oh! Aaah!
Hi. You're home late.
Oh. Sorry, hon. I wasjust having
some dental work done on my arm.
So, what was the— Ned!
What are you doing?
W-What do you mean?
Well, I'm no detective, Ned,
but you are hanging from the chandelier.
I just thought it might
look better somewhere...
it can't fall on us
and crush us in our sleep.
What is going on?
Hey, hon—
did you ever get the feeling
that you were being watched?
Um, yeah. Sure. I suppose.
And then you get the feeling
that maybe that thing watching you...
is, uh, a giant elephant.
Um—
And you know howyou get that weird feeling
that your world is actually a tiny speck...
and that the elephant...
that l talked about earlier...
is carrying it around on a flower...
and you realize that ifyou tell anybody,
they'd thinkyou were crazy.
But you still feel a responsibility
to keep everyone safe.
You know that feeling?
Um, you know,
I'm gonna have to say no.
Do you know that feeling?
Ah!
No.
Yawn.
Wow, I am beat.
Time to hit the hay, I guess.
Sweetheart, I know
you're under a lot ofstress.
And ifyou're seeing
elephants and flowers, then fine.
Just don't tell anyone else
that story. Okay?
And remember,
it's not the end ofthe world.
The end ofthe world?
Horton to Mayor. Horton to Mayor.
Come in, Mayor. Over.
Horton? Ohh.
I get terrible reception here.
How about this?
If I get up real close, can you read me?
Yep. Roger that.
Are we at that safe place yet?
Almost. I'm pretty sure
the worst part's over.
This is your elephant speaking.
Just sit back, enjoy the ride,
and we'll have you to Mount Nool in no time.
- No, you can't have ice cream for breakfast.
- Please!
Who's that?
Is there someone else there?
Well, that's my wife and kids.
- You have a family.
- I do indeed.
A beautiful wife, 96 daughters...
and one son.
Oh-ho-ho-ho. Busy guy.
And we all share one bathroom.
You know how that is.
Yeah. Don't I know it?
Bathroom?
- Ned?
- What?
Sweetheart, you know
you're on the roof, right?
- Please, Mom.
- What's that? No, you need to go to bed.
Daddy's having a breakdown.
Ned, what are you up to now?
I wasjust about to put the kids to bed
when I got offthe roof.
And, uh, that's—
that's what happened. Right.
- Daddy?
- Yes?
- Can I have a glass ofwater?
- Ofcourse.
- Me two!
- Me three!
- Me six!
- Me seven!
- Me 39!
- Me 28!
Okay.
- Hey,JoJo. Whoa.
- Huh?
Lotta liquid. Lotta liquid.
Just the person I wanted to see.
Yeah, I realize that we have not been
seeing eye to eye lately.
And most of it is my fault.
That's true.
You know what I've been
trying to do?
I have been trying to impose
my vision ofyour future on you.
Let me make this perfectly clear.
JoJo, you can be
whatever kind of mayoryou want to be.
Hands-on, strong and silent, outspoken—
it's up to you.
Well, good.
I feel so much better.
I am expecting big things from you,
young man. Big things!
All right. Good night.
Good stuff. Good talk.
Then JoJo snuck out, feeling lonely and sad...
and tragically misunderstood
by his dad.
And where was he going
at such a late hour?
Up to Who-ville's
abandoned star-studying tower...
a place where the boy
felt contented and free...
a place he could be
what he wanted to be.
And what was inside there,
l'd say if I could.
But up above,
the kangaroo was up to no good.
Can l come out now, Mom?
No, Rudy. Stay in your room.
- But, Mom—
- Stay inside.
Mr. Vladikoff?
Eating. Go.
Yes, I-I realize you're busy,
but I need your help.
It's Horton.
He's become obsessed
with a clover...
and he actually thinks
there are little people on it.
I want that clover destroyed.
Sure. What a big deal this is...
foryou, bro.
I'd do it myself, but, being a lady...
I prefer not to get my hands dirty.
But I hearyou have
no problem with that.
No. No problem.
Easy peasy.
But I will only do this
for a price...
in exchange
for a brand-new pair of―
No.
This...
- little kangaroo.
- Mom!
Quiet, Rudy.
Mommy's thinking it over.
Huh.
Well, thanks,
but on second thought...
I think I'm going to have the Wickersham
brothers take care ofthis for me.
Yeah, ofcourse, Wickersham.
I mean, they-they're classy operation.
They do― Wait! No!
You can't go with Wickersham!
No, no. No, no. The Wickershams
would be perfect for thisjob.
But they're monkeys!
Is not scary.
Oh, thanks anyway.
Maybe next time.
Wait. Here's what I will do
to precious clover.
I will take it, I will crush it...
and I will devour it.
Bigger than it look. One second.
Holy moly.
Hang on.
Then I regurgitate it.
Then I'm gonna devour it
second time.
So, two times devoured.
Sounds nice.
But l think I'll talk
to the Wickershams.
Wait.
Here is best part.
I do all— gratis.
That's free, bro.
What do you think?
Huh?
Deal.
Yes! Score!
Thanking you.
You won't regret.
Oop!
Whoa! Whoo!
Mayor!
Open up, Mr. Mayor!
Mr. Mayor!
It's snowing!
In the summer!
Yes. Yes, it is.
It's a dramatic change
in the weather...
as if we were a speck
floating through space.
I don't know how you knew,
but s-somehow you did.
And Who-ville is headed for disaster.
- Oh. Horton.
- What?
Uh, nothing. I'm on it.
It's up to us to save
the people ofWho-ville.
- Whoa!
You're small, but there are
a lot ofyou. Ooh!
That's―
Okay. Anybody else?
Good.
No, no. No enjoyment. This is not fun.
It is a sign ofdoom.
Ah, sweetie, that's—
No! No, no, no, no.
Danger! Danger!
- Whee!
- Whoa!
Stop having fun immediately!
This is dangerous.
Okay.
Snowbank!
- Horton!
- Huh? What?
Hey there.
We're in big trouble down here.
It's happening. It's snowing
in the middle ofsummer.
- It's the end ofthe world!
- Whee!
Hold on, Mayor.
I think I know what your problem is.
Aw!
There. That better?
That seems to have worked.
Do I smell peanuts?
Yeah. They're my favorite snack.
But they tend to linger.
Bleh!
Oh!
Finwick, no.
Uh-oh. Hang on, Mr. Mayor.
I may have to put up a fight.
A frightened elephant can be very dangerous!
All right! You've called down
the thunder, buddy!
You hungry for trouble?
I'm an all-you-can-eat salad bar. Take a bite!
I hate running.
Morton?
Don't do that.
Horton!
Horton— D'oh!
There you are.
We got trouble. Wait.
Stay, wait. Did you hear that?
No, I'm here.
Okay, listen. No. Go.
Kangaroo has gone nuts, bananas.
She's telling everyone that you
should be kicked out of Nool.
She said that?
I thought we were friends.
- Word is she's gone to Vlad.
- Vlad?
Vlad. I know two Vlads.
Is it the bad Vlad
or the bunny Vlad that makes the cookies?
Yeah, Horton, she's sending you
a bunny with cookies.
I think we can assume
it's the bad Vlad.
Yeah, that's a good call.
So unless you're cool
with giant, razor-sharp claws...
ripping the flesh offyour body...
I'd get rid ofthe clover.
I can't. I promised the mayor.
I meant what  l said,
and I said what I meant.
And an elephant's faithful 1 00%.
Please, for me,just this once...
be faithful 99% ofthe time.
I've never gotten 99% on anything.
And l think I'm awesome.
So come on.
I meant what I said,
and I said what I meant.
I'm not gonna say it.
You can do that all day.
It's not happening.
- An elephant's faithful 1 00%.
- That's right.
That's my code, my motto.
But thanks for the warning.
"Motto." Okay.
But watch the skies.
Keep watching the skies!
Mayor! You need to get
everyone underground now!
- Two, three, four.
- I don't want to sound the alarm.
But there's a good possibility...
- we may be attacked by a giant, carnivorous bird.
- What?
There's a small chance it could be a bunny
with cookies, but I wouldn't count on it.
Oh, they are formidable. Whoop.
Mayor? Are you there?
Yeah. No, that's a great idea.
It'sjust—
In order to get everyone mobilized...
I'd need the okay
ofthe city council.
And they never listen to me.
I've been called a boob—
several times.
I can't do it.
You have to talk to them, Mayor.
Okay, listen.
Bad Vlad! Bad Vlad!
Ooh! Bad Vlad!
That is definitely not a bunny.
Lost him.
Meant to lose him, and I lost him.
Heh. Yeah.
This tree for real?
Come on.
Hang on, Who-ville!
This is gonna get rough!
Oh!
Now you're going to get it!
Get ready for the best!
Leave me alone!
Hort― Ow!
Horton!
Whew!
I just know he's gonna
jump out somewhere.
- Hello.
Ooph!
"Chessmate."
Now it's time for me
to take clover...
and crush all
the little people on it.
Sorry, this is where we get off.
Right in the beak!
Cool line.
Usually I can't think
ofthose things till later.
- Mayor?
- Ah, Horton.
- Are you okay?
- Um—
Well, more or less.
- What happened? The bird?
- Yeah, it attacked me.
Mayor, your people are in danger.
Huh? You know what?
I'm gonna do it.
I am going to go out there
and tell them what is going on.
Perfect. Now, quick, get going.
Hey, Mr. Mayor! Something's wrong!
My basement is in the attic!
- The science museum is history!
- The Lost and Found is missing!
What's going on, Mr. Mayor?
I'm declaring a state ofemergency!
Don't worry! Don't worry!
The mayor is just being a moron.
No, wait! Who-ville is in terrible danger.
Everyone needs to get down
to the underground storage area immediately!
Fine! Fine.
Let's do this democratically.
Who wants thejoy and glory
and festivity ofthe Who-centennial...
to proceed as planned?
- And who, like the mayor—
- Uh—
thinks it would be better
to spend the Who-centennial...
in an underground storage area?
Yeah!
Wait! You've got to listen to me!
Our whole world could explode!
Much more quickly!
And ourworld wouldn't
make that noise.
The people have spoken, Mr. Mayor.
You're finished.
No one believes you.
No one supports you.
Horton believes me.
Horton?
Who's Horton?
Horton is a giant elephant in the sky!
- Huh?
- Don't bother looking. He's invisible.
And he's the one
risking his life to get Who-ville—
which, by the way,
is a speck on a clover― to safety!
l can prove it.
Horton's voice comes out ofthis horn.
He's lost his mind.
Horton!
I have all the Whos
gathered in Town Square.
Let them knowyou're there!
Gee.
This is kind ofa high-pressure
situation then.
l don't hear anything.
Wow. I am really drawing a blank here.
I know!
Horton.
Horton, we're waiting.
Time to show everyone
that you exist...
and, by extension,
what a non-boob I am.
Wait! Everyone, look at the wind.
What do you think that that means?
It means—
It means, obviously―
Let the kite-flying race begin!
What a burn on you, Horton!
Ooh! Brain freeze!
Give me back...
- my speck!
- Huh?
Not this time, guy.
I am so sorry that I let you down.
But this― This is bigger than me.
Get the family together
and get somewhere safe!
I will! I believe you.
I've got you now, elephant.
No! No! No!
Oh, no.
Oh!
Yeah!
Mayor?
Anybody there? Hello?
Anyone?
But clover by clover by clover, he found...
that the one that he sought for
was just not around.
Mayor?
Hello?
And by noon,
poor Horton, more dead than alive...
had picked, searched and piled up
nine thousand and five.
Hello?
Sorry to botheryou, nobody.
Knock, knock.
This is where you'd say,
"Whos there?"
If there were any Whos there.
Get it? "Whos there?"
All day he looked, looked on and on...
until his hope was almost gone.
No, no.
No! Please, no!
Oh! This isn't fair!
But wait!
Could this one be the one?
Was all his searching finally done?
Ah, yes.
For this was the hour.
Horton had found them
on the three-millionth flower.
Mayor! Mayor! I found you!
Mayor?
Are you there?
Mayor.
Mayor, are you there?
Mayor?
Mayor!
Uh, no. This is Floyd.
Can I take a message?
Mayor! You're okay!
Horton! Horton!
Stop! Stop it!
Sorry. It must've been rough down there.
l can't believe I found you.
You really had me worried.
Say! The mayor was right!
Daddy! Daddy! Daddy!
Oh! Okay, I'm all right.
- Toof!
- And so are you.
Citizens ofWho-ville!
I'd like you to meet
our friend Horton.
He's going to help us.
l've got this.
- This is the chairman.
- Idiot!
You're finished in this town.
Is that understood?
Finished! You boob!
No, I'm justjoking.
Oh.
Good one.
Horton, this is my wife, Sally.
You exist!
This means my husband isn't crazy.
Hooray!
And a few of my daughters:
- Haley, Holly, Hooly, Hilda and Hedy.
- Hi!
And here is Miss Yelp, my loyal assistant.
- And here's Dr. Larue.
- You saved us!
And Burt from Accounting.
And Mrs. McGillicuddy and Mr. Farfoogan.
- From the Clugan Farfoogans.
- Oi! Oi! Oi!
And the old man in the bathtub.
Let's not overwhelm the poor fella.
He's never gonna remember all these names.
Well, I'll try my best...
Sally, Chairman...
Haley, Hooly, Holly, Hilda, Hedy.
Miss Yelp.
Dr. Larue, Burt from Accounting,
Mrs. McGillicuddy...
Mr. Farfoogan
ofthe Clugan Farfoogans.
And wasn't there an old guy
in a shower?
- Mmm, bathtub.
- Ooh! Yeah.
We're all here, Horton.
And we all believe in you.
Wow. That's awesome.
And it's a responsibility
l do not take lightly.
l promise you a future
that is safe, sound and stable.
We will create a world where every Who
is endowed with three inalienable rights...
to be determined at a later date.
And, uh, we will, uh,
put a speck on Mount Nool...
before the end ofthis, uh, decade.
Oh!
This-This elephant is crazy!
Oh, my goodness.
I gotta tell everybody.
I need to get to the kangaroo. Whoo!
Wait till they find out about― Oh!
Oh! You should have been seeing me.
l really let elephant have it.
I chase him. I torment him.
I break him into million
little elephant pieces.
It was thing of beauty. Really.
My best work. Classic Vlad.
- And the clover?
- Clover is finished.
No way in million years
Horton find it.
Read my beak.
Clover is gone forever.
I just saw Horton,
and he is still talkin' to that clover!
ldiot!
Whoa. Come on.
I'm your bro.
It's me you are talking to.
We have history.
Come on. Let's not forget—
I did this for free.
What is happening
to theJungle of Nool?
There once was a time
when people were people...
- and specks were specks.
- Mm-hmm.
Well, I say,
ifyou can't see it, hear it or feel it...
it doesn't exist!
Our way of life is under attack.
And who's leading that attack? Horton!
Whoa!
Whoa! Whoa!
Wait a minute.
This is Horton we're talking about.
You all know him.
He wouldn't hurt a fly―
except for that fly city he sat on,
but he didn't do that on purpose.
Shut up, mouse.
Yeah. That's weird.
My brownies are burning.
I gotta go.
Are we going to let
troublemakers like Horton...
poison the minds ofour children?
Not the children!
When Horton tells the children
about worlds beyond thejungle...
he makes them question authority―
which leads to defiance,
which leads to anarchy!
Yeah! Horton must pay!
- It's that speck!
- We have to do something!
- For the children!
Are we going to let him
get away with this?
No!
Let's get him!
Hmm?
Morton?
l told you— 100%!
Horton!
Morton, pick up your feet. Geez!
It's not me!
Oh. I see. It's an angry mob.
Sorry, Morton. I thought it was you
that was making all the―
But it's― Oh, darn.
Everybody! Come on!
Run, Horton!
- There he is!
- Get the speck!
Let's rope him!
Let's cage him!
No!
Stop!
Hey, fellas. Good to see ya— all at once.
You look really great as a horde.
Horton, Horton, Horton.
Look at the mess
you've created foryourself.
All this hullabaloo
over a silly little flower.
It's a speck.
Right. I mean, it's silly, really...
all this talk of roping you
and caging you, and, well...
we don't need to go
into the details.
The point is, this angry mob,
all-all the trouble you're in—
it can all go away.
Really?
Of course.
All you have to do
is admit to everyone...
that there are no little people
living on that speck...
that you were wrong and I was right.
You do that, and things can go
right back to the way they were.
But ifyou don't...
you're going to have
to pay the price.
Heh. So l just have
to say it isn't true.
Hmm.
Go ahead— rope me, cage me.
Do whateveryou want.
But there are people
on this speck...
and they have a mayor who has 96 daughters
and one son named JoJo...
who all share a bathroom,
whatever that is.
And even though
you can't hear or see them at all...
a person's a person,
no matter how small.
Huh? Hmm?
That was beautiful, Horton.
Rope him! Cage him!
Burn that speck
in a pot of boiling Beezlenut oil!
Hmm.
They don't believe we're here.
We've got to make some noise!
We are here! We are here!
We are here!
We are here. We are here. We are here.
- We are here! We are here!
- Come on!
We are here! We are here!
- Everybody!
- We are here! We are here!
We are here! We are here!
We are here!
This will teach you not to make up stories
about people on specks!
Listen. There they are!
- Rope him!
- Cage him!
It's not working.
I can hearyou, but their ears
aren't strong enough.
We need to be louder!
Get every Who to make noise!
Everyone!
We are here!
We are here! We are here! We are here!
JoJo, where are you going?
We need every voice! JoJo!
You need to make some noise
down there...
or we'll all be destroyed!
The mayor grabbed a tom-tom
and started to smack it.
And all over Who-ville,
they whooped up a racket.
They rattled tin kettles.
They beat on brass pans.
On garbage pail tops
and old cranberry cans.
They blew on bazookas
and blasted great toots.
On clarinets, oom-pahs
and boom-pahs and flutes.
There!
We are here!
Can they hear us now?
Listen, please!
It's the most beautiful thing ever.
- I don't hear nothin'!
I don't think so.
But keep trying!
I'll never give in!
Are you sure that every Who
down in Who-ville is trying?
♪ We are here, we are here ♪
We are here! We are here!
- Where's JoJo?
- Probably at the old observatory.
♪ We are here
We are here ♪
Oh! Oh! Hey!
There's a limit!
That's not supposed to stretch that far!
Ow! Ow! Ow!
Oh.
JoJo. You built this?
Whoa-hoo-hoo!
Ooh!
We are here!
We are here! We are here!
You're making a mistake!
- But, Mom!
- This doesn't concern you, sweetie.
Back in your pouch!
♪ We are here
We are here ♪
Everybody! Don't stop!
Keep going!
This is gonna do it!
We are here! We are here!
- Can they hear?
- No!
We are here. We are here.
We are here.
No matterwhat happens,
I couldn't ask for a better son.
Hey.JoJo?
- Come on! Keep going!
- We are here!
No!
We are here! We are here!
We are here!
No!
We are here! We are here!
We are here!
Yopp!
I hear it! I hear it!
They are there!
And that "yopp"...
that one small extra "yopp"
put it over...
and all the Who noises
burst out ofthe clover.
- I hear it!
- Me too!
- So do I!
We are here!
Rudy, give me that.
Come. Ru—
Rudy, get back in the pouch. Now.
No, Mom.
Wha— Wickershams, get that clover!
Well, a-anybody, take it from him.
- Hmm?
- Oh!
You did it, Mayor. You did it.
We did it!
- Yeah!
- Whoo!
Well done, Son.
All right, Mayor!
Dad! You're one ofthe greats.
Whoa! Easy, everyone. Easy!
Oh, hi, Vlad.
Well, I shouldn't, but—
Oh, man, that is nice touch.
I am a mess with this, right?
Emotional!
Here come the waterslide!
There's so many people to thank―
the good people of Nool...
- who put me in a cage and poked me with sticks.
- That was me!
My buddy Morton, for being the only one
who stood by me. Well, not right by me.
He hid in the bushes,
sending me good thoughts. He's small.
Dude, you are a warrior poet.
And most ofall,
I'd like to thank the mayor ofWho-ville...
who believed in me
from the beginning.
Oh, Horton.
We're going to miss you.
Gee.
What are we gonna do
without you, Horton?
Aw, don't worry.
I'll always be around.
♪ And even as I wander♪
♪ l'm keeping you in sight ♪
♪ You're a candle in the window ♪
- ♪ On a cold, dark winter's night ♪
- Beautiful metaphor.
♪ And I'm getting closer♪
♪ Than I ever thought I might ♪
Whoo! That's a little high for me.
- ♪ Baby, I can't fight this ♪
- ♪ Feeling anymore ♪
♪ I've forgotten
what I started fightin' for♪
Ahh.
♪ And if I have to crawl
upon your floor ♪
♪ Come crashing
through your door♪
♪ Baby, l can't fight
this feeling anymore ♪
♪ l can't fight this feeling ♪
- ♪ Anymore ♪
- Whoo!
And so all ended well...
for both Horton and Whos...
and for all in thejungle,
even kangaroos.
So let that be a lesson
to one and to all.
A person's a person,
no matter how small.
Ahh.