Hello?
Hello.
Who's there?
This is the Mayor.
The Mayor? The Mayor!
I'm talking to the Mayor!
I knew it. I knew it. I knew it.
I knew there was life on this speck.
"This speck"? What speck?
Well, I don't exactly know
how to tell you this, but...
You're living on a speck.
Well, I hate to disagree with you,
O voice from the drainpipe,
but I live in Whoville.
Well, then, Whoville's a speck.
Right.
Okay, seriously, who is this?
Is this Burt from accounting?
No. This is Horton. I'm an elephant.
Okay, "Horton."
Fake name. Where are you?
Well, from where you're standing,
I guess I'm in the sky.
Compared to you, I'm enormous.
Which is saying something,
because I've slimmed down quite a bit.
I swim.
Your whole world fits on a flower
in my world.
Oh, man, this is even pushing it
for you, Burt.
Don't believe me? Watch what happens
when I put you in the shade.
This is absolutely impossible...
Dark.
Light.
Light. Dark, light, dark, light,
dark, light, dark.
Light!
Don't you see?
We're in the middle of some kind of
amazing cosmic convergence.
Two vastly different worlds,
miraculously crossing paths!
Mine, colossal! Yours, miniscule.
Yet somehow we've managed
to make contact.
If you think about it, it's pretty amazing.