(ROARS)
NARRATOR:
Millions of years ago,
this planet we call Earth
was quite a different
place indeed.
(RUMBLING)
The land was still forming.
Strange plants abounded.
And the world was populated
by those most remarkable
of creatures,
the dinosaurs.
Though very different
from us in many ways,
these ancient giants
resembled us
in some ways, too.
They ate.
(ROARING)
They fought.
(LAUGHING)
They played.
(YAWNING)
They slept.
And sometimes, perhaps,
they even dreamed.
(GASPS)
Huh?
(GRUNTS)
(CHUCKLES)
Whoa! Whoa!
(EXCLAIMING)
Huh?
(GASPS)
Look!
What is it?
It's incredible.
It's beautiful.
Oh, my!
It's awesome!
Oh!
(SCREAMS)
(PANTING)
(SNORING)
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
Phew! It was just
a sleep story.
(SIGHS)
(SNORING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
DUCKY:
I'm going to get you.
Yep, yep, yep.
Oh, no, you're not.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Oh!
(LAUGHING)
(CHIRPING)
Can't catch me!
I can, too!
Yep, yep, yep.
(GROANING)
(LAUGHING)
(PANTING) Or maybe not.
Huh?
Me know you no
catch me neither.
(GRUNTS)
(LAUGHING)
Then I will catch Spike.
(DUCKY LAUGHING)
Whoa!
(THUDDING)
Oh!
Ow.
Ah!
Don't even
think about it!
(GASPS)
LITTLEFOOT: Ducky!
Aha!
(LAUGHING)
I'm going to get you!
LITTLEFOOT:
Can't catch me!
DUCKY:
I'm right behind you.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
LITTLEFOOT:
I'm too fast for you.
(LAUGHING)
Hey!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(PANTING)
Tag. You are it.
Yep, yep, yep.
(GROANS)
Did you no hear?
You it!
Huh?
What part of "it"
don't you understand?
Uh, I'm sorry,
I just...
(SIGHS)
It's the great circle.
You see it every day.
Why is it suddenly
so interesting?
I don't know. I...
It looks like something
I saw in my sleep story
last night.
Sleep story?
Yep, yep, yep.
I have sleep stories
all of the time.
I love them.
I see myself floating down
wide waters covered with
good smelly flowers.
(SNIFFING)
(SIGHS)
Me have sleepy stories
about flying way up over
high hills and tall trees.
(EXCLAIMS)
Me bet me know
what Spike have
sleep stories about.
What about you, Cera?
Don't you ever have
sleep stories?
Three-horns never
have sleep stories.
They're for babies.
They're all just full
of dumb stuff that
could never happen.
Hmm. I guess
you're right.
In my sleep story
last night,
I saw you butt your head
against this tall rock,
and it split right in half.
Really? I did that?
Yeah, but like you said,
sleep stories are dumb.
Something like that
could never really
happen.
Oh, now, wait! I didn't say
everything that happens in
a sleep story is dumb.
Sure you did.
Uh-huh!
I did not!
I said some things.
But this head-butting thing,
I could do that.
LITTLEFOOT:
Sure you could.
Yeah, right.
(ALL LAUGHING)
I could, too.
There's not a rock in
the whole Great Valley
that I couldn't crack
with my head.
Oh, yeah?
Hmm. Let's see.
How about that one?
PETRIE: Yeah, that one.
(WHIMPERS)
Well?
Uh, sure.
I could do that.
No problem.
Great.
Oh, okay.
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
(THUDDING)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
I'm going home.
My head hurts.
I didn't mean to make
her hurt her head.
Me think you mainly
hurt her brag-bone.
(GROANING)
(GASPS)
Uh-oh.
What is it, Littlefoot?
What's the matter?
I... I don't know.
I just can't sleep
for some reason.
Oh, neither can I,
Littlefoot, and I
think I know why.
For some time now,
I've been feeling
restless,
as if there is some place
I need to go, but I...
I don't know where.
Me, too, Grandpa, me, too.
That's just how
I feel tonight.
I think this feeling
has something to do
with the sleep stories
I've been having.
(GASPS) You've been
having them, too?
Hmm. Grandma, too.
We've talked about it.
I think the time has come
for us to go on a journey.
A journey? When? Where?
Just you and me?
And Grandma.
And others, too, I think.
I really don't know,
but we must leave soon.
Lie back down now.
Get some rest.
We might leave tomorrow.
A journey!
(SIGHS)
What kind of journey?
You mean like a trip?
Yeah, I guess so,
sort of like
an adventure.
(GASPING)
So let me get this straight.
You've been having sleep
stories, so you're going
on an adventure,
but you don't know when,
and you don't know where,
and you don't know why.
But you'll just sort of feel
when it's time to leave
and then you and
your grandparents will
just sort of wander off.
Is that it?
Yeah.
That about sums it up.
(SCOFFS) I'm glad
three-horns don't have
adventures like that.
Hmm?
Well, me think
it sound fun.
Mmm-hmm.
What kind of adventure
do you think it will be?
I... I just don't know.
A trip down
the deepest caves?
A climb into
the highest
mountains?
A swim across
the biggest water?
* I'm going to
go adventuring
Adventuring?
* I'm going to
go adventuring
* And who knows
what I'll find?
* He's going to see
the great beyond
* Across the mud,
beyond the pond
BOTH:
* He's going to see
the great beyond
* I'd rather stay behind
Hmph!
* Will there be
ugly bugly things
* With ickly, tickly
prickly wings?
* A front that bites,
a back that stings?
(SNARLING)
* You never know
* Will there be things
with sharply teeth?
* Up above and underneath
* I'll bet it's so
* Then please don't go
* I'm going to climb
the mountain tall
* Where fires burn
and rocks can fall
* And scary things
can creep and crawl
* With one big googly eye
(SCREAMS) Stop!
* He's going to reach
the highest high where
even flyers never fly
DUCKY:
* Maybe he will
touch the sky
* Well, I won't
say goodbye
DUCKY:
* Will he cross
the big, big water
* Where it's hot
or even hotter?
* Bet he's gonna
meet a lot of
Sharpteeth there
Yeah.
* Will there be
yummy things to eat?
* Will there be things
that ouch your feet?
* Will you be brave?
* Will you be scared?
* No! I'm going
to go adventuring
ALL:
* Adventuring, adventuring
* And when I go adventuring
there'll be so much to do
ALL:
* But if you go
adventuring, adventuring
* There's just one thing
* You know what you are
going to have to do
* You're going to have to
take us all with you
(CHUCKLES)
Oh, yes, yes, yes.
Please!
Hmm!
ALL:
* We want to go
adventuring, too *
(FOOTSTEPS THUDDING)
Huh?
Littlefoot, it's time.
(GASPS)
(SQUAWKS)
(SIGHS)
Oh! Me miss
him already.
I still wonder
where he is
going to go.
Ah, who'd wanna go on an
adventure with a bunch
of Longnecks, anyway?
Me would.
Mmm-hmm.
LITTLEFOOT:
Grandma, are we there yet?
GRANDMA:
No, Littlefoot, not yet.
LITTLEFOOT:
But you do know where
we're going, right?
GRANDPA:
Not exactly, Littlefoot.
LITTLEFOOT:
Then how will you know
when we get there?
I'll just know.
(GASPS)
I'm glad we're not there yet.
I don't like this place.
What do you think,
Littlefoot? Do you like
this place any better?
(GRUNTS)
At least
there's stuff to eat.
Mmm.
Watch your step, dear.
This is deeper
than it looks.
Doesn't look
too deep to me.
Besides, there are
rocks to walk on.
Whoa! Oh!
GRANDMA:
Littlefoot, careful.
Hey, look at me!
This is fun!
GRANDMA: Careful.
Slow down, Littlefoot,
and watch where
you're stepping.
You better walk faster
if you wanna keep up
with me.
(BOTH GASP)
GRANDMA: Littlefoot!
GRANDPA:
Littlefoot, stop! No!
(GROWLING)
Ahhh!
(PANTING)
Wow!
I hate those things,
don't you?
They're so annoying
when they nibble
on your foot.
How can we thank you
for saving Littlefoot?
Littlefoot.
Is that you?
Oh, cute.
I'm Sue, and you don't
have to thank me.
It was fun.
What's the point
of having big feet
if you don't
step on bad guys
every now and then?
I... I don't wanna
be pushy or anything,
but could I tag
along with you?
I think we're headed
the same way.
We'd be honored.
Thanks.
(SNARLING)
(YAWNING)
Huh?
(YAWNS)
Oh! You've had a busy day,
haven't you?
Uh-huh.
And I bet you haven't been
sleeping too well the last
few days either, right?
How did you know?
I just figured you and
your folks were out here
for the same reason as me.
The sleep story, right?
Yeah, the one about...
The great circle.
Whoa!
I wonder if everybody
had the exact same
sleep story.
Everybody?
What do you mean?
You think there are others
who've seen that story
in their sleep?
Why not?
What makes us think
we're so special?
I'll bet Longnecks
everywhere are having
that sleep story.
And since it was the sleep
story that started us all
on this journey,
I think we're going
to meet a lot of
Longnecks on our way.
Hmm.
Of course,
always the tallest one,
story of my life.
Just once,
I'd like to meet someone
I could look up to.
You know?
Good night, Littlefoot.
Sleep well.
(SNORING)
(GROANING)
No. No!
ALL: Hurray for the Longnecks!
Long live Littlefoot! Yay!
Huh?
(ALL MURMURING)
ALL: Littlefoot! Littlefoot!
Littlefoot! Littlefoot!
Littlefoot!
Huh? Dad?
Littlefoot, Littlefoot!
No!
(SNORING)
(MOANING)
Ouch!
Shh! Come on!
Come on where?
(SOFTLY) Sorry. Where?
We are going to see just
what kind of an adventure
Littlefoot's having.
Yep, yep, yep.
Let us wake up
Spike, too!
Spike, Spike, wake up!
(GRUNTS) Spike.
Spike! Spike.
CERA:
Ducky, we don't have
all night. Let's go.
(GRUNTS)
(EXCLAIMS IMPATIENTLY)
(SQUEALS)
I do not think
he is awake yet.
Spike?
I think he bent my beak.
Psst!
Petrie, wake up!
(SNORING)
Petrie, Petrie!
Psst! Petrie!
(GROANING)
(SQUAWKS)
Nice flying.
You ready?
(SPLUTTERS)
Me always ready.
Then let's go
find Littlefoot.
What happened
to your beak?
(GASPS)
How we find them, anyway?
They long gone.
One good thing about
Longnecks, they leave
big footmarks.
Mmm-hmm.
Grandma,
in your sleep stories,
did you see scary things?
Well, dear, I saw things
I can't quite explain.
That doesn't mean
they're scary.
I also saw some
beautiful things.
It was all mixed up together.
And in the end of
each sleep story,
when I woke up,
I just had the feeling that
whatever was going to happen,
I was supposed
to be there.
Yeah, me, too.
Grandma? Whoa!
(STRAINING)
Do you think
all Longnecks got
the same feeling?
Will they all be
wherever it is
we're going?
I think so, Littlefoot.
We'll see.
But what are we
gonna see, Grandma?
I don't know, Littlefoot,
something wonderful.
Yuck! I really do not
like this place.
It is worse
than the high place
with the deep holes.
Nobody's asking you
to move here.
I do not want to
sleep here either.
(SQUAWKING)
So let us hurry
and get through it.
Huh?
You sure
this right way?
The footmarks
led us here.
Besides, you got
any better ideas?
(GROANING)
(SPLUTTERING)
Nope.
Good.
(SNARLING)
Whoa!
Ew! It's squishing
between my toes.
(GROANS)
I would not swim in that
for all the tree stars
in the world. No, no, no.
Huh?
Hey, watch it!
Well, go on.
But I'm not sure
which rock to
step on next.
This one's closer,
but it looks
sort of slippery.
That one is farther away,
so you might not make it.
You would step in
the icky goo again
and that is bad.
But if she slip on
close one, she may
be fall in all the way,
and that be worser.
Me think she can
get to farther one,
she good jumper.
I'm not saying
she is not,
but what about
if that rock is as icky
and slimy as this one?
(GASPS)
Me no think of that.
You have to think
of everything
when you are in an icky,
gooey place like this.
PETRIE:
Oh, that very good point,
but which rock next?
Hey, what if she lands
on the first rock with
her back feet?
Me think you got
something there.
Sure, and if she can...
(ROARING)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
DUCKY: What was that?
PETRIE: Me no know,
but me think
it's coming this way.
(GROWLING)
(SCREAMING)
(SNARLS)
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
Hey, Ducky was right,
that the way to do it.
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS) This stuff slimy.
(YELLING)
Uh-oh.
(YELLING) Oh!
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh!
(SPLUTTERING)
(ROARING)
(STRAINING)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
Huh?
Uh-oh.
(SCREAMS)
(YELLING)
(SIGHS WITH RELIEF)
Yes!
Uh, I meant to do that.
He will not stay
down there forever.
Me think you right.
(ALL LAUGHING)
(SNARLING)
Keep moving,
we're almost there
I can see the shore.
(PANTING)
Ha! Guess I taught
that guy not to mess
with a three-horn.
Now that we on dry land,
can we please find place
to sleep?
Like where,
for instance?
(GRUNTS) Oh!
This look good to me.
(SNORING)
Do not worry, Cera.
We will find Littlefoot
in the morning.
(TIREDLY) Yep, yep, yep.
(SNORING)
(YAWNS)
(STRETCHING)
(GASPS)
Wow! How many do you
think there are now,
Grandpa?
I've never seen
so many. Whoa!
What is it, Grandpa?
You see something,
hear something?
(GASPS)
Is it a Sharptooth?
Hush, Littlefoot.
Sue, could you?
Sure.
You wanna go for a ride?
You bet!
Careful now.
GRANDPA: Climb to the top,
Littlefoot, and look through
the gap in the tree stars.
I'm almost there, Grandpa.
I'm almost there.
(GASPS)
Well, Littlefoot?
What do you see?
Grandpa,
I think we're here.
Hmm?
(DUCKY SNORING)
Ducky, wake up!
(WHIMPERING)
(YAWNS)
It cannot be morning
already. No, no, no.
Petrie, let's go!
Get up!
(GROANING)
(YAWNS)
Me so tired.
We go so far already.
That's 'cause we're
trying to catch up
with Littlefoot.
(SIGHS)
But we do not know
if we're still going
in the right direction.
I say we go around
this big old boulder
and look for footmarks
coming up out of
the icky place.
(SIGHS)
Whatever you say.
(SPIKE SNORING)
(SIGHS) And will somebody
please wake up Spike?
Spike.
Spike!
(GROANS) Huh?
That's better.
(SNORING)
Spike, I mean it,
get up right...
(SNORING CONTINUES)
Huh?
That not Spike.
I did not know
boulders could snore.
They can't,
but Sharpteeth can!
(GRUNTS)
(SNIFFING)
(SNARLING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(ROARING)
(SCREAMING)
Quick, in there!
(ROARING)
(FOOTSTEPS THUDDING)
DUCKY: Is he gone?
PETRIE: Me don't know.
That is the last time I
trust Petrie to pick out
a boulder to sleep near.
Hey, it was dark,
okay?
(FOOTSTEPS THUDDING)
(ALL SCREAM)
(CHUCKLING)
You can come on out now,
youngsters, he's gone.
You... You sure?
Oh, yeah. Those critters
are big, but dumb.
Mmm, mmm, mmm.
You kids fooled him good.
Yeah, we sure did.
Teach him to chase us.
Hmph!
You little ones
gonna be okay
on your own?
Us? Sure.
Then I'll just be
moseying along.
Happy trails to you.
DUCKY: Goodbye.
Are we really going
to be okay?
Of course we are.
I hope.
Come on, hurry,
we're almost there.
We're almost there!
Wow!
GRANDPA:
Come on, Littlefoot.
(INDISTINCT MURMURING)
Oh! Excuse me.
My goodness.
No problem.
No problem at all,
little lady.
Little lady? (GIGGLES)
(BOTH SIGHING)
That's better.
What is this place,
Grandpa?
I don't know, Littlefoot.
It...
It looks like a big hole.
But what could make
a hole this big?
(RUMBLING)
(GASPS)
Grandpa, in my sleep story,
I saw the great circle
falling.
This must be where it...
(SNORING)
...happened.
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(EXCLAIMS)
Whoa!
(LAUGHING)
Watch where you're
going, clumsy!
You tripped me!
Did not.
Did, too!
Did not!
Not!
Too!
Oh, yeah?
Yeah!
Wanna do
something about it?
BRON: Shorty?
Shorty,
what's going on?
Ow! He stepped on
my tail, on purpose.
Who did?
Him.
Him? You mean the one
you tripped?
Yeah, he... I mean, no,
I didn't trip him.
Shorty, come on, it's me.
Now give me the truth.
Oh, okay. I tripped him.
So what do you
say now?
Sorry.
It's okay.
Shorty is a good
kid at heart.
He just likes to
get things started.
You okay?
No permanent damage?
(CHUCKLES) No, I'm fine.
Good.
Name's Bron.
What's yours?
Littlefoot.
No kidding? That's funny.
They called me Littlefoot
when I was young.
Really?
That is kind of...
GRANDPA: Littlefoot!
LITTLEFOOT:
Here I am, Grandpa.
Your Grandma and I
wondered where you
had gotten to. We, uh...
Bron?
Papa Longneck?
Uh, Littlefoot...
This is your father.
(GASPS)
Littlefoot, I...
GRANDPA: Littlefoot!
Wait, come back.
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
Hey!
MALE: Ow! Watch it!
FEMALE: Whose kid is that?
Got any suggestions?
I'm not swimming
in that fast water.
No, no, no.
Maybe I can help.
(ALL SCREAMING)
Are you following us?
(CHUCKLES)
Not hardly.
I got my own way to go.
You just seem to keep
passing across it.
Yeah, well, that's real
interesting. Bye!
You sure you couldn't
use some help now?
No, thanks, we'll be
fine on our own.
Suit yourself.
(WHISPERING)
(GASPS)
No, no, no. Not me!
Oh, come on!
Don't be babies!
If you get a good
running start,
you can jump over
that water easy.
Fine, then you go first.
Okay, then. I will.
You go any farther,
you be back in
Great Valley.
(GULPS)
Fine!
(GRUNTING)
(ALL GASPING)
(SCREAMS)
Thanks, but I could've
made it if I'd gotten
a better start.
(LAUGHING)
I never doubted it
for a minute.
I had an idea of my own
about how to get you
across the water,
if you're of a mind
to listen to it.
Mmm-hmm.
Sure, why not?
(GRUNTING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
Phew! Not as young
as I used to be.
Well, here we are
on the other side.
But is this the way
you wanted to go?
Not sure, but somehow,
it feels right.
Yeah, I guess
it is at that.
You mean, you no know
which way you go?
Not exactly.
See, I've been having
these sleep stories.
(GASPING)
You know, I think we might
be going the same way
as you after all.
Littlefoot.
Littlefoot,
we have to talk.
Where were you
all this time?
Where were you?
Oh, Littlefoot.
Your mother and I knew
we were going to have
a hatchling.
You see, we wanted to
raise you in a safe place.
So before you were
even an egg,
I went off to find
a new home for all of us.
When I got back,
the earthshakes had
changed everything.
It took me so long to find
where the nest had been,
and nothing was left
but a crack in the earth
as deep as a mountain is high.
As I searched for your mother
and the young one I knew
had been born,
the great circle rose
and fell many times,
but I couldn't find you
anywhere.
I finally met someone
who told me about...
About your mom
and a Sharptooth.
But he had no word about you,
so I kept searching.
And then one day,
I met a group of
young Longnecks
wandering in the wilderness
with no grownups
to protect them.
At first I hoped
one of them was you,
but I soon realized
that wasn't the case.
But they came to depend on me,
so I stayed with them,
took care of them.
And then some others
joined up with us.
And then some more,
and some more.
In time, we were a herd.
You mean,
you're the leader
of a whole herd?
Yeah, I guess
you could say that.
Wow.
And look at you!
You've grown up to be
a fine young Longneck.
Just like I'd hoped
you'd be. Your mom
would be proud.
She'd be proud
of you, too.
LITTLEFOOT:
* It's nice to have a dad
that you can be with
Ha!
* To share a part of
each and every day
* Who you can talk and joke
and play and eat a tree with
* Who wants to hear the
things you have to say
* Who will lift you up
when the water's too deep
(YAWNING)
* Who'll stay by your side
while you're falling asleep
* Who understands
whenever you feel sad
* It's really awfully nice
to have a dad
* Friends are important,
they're such a big part
of you
* But I always thought a dad
would be something special
* Now I know it's true
* It's great to have a dad
you can have fun with
* A dad who's got a neck
that's extra-long
* It's good to have someone
to be a son with
* Who's big and brave
and wise and kind
and strong
* He'll laugh at
the silly things you do
(BOTH LAUGHING)
* And when you're in trouble
he'll pull you through
* Even with the love
I've always had
* This is something new
I've found a dad
* My dad
* And since you came my way
I'm, oh, so glad
* And I'm proud to be your son
'cause you're my favorite one
* And only dad
* Me and my dad
* Just me and my dad
Hmph!
Huh?
Hey, Dad?
Yes, Littlefoot.
Was Shorty one of
the young ones you found
wandering in the wilderness?
Yes, he was.
Most of the others have
been adopted by grownups
in the herd, but not Shorty.
(ROARS)
LITTLEFOOT:
Hey, Shorty!
(GASPS)
(SQUEALS)
Hey, nice hit.
Ah!
You know,
anytime you wanna be
with my dad and me...
Listen, pal, I can be with
Bron anytime I want to.
You got that?
I know him
better than you do.
Well, I...
Yeah, and he
likes me better.
Oh, yeah?
Well, he's my dad.
Ow, that hurt!
Wanna do something about it?
(SIGHS)
No, thanks.
That's what I thought.
Coward! Baby! Huh?
Anyway, that's what my
sleep story was like.
Pretty mysterious.
What do you think
it means?
Don't really know.
But it put me in mind
of a story my granddaddy
used to tell me.
It seems that a long,
long time ago,
the night circle got jealous
of the great circle.
What do you mean, jealous?
Jealous why?
Oh, on account of how
the great circle is
so much brighter
and folks stay
awake for it,
but sleep while the night
circle is up there.
Things like that.
(WHIMPERING)
You better keep moving,
kids. Not safe to stand
in one place too long.
(SCREAMING)
Anyway, so the night circle
grabbed the great circle
and threw it from the sky
so it'd smash into
the world below.
(GASPS) Oh, my!
But there just so happened
to be a herd of Longnecks
standing down there,
and they stretched
their necks up
and caught the great circle
on their heads
and then shoved it right
back up into the sky.
Now, how about that?
So that's why,
to this very day,
we have such long necks,
so we can put
the great circle
back up in the sky.
Longnecks saved
the world, huh?
Well, that's the story.
Whether or not
you believe it,
it's up to you.
Ah!
Pat!
Oh!
Kids, run!
Spike, come on!
(STRAINING)
Let's get out here.
Hurry, hurry!
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTS)
That looks like
a pretty bad burn, Pat.
Would have been a lot worse
if it hadn't been for you
kids. I owe you my thanks.
(GROANING)
This'll slow me down
some, though. You'd best
be moving on without me.
If you keep heading toward
those hills, I think you'll
find your friend.
But we cannot
go without you.
No, no, no.
Me no think so neither.
Now, children,
there's no sense
in all of us missing...
Well, I don't know what.
But I got a feeling it's
going to be spectacular.
(WHISPERING)
We've talked it over
and we're not going
without you.
We'd rather just
stop right here.
Huh?
Well, what do you know?
For once in my life,
I can't think of
a word to say.
What do you think
is going to happen?
I don't know, Littlefoot.
Something wonderful.
That's just what
Grandma said.
Well, great minds
think alike.
Yeah. (CHUCKLES)
You love your grandparents,
don't you?
Well, yeah, sure.
I mean, they take
care of me.
Hmm.
Kind of like
me and my herd.
Have you thought about
what happens now, with us?
Huh?
What do you mean?
Well, now that I've
found you, I don't
want to lose you.
Oh. Yeah.
I know. Me neither.
(LAUGHS)
You don't have to
decide anything now.
Hey, how come
we haven't seen
any Sharpteeth?
Sharpteeth are cowards.
Look how many of us
there are.
A Sharptooth would never
attack a group this size.
Remember, they only hunt
in twos and threes.
(CHUCKLES)
Your friend Sue
could handle
that many herself.
LITTLEFOOT:
(CHUCKLES) Yeah.
Come on, dear, let's go
to the watering hole.
(SNORING)
Oh!
Littlefoot.
Sorry, I woke you up.
I just...
I just felt like
sleeping here tonight.
(CHUCKLING) Oh!
We missed you too,
Littlefoot.
You know, Littlefoot,
it's only natural that
you want to be with
your father right now.
Your grandma and I
love you no matter
where you are.
We just want you
to be happy.
(SIGHS HAPPILY)
(SNORING)
(YAWNS)
Huh?
(EXCLAIMING)
Shorty! Hey, Shorty!
Oh, it's you.
Yeah, it's me.
Where are you going?
What's it to you?
It's just that...
It's still kind of dark,
and you're out here all alone.
My dad probably
wouldn't like it.
Oh, right.
Like he'd care.
Now that he's found you,
he'll ignore me like
everybody else.
Shorty, you'll always
be special to Bron.
You've known him
all your life, almost.
I just met him.
I was kind of hoping...
I thought maybe we could be,
like, you know...
Like brothers.
Come on, let's go back.
Yeah!
Something's
about to happen.
I know, I can feel it.
(GRUNTS)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Petrie!
Where did you come from?
Littlefoot,
me knew that you!
Me see you from
way far, and me say,
"That Littlefoot!"
But the others,
they no believe me, so...
Others? The whole gang?
Are they here, too?
Oh, sure. All here.
Be here real soon.
(FOOTSTEPS THUDDING)
That be them now.
Huh?
(ROARING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
PETRIE: That not them!
(SCREAMING)
What are all you guys
doing here?
Running away.
(SCREAMING)
PAT: Run for it, kids,
I'll keep him busy.
(ROARING)
Hold it!
We can't leave him,
he's a friend of ours.
Good idea.
Take that!
(GRUNTS)
(GROWLING)
(GRUNTING) Yeah!
Come on!
Let's go help him.
(GRUNTING)
(ROARING)
(DISTANT SCREAMS)
Huh?
Littlefoot!
(ALL GRUNTING)
Come on, Pat, hurry!
(ALL GASP)
(ROARING)
BRON: Up here, coward!
(GASPS) Dad!
Did you say "dad"?
(SNARLING)
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
(ROARING)
Thanks, stranger.
Come on! Move along,
move along, young ones.
It's okay.
We should be safe now.
(GROWLING)
Huh?
(GASPS)
(ROARING)
(SCREAMING)
Run, kids,
get out of there!
(ROARING)
(INDISTINCT)
What is it?
What's out there?
Oh, no. There's three
Sharpteeth now.
And Littlefoot.
(SNARLING)
Oh, no!
I'm coming, Dad!
(SCREAMS)
Littlefoot, be careful!
(ROARING)
(SCREAMS)
Littlefoot! No!
(GRUNTS)
Don't go! Sharpteeth
are out there!
So is our grandson.
Littlefoot,
help your grandpa!
I can handle this one.
(GROANS)
(THUDDING)
Oh, my! After all these
years we still make
a pretty good team.
Yes, we do.
(SNARLING)
LITTLEFOOT:
Oh, no! Cera, Pat!
They need help.
(SCREAMING)
(SHORTY LAUGHS)
(GRUNTING)
(THUDDING)
Wow! That was
a great move.
You're not
so bad yourself,
for a Longneck.
Littlefoot,
are you all right?
Yeah.
You and your friends
get up to the top.
It's time.
LITTLEFOOT: Hang on, Dad,
they're coming to help us.
I do not think so.
(GASPS)
(ROARING)
PETRIE: What happening?
Where they all going?
This no look good.
(WHIMPERS)
(PANTING)
What is it?
What do they see?
I don't know.
BRON: Hurry, Littlefoot,
it's starting.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Come on, guys,
hop on!
Now don't look straight
at the great circle.
Might hurt your eyes.
BOTH: Wow!
(ROARING)
It's just like
in my sleep story.
The great circle's going dark
and then it's going to fall.
We got to catch it.
(GRUNTING)
(ROARING)
(STRAINING)
Huh?
(GASPS)
(ALL MURMURING)
MALE: It's wonderful!
Look at it.
It's beautiful.
Oh! That was incredible.
I told you it would be
something wonderful.
Dad, we did it.
We did it!
Mmm-hmm.
We all did.
I don't believe it!
Longnecks saved the world.
This is gonna kill my dad.
Well, kids,
it was a pleasure
to travel with you.
Glad we fell in together,
but I think it's about
time for me to...
Pat, wait, we, uh...
We had an idea.
Go on, you ask.
Oh, oh, okay.
Um, we thinking, maybe,
if you don't mind...
I mean, if you wanna...
Maybe...
Well, spit it out, kids,
I'm not getting any younger.
I got to be moseying on.
That's just it!
Mosey with us.
Come again?
That is the idea.
Come to the Great Valley.
There's lots of room.
And no Sharptooths
neither.
Well, I'll be.
You really think I could?
Mmm-hmm.
Sue?
Does this mean you
won't be walking
back with us?
(CHUCKLES) Yeah.
Sorry, Grandma.
Actually,
I'm not sorry at all.
(GIGGLES)
It was wonderful
to meet you, dear.
Have a lovely
journey home.
SUE: You, too. Bye!
(GRUNTS)
Doesn't it hurt?
What's the trick?
The trick is
not minding.
Wow!
(FOOTSTEPS THUDDING)
Shorty,
I'll be right back.
You don't look like
somebody who just
saved the world.
Oh, hi, guys.
Why you no happy?
It's my dad.
Uh-oh. Did you two
have a fight?
Huh? No. He's great.
That's the problem.
I just found him.
I mean, I didn't even
know I had a dad.
Now, I don't
wanna lose him.
I don't wanna leave Grandma
and Grandpa, or you guys,
but I can't give my dad up.
I just met him.
I don't know
what to do.
Well, me can't tell you
what best for you,
but we always your friends,
no matter where you go.
* Sometimes friends
have to leave
* It's very sad but true
* But this me do believe
* Friends still
a part of you
* And if you go away
* And live some other place
* I will think
of you each day
* And see your smiley face
BOTH:
* And we will always
be your friends
* No matter where you are
* Just around the bend
* Or very, very far
* Wherever you will go
* When you reach
your journey's end
* No matter what
* We'll always be
your friends
* We will always be
* Although we're far apart
* I'll see you in my dreams
* And feel you in my heart
* And we won't be surprised
* If we meet again
* And when we do
* We still will be
* Your friends
* Your very truest, bestest
* Friends
BRON: Okay, then.
Good job today,
big guy.
Thanks, Dad,
you, too.
BRON: Come on, son,
the herd's gathering.
I can't wait
to introduce you
to the herd back home.
I've always told them
I had a son somewhere.
I just can't wait
to see their...
Dad?
Yes, Son?
(SIGHS)
Can I tell you
what I've decided?
I've been thinking about
this a lot, and I really
wanna go live with you.
Well, that's great,
'cause I...
But I can't.
Huh? Littlefoot.
Grandma and Grandpa really
need me, and I need them.
And my friends.
You know,
they came all this
way just to find me.
And I'm just not ready
to leave them yet.
But Littlefoot, I...
I can't just leave
my herd.
They depend on me.
I'm their leader.
I know. For some of them,
you're even more than that.
BRON: Yes, I know.
I'm really happy
I finally found you.
And when I'm older,
we can have some more
adventures together.
Can't we?
Count on it.
Hey, who knows?
One of these days, I might
drag my whole herd over to
the Great Valley for a visit.
I love you, Son.
Me, too.
I'm ready
to go home now.
(BOTH GASPING)
Hey, Shorty,
want a lift?
Whoa! Hey!
NARRATOR: And so the great
herd of Longnecks dispersed.
Littlefoot had found
his father and had
saved the world.
GRANDPA: Come on, kids!
For Littlefoot and his
father, there would be
more adventures to come.
But for now,
he headed for home,
the Great Valley.
DUCKY: I just have
one question.
Do we have to go back
through the swamp?
* Sometimes friends
have to leave
* It's sad, but true
* But this I do believe
* They stay a part of you
* And if you go away
* To live some other place
* I will think
of you each day
* And see your smiling face
* And I will always
be your friend
* No matter where you are
* Just around the bend
* Or very, very far
* Wherever you will go
* When you reach
your journey's end
* No matter what
* I'll always be your friend
* I will always
be your friend
* Although we're far apart
* I'll see you in my dreams
* And feel you in my heart
* And though
the years may fly
* I know we'll meet again
* And when we do
* I still will be
* Your friend
* I'll always be
* Your truest
* Friend