Who's there?
I said, "Who's there?"
Oi, sir!
Sir?
Ah, dear, dear, dear.
- I have it. Take me to her.
- Yes, master.
She's been waiting.
As have I.
Hmm.
Oh, Van Helsing,
that last target was a civilian.
You know,
one of those innocents...
you Knights of the Holy Order are
sworn to protect from the dark forces.
Oh, I don't know, Carl.
I thought I detected...
a hint of demonic influence
in its beady little eyes.
Beady?
Van Helsing.
Carl.
CardinalJinette.
You are needed.
Next tableau.
And there,
the second victim.
Next tableau.
Victim three, what they
could find of her. And again.
The latest victim.
Those women died
at the hands of a monster.
But from eyewitness accounts,
one who was once a man.
Keep in mind that this man's soul
can still be saved.
Not every soul deserves to be.
Van Helsing,
since time immemorial,
the Knights of the Holy Order
have served and sacrificed...
as humanity's protectors
from an evil so ancient...
all have forgotten it
but we few.
That monster showed no mercy
to those women.
To remain true to our calling,
we must believe all souls
are worthy of salvation.
Stop him? Save him?
First someone's gotta find him.
And London's a city of almost four million
people. Shouldn't be a problem, Carl.
The murders were committed
in the same small section of the city.
And all with a surgeon's scalpel.
Now that suggests the murderer resides in the
area and is involved in the study of medicine.
Of course. A scientist. We
see this all the time. We do?
When their studies exhaust them, they're
tempted to take the easy way out...
to find whatever it is
they're looking for.
The unholy way, you mean.
Using the dark arts to change
from man to monster.
No doubt calling forth
demonic familiars to serve him.
And would you have it
any other way?
Oh, this I like.
Put her down!
Happy to oblige.
Oopsie.
It's him, I tell ya.!
He's the killer.! Get him, lads.!
Tell the hangman
Mr. Hyde says hello.
Don't let him get away!
Bloody hell! He's gone.
Like a blooming ghost.
Perfect. A monster that stops
to wipe his feet.
Clever, whoever you are,
but not clever enough.
Mum, Dr. Jekyll has arrived.
He may enter.
You're late this evening, Doctor.
We grew concerned. Your Majesty,
you should know by now...
that nothing and no one
shall ever keep me from you.
We are comforted by that.
We do look forward
to your visits.
Whatever medicinal miracle it is...
you conjure up
from your concoctions,
we feel better and better
after each of your visits.
As do I, Your Majesty.
Truly, we do not know...
what we would do without you.
Oh, my.!
Everything is so... twirly.
I'll take care of her now.
Yes, master.
After you.
Careful, Your Majesty.
I wouldn't want you to fall.
To have you so close to me,
I cannot help but recall
the first time I gazed upon you...
so many years ago.
You were the very flower
of womanhood.
Newly on the throne.
I was a mere youth.
An impoverished student
of the medical arts.
And though I was just
one of thousands in the crowd that day,
I knew you saw me too
and shared my love.
Don't fret, my dear.
You'll soon remember
everything as I do.
But I do remember... something.
I'm... I'm the queen.
And you, my brilliant doctor,
you've been treating me for that horrid
illness that makes me feel as if...
as if I were
a doddering old relic.
How better to prove
the depth of my love for you.
Now welcome, dear heart, to
what will soon be our new home...
away from prying eyes,
after our marriage,
of course.
Marriage? But am I not still ill?
You shall have your medicine
every night...
to keep you young and mine forever.
Could you stop squirming?
If you bought me the proper-sized corset,
I wouldn't have to squirm.
There. A vision of loveliness.
I told the cardinal when he got
your cable I am not a field man.
There's not much danger of you being
mistaken for any kind of man, Carl.
Oh! You put on too much powder.
And this lip rouge
with this scarf?
No real lady would be caught dead with...
Perhaps not the best choice of words.
Carl, for a friar, you know
an awful lot about lip rouge.
Anything worth doing is worth
doing well, even being demon bait.
Well, it's not as if
I could put an innocent life at risk.
What about my innocent life?
If you truly believe this is
beyond the scope of your calling...
Don't worry.
I know exactly what I'm doing.
That's what worries me.
Come on, ducky. What do ya
say? Let us buy you a pint.
Oh, I don't know.
Would you happen to be
a gentleman of medicine?
If that's your fancy, girlie,
I can play doctor
with the best of'em.
Physician, heal thyself.
Men, they're all the same.
Should we try another street corner?
Van Helsing,
where are you hiding now?
- It's about time you showed up.
- Sorry to keep you waiting, milady.
I am not a lady!
That's all right.
I'm not a gentleman.
You've only got one way
out of this.
I know.
You're no priest, man.
You don't miss much.
Ah, the fetching lady friend.
Stay there.
Don't shoot! I have no money!
I beg your pardon.
Can you guess what happens next?
This is where you get off.
Van Helsing,
how did you get here?
I, uh... I put on the brakes.
How did you get here?
Well, according to the map,
after 9:00, the Marelybone line...
Let's go see
what's left of our friend, huh?
I don't understand. How can I keep
losing the trail of something so big?
And what's this?
It's my new invention.
La santa pistola de agua.
The holy water pistol?
Mm-hmm.
I thought it might come in
handy sometime. It might.
It's as if the holy water
made contact with something...
Unholy.
Wherever he's going,
he's following this sewer line.
We've reached the end of the line.
Decaying flesh and sulfur.
This is his lair.
Exactly how do you propose we cross
that flaming moat of certain death?
The same way
Hyde must have.
Those stepping stones.
I'll go first, shall I?
I could have been a Franciscan,
but, no!
I had to travel. See the world.
Well done.
Carl, look out!
Elizabethan. Sixteenth century.
I know those uniforms.
- They're beefeaters.
Of the dead!
Carl, in our line of work,
there's dead...
and there's dead.
All right, that's settled.
They're really dead.
Van Helsing!
Get up the stairs.
What?
Carl, the pistola.!
Of course.
That'll work.
Van Helsing, listen.
I'm truly sorry...
for calling you an arrogant,
reckless popinjay.
You never called me
an arrogant, reckless popinjay.
Well, not to your face.
Dr. Jekyll, are you there?
Who are you?
Gabriel Van Helsing, miss.
And I'm...
You should not be here,
Mr. Van Helsing.
Hmph.
Well, don't mind me.
I'm not certain
you should be here, miss.
Very humorous, sir.
But you please me.
So you may address me as mum.
All right, mum.
Who's Dr. Jekyll?
My physician. I've been very ill.
Ill? With what?
You look fine to me.
I'm... not sure.
Well, that's something we can talk about
later. Right now, you have to leave this place.
- Are you giving me an order?
- Pretty much.
Sir, since it is obvious
you do not recognize me,
I am Alexandrina Victoria Wettin,
by the grace of God of the United
Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland,
queen, defender of the faith.
Queen Victoria?
Seriously?
Carl, meet Queen Victoria.
Van Helsing, Queen Victoria
is a worthy matron of a certain age.
And this is an unholy lair where all
manner of enchantment is possible.
Whatever are you two
speaking about?
We know we're looking
for someone trained in medicine.
So why not consider the doctor
who's been treating the queen?
- The royal physician?
- His name is Dr. Jekyll. And we are to be married.
When?
Tonight.
And once we are wed,
he can give me my medicine every night.
So I shan't ever be ill again.
It fits, Carl!
A man of medicine
in love with the queen...
driven to restore her youth
looking for the easy way.
If Dr. Jekyll has concocted a potion that uses the life
he stole from his victims to give youth to Victoria...
Then if they marry,
these murders will never stop.
I have no idea
what you're prattling on about.
What murders? Why would I
need someone to give me youth?
- I'm only 20 years old!
- Your Majesty, you're 70.
And you were married
for... for decades.
You also have nine offspring,
all grown,
and more grandchildren
than any man can count.
I think you and your friend
should see a doctor of your own, or...
Dr. Jekyll.!
Stand back, Victoria.
I'll save you.
Come, Victoria.
Where?
Where we can be safe together.
I admit,
I don't have much experience,
But this is not going well, is it?
That way!
A dumbwaiter shaft?
How are we supposed to use it without
someone up there to pull the rope?
Fly?
Good idea.
Carl, grab hold!
Of what?
That worked.
Oh, maybe for you.
Please, Doctor.! You must explain.!
Oh, my goodness!
This is Buckingham Palace
and that's the Golden Jubilee balloon.
Your Majesty! Victoria, stop!
You're in danger!
Wait, Doctor!
They said the strangest things...
about you and me.
Lies! All lies!
Into the basket with her.
Cut the rope!
Don't wait for me!
We are carrying extra weight!
Whoever that meddler is, I
won't let him take you from me.!
- I won't!
- Doctor, what are you doing?
You're safe now.
Why are you doing this?
For your... love.
No! He'll never take you!
Not from me!
- Victoria.
- Forgive me, my love.
- I have no other way
to keep you with me.
Stay behind me.
- Who are you?
- What you fear most.
You had your chance.
I'm not here to kill you.
I'm here to save you.
- Too late.
- Good.
No.!
Victoria!
Ah, damn you!
Van Helsing, I can't!
Just lie back, close your eyes
and think of England.
Well, that wasn't so bad.
I agree. It was awful.
Your Majesty,
as I understand such things,
the light of day will lift
the enchantment and restore you.
So I will bid you farewell.
But wait.
There's so much more...
I mean, I...
I must reward you.
That's really not necessary.
A vow of poverty and all that.
Not all rewards
must be material.
For your reward, you may kiss
your queen... on the royal cheek.
I would be honored, mum.
Huh? Hmm.
Psst!
Psst.!
We are not amused!
Guards.!
Oh, dear. Let's go, Carl!
Guards! Guards!
You'll need to report to the
cardinal in person. What do I say?
This isn't over.
Hyah!