I really like this thing.
All right then.
Why don't we have some tea?
Ponyo, will you
hold the light for me?
- Coming!
- Let's see if the water is working.
- It's working!
- It worked!
It's because we have
our own water tank up on the hill.
And who thinks the stove will light?
And light! All right.
- All right!
- We have our own propane tank.
- Please have a seat at the table.
- OK!
Ponyo, over here.
This is what you do.
Now, put your stuff down.
- You need to use your hands.
- No, I'll use feet!
Look at that!
What is it?
Look at her feet.
They're just like hands.
Here you go.
Here.
Thank you for the tea!
Ah, that was delicious.
So, what shall we do next?
- Ponyo wants ham!
- All she thinks about is ham, Lisa.
I better make some dinner then.
But, first,
we should start the generator.
We generate power
to talk to Koichi on the radio.
Koichi is my dad.
- Is he an evil wizard?
- No, of course not.
He's the captain of the ship
called Koganei Maru.
What about your dad, Ponyo?
His name is Fujimoto.
He keeps me in a bubble!
- What?
- So I ran away.
What about your mom, then?
I love my mom very much!
- But she can be very scary.
- Just like my mom.
Ponyo, over here, please.
I wonder if the fuel has gone bad.
- Maybe it's clogged.
- It's clogged.
It's clogged over there.