A long time ago,
at least 3500 million years ago,
the earliest form of life made
its first appearance on Earth.
These single-celled creatures
developed and grew,
and changed a
million times over.
Until, at last, there was a
creature able to leave the sea,
and to crawl out
into an unknown world.
From this small,
fish-like creature
came hundreds of other animals.
The mightiest of
which was called...
The dinosaur!
For most of the
Earth's dinosaurs,
life was filled with danger.
But for the fortunate leaf-eating
dinosaurs of the Great Valley,
life was peaceful,
and food plentiful.
The Great Valley was
the perfect place for children
like Littlefoot, the long
neck, Cera, the three-horn,
Ducky, the swimmer,
Petrie, the flyer,
and Spike, the spike-tail,
to grow and learn
and play.
I got it!
Now me got it!
Ow! Oof!
Go, Spike!
Oh!
Did you get it, Spike?
Did you, huh?
Yep, yep, yep!
You got it!
I found another one!
Hi, Hyp. Can we have
our rock back, please?
Your rock? Who said
it was your rock?
Yeah, who said it was your rock, huh?
Who said? Who said?
Oh, uh, yeah!
Well, gee, no one.
We were just playing with it.
So give it back, Hyp!
But I didn't
hear you say please!
That's because I didn't!
Hey! Maybe we
can all play, together!
Good idea, Littlefoot,
we all play!
Yep, yep, yep!
The more the betterer!
What do ya think, guys?
Wanna play with these...
Babies?
Who's he calling babies?
Us?
Me no baby!
Me big!
Yeah, big baby.
Me no like them.
Me neither, I'll show 'em!
Cera!
I'm busy!
Try and get us!
Yeah, try!
Whoa, what's that?
It's a...
Earthshake!
Rocks fly?
Flying rocks!
Daddy!
Mama!
Grandma! Grandpa!
Fly, children! Fly!
Run!
Littlefoot!
Look out!
Littlefoot...
I'm in here, Grandma.
Are you all right, little one?
Would you like to come out now?
Gee. That wasn't a regular
kind of earthshake, was it?
No, Littlefoot, it wasn't.
Then what kind was it?
We don't know, Littlefoot.
Perhaps it had to do with those
great rocks falling from the sky.
Oh, yeah! I saw 'em!
And I saw that big one land
somewhere in the Mysterious Beyond!
I sure wish we could go find it!
Yes, that would be an
adventure now, wouldn't it?
Well I think we've had enough
adventure for one day.
Come. It's time to settle
down for the night.
It's beautiful,
isn't it, Grandpa?
Oh, yes, Littlefoot,
beautiful and mysterious,
as is so much in our world.
Well, at least
the danger has passed.
Huh?
What? Look,
everyone! Where did the water go?
It stopped flowing!
How can that be?
What will we do without water?
Grandpa? Why did the
Thundering Falls stop?
I don't know,
Littlefoot, I don't know.
Littlefoot, go and play.
Grandpa and I must talk
with the other grown-ups.
Sure, Grandma!
See ya later, Grandpa!
This has never happened before!
Hey, guys!
Guess what happened
to the Thundering Falls?
Shhh! We are trying
to find Cera.
She has hided from us.
But...
Uh! Me no find
Cera anywhere!
Guess what, Petrie?
What? You no
find Cera either?
Cera is a very good
hider, she is!
Boo!
I scared you,
I scared you! I did!
You no scare me, Cera.
Me un-scareable!
Petrie? You're
hurting my nose.
Oh, sorry.
Me no know my own strength.
Now who's going to hide?
Littlefoot?
Okay, but first I wanna
tell you something!
Well, hurry it up,
we wanna play!
I saw...
Uh... Hey!
Spike is taking your
turn for you, Littlefoot.
My brother is not
a very good hider, oh no.
Now just what were you
going to say, Littlefoot?
It's the Thundering Falls!
It's not giving us any water!
You gotta come see!
Why don't you hatchlings
go run and see?
Yeah! Run and see!
Run and see!
Oh...
Uhh, yeah!
Try and make us!
No, Cera, no!
Oh, don't worry,
I won't hurt 'em...
Much!
Nyah!
Put those away.
How come all you ever
wanna do is fight, Hyp?
Yeah, fight!
Ow! Fighting hurt.
Yeah, it does
give ya ow-ees, Hyp.
Why do we do it?
Why?
Because we're bigger!
And bigger is smarter!
Bigger is meaner!
And bigger is better.
When you're big You can push
All the little ones around
They're looking up
While you are looking down
You can snap a tree in two
Like it was just a twig
Things are better
When you're big
You can do
Anything you want to do
All the rules that
grown-ups make
They don't apply to you
Not to you You can
splash in all the puddles
Gulp and slurp and swig
Ooh, ah!
The world is wetter
When you're big
Glug, glug, glug
You can snort You can snort
You can growl You can growl
You can stomp You can stomp
You can howl You can howl
You can bonk someone
smaller on the head
On the head
You can take La, la, la, la
What you want La, la, la, la
Play all day in the swamp...
La, la, la, la, la, la, la, la
And you never, ever
Have to go to bed
When you're big You can step
On little people's toes
Oh, yeah Munch on their lunch
Lunch!
And bop them in the nose
Oh, yeah
Three-horns and long necks
And Duck Feet too Duck Feet too
They all have to do
Anything you want them to
You want them to
And if they don't You can
plop them in the goo
Don't you forget
What you want, you get
Things are better when you're
big Sha, la, la, la, la, la...
Ooh...
When you're big
Sha, la, la, la, la,
la, la, la, la, la, ooh...
When you're big Sha, la,
la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la
When you're big
But Hyp, when you're all grown up,
you won't be very big at all.
Yeah! Your kind
never gets very big.
When we grow up,
we'll be much bigger!
Uh-huh, uh-huh, much,
much, much, much bigger!
Oh yeah? Well, I'm gonna see
to it that you never grow up!
Uh, yeah!
Never grow up, never!
Uh, how are ya
gonna do that, Hyp?
Sheesh, you're dumb!
Lemme lay it out for you.
First we chase 'em,
second, we catch 'em!
Third, we hurt 'em! See?
Uh, no, Hyp, I don't see.
Anybody.
Me neither.
What?
C'mon! Pound 'em later!
As you all can see, our
Valley is quickly drying up.
Yes, we see it
and feel it as well!
There is less and less
water to drink!
And green food to eat!
I know. That is why our
herds must work together,
to save the little water
we have left.
From now on, we must drink
only what we need to survive,
and no more.
Hopefully, soon the Thundering
Falls will bring us water again.
If not,
we may have to
leave the Great Valley.
Leave the Great Valley?
Never! It's our home!
Then, until the water returns,
we must not use the water
we have left unwisely.
Three-horns never
use water unwisely,
but your herds do!
Our herds? What makes you think
our herds would do such a thing?
You drink greedily with
no concern for others!
Can you believe
he's saying that?
Well I've seen
three-horns waste!
What?
You take long baths even if
you're the least bit dirty!
And, I've seen kind waste too!
Splashing water
needlessly. For shame!
Impossible! I never did
such a thing!
Hey! Let's play bullies.
I'll be Hyp!
I'm gonna get you!
Not if I get you first!
Me wanna play bullies too!
Hey, hatchling!
You no eat my green food!
Humph! Me go play
bullies someplace else!
Oh!
Petrie, you are flyer,
not a swimmer!
Me no bully either.
But I am!
Aww!
Not again!
Oh, no, no, no, no, no!
It them!
Thought you hatchlings could
play in our swimming hole, huh?
They're beginning
to get on my nerves.
Can we teach 'em a lesson, Hyp, huh?
Can we, huh?
Be my guest, Nod!
Run!
Ugh!
See ya! Wouldn't wanna be ya!
This is not funny!
Now, someone splashed me,
and wasted precious water!
Huh? Littlefoot!
Are you all right?
Uh-huh,
but I think I'm in trouble.
Your Littlefoot is
guilty of wasting water!
What happened, Littlefoot?
It was an accident,
Grandpa, honest.
I'm sure it was, Littlefoot.
Our children don't understand
the water problem.
The Great Valley has always given
them everything they need.
What are those grown-ups
talking about?
What water problem?
Isn't the Thundering
Falls coming back?
I don't know.
Well it should!
Why wouldn't it?
Maybe it is tired
and needs to rest.
We need to teach our
children how to use
the remaining water wisely.
Speak for yourself, long neck!
My Cera would never waste!
Your Littlefoot
is a bad influence!
That's not true!
What is in-flu-ence?
Me no know.
Come, Cera. You're not to play
with the little long neck anymore.
But, Daddy!
My friend, I think
you're acting rashly.
Littlefoot is not to blame.
I said come, Cera!
No!
Cera!
I'm your father and I
know what's best for you!
Petrie?
It's time to go home!
Oh... Bye, bye.
Coming, mamma!
Come, Ducky!
Spike, you too.
Do not worry, Littlefoot.
You are not
an in-flu-ence,
whatever that is.
I don't understand, Grandpa.
Why does Cera's dad
think I'm bad?
Oh, he's just
confused, Littlefoot.
Sometimes fear makes
grown-ups do strange things.
I don't understand, Daddy!
You need friends
who know how to behave!
Especially in times like this.
Littlefoot is my friend!
He'll always be my friend!
Cera, I'm your father.
I want what's best for you.
No you don't! You just don't
want me to have any fun!
Cera, please.
I'm just trying to...
Oh, as a parent I...
Ugh!
Time to wake up, my little one.
But Grandma, it's early,
and I'm still sleepy.
You must get up, Littlefoot,
if you want to drink
the morning dew with us.
The morning dew?
Yes, it collects on the
leaves in the early morning.
If we hurry,
we can drink the dew
before the Bright Circle gets too
high in the sky and dries it all up.
Oh, all right.
Here, Littlefoot, drink this.
I think you'll
find it delicious.
Oops. It... It broke.
It's not your fault, Littlefoot.
The treestars are very dry now,
and crumble easily.
But when will everything be
green and wet again, Grandma?
I don't know, I hope soon.
Well, what's going to
happen if it's not soon?
Water will get harder
and harder to find.
Soon, everything will be
as dry as that treestar.
And it will be easier
for fires to start.
Fire?
Yes, Littlefoot,
which is why you must remember the
escape paths we've shown you.
Don't worry, Grandma,
I'll remember!
I think we're in luck!
There's still quite a few
green treestars left here.
Come on, then, let's eat.
Yeah, let's eat!
These don't look too good,
but I sure am hungry.
They taste terrible!
Here, Littlefoot, try these.
They're still very green.
Thanks, Grandpa!
Go on, Littlefoot, eat up.
But... What about you?
Don't you want some?
Thank you, Littlefoot, but
Grandpa and I will be fine.
Yes, you're still growing.
You need the very best
green food we can find.
Well... Okay.
That was good!
But I sure am thirsty.
When is it our turn for water?
Our turn for water is when the bright
circle touches the smoking mountain.
But if you are thirsty...
I think you can
have a drink now.
After all, we never agreed
that the children
should have the same water
restrictions as the elders.
Oh, boy! Water!
It's not your time
to drink, long necks!
What do you mean,
"Not our time"?
We agreed that all herds must take
turns drinking at the watering hole.
Yes, we all agreed, but I didn't
think that it included the children!
It really isn't fair to them.
There is no fair when
it comes to survival!
When life is tough
You've gotta be tougher
If you want to stay alive
When the trail gets rough
You've gotta get rougher
To help your family survive
You can't run around in circles
Wondering what to do
Someone's gotta be
The voice of reason
Is it you, or you, or you?
When things around us
are going bad
We all better be strong
We could lose everything we have
If this goes on too long
Don't stand around here talking
I say "That's not enough!"
No tears, no sighs
Don't close your eyes
We've gotta stand tough
I used to hear my father say
"Stand and fight Don't run away"
He made me what I am today
I'm here
And I'm tough
When times are hard
You better be harder
You don't know what's in store
You think you're smart?
You've gotta be smarter
Than you ever were before
You say I'm mean
You say "Why bother?"
Well, I have a daughter
And I'm her father
I'm gonna make sure
We all have water enough
That's why I'm tough
I'm standing tough
We've got to stand tough
You don't like it?
Tough.
Littlefoot!
Huh?
Over here!
Hurry!
You judge us wrongly,
three-horn!
I'm only doing
what needs to be done!
But this is going too far.
Oh, what are we going to do about
the grown-ups, Littlefoot?
They're acting like babies!
I know.
And it's all the Thundering
Falls' fault too!
If we had more water, this
wouldn't be happening!
That's it, Cera!
What's it?
Water!
If we find some, the grown-ups
will stop being mad!
Maybe, except for my dad.
He's always mad.
Yeah, he is kinda grumpy.
But I'm sure it's just because
he's so worried about the water!
Yeah. Anyway,
let's go get Petrie, Ducky and
Spike and find some water!
How about a compromise?
No! We must be firm!
Can't we agree on anything?
Are we all here?
Yep, yep, yep, we are all here!
Oh, no, we are not.
Where is Spike?
Well, don't ask me,
he's not my brother!
Oh, Spike! Where are
you, little brother!
What that?
It sound like monster!
Do not worry, Petrie,
that is not a monster,
that is Spike!
Spike?
That is his sleeping sound.
Come on, I will show you.
See!
You're right, Ducky!
Get up, silly!
This is not nap time,
this is get up time!
You wake up now, okay, Spike?
Oh, Spike up!
Ugh! Spike down.
Spike, no!
Ow!
Are you okay, Petrie?
Uh-huh.
Spike sure heavy sleeper.
We gotta wake him up because it's gonna
take all of us to find more water.
Water? Yes,
me help find water!
Spike, stop!
Me no find water yet!
Don't worry, Spike.
We'll find it. I just know we will.
We'd better! Because if our
parents stay mad any longer,
I'm just going to scream!
Oh, I will scream too!
Petrie good screamer!
Ahhh! Ahhh! Ahhh!
What about you, Spike?
How we find water, Littlefoot?
We smell for it, silly.
Oh, yes!
Smell for it!
With our noses!
I know how to do that.
No smell so hard, okay, Spike?
This is serious, Ducky!
Oh yes, Cera, I know!
I know!
It's not your turn!
Now, go on!
Hmph!
My sniffer is very,
very sniffed out.
Well I'm so thirsty
I could drink a lake.
Me too.
If we could find one.
Funny, me smell water
but me no see water.
Did you hear a splash?
Uh-huh!
Water!
All right, water!
Woo-hoo! Yippee!
Mmm.
Mmm!
That was so good!
Oh yes! This is the
yummiest water ever! It is!
And we drink all we want
and no one yell at us!
Ah!
There they are. And would ya
look at what they found for us.
Yeah. What is it?
Hi ya, hatchlings.
Huh?
Say bye, bye water.
Why?
Is it going somewhere?
No, but you are!
This is our water now!
So give it back!
Give back? But it
already in my tummy!
But do you not want to share?
We don't share with anybody.
Do we?
Uh, no. Na-uh!
Nobody!
So I'm warning you, small fries!
If you tell anybody else
about this water,
you'll be very, very, sorry!
We're telling! And you
better not try and stop us!
Ahhh!
Hurry!
Get 'em!
We can't let 'em tell!
What am I running for?
I'm not of afraid of those...
Hey!
What's the big idea?
No time to fight bullies, Cera!
We go tell grown-ups
about water!
Where'd they go, Hyp?
Huh?
Where'd they go?
If I knew, I
wouldn't be looking for 'em!
Yeah!
Dummy!
Uh-oh!
Ahhh!
Keep running!
Are they still after us?
Me no know! Me too
scared to look!
Spike! You are going
the wrong way!
Whoa!
Hooray! Now you are
going the right way!
Why are we going this
way anyway, Littlefoot?
We're tired and this
way is hard!
Because! This is the shortest
way back to the grownups!
And it'll be harder for
the bullies to follow us!
Ahhh!
It is the Mysterious Beyond.
And it have water.
Whole bunches!
The flying rocks musta caused slides
in the Mysterious Beyond, too.
Yeah, and those dumb slides
blocked up our water!
C'mon! The grown-ups
will know what to do!
Whoa!
Bad weather for flying.
Look out!
Back this way!
I know another path!
Ahhh!
That's enough!
You've had your share for today!
The Three-horn is getting
far too bossy. I agree.
Grandpa! Grandma!
Daddy!
Fire! There's fire
in the Valley!
Are you sure, Littlefoot?
Yes, Grandpa! It's
near Two Boulder Pass!
Yes, we can see the
fire signs from here!
Two Boulder Pass?
That's close to here!
We must run!
Calm yourselves! We will
lead you to safety!
No, I will! They'll be
better off following me!
This way!
Hmph!
But you're heading downwind where
the fire will surely spread!
We must go upwind of the fire!
Do as you will, long neck! But Cera
and I go this way! Come, Cera!
But Daddy!
The others can do
what they want!
But you are my daughter
and you will do as I say!
I'm... I'm...
I'm going with my father.
I do not feel good about this.
Oh no, I do not.
Grandma! Grandpa!
Can't you stop them?
I have to go after them.
Yes.
Littlefoot, you come with me.
We'll lead the others to safety.
But what about everybody
else in the Valley, Grandma?
What will happen to them?
They'll use the escape routes
closest to them. Now come!
Everyone follow me!
Children first!
Ahhh!
Cera!
Grandma!
What's wrong?
The smoke is too thick!
You'll have to lead!
But, I...
Follow me, everyone!
I can't see!
Littlefoot, the grown-ups cannot see good.
They cannot.
But they can hear.
Follow my voice!
And stay close to the
one in front of you.
Keep your heads down.
It's not much further!
Are you sure
this is right, Daddy?
Of course, I'm sure!
Ahhh! Daddy!
This way, Cera!
Ahhh!
No!
We're trapped!
Three-horns!
Over here!
Hurry, Cera!
Are you all right, Cera?
Yes, Daddy.
Come.
Grandpa!
Oh, they made it!
I was so worried!
I'm fine, dear, really.
How is everyone else?
Our group got here safely.
Thanks to Littlefoot.
Oh, yes! Thanks to Littlefoot!
We are all very lucky.
Lucky?
How can you say we are lucky
when our Valley burns?
We are without water and
now we are without a home.
All is lost.
All is not lost, my friend.
You still have Cera. And you are
still here, able to care for her.
Oh, you are right.
Thank you, long neck.
But the three-horn
speaks the truth!
We're doomed!
We'll never be able to go
back to the Great Valley!
Never go back to the Great Valley?
Oh, no!
The water!
We forgot to tell
them about the water!
Grandma! Grandpa!
We found water!
Water?
Where, Littlefoot?
It's stuck!
Behind the Thundering Falls!
The flying rocks did it.
They did!
Which means...
The water is trapped in
the Mysterious Beyond.
The Mysterious Beyond?
We can't go there!
It's dangerous!
Of course, it's dangerous!
But no place is safe now! We
must go and free the water!
But such a huge
gathering place of water
will attract other creatures
besides ourselves.
In the Mysterious Beyond
there will be sharpteeth.
Sharpteeth!
I do not like sharpteeth.
Oh, no.
Their teeth are too sharp.
Still, we must do something.
We must come up with a
plan to free the water.
I have a plan!
I hope it's better than
your fire escape plan!
Please! This is
no time to argue.
At least I had a plan!
Stop! You're acting
like children!
Huh! We
no act like that!
I have a plan, too.
1 Mine's better!
2 Listen to mine!
I'd sure like to get
to that water first!
Before the rest of those
dummies go slobbering in it.
But you heard
the grown-ups, Hyp.
What about sharpteeth?
What about 'em?
Well...
You tell him, Mutt!
Huh, well...
Well, uh... they're bad.
Uh, yeah!
And scary too!
Come on, you're just
afraid of 'em as we are!
Me? I'm not afraid of anything!
Bet you are!
Bet I'm not!
You were afraid of those
big flying rocks!
I was not! I just ran
cuz you guys did.
I didn't
want you to feel stupid!
Well, then.
Prove it!
All right, I will. I'm
getting me some tasty water!
And you babies can stay here!
Well, I'm not a baby!
Yeah.
Me neither.
Uh, Hyp!
Wait!
Ah, yeah!
For us!
1 We must act now!
2 We must not act rashly.
They are so dumb!
Didn't they hear what the
grown-ups said about sharpteeth?
I guess not.
Well, if they get eaten
it'll just serve them right!
Cera!
That is not nice!
I don't care.
They deserve it!
Uh, I don't know you guys.
Maybe we should do something.
Like what?
Like...
Tell their parents
where they went?
All of our parents
are too busy arguing!
Your plan is too dangerous!
1 Yours is no better!
2 Then listen to mine!
Yours? Don't be silly!
Then... Maybe we
should go stop them.
Us?
Stop them?
They hate us!
They will not listen!
I know, they're bigger.
But, definitely not smarter.
Still, we have to try!
But why?
They have feelings
just like we do
They have problems too
We think because
they're big they don't
But they do
They're louder
and they're stronger
And they make a bigger fuss
But way down deep inside I think
They're kids like us
They have parents just like ours
Who tell them what to do
They have feet
and tails and horns
And scale and noses too
And when the earth is shaking
They run and hide because
Even if they think they're tough
They're still kids like us
It's just too
dangerous, Littlefoot.
Yes, it is.
And they're too mean.
Very, very mean.
Maybe when you're bigger
You think you should pretend
You're not afraid
of scary things
That you don't need a friend
But they're just kids in trouble
They need someone to trust
If we can bring them home
Show them they're not alone
That they're just kids
Kids like us
I just have to try
and stop them.
You guys do what you want.
Last one after Littlefoot
is a scaredy-egg!
Me no scaredy-egg.
Wait for us! We are not
scaredy-eggs either!
Are ya sure this is the right
way to the water, Hyp?
Sure, I'm sure!
I'm, uh, just taking
us this special way
so we don't run
into any stupid sharpteeth.
Wait for me!
C'mon, guys!
Wait!
Ah-Ah-Ahhh!
Stop whining, Mutt!
This is easy!
Uh...
Well whaddya know!
A little watering hole.
Just for me!
Ow!
You guys can have some.
If I leave any!
Woo-hoo!
Water!
Huh?
I'm sinking!
Don't just stand there!
Pull me out!
Oh, yeah! Uh, right!
Whadda we do?
I dunno. Whaddya
think we should do?
Somebody do something!
Help!
That's Hyp!
Get me out!
You pull him out!
But what if I get stuck?
Then I'll pull you out!
But what if you get stuck?
He's stuck in a tar pit!
Stop moving, Hyp!
It'll only make you sink faster!
We'll have to pull him out!
Everybody line up!
Okay! When me say 'Pull.' Pull!
Hey! You're squishing me! Sorry.
Ya-ha!
Petrie!
Pull!
Are ya, are ya okay, Hyp?
Are ya?
Of course I'm okay!
I was never not okay!
He a big, fat, fibber!
Yeah! We helped you
and you know it!
I don't need anybody's help!
Not now, not ever!
DUCKY But everyone needs
help some time. They do!
Ha!
Ahhh!
Help!
There they are!
Littlefoot?
This is no time to go exploring!
Didn't you realize you wandered
into the Mysterious Beyond?
We weren't exploring, Grandpa.
We were trying to stop the bullies,
um, I mean Hyp and his friends,
or they mighta gotten hurt!
Hyp! Here we are
chasing after you
when we should be finding
a way to free the water!
I thought I told you to
stay where it was safe!
Don't look at me that way!
I'm your father and I
know what's best for you!
Yelling is no way to teach
your child what is right.
Or to show that you care.
How would you know?
I know because...
Because I have a daughter.
And I yell at her, too much.
Especially when I'm
worried for her safety.
You don't have to worry
about me, Daddy.
If you always react with anger,
that's all your son will know.
And, that's all he'll be
able to express to others.
What?
I know now that we can't
live together that way.
With such anger between us.
Our kids found water because
they worked together.
Now we must work together too.
At last, we all agree.
Oh! What's the matter with you?
Nothin', except
I think we're in trouble.
Yeah, so what else is new?
That!
And that!
Children!
Stay behind me!
And me!
Come at us in two!
Littlefoot! You and your
friends run to safety!
Through here, kids!
Follow me!
Grandpa!
Don't look back!
C'mon!
We can't let them pass!
They've gone after the children!
Stay close! We're
going to get help!
Stop where you are, sharpteeth!
They're leaving!
Yes, but why?
Something bad
is happening up there!
Ahhh!
Stop you babies!
Me first!
Hyp!
Look!
Oh, no!
Daddy!
Grandpa!
You kids get to the top of
that dam where it's safer!
But what about
the grown-ups?
Just get outta here!
I'll handle this!
C'mon!
Look at your
dad risking his neck.
Yeah, what a dope.
He is not!
Dad!
Nyah! Nyah!
Can't get me!
Son!
Waa!
The grown-ups
are all right!
I'm outta here!
That serves sharp tooth right!
He bigger bully than you!
Hey, watch it!
Come on. Let's get
him with more rocks.
Are you nuts?
By the time you budge
that those sharpteeth
will be picking their
teeth with our bones!
We've gotta try!
Move over, hatchlings!
This isn't gonna work.
Hyp!
Oh, forget him,
Littlefoot. He's a creep.
Who're you calling names?
Now, get in there and help!
You creeps.
Okay everybody.
Let's get 'em!
Yeah! Woo-hoo!
We did it!
Leave our children alone!
We've got to stop the fighting!
Then let's squish those
sharpteeth, once and for all!
Ugh!
Huh?
Look, water!
We unlocked the water!
Run!
Looks like you and your friends
saved the day, Littlefoot.
I think we all did, Grandpa.
Spike likes you now.
He does.
And so, with
the return of the water,
the Great Valley dinosaurs
were able to go home again.
But the home they returned
to wasn't the same.
Fire had destroyed
much of their green food.
But instead of giving
in to despair,
the dinosaurs divided into groups to find
the spots where green food still grew.
Hey, everybody!
We found more!
Did you hear that?
More green food!
How wonderful!
Where?
I mean... Where, son?
In a little canyon
not far from here, Pop!
If we share there should
be enough for everyone!
You feeling okay, Hyp?
You're talking about sharing!
Ah, yeah!
Sharing!
I know that!
Not sharing is for scaredy-eggs!
Right?
Right!
Sharing is good!
Yep, yep, yep!
C'mon!
Everybody follow us!
And so, as it turned out,
the dinosaurs traveled from
green spot to green spot,
eating their fill.
Each helping the others
to find what they needed.
Each learning
the special kind of joy
which comes from
giving to others.
And, in the years to come.
This story of sharing
was told over and over again.
Until it became known as...
The Time of the Great Giving.