September 21, 1945. That was the night I died.
Damn tramps.
Watch it!
- Disgusting!
- Is he dead?
The Americans'll be arriving any day now.
These bums are disgrace!
Mama...!
Tell me, what day is it?
Setsuko...
Another one.
- What is this stuff?
- Never mind that. Just dump it!
This one's a goner, too.
You can see it in their eyes.
Grave of the Fireflies
Production Designer &
Executive Producer RYOICHI SATO
Original Story by AKIYUKI NOSAKA
Character Design YOSHIFUMI KONDO
Art Director NIZO YAMAMOTO
Music MICHIO MAMIYA
Layout YOSHIYUKI MAMOSE
Character Color Design MICHIYO YASUDA
Director of Photography NOBUO KOYAMA
Sound Design YASUO URAKAMI
Producer TORU HARA
Written & Directed by ISAO TAKAHATA
Air raid! Get to the shelters! Quickly.
We're in for a big one this time!
The shelter behind the
firehouse should be safest!
- It's hot!
- Be a good girl. Try to be patient.
Well, I'd better get over to the shelter.
So, be careful, Seita, and get
over there as soon as you can.
Setsuko, be a good girl
and listen to your brother.
Mom, never mind us! Get to the shelter!
Yes, yes.
Do you have your medicine with you?
I have it right here. Don't worry.
I hate the shelter!
Well, you'll be sorry if you
get blown up by a bomb!
Now get on.
My doll!
Air raid!
Seita!
Get down!
Seita! Seita! Seita!
Seita!
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
Get away people! Get inside.
Take what ever you can carried.
Long live the Emperor!
We're safe here. Don't worry, okay?
But, where's Mama?
Right, she's in the shelter.
The firehouse shelter can take
a hit from a 250-kilo bomb easy.
Don't worry about her.
She'll probably go to
Niponmatsu station to find us.
We'll go and meet her there.
Let's just rest a bit.
- Are you okay, Setsuko?
- I lost one of my shoes.
I'll buy you even better ones.
I have money.
Open this.
Wow, Setsuko, you're rich.
Black rain, from the bombing.
Look, it's all gone!
That was the civic hall.
We ate lunch there, once.
- Seita, is our house gone too?
- Probably.
What'll we do?
Dad'll make them pay for this!
Mother, mother!
Well, it's not like I was the
only one who lost his house.
We're all in the same boat.
Well, at least we're still alive.
There were two direct hits. The
fires are impossible to put out!
When you try to smother them,
it just spreads the oil around.
It's not her. She's not down here!
- Seita, I have to pee.
- Okay.
Attention, all residents of
Ichirizuka and Kaminishi!.
Please report to the elementary
school for first aid services!
What's wrong?
- My eye hurts.
- Don't rub it.
We'll get it washed out at the school.
Where's Mama?
- She'll be there.
- At school?
Yes. Let's go.
Seita! Come.
Have you seen your mother yet?
She's been injured. Go to her.
I'll watch your sister.
Wasn't that scary, Setsuko?
Seita has to go somewhere.
We'll wait for him together?
Seita. I'm glad you're here. Are you okay?
- My mom...?
- This way.
This is your mother's, isn't it?
In here.
She's finally falling asleep.
She really should be in a proper
hospital. We can't do much
I don't think they've did hit the
Kaisei hospital in Nishinomiya.
My mother, my mother has heart
trouble. Can she get her medicine?
I'll find out.
I'll be around if you need me.
Mom...
- You saw her?
- Yes.
I'm so sorry.
I'm thirsty.
If there's anything I can do, just ask.
Did you get your ration?
I'll get it for you!
Keep this ring in your
purse. Don't lose it. Okay?
Mom's been hurt, Setsuko.
But, she'll get better soon.
But, where is she?
In the hospital. In Nishinomiya.
We'll stay here at the school tonight.
Then tomorrow we'll go to stay in
our aunt's house near the hospital.
Is that okay?
We'll all staying on the second
floor. Why don't you stop by later?
Thanks for all your kindness. We will.
See you later then, bye bye now.
Want some?
I want to see Mama.
Maybe tomorrow. It's too late now.
Watch me, I'm good at this!
We haven't unbandaged her. Believe
me, you don't want to see the body.
With this heat we're having, she'll
have to go on the truck today.
Where's your sister?
In Nishinomiya. We have a distant aunt there.
I think she'll take care of us.
I see. Lucky for you.
I'd better get back to work. Good luck to you.
Mama!
Where is she?
Is she still sick, Seita?
- Yeah. Yeah, she still sick.
- Welcome back.
- How was your mother? Is she at Kaisei?
- Huh? Yeah.
Lucky your dad's in the Navy.
You get to have a truck
help move you over here!
I've laid out futons and
mosquito netting in your room.
Thank you.
Doesn't Mama need her ring?
Did she give it to me?
Just be careful you don't lose it.
Setsuko...
When Mom's a little better,
I'll take you to see her.
Time for bed. Okay?
Bonito, herring, dried potato, pickled plums.
And I do believe this is butter!
All these things are so hard
to come by nowadays.
But, soldiers family always get the best.
Anyway, did you stop by the hospital today?
I'd glad to tell your mother
what's been happening.
And I could take Setsuko along to visit her.
How bad?
My mom died while she was still at the school.
What? She's dead!
Then, why didn't you tell me? Why
were you hiding it? Answer me. child
I didn't want Setsuko to know.
So, she's dead... how awful! Well, you'd
best write your father and tell him!
Seita!
Look! She bought me new shoes!
Good for you, Setsuko.
Hello there!
Don't be too long.
We won't be.
What's that noise?
Huh? Bullfrogs. There's nothing to be scared of.
Firefly!
Ready? Catch it.
Ah... you squashed it.
Ew! It smells!
Don't squeezed so hard.
There're millions of them!
- Hey, Setsuko, close your eyes and say "Ah."
- Why say that?
Come on, just do it. "Ah."
Fruit drop!
Fruit drop! Fruit drop! Fruit drop!
I almost swallowed it.
- We're home.
- Where were you, two?
- Did you thank the lady?
- Yes, ma'am.
That food looked good.
Seita. Shouldn't you be going to school?
or something?
Yeah, but the steelworks they
had me working in was bombed.
and my school burned down.
There's no place to go.
Well, I hope you've written to your father.
- I did that. I sent it to the Naval Office.
- When?
Just after we came here. Umm...
I guess is about 10 days ago?
That's seems strange.
There should have been a reply by now.
Return the scissors when you've
finished with them, Setsuko.
Any news on the war?
Begining to look hopeless.
It seems that the more factories we lose,
the harder the others have to work.
The war affort is eating up all of us, why is?
You're right. That's why
food's getting so hard to find.
Our soldiers aren't the
only ones who are suffering.
You work for our country's
defense too, young lady.
You eat up and work as hard as you can!
Not again.
So you've taken in a couple
of homeless children?
Poor things, losing their
mother when they're so young.
- What's wrong? You got an itch?
- It's hot. I hate shelters!
Just hang on. We'll be out
of here as soon enough.
Hey, you wanna go to the beach?
Yeah! Yeah! Let's go!
It's all vegetable fields now.
Come on.
- What're they doing?
- They making sea salt.
It's all the salt and soy sauce is rationed.
Alright, hurry up, Setsuko!
It might be a little cold.
It's cold!
Feels good, right? You won't itch now.
It's a big bath!
Hey!
Come back here! Come back here!
I'm a bear! I'm gonna eat you!
Snipy... snipy... snipy... cut.
snipy... snipy... snipy...
What's wrong? Is he sleeping?
Don't look at that.
When it gets a little warmer,
I'll teach you how to swim.
Lets swim, then eat.
We'll swim, and that'll make us hungry.
Seita!
Setsuko!
You're hungry, aren't you?
There's food for you here.
Mother! How are you? Were you waiting long?
- Are you alright my daughter?
- I'm fine. Really! They're very nice here.
I'm hungry.
Let's get home before we're
caught in next the raid.
I'm tired. Carry me.
Air raid!
Your mother will not be needing
her kimonos anymore, Seita.
Why don't you, trade them for some rice.
I've been trading off my
things bit by bit for food.
You can probably get a full toh of rice for them.
- That much?
- You need your nourishment.
You can't be a soldier if
you don't grow up healthy.
A whole toh of rice?
Your mother would be glad you
didn't let them just go to waste.
Why don't I take them for you?
No!
- No!
- Setsuko. You're awake.
No! No! They're Mama's! No! They're
Mama's! Don't take them! No!...
Setsuko. Let them go!
Setsuko. Setsuko. No! Setsuko.
- Fine rice, isn't it?
- Yes, it is.
We'll have a proper rice
dinner tonight, Setsuko.
Here, this is yours.
White rice, Setsuko!
Here you go.
With my daughter and our
lodger working so hard...
I've felt just terrible not
having rice to give them.
It's great, huh? Real white rice!
More, please!
Surely.
You're just gobbling it down
tonight, aren't you, Setsuko?
Uhum... it's very good!
- What's wrong?
- I don't want rice porridge!
Don't we have any more those pickled plums?
Uhm... we finished those off ages ago.
- Hi.
- Here's your lunch.
Thanks. I'd better get going.
- Bye, Mom.
- Take care.
We'll have rice balls for
lunch. Just hold on 'til then.
You stop that! You'll have
porridge for lunch too!
Do you think a lazy slug like
you deserves the same...
as people who work so hard for our nation?
Really, Seita, you're old enough to know
now that everyone has got to cooperate.
You keep saying you want rice,
but do you do anything to earn it?
No, you absolutely do not!
I even give you some rice,
and you still complain!
- But it's our rice from rice toh.
- Oh, so now I'm cheating you, am I?
How dare you say that! After
I take you two in to my home!
Fine!
Here's a new rull, from now on,
we'll just make our own dinners!
Tell me Seita, you have other
relatives in Tokyo, don't you?
On your mother's side of the family?
Why not write to them? We
could be bombed any day!
I don't know where to find them.
Let's go home, Mommy.
Uh-huh. Daddy's waiting for us.
# Frogs are singing, it's time to go home #
Sorry you had to wait so long.
- What's wrong?
- I'm hungry.
- I'm thirsty too.
- Okay.
Here, have a fruit drop.
Mom has 7000 yen in the bank.
7000. That's more than enough for us
to live on, so you don't worry, okay?
I'm telling Dad to write back soon, because
you're waiting. Here right in here.
You're in luck.
You can't buy a stove like this easily
nowadays. You know what I mean?
It's almost impossible to
find any hardware to sell.
I'll take that comb, and...
Do you have an umbrella?
An umbrella... oh, yes!
# It's raining, it's raining
it's raining, it's raining #
# Big brother's coming home
with an umbrella just for me #
# Drip-drop, plip-plop, down the rain comes!
Drip-drop, plip-plop, down the rain comes! #
That's should do it!
- You be careful with that fire.
- Right.
What are they up to?
- They're doing their own cooking, now.
- Good for them! It's about time. More, please.
Mom, did you scold them again?
Yes, but they refuse to apologize.
And that boy even bought
a stove. Just to spite me!
Finished!
That's bad manners, Seita.
We can sit any way we want. Doesn't matter.
There. Rice for two.
- That's it?
- Yup!
Next ration will be in July.
Let me!
Ready?
Here.
Do you like it?
It's all different tastes!
Grape, strawberry, mint and melon. It's
all in there. Now drink it all up, okay.
It's all gone.
Great. They left the dishes for me to do.
So selfish.
Honestly! Those little brats
are two of the worst!
Not again!
Seita, please, that man and my daughter
work for our nation on day long!
We can't have her crying keeping them awake.
We've enough trouble getting any
sleep with all these air raids!
Attention, attention. Report
from Central Military Division.
Several waves of enemy
bombers are approaching.
Going to the shelter again, Seita?
You're old enough to help fight the fires,
aren't you? aren't you? aren't you?
I want to go home. I hate living with her!
We don't have a house to go back to.
# With a great big streamer
shape like a carp in the wind, go#
shaped like a carp in the wind #
# That big one's the Papa and
that little ones the kids #
- Stop it!
- # We... #
Don't you realize that there's a war going on?
You two are nothing but trouble for me!
A couple of pests, that's what are you!
You're no help at all during the raids.
You could just go and Live in
that shelter for all I care!
That's it.
We can live here.
No one using it. It's seems sturdy enough.
And we can just live like we want to!
Can we really live here?
We've bothered you long enough.
We're should be leaving now.
You're leaving...? For where?
Haven't really decided yet.
Well, then you two. Bye-bye,
take care of yourselves.
This'll be the kitchen!
And this'll be the front door!
But where's the bathroom, Seita?
That can be anywhere. You
wanna go somewhere with me?
Thanks a lot. Where you
want leave the wagon?
Just leave it right there.
Do you think, maybe, you can sell my sister
and I some food and maybe some straw?
I guess. Not much left, though.
- My mouth's watering!
- Let's eat.
Well, I guess, we can always eat frogs.
- Frogs?
- Yeah. They're great.
You'd better get under the mosquito net.
What's wrong?
I forgot my toothbrush.
One night without it won't matter.
It's getting pretty buggy at here.
You'd better go, get under the net.
It's dark in there. I'm scared.
I have to pee, Setsuko. How about you?
Look, kamikaze.
- It looks like a firefly.
- Yeah.
Let's catch some.
Okay, get in.
Ready?
I can see you!
I can see you, too.
A hair clip.
Hey, let's get as many as we can!
I went to see a naval review one
time, just before you were born.
Naval review...?
Yeah. Dad's cruiser, the "Maya", was in
formation with the fleet in the harbour.
# Mighty fortresses floating on the seas #
# Defending our homeland
from invaders near and far #
Enemy plane!
I wonder where Dad is fighting now.
Get off me, Seita!
What you doing?
Making a grave. Mama's in a grave too.
Auntie told me.
She said Mama died, and she's in a grave now.
We'll going and visit her grave sometime.
Do you remember the graveyard,
the pretty one, out near Nunobiki?
That's where she is now.
Under a big camphor tree.
Why do fireflies have to die so soon?
Hey, it looks like somebody's living here.
- Probably lost their house.
- Maybe it's some crazy hermit.
- It's a swing.
- Hey, a kid lives here. What's this?
Rest in Peace! Rest in Peace!
I wish it was real food.
- It says "Setsuko".
- Look! Dried out frogs!
Who'd wanna eat that?
Nobody I know would ever eat this stuff!
Ground soybeans!
And I thought the food I got was bad!
A ghost, a ghost!
I've traded everything for
rice. Even my mom's kimono.
There's nothing left to trade.
Please, I can pay you good money for the rice.
Sorry. I can't trade or sell anything to you.
I'm a farmer, but even I
don't have any rice to share.
- Don't you have other relatives?
- I don't know how to contact them.
Then take my advice and go
back to that woman, son.
Everything's rationed now.
You can't survive outside of the system.
Just swallow your pride and apologize.
Thanks, anyway. I'll just
go and ask someone else.
You're a son of navy man,
right? So, try to be brave.
Is it okay?
Oh, No!
It doesn't matter if you like
it or not. You have to eat!
You need to, so you can grow up strong!
Seita...
I feel... I feel funny.
Are you cold
I've been having diarrhea.
Hey you...!
I'm sorry!
Sir, forgive me! I didn't mean to.
My sister's sick. I just
wanted to get her some sugar!
Yeah, sure! Stealing food's
a serious crime in wartime!
You god damned...! Come back here!
What the hell...? Potatoes too?
So you're the one who's
been stealing my crops!
Seita!
- I'm sorry! I'll never do it again, I swear!
- Seita.
- Tell it to the cops! I'll take you there myself!
- Now walk! I hope they lock you up!
- No, please.
- Seita! Seita!
- Please, she's sick! She needs me!
- Move.
- Seita!
Seita!
Seita... Seita...
Base on what you both told me, the
nature of the crime is very clear.
So I thank you, for information, so I'll
take care of this. You may go now.
- What, officer...
- You've knocked this poor kid around enough.
I'm even tempted to call it...
- Assault!
- I... er... thank you, sir!
They hit Fukui tonight, you know.
Would you like a glass of water or something?
Setsuko.
Seita!
Seita.
Should I get a doctor, Seita? Where does it hurt?
Setsuko!
I have to go to the bathroom.
Can it wait a little bit?
Hop on.
# Brother's gone to the mountain
to bring back some firewood... #
Hurry, come on.
Setsuko. Dinner.
This pumpkin's great. Tastes
just like sweet bean jelly.
I don't like that stuff.
Look, if you don't eat, Dad'll blame me for it.
Come on, ready? I'll even help you, okay?
Now come on, cheer up and eat!
Once you get better, I'll take you
to the beach again, Setsuko.
Now I'll really get you
something good to eat, Setsuko!
S... Seita...
Seita...
These were your mother's?
Don't make me laugh!
Try to pawn off your garbage on me? Here.
Setsuko... Setsuko.
Setsuko!
Seita... water...
Breathe in.
And out.
She's been having diarrhea for a while now.
Prickly heat, rashes are all over her, and
salt water seems be hurting her skin.
Weakening from malnutrition. due to the diarrhea.
Next patient?
Can you give her medicine or a shot?
- Don't wanna shot.
- Please, doctor, help her!
Give her medicine? All this
child needs is... some food.
- She needs food...
- How can I help you?
Where I suppose to get food?
- I'm so hungry. What do you want to eat?
- Tempura, sashimi, jelly...
Anything else?
Ice cream. And also... I want fruit drops.
Fruit drops? Okay!
I'll withdraw the money and
buy you all the food you need.
Don't want anything. You can have it.
Don't go! Stay with me! Don't leave me alone!
And don't you worry, Setsuko.
I'm going to buy you some good,
and nourishing food, okay.
And I'll never... I never ever
leave you again. Never, ever.
I promise.
- 3000 yen.
- There's a typhoon coming?
That's great, we get our "Divine
wind" after we surrender. Figures...
Surrender...? You mean, we've lost the war?
Haven't you heard, young man?
You telling me Japan's lost the war?
The Great Japanese Empire?
Yeah. Surrendered unconditionally.
- But what about the fleet? Are they...?
- All gone.
The all fleet been sent to the bottom
of the sea. Not one left afloat.
What?
Was my Dad's ship sunken, too? Please
tell me. Is that why he hasn't written?
How the hell should I know?
Crazy kid.
Damn him!
I'm so hungry.
Daddy.
Now Dad's gone too. He's dead too. Dad...
I'm sorry I'm so late, Setsuko. I'll go
ahead and start making up some rice.
Up they go.
And down again.
Firefly's stopped.
I bought us some chicken, some eggs.
And I also have...
Setsuko, what's in your mouth?
Setsuko, what are you eating?
This is a marble. It isn't a drop!
I brought you something special,
and I know that you gonna like it.
Seita, have one.
Setsuko, what...?
Rice balls.
I made them for you.
Here. Have one.
- You don't want them...?
- Setsuko!
Look, it's a watermelon.
and I didn't have to steal it.
Here, eat it.
It's good...
Hold on of this, and I'll go make
some rice gruel with eggs.
I'll leave the melon here for you.
Okay?
Seita.
Thank you.
She never woke up.
There you go. Charcoal for the cremation.
Now, since it's a child, make
sure you do it at a temple.
The body should be lightly dressed,
and use beanstalks for a good fire.
Spite of it all. Lovely day.
It's so good to be home! It hasn't changed a bit.
The old phonograph.
I've missed this view.
Come back soon!
The next morning, I put some
of Setsuko's ashes into...
the candy tin, and then climbed down the hill.
I never went back to the shelter.
Seita...
Seita.
Time for bed. Okay?