Dad, do you want some candy?
Thanks. Aren't you tired?
All right
We're almost there
Mei, hide
It wasn't a policeman
Hello
Are your parents around?
Thanks
I'm Kusakabe
We've just arrived
A pleasure to meet you
Welcome
Thank you
Here we are
Wait
Mei, there's a bridge
A bridge?
See that flash?
Fish too
So, you like it here?
Dad, it's terrific
Look, a tunnel of trees
Is that our house?
Come on
It's a wreck
Wreck
Looks like a haunted house
Haunted?
And it's all rotten
It's gonna fall down
Fall down
Look, Mei
See?
It's huge
Dad, there's a huge tree
It's a camphor tree
Camphor tree
Oops
An acorn
Show me
Another one
It's mine
Out of the way
I can't open the screens
Acorns
There's acorns in the house
They dropped from up there
Maybe there are
squirrels in here
Squirrels, really?
Or rats; they like acorns too
I'd rather have squirrels
Where shall I put this?
Here
I'll get the door for you
Satsuki, open up the kitchen
Okay
It's just round the back
Mei, come on
Wait for me
Hurry
Ready?
Bathtubs
There's nothing here
That's the bathroom
Dad, there's something in here
A squirrel?
I don't know
A bunch of black things
but not roaches or mice
Really?
Can you see 'em?
I think they were dust bunnies
Dust bunnies?
Like in my picture book?
That's right
Ghosts don't come out
on days like this
When you walk into
a dark room from outside
your eyes dim and so
the dust bunnies come out
Oh, I see
Come here, dust bunnies
Come out, come out
wherever you are
Let's get to work
See if you can find
how to get upstairs
Get up there and
open all the windows
Sure
I'm coming, too
Toilet
Not here
Nothing here
Nothing
Nothing Nothing
Mei, it's here
It's pitch black
Dust bunnies
Another acorn
Come out, dust bunnies
Are you there, Mr. Dust bunny?
Nothing
Dad
There's definitely
something here
That's exciting
I've always wanted to live
in a haunted house
I'm coming
I got it, Satsuki
Mei
You're full of energy
This is Nanny
She's come to
look after the house
I'm Satsuki and
this is my sister, Mei
Nice to meet you
Nice to meet you both
I'd have cleaned up
If I'd known
you'd be this quick
No, you've done plenty
Lately I've been so busy
in the rice paddies
I only did a bit of dusting
Mei, what have you done
to your hands?
The dust bunny got away
Your feet, too
Mine are black, too
That must be
the soot spreaders
Those little
black, fuzzy things that fly?
That's right
They breed in
empty old houses
and cover them
with soot and dust
I could see them
when I was little
Now you can too, huh?
Are they like goblins
or something?
Naah, nothing so scare
If you keep smiling
they'll soon leave the house
They're probably deciding
where to go next, right now
Mei, they're going away
That's no fun
What happens if a huge one
comes out, like this?
I wouldn't be scared
Okay then
I won't walk you to
the bathroom at night
Okay, cleaning time
Could you get some water
from the stream?
From the stream?
I'm coming, too
Mei, wait there
Did you get a fish?
Nanny, it's coming out
Good
keep pumping
'til the water gets cold
Okay
May I help you?
Huh, my Mom for Granny
Yes?
Wait, what is it?
Is that you, Kanta?
You live in a haunted house
Kanta, stop it
I did the same kind of thing
when I was his age
I hate boys
But, I really love
Nanny's rice cakes
Eat as much as you want
Thank you
Thank you very much
for your help
Good bye
Dad, the house
is going to fall down
I hope not
we've only just moved in
Come on, let's laugh to
keep the bogeymen away
I'm not scared
I mean it. I'm not scared
One-two, one-two...
Come on
keep up the good work
Okay, Washing finished
Here we go
Nanny
Hello
Hard at work?
Where're you all heading?
To visit Mommy
in the hospital
That's nice
Give her my regards
Okay
This way...
Hello
Hello, there
Mommy
So glad you came, my dear
Daddy took the wrong road
Really?
Hello, Satsuki
It's a school holiday, today
How nice
Daddy is talking
to the doctor
It's so good to see you all
Have you settled into
the new house?
A haunted house?
Mom, do you like ghosts?
Of course, I do
I can't wait to see them
See, I told you, Mei
Mei was worried that
you wouldn't like ghosts
What about you two?
I love them
I'm not scared of them
Are you fixing
Mei's hair, Satsuki?
It's really
good Lucky girl, Mei
But she always
gets mad at me
That's 'cuz
you won't stay still
Come here, Satsuki
Isn't yours too short?
No, I like it like this
Do mine, Mommy Mine, too
Wait your turn
Wavy hair, just like mine
when I was your age
Will it be like yours
when I grow up?
Probably
You take after your Mom
Mom looked really well
You're right
The doctor says
she'll be home soon
Soon?
Like tomorrow?
You always say this
Tomorrow is a little too soon
Mom said she'll sleep
with me in my bed
Weren't you saying
you're big enough
to sleep alone?
Mom is special
Dad
Time to get up
Wake up
Sorry, I overslept again
I've got to bring
a box lunch today
I totally forgot about it
It's all right
I've made something
for all of us
It's burning
Let me do it
Here, this is yours, Mei
It's for me
Mei, sit down and eat
Here
Wrap yours
Satsuki
I'm coming
You made a friend already?
She's calling you
Yup, that's Michiko
Gotta go
See ya
See you later
Morning
Hi, let's go
Daddy
Do I look all grown up?
Yes, dear
And where might you be going?
I'm just going out
Daddy, is it lunch yet?
Already?
You be the flower shop, Daddy
Pole tads
Got no bottom
Gotcha
Who are you?
A big Dust bunny?
To-to-ro?
You're Totoro
I bet you're Totoro
Totoro
See you
Okay, catch you later
I'm home
Hey there
Is it that late already?
Where's Mei?
I'm off to Michiko's
We haven't eaten yet
Is Mei in the garden?
Mei
Dad, I found her hat
Mei...
Wake up, Mei
You shouldn't sleep here
Where's Totoro?
Totoro?
Where?
Were you dreaming?
Totoro was here
You mean that troll
in your picture book?
Yeah
He was all hairy with
a big mouth like this
There's a tiny one
and a little one
and a huge one like this
There you are
This is a great hiding place
Dad, Mei said
she saw a Totoro here
A Totoro?
It's this way
Hey, wait for me
Is it here?
No
It went to a big tree
But there wasn't
any other path
Come back, Mei
Mei, back
But it's true Totoro was here
I'm not lying
I know, Mei
I didn't lie
Neither of us think
you're lying
You probably met
the king of this forest
You were very lucky
He doesn't come out very often
We should go to the shrine
to pay our respects
Pay our respects?
To this forest
Mei, you're getting heavy
Daddy, look
That camphor tree
What a big tree
It's here
Is that the tree?
Dad, hurry up
The hole has gone
Are you sure it was here?
The hole disappeared
I told you he doesn't
come to see us often
But, will he come again?
I want to meet him, too
If you're lucky, sure
What a beautiful tree
This tree must have stood
here for years and years
Trees and people
used to be good friends
I saw that tree and
decided to buy the house
Hope Mom likes it too
Okay, let's pay our respects
then get home for lunch
Oh yeah
I promised
to go see Michiko
I want to go, too
Attention
Thank you for
looking after Mei
Thank you very much
Last one home's
a rotten egg
That's not fair, Dad
Wait
Hurry up
Wait for me
Dear Mother
Something amazing
happened today
Mei met a giant Totoro
And I'm hoping to see
him myself soon, too
Kanta, hurry up
You'll be late
Coming
Mei?
Excuse me
Yes, Satsuki?
It's my sister
What happened, Nanny?
I'm sorry
She insisted that
she be with you
It's Dad's day
at the university
You promised to be
a good girl at Nanny's
I still have two more classes
and Nanny's too busy for this
She was good up 'til now
weren't you?
I'll go talk to my teacher
Since Satsuki's mother
is in the hospital
I want you all
to be nice to her
Yes
What's that?
It's Totoro
Mei, you should keep quiet
Okay
Bye bye, Mei
I can't stay after class today
We'll let teacher know
See you
Hurry up, it's going to rain
Okay
Here it comes
Here
I won't cry. Aren't I good?
It's getting worse
Dear Guardian Spirit
Let us stay
until the rain stops
But...
That was lucky
It's got holes in it
Daddy forgot his umbrella
I'm going, too
I said I forgot it
What idiot forgets his
umbrella on a rainy day?
Ouch
You broke it playing, I bet
I did not
Excuse me
Hello, Satsuki, Mei
Grandma
I'm sorry about Mei today
Not at all
Sorry we couldn't do more
Kanta lent us this umbrella
He did?
A broken old thing like that
Mei was with me, so I was glad
But I'm so sorry
that Kanta got wet
Thank you very much
Not at all
It probably
cleaned him up a little
Are you off to
meet your father?
Yes
What good girls you are
Bye bye, Mei
Bye bye
Who was that?
I don't know
Just in time
Getting on?
All right, drive on
Daddy wasn't on it
He'll be on the next one
Why don't you wait at Nanny's?
Are you okay?
Mei, sleepy?
I told you
Wanna go to Nanny's?
It won't be much longer
Hang in there
It's late
Come on
Are you Totoro?
Wait a minute
You can use this
Take it, Mei's slipping off
Hold it like this
Here's the bus
He took Daddy's umbrella
I'm sorry
All right, drive on
The train was late
and I missed the bus
Were you worried?
We met him, Dad
He was here
And the cat bus
What?
It was huge
With big eyes like these
We met him
We met Totoro
How wonderful
Come on, Daddy
Dear Mother
I can't tell you
how excited I was today
It was the scariest
funniest day
I've ever had
Totoro gave us
a lovely present
wrapped in bamboo leaves and
tied with dragon whiskers
When we opened it
it was full of magic nuts
and seeds
We decided to plant them
in the garden
to make a lovely forest
But they haven't sprouted yet
Mei sits there all day
waiting for them
She looks like a little crab
It's nearly summer vacation
Dearest, dear Mom
get well soon
Love, Satsuki
Come on. Bed time
Lights off
Wait, Dad
Daddy, do you think
they will come out tomorrow?
Well, I'm sure
Totoro would know
Good night
Wake up, Mei
That's where
we planted the seeds
Wow, we did it
We're the wind
There are no trees
Yes
It was a dream...
But it wasn't a dream...
We did it
Mr. Kusakabe. Telegram
Mr. Kusakabe
Telegram
Anyone home?
Nanny
I'm here
This one is ripe
What about this one?
That's good, too
Your garden's a treasure house
Let's take a little break
These should be cold now
Looks delicious
So good
The sun blessed these
So they're
really good for you
Would they help my Mom, too?
Of course
If she eats my vegetables
she'll get better right away
She's supposed to
be back next Saturday
She'll sleep in my bed
At last
That's wonderful
But it's only
for a couple of days
To get used to the new house
I see
We'll feed her
lots of vegetables, then
I'll give her this corn
I picked
I'm sure
she'll be very pleased
I know
There was a telegram for you
For us?
Dad won't be back till late
what shall I do?
Open it
it might be important
PLEASE CONTACT, HOSPlTAL
It's from Mom's hospital
Something's happened to her
Nanny, What shall I do?
Calm down
Do you know
where your Dad is?
I know his office number
But we don't have a telephone
Kanta
take her to use the phone
in the main house
Mei, stay here with me
Stay with Nanny, Mei
Hello
I'd like to make a
long distance call, please
It's Tokyo 31-1382
Yes
A cute girl, Kanta
Hello?
Yes
Hello, may I speak to
Dader. Mr. Kusakabe?
It's his daughter, Satsuki
Yes
Daddy?
It's me, Satsuki
Hello, what's up?
From the hospital?
Okay
I'll call them right away
Is there anything wrong
with Mom?
Don't worry
I'll check up and
call you right back
I'm hanging up now
stay there
May I stay here
until he calls back?
Stay as long as you like
Satsuki
No
This corn is for my Mommy
No, it's my Mom's
Listen, Mei
Mom's not well
So she's not coming home
this time
No
There's nothing we can do
You don't want her
to get worse, do you?
No
It's just for
a few more days
No
So you don't care
if she dies, do you?
No
Stop being silly. I'm going
Let's go, Mei
I hate you, Satsuki
We should bring the washing in
Don't worry too much, Satsuki
Nanny's here to help
so cheer up
Your Dad said
he'll stop by the hospital
to check on her
Besides, it's just a cold
she'll be back next week
They said it was just a cold
when she went into hospital
But what if she dies
Don't be silly, Satsuki
Maybe Mom will
Stop it
Nobody would leave two
pretty little girls like you
There, there
Don't cry
I'll be here until
Daddy comes back, okay?
Mei
Did she come back?
Wasn't she at the bus stop?
That's strange
Where has she gone?
I was nasty to her
'cause she was being silly
Maybe she's heading
for the hospital
The hospital?
It would take
a grown up three hours
I'll go look
Kanta, hurry
Tell your dad
that Mei is missing
Stupid Mei
Always getting lost
Mei
Excuse me
Have you seen
a little girl pass by?
She's my sister
No, I don't think so
I'm sure I would've noticed
Maybe she wasn't here
Are you sure
she came this way?
I don't know
Mei
Please, stop
Jerk. What are you doing?
I'm looking for my sister
Have you seen a little girl?
Your little sister?
She's four
I think she's heading
to the hospital
Did you see anyone?
No. We just came from there
but we didn't see anyone
Thanks anyway
Where have you come from?
From Matsugo
Really?
Good luck
See you
Satsuki
Kanta
Find her?
No
And you?
Dad and the others
are looking for her
I'll go to the hospital
you go back home
I guess she got lost
on the way to the hospital
They found
a sandal by the pond
We're not sure
if it's hers or not
Did you find her?
Dear Lord
please protect her and...
It's too deep here
better search further away
Hey, are there any poles left?
Grandma, Satsuki's here
Nanny
Look, is it hers?
No, it isn't
Thank heavens
I was sure it was hers
Hey, Nanny was jumping
to conclusions
It's not hers
Where's she gone then?
Let's start from scratch
We better hurry
it'll be dark soon
I really appreciate
your help, everyone
Please, help me Totoro
Mei is lost
It'll be dark soon
I'm sure
she's scared somewhere
Totoro
Totoro, Mei is lost
and we can't find her
She must be scared
please help me find her
I don't know what to do
They can't see the bus
"FOREST-SWAMP"
"CEMETERY-SHRlNE"
"MEl"
Mei...
The trees are
moving out of the way
Mei
Satsuki...
Mei Satsuki
You silly girl
I'm sorry
You wanted to
take the corn to Mom?
"HOSPlTAL"
Will you take us
to the hospital?
Thank you so much
I'm sorry
They didn't need to send
a telegram just for a cold
The girls must be worried
I'm sorry to upset them
They'll be fine
As long as you're okay
We've all learned to cope
This'll just postpone
the enjoyment
They've put up with it so well
I'm especially sorry
for Satsuki
she's so sensitive
You're right
I 'm going to spoil them
for a while
when I come home
Oh no
She's laughing
Looks like she's fine
I can't wait to
get back on my feet
Look
Where did that come from?
What?
I could swear
I just saw Satsuki
and Mei laughing up
in that tree
Maybe they were too
Look
"For Mother"