Anna, Elsa.
Bed time's soon!
Ah oh, The princess is trapped in the
snow goblin's evil spell!
Quick Elsa, make a prince,
a fancy one!
Oh no, the prince is trapped too!
Who cares about
danger when there's love
Uh, Anna, blurgh...
Kissing won't save the forest.
The lost fairies cry out!
What sound does a giraffe make? - I dunno.
Nevermind. They wake the Fairy Queen.
Who breaks the spell and saves everyone.
And they all get married!
-What are you playing?
-Enchanted forest.
- The prince and the princess - whoosh!
That's like no Enchanted Forest I've ever seen.
You've seen an Enchanted Forest?
- Wait, what?
I have, once.
And you never told us this before?
Well, I could tell you now.
If you.. ah...
Okay, tell us now.
Are you sure about this?
It's time they know.
- Let's make a big snowman later.
- If they can settle and listen.
Far away,
As North as we can go.
Stood a very old and very
Enchanted Forest.
But it's magic wasn't that of
goblin's spells and lost fairies.
It was protected by the most
powerful spirits of all.
Those of Air, Fire
of Water
And Earth.
But it was also home to the
mysterious Northuldra people.
Were the Northuldra magical, like me?
No Elsa, they were not magical.
They just took advantage
of the forest gifts.
Their ways were so
different from ours.
But still,
they promised us friendship.
In honor of that,
your grandfather, King Runeard,
built them a mighty Dam to
strengthen their waters.
It was a gift of peace
- That's a big gift of peace
And I was so honored to get to go to the
forest to celebrate it.
-Stand tall, Agnarr.
I wasn't at all prepared for what the day would bring.
We let down our guard.
We were charmed.
It felt so...
Magical.
But something went wrong.
They were attacking us.
Get behind me!
It was a brutal battle.
Your grandfather ...  - Father!
was lost.
The fighting enraged the spirits.
Look out!
They turned their magic against us all.
There was this... voice.
And someone saved me.
I'm told, the spirits then vanished,
and a powerful mist covered the forest,
locking everyone out.
And that night, I came home
King of Arendelle.
Woah, Papa, that was epic.
Whoever saved you,
I love them.
- I wish I knew who it was.
What happened to the spirits?
What's in the forest now?
- I don't know.
The mist still stands.
No one can get in.
And no one has since come out.
- So we're safe?
Yes, but the forest could wake again.
And we must be prepared for what
ever danger it may bring.
And on that note, how about we say
good night to your father?
Oh, but I still have so many questions!
Save them for another night Anna.
Ah, you know I don't have
that kind of patience.
Why did the Northuldra
attack us anyway?
Who attacks people who
give them gifts?
Do you think the forest will wake again?
Only Ahtohallan knows.
- Ahtoho-, what?
When I was little,
my mother would sing a song about
a special river, called Ahtohallan,
that was said to hold all the answers
about the past
about what we are a part of.
Wow, will you sing it for us? Please?
Okay, cuddle close.
Scooch in.
♪ Where the northwind meets the sea ♪
♪ There's a river full of memory ♪
♪ Sleep, my darling, safe and sound ♪
♪ For in this river all is found ♪
♪ In her waters, deep and true ♪
♪ Lie the answers and a path for you ♪
♪ Dive down deep into her sound ♪
♪ But not too far or you'll be drowned ♪
♪ Yes, she will sing to those who hear ♪
♪ And in her song, all magic flows ♪
♪ But can you brave what you most fear? ♪
♪ Can you face what the river knows? ♪
♪ Where the northwind meets the sea ♪
♪ There's a mother full of memory ♪
♪ Come my darling, homewardbound ♪
♪ When all is lost, then all is found ♪
Your Majesty, -Oh!
They're ready.
Hehe, excuse me.
I'm coming.
Do you hear that?
- What?
Nevermind.
Enjoying your new permafrost, Olaf?
I'm just living the dream Anna.
Oh, how I wish this could last forever.
- Mmmmm.
And yet change mocks us
with her beauty.
- What's that?
- Forgive me, maturity is making me poetic.
Tell me, you're older and
thus all-knowing.
Do you ever worry about the notion that
nothing is permanent?
Ahh, no.
Really, Wow, I can't wait until I'm aged
like you, so I don't have to
worry about important things.
That's not what I mean.
I dont worry
because... well I have you
and Elsa, and Kristoff, and Sven and
the gates are open wide and...
and I'm not alone anymore...
♪ Yes, the wind blows a little bit colder ♪
♪ And we're all getting older ♪
♪ And the clouds are moving on with
every Autumn breeze ♪
♪ Peter Pumpkin just became fertilizer ♪
♪ And my leaf's a little sadder and wiser ♪
♪ That's why I rely on certain certainties ♪
♪ Yes, some things never change ♪
♪ Like the feel of your hand in mine ♪
♪ Some things stay the same ♪
♪ Like how we get along just fine ♪
♪ Like an old stone wall
that'll never fall ♪
♪ Some things are always true ♪
♪ Some things never change ♪
♪ Like how I am holding on tight to you ♪
♪ The leaves are already falling ♪
♪ Sven, it feels like the future is calling ♪
♪ Are you telling me tonight you're
gonna get down on one knee? ♪
♪ Yeah, but I'm really bad at
planning these things out ♪
♪ Like candlelight and pulling of rings out ♪
♪ Maybe you should leave all
the romantic stuff to me ♪
♪ Yeah, some things never change ♪
♪ Like the love that I feel for her ♪
♪ Some things stay the same ♪
♪ Like how reindeers are easier. ♪
♪ But if I committ and I go for it. ♪
♪ I'll know what to say and do ♪
♪ Right?! ♪
♪ Some things never change ♪
♪ Sven, the pressure is all on you.. ♪
♪ The winds are restless ♪
♪ Could that be why I'm hearing this call? ♪
♪ Is something coming? ♪
♪ I'm not sure I want things
to change at all ♪
♪ These days are precious ♪
♪ Can't let them slip away ♪
♪ I can't freeze this moment ♪
♪ But I can still go out and seize this day ♪
♪ Ah ah ah ah ah ah ♪
♪ The wind blows a little bit colder ♪
♪ And you all look a little bit older ♪
♪ It's time to count our blessings
beneath an autumn sky ♪
♪ We'll always live in a kingdom of plenty ♪
♪ That stands for the good and the many ♪
♪ And I promise you the flag of Arendelle will always fly ♪
♪ Our flag will always fly! ♪
♪ Some things never change ♪
♪ Turn around and time has flown ♪
♪ Some things stay the same ♪
♪ Though the future remains unknown ♪
♪ May our good luck last,
may our past be past ♪
♪ Time's moving fast, it's true ♪
♪ Some things never change ♪
♪ And I'm holding on tight to you ♪
♪ Holding on tight to you ♪
♪ I'm holding on tight to you ♪
Ahh, okay. Umm...
Lion. Grizzly bear.
Monster. Ug Bear!
Angry face! Ag Bear!
Hunt!
Unreedemable monster!
-Greatest mistake of your life!
Who didn't even kiss you.
Villain.
-Ooh...
We all kind of got it.
Okay, Olaf, you're up.
- Okay.
So much easier now
that I can read.
Lightning round.
Boys against girls.
Okay, I'm ready, I'm ready, Go!
Unicorn. Ice cream. Castle.
Oaken. Tea pot. Mouse.
Ooh, Elsa!
I don't think Olaf should
get to rearrange.
Doesn't matter. This is gonna be a cinch.
Two sisters, one mind.
- Thank you.
- Okay, here we go.
You got this Elsa.
Anytime.
Just do it with
your body. Nothing. Air.
Trees, people, treeple.
Oh that's not a word...
shovel boy, teeth?
Oh, doing the dishes.
Polar Bear. Hey. Sorry.
You gotta give me something.
Uhm, Alarmed?, Distracted?
Worried? Panicking?
Disturbed, oh, come on. You
definitely look disturbed, oh.
We won. - Rematch?
Oh, you know what, I think I'll turn in.
- Are you OK?
Just.. just tired.
Good night.
Yeah, I'm tired too, and Sven promised
to read me a bedtime story.
Didn't you Sven.
- Did I?
Oh you do the best voices  like
when you pretend to be Kristoff and
you're like 'I'll just need to
go talk to some rocks
about my childhood and stuff.'
- How about you guys start without me?
Does Elsa seem weird to you?
She... seemed like Elsa.
That last word, really seemed
to throw her, what was it?
I don't know, um,
I don't know, but ... - Ah
Ice.
Oh come on, she couldn't act out ice?
I better go check on her.
Thanks honey, love you.
Love you, too.
It's fine.
Come in.
Yup, something's wrong.
- With you? - No, with you.
You're wearing mother's scarf.
You do that when something's wrong.
Huh, did we hurt your feelings?
I'm sorry, if we did. You know, very
few people are actually good at
family games, that's just a fact.
No that's not it.
Then what is it.
There's this...
I just don't want to mess things up.
What things? You're doing great!
Oh Elsa, when are you going to see
yourself the way I see you?
What would I do without you?
You'll always have me.
I know what you need. Come on.
Come here. - What?
- Mama's words, cuddle close.
- Scooch in.
- Mhmm.
♪ Where the northwind meets the sea ♪
♪ There's a river full of memory ♪
♪ -I know what you're doing ♪
♪ Sleep, my darling, safe and sound ♪
♪ For in this river all is found ♪
♪ I can hear you ♪
♪ But I won't ♪
♪ Some look for trouble, while others don't ♪
♪ There are a thousand reasons I
should go about my day ♪
♪ And ignore your whispers
which i wish would go away. Ohh... ♪
♪ Whoa ♪
♪ You're not a voice ♪
♪ You're just a ringing in my ear ♪
♪ And if I heard you, which I don't ♪
♪ I'm spoken for I fear ♪
♪ Everyone I've ever loved
is here within these walls ♪
♪ I'm sorry, secret siren, but
I'm blocking out your calls ♪
♪ I've had my adventure, I don't
need something new ♪
♪ I'm afraid of what im risking
if I follow you... ♪
♪ Into the unkown! ♪
♪ Into the unknown!! ♪
♪ Into the unknown!!! ♪
♪ What do you want? 'Cause
you've been keeping me awake ♪
♪ Are you here to distract
me so I make a big mistake? ♪
♪ Or are you someone out there
who's a little bit like me? ♪
♪ Who knows deep down I'm
not where I meant to be? ♪
♪ Every day's a little harder
as I feel my power grows ♪
♪ Don't you know there's part
of me that longs to go ... ♪
♪ Into the unknown! ♪
♪ Into the unknown!! ♪
♪ Into the unknown!!! ♪
♪ Are you out there?
Do you know me? ♪
♪ Can you feel me
Can you show me ♪
♪ Where are you going?
Don't leave me alone ♪
♪ How do I follow you? ♪
♪ Into the uknown!!! ♪
Air, fire, water, earth.
The water.
The air rages, no fire, no water.
The earth is next.
We have to get out.
It'll be okay, evacuate to the cliffs.
Oh no, I'm gonna blow!
- I got you.
Yes, everyone's out and safe.
Here, take one of these.
You okay there, Olaf?
- Oh yeah.
We're calling this, controlling what
you can when things feel out of control.
Okay, I don't understand.
You've been hearing a voice
and you didn't think to tell me?
I don't want to worry you.
We made a promise not to
shut each other out.
Just tell me what's going on.
I woke the magical spirits at
the Enchanted Forest.
Okay, that's definitely not what
I thought you were gonna say.
Wait, the Enchanted Forest?
The one father warned us about?
Yes. Why would you do that?
- Because of the voice.
I know it sounds crazy,
but I believe whoever is
calling me, is good.
How can you say that?
Look at our kingdom. - I know, it's
just that my magic can feel it.
I can feel it.
Okay.
Oh no, what now.
The Trolls?
Kristoff, we missed you.
Pabbie. - Well, never a
dull moment with you two.
I hope you're prepared for
what you have done, Elsa.
Angry magical spirits are
not for the faint of heart.
Why are they still angry? What does
all of this have to do with Arendelle?
Let me see what I can see.
The past is not what it seems.
A wrong demands to be righted.
Arendelle is not safe.
The truth must be found.
Without it
I see no future.
No future?
When one can see no future,
all one can do is the next right thing.
The next right thing?
Is for me to go to the Enchanted
forest and find that voice.
Kristoff can I borrow your wagon,
and Sven?
- I'm not very comfortable with the idea of that.
- You are not going alone.
Anna, No, I have my powers
to protect me, you don't.
Excuse me, I climbed to the north mountain, survived
a frozen heart, and saved you from my ex-boyfriend,
and I did it all without powers,
so you know, I'm coming.
Me too, I'll drive.
- I'll bring the snacks.
I will look after your people.
Please make sure they stay out of
the kingdom until we return.
Of course.
- Let's let them know.
Anna, I'm worried for her,
we have always feared
Elsa's powers were too much
for this world.
Now,
we must pray they are enough.
I won't let anything happen to her.
Who's into trivia? I am, ok.
Did you know that water has memory?
True fact, it's disputed by
many, but it's true.
Did you know men are six times more
likely to be struck by lightning?
Did you know gorillas burp
when they're happy?
Did you know we blink
4 million times a day?
Did you know wombats poop squares?
Did you know sleeping quietly
on long journeys prevents insanity?
Yeah, that's not true. - It is.
- It is defenitely true. - It's the truth.
Hmm, well that was unanimous.
But I will look it up
when we get home.
They're both asleep.
So... what do you wanna do?
Sven, keep us steady, will you?
Anna. Hm. Anna, remember our
first  trip like this when
I said you'd have to be crazy to want to marry
a man you just met. - Wait, what?
Crazy? You didn't say I was
crazy, you think I'm crazy?
No, I did, you were...
not crazy, clearly.
Just naive, not naive,
just ah.. just new to love.
Like I was, and...
when you're new, you're
bound to get it.. wrong.
So you're saying, I'm wrong for you.
What? No, no, I'm not saying you're wrong,
or crazy, I'm sayi-... - Kristoff, stop, please.
- Good idea. - I hear it.
I hear the voice. - You do?
Olaf, wake up.
- Whoa.
- Wow.
Promise me, we do this together, okay?
I promise.
It's okay.
Did you know that an Enchanted Forest
is a place of transformation?
I have no idea what that means.
But I can't wait to see what it's
gonna do to each one of us.
What is this?
What was that?
No, no, no.
And we're locked in.
I probably should've seen
that one coming.
This forest is beautiful.
The Dam... It still stands.
It was in Grand Pabbie's visions, but why?
I don't know, but it's still in
good shape, thank goodness.
What do you mean?
Well if that Dam broke, it would
send a tidal wave so big, it would
wash away everything on this fjord.
Everything? But..
Arendelle's on this fjord.
Nothings gonna happen to Arendelle
Anna, it's gonna be fine.
Come here.
You know, under different
circumstances, this would be
a... pretty romantic place.
- Don't you think?
- Different circumstances?
You mean like with someone
else? What? No, no, I'm saying...
Hm, just in case we don't
make it out of here.
You don't think we're gonna
make out of here?
No, no, I mean, no, we
will make it out of here
Well, technically the odds are kinda
complicated, but my point is..
In case we die
You think we're gonna die? No! no!
No, we will die at some point...
- I swore that I wouldn't leave her side.
- Not even any reason time will we die but...
- Elsa?
- Way far in the future, we will die.
Don't patronize me.
Elsa, there you are.
- You okay? - I'm fine.
- Okay, good.
Where's Olaf?
Umm, Anna?
Elsa?
Sven?
Samantha?
I don't even know a Samantha!
That's normal.
What was that?
Samantha?
♪ This will all make sense when I am older ♪
♪ Someday I will see that this makes sense ♪
♪ One day, when I'm old and wise ♪
♪ I'll think back and realize
♪ That these were all completely normal events ♪
♪ Ah! ♪
♪ I'll have all the answers when I'm older ♪
♪ Like why we're in this dark enchanted wood ♪
♪ I know in a couple years ♪
♪ these will seem like childish fears ♪
♪ And so I know this isn't bad, it's good ♪
Excuse me.
♪ Growing up means adapting ♪
♪ Puzzling out your world and your place ♪
♪ When I'm more mature ♪
♪ I'll feel comfortably secure ♪
♪ Being watched by something ♪
♪ with a creepy, creepy face ♪
♪ See, that will all make sense when I am older ♪
♪ So there's no need to be terrified or tense ♪
♪ I'll just dream about a time ♪
♪ When I'm in my aged prime ♪
♪ 'Cause when you're older ♪
♪ Absolutely, everything makes sense ♪
♪ This is fine ♪
Olaf!
Hey guys, meet the wind spirit.
Coming through.
Oh, I think I'm gonna be sick.
I'd hold your hair back, but
I can't find my arms.
Hey! Stop!
Elsa!
Let her go.
Anna, be careful!
- That's my sister.
Prince Agnarr.
For Arendelle.
Are you ok?
- I'm fine.
What are these?
They look like moments in time.
What's that thing you say Olaf?
Oh, my theory about advancing technology's
is both our savior and our doom?
No, not that one, the one
about... - The one about cucumbers?
No. The thing about water.
Water has memory.
The water that makes up you and me
has passed through at least 4 humans
and or animals before us.
And remembers everything.
The wind's back!
Delicious! I think
I'll name you Gale.
Get out there.
Oh, hi, aren't you curious!
You in a better mood now?
Father.
That's father.
This girl...
She's saving him.
She's Northuldra.
What is that?
Olaf get behind me.
- Why are you gonna do with that?
- I have no idea.
Lower your weapon!
- And you lower yours!
- Arendellian Soldiers?
- Threatening my people Lieutenant?
- Invading my Dam space, Yelena?
Why does that soldier looks so familiar?
Lieutenant, get the sword!
That was magic.
- Did you see that?
- Of course I saw it.
Well, you chose a nice cold greeting.
- They've been trapped in here this whole time?
- Yeah. - What do we do now?
I got this, hi I'm Olaf.
Oh sorry, yeah, I just find
clothes restricting.
Bet you're wondering who
we are and why we're here.
It's really quite simple.
It began with two sisters.
One born with magical powers.
One born powerless,
their love of snowmen?
Infinite!
Anna, No! Too high.
Blast!
Ooww, Mama, Papa, Help!
Slam!
Doors shutting everywhere,
Sisters torn apart.
Well at least they have
their parents.
Their parents are dead.
Oh, hi I'm Anna, I'll marry
a man I just met.
Elsa's gonna blow, snow,
snow, ah run!
Magic pulses through my snowflakes.
I live, ice palace for one,
ice palace for one.
- Get out Anna.
- My heart.
- Oh my goodness.
Only an act of true love
can save you.
- Here's a true love's kiss.
You're not worth it. Guess what.
I'm the bad guy.
What?
And Anna freezes to death, forever.
Oh, Anna!
Then she unfreezes.. oh and
then Elsa woke up the magical spirits.
And we were forced out
from our kingdom,
Now our only hope is
find the truth about the past,
but we don't have a clue
how to do that,
Excepts Elsa's hearing voices,
so we got that going for us.
Any questions?
I think they got it.
Are you really queen of Arendelle?
I am. Why would nature reward
a person of Arendelle with magic?
Perhaps to make up for the
actions of your people.
My people are innocent, we
would have never attacked first.
May the truth be found.
- Hi, I'm sor-, uh, what's happening?
- That's it!
Lieutenant Mattias, library,
second portrait on the left,
You were our father's official guard.
Agnar.
What did happened to your parents?
Our parents' ship went down
in the Southern Sea 6 years ago.
I see him.
I see him in your faces.
- Really?
Soldiers.
We maybe getting on in years
but we're still strong
and proud to serve Arendelle.
Wait, please.
Someone has called me here.
If I can just find them.
I believe they have the answers
that may help us free this forest.
Trust me, I just want to help.
We only trust nature.
When nature speaks...
...we listen.
This will all make sense
when I'm older.
Fire spirit.
Get back everyone! Go to the river!
No, no, no no - the reindeer...
that's a dead end.
Come on Sven, we'll get them.
Elsa, get out of there.
No, no, no.
Elsa.
Come on buddy, we can do this.
Anna.
- Get her out of here!
- No! Elsa!
They're all looking at us, aren't they?
Got any advice?
Nothing? Hmm.
Should I know what that means?
You hear it too.
Somebody's calling us, who is it?
What do we do?
Okay, keep going north.
Elsa!
Oh thank goodness. Anna. Are you okay?
-What were you doing?
You could have been killed, you
can't just follow me into fire.
You don't want me to follow you into
fire, then don't run into fire.
You're not being careful Elsa.
I'm sorry, are you okay?
I've been better.
I know what you need.
Where did you get that scarf?
That's a Northuldra's scarf.
- What?
- This is from one of our oldest families.
It was our mother's.
Elsa.
I see it, it's mother.
Mother saved father's life that day.
Our mother was Northuldra.
We are called Northuldra.
We are the people of the sun.
I promise you.
I will free this forest,
and restore Arendelle.
That's a pretty big promise Elsa.
Free the forest.
Wow.
Im sorry, It's just ... ah.
Some of us were born in here, we've never
even seen the clear sky.
I get it.
- Name's Ryder.
- Kristoff.
I heard the voice again.
We need to go north. - But the earth
giants now roam the north at night.
You can leave in the morning.
- I'm Honeymaren.
- Honeymaren, we'll do all we can.
Hey, let me ask you,
how do you guys
cope with the ever increasing complexity
of thought that comes with maturity?
Brilliant.
It's so refreshing to talk
to the youth of today.
Our future's in bright hands
Oh no, no, no..
Don't chew that, you don't
know what I've stepped in.
I can't seem to
get her attention.
- Or even say the right thing.
- Well, you're in luck.
I know nothing about women.
But I do know that we have the
most amazing way of proposing.
If we start now, we'll be ready by dawn.
- Really?
Best part?
It involves a lot of reindeer.
Hey, back at home, Halimah's
still over at Hudson's hearth?
She is. - Really?
She married? - Mm-mm.
- Oh wow, why doesn't that make me feel better?
- What else do you miss?
My father.
He passed long before all this.
He was a great man.
Built us a good life in Arendelle, but taught me
to never take the good for granted.
He'd say, be prepared!
Just when you think you found your way,
life will throw you onto a new path.
What do you do when it does?
Don't give up.
Take it one step at a time.
And...
Just do the next right thing.
Yeah, you got it.
I wanna show you something.
May I?
You know, air, fire, water and earth.
- Yes.
- But look.
There's a fifth spirit.
Said to be a bridge between
us and the magic of nature.
- A fifth spirit?
- Some say...
they heard it call out the
day the forest fell.
My father heard it.
Do you think that's who's calling me?
Maybe.
Alas, only Ahtohallan knows.
Ahtohallan.
♪ Dive down deep into her sound ♪
♪ But not too far, or you'll be drowned ♪
Why do lullabies always have to
have some terrible warning in them?
I wonder that all the time.
Earth giants.
What are they doing down here?
Hide!
They're coming!
This is why we
don't play with fire.
Ah, I can't stay mad
at you, you're so cute.
Please tell me, you are not
about to follow them.
What if I can settle them like
I did the wind and fire.
Or what if they can crush you
before you even get the chance.
Remember, the goal
is to find the voice,
find the truth and get us home.
- Hey guys, that was close.
- I know.
The giant sensed me.
They may come back here, I don't
want to put anyone at risk again.
And you're right Anna,
we've got to find the voice.
- We're going now.
- Okay, we're going, let me just...
Wait, where are Kristoff and Sven?
Oh yeah, I think they took off with
that Ryder guy and a bunch of reindeer.
They left?
Just left without saying anything?
Who knows the ways of men.
Am I supposed to feel this ridiculous?
Oh yeah, definitely.
- Everyone ready?
- Ready. Ah, I could use a rehearsal
- I love love..
- Wait, you talk for them too?
- I do.. - It's like you can
actually hear what they're thinking.
Yeah and then you.. you just say it.
And then you just say it.
Okay, here she comes.
Princess Anna of Arendelle.
My fiesty, fearless,
ginger sweet love.
Will you marry me?
Um, no.
The princess left with the queen.
What queen? What?
Wait. What?!
I wouldn't try to follow,
they're long gone.
Long gone?
So yeah.
Um, we're heading west, to the Lycan
Meadows, you can come with us if you want.
Hey, um.
- I'm really sorry ...
- No, it's fine.. - Yeah, yup.
Hm, okay, I'd better go pack.
- You coming with?
- I'll just ah, dah I'll meet you there.
Ahh, you know where you're going.
Yah.
Yah, I know the woods.
♪ Reindeers are better than people ♪
♪ Sven, why is love so hard? ♪
♪ You feel what you feel ♪
♪ And those feeling are real ♪
♪ Come on, Kristoff. Let down your guard ♪
♪ Again, you're gone ♪
♪ Off on a different path than mine ♪
♪ I'm left behind ♪
♪ Wondering if I should follow ♪
♪ You had to go ♪
♪ And, of course, it's always fine ♪
♪ I probably could catch up
with you tomorrow ♪
♪ But is this what it feels
like to be growing apart ♪
♪ When did I become the one
who's always chasing you heart? ♪
♪ Now I turn around and find
I am lost in the woods ♪
♪ North is south, right
is left when you're gone ♪
♪ I'm the one who sees you home
But now I'm lost in the woods ♪
♪ And I don't know
what path you are on ♪
♪ I'm lost in the woods ♪
♪ Up 'til now ♪
♪ The next step was
a question of how ♪
♪ I never thought it was
a question of whether ♪
♪ Who am I, if I'm not your guy? ♪
♪ Where am I, if we're
not together ♪
♪ Forever ♪
♪ Now I know you're my true north ♪
♪ 'Cause I am lost in the woods ♪
♪ Up is down, day is night ♪
♪ When you're not there ♪
♪ Oh, you're my only landmark ♪
♪ So I'm lost in the woods ♪
♪ Wondering if you still care ♪
♪ But I'll wait ♪
♪ For a sign ♪
(♪ For a sign ♪)
♪ That I'm your path ♪
♪ 'Cause you are mine ♪
♪ Until then ♪
♪ I'm lost in the woods ♪
♪ Lost in the woods ♪
(♪ Lost in the woods ♪)
(♪ Lost ♪)
Hey Olaf, umm.
Maybe just one of you
should do it.
I agree, she's a little pitchy.
Hey, Gale's back.
What?
- How can it be?
- What is it?
Mother and father's ship.
But this isn't the Southern Sea.
No, it isn't.
Why is their ship here?
How is it here?
It must have been washed
in from the Dark Sea.
What were they doing in
the Dark Sea?
I don't know.
How did the ship get through the mist?
I thought nobody could but us,
unless...
Nobody was on it.
There's gotta be something here.
Wait, wait, look around.
Every Arendellian ship
has a compartment, waterproof.
That's very clever.
Although it does make me wonder why they
don't just make the whole ship waterproof.
Here!
What language is this?
I don't know, but look,
this is mother's handwriting.
The end of the ice age,
the river found but lost.
Magic's source.
Elsa's source?
It's a map.
They traveled north.
Planned to cross the Dark Sea to...
Ahtohallan.
- It's real?
- Ahtoho- what?
Ahtohallan.
It's a magical river said to hold
all the answers about the past.
Reinforcing my water
has memory theory.
Water has memory.
Elsa?
I wanna know what
happened to them.
- Ahtohallan has to be the source of her magic.
- We keep going.
But Elsa ...
The waves are too high..
Elsa!
Hey, hey hey, what are you doing?
This is my fault, they were
looking for answers about me.
You are not responsible
for their choices, Elsa.
No, just their deaths.
Stop. No.
Yelana asked why would the spirits reward
Arendelle with the magical queen?
Because our mother saved our father.
She saved her enemy.
Her good deed was rewarded.
With you.
- You are a gift.
- For what?
If anyone can resolve the past,
if anyone can save Arendelle
and free this forest, it's you.
I believe in you Elsa.
More than anyone or anything.
Honeymaren said there
was a fifth spirit
A bridge between the magic
of nature and us.
- A fifth spirit.
- That what's been calling me.
From Ahtohallan.
The answers about the past
are all there.
So we go to Ahtohallan.
Not we.
Me.
What?
The Dark Sea is too dangerous
for us both.
No, no - we do this together.
Remember the song, go too
far and you'll be drowned.
Who will stop you
from going too far?
You said you believed in me,
that this is what I was born to do.
And I don't want to
stop you from that.
I don't want to stop you from being
whatever you need to be, I just-
don't want you dying.
Trying to be everything
for everyone else too.
Don't do this alone.
Let me help you, please.
I can't lose you Elsa.
I can't lose you either, Anna.
Come on.
Wait, what? What are you doing? Elsa!
No, no ...
Olaf, help me stop.
Give me a hand!
Hang on!
Oh no.
Come on!
Anna, this might
sound crazy, but I'm
- sensing some rising anger.
- Ah, Now I am angry, Olaf.
- She promised me we'd do
this together. - Yeah, but ...
What I mean is I'm sensing
rising anger in me.
- Wait, you're angry?
- I think so.
Elsa pushed me away too and
didn't even say goodbye.
- And you have every right to
to be very, very mad at her.
And you've said some things
never change, but since then,
everything's done nothing
but change. - I know.
But look.
I'm still here holding your hand.
Yeah, that's.. that's a good point Anna.
I feel better,
you're such a good listener...
Shh, shh, shh!
Don't shh me..
No, no!
Oh the Giants, they're huge.
Hang on Olaf.
Try not to scream.
Found it.
Thank you.
Where are we?
In a pit, with no way out.
But with this spooky
pitch black way in.
Come on, it'll be fun,
assuming we don't get
stuck here forever
and no one ever finds us
and you start and I give up.
But bright side...
Elsa's gotta be doing a whole
lot better than we are.
Ok.
Of course.
Glaciers are rivers of ice.
Ahtohallan is frozen.
I hear you, and I'm coming.
♪ Every inch of me is trembling ♪
♪ But not from the cold ♪
♪ Something is familiar ♪
♪ Like a dream , I can
reach but not quite hold ♪
♪ I can sense you there ♪
♪ Like a friend, I've always known ♪
♪ I'm arriving ♪
♪ And it feels like I am home ♪
♪ I have always been a fortress ♪
♪ Cold secrets deep inside ♪
♪ You have secrets too ♪
♪ But you don't have to hide ♪
♪ Show yourself ♪
♪ I'm dying to meet you ♪
♪ It's your turn ♪
♪ Are you the one I've been looking for ♪
♪ All of my life? ♪
♪ Show yourself ♪
♪ I'm ready to learn ♪
♪ Ah ah ah ah ♪
♪ I've never felt so certain ♪
♪ All my life I've been torn ♪
♪ But I'm here for a reason ♪
♪ Could it be the reason I was born? ♪
♪ I have always been so different ♪
♪ Normal rules did not apply ♪
♪ Is this the day? ♪
♪ Are you the way ♪
♪ I finally find out why? ♪
♪ Show yourself ♪
♪ I'm no longer trembling ♪
♪ Here I am ♪
♪ I've come so far ♪
♪ You are the answer I've waited for ♪
♪ All of my life ♪
♪ Oh, show yourself ♪
♪ Let me see who you are ♪
♪ Come to me now ♪
♪ Open your door ♪
♪ Don't make me wait ♪
♪ One moment more ♪
♪ Oh, come to me now ♪
♪ Open your door ♪
♪ Don't make me wait ♪
♪ One moment more ♪
Mother!
♪ Come, my darling, homeward bound ♪
♪ I am there! ♪
♪ Show yourself, step into your power ♪
♪ Throw yourself, into something new ♪
♪ You are the one you've been waiting for ♪
♪ Love of my life ♪
♪ Show yourself ♪
...I love Olaf, and I love warm hugs..
I love you Olaf.
♪ Here I stand, in the light... ♪
...like a chicken with the
face of a monkey!
I just wasn't looking where I
was going, but I'm great.
Actually ... Prince
Hans of the Southern Isle.
I love you. I need to
tell you about my past.
- And where I'm from.
- I'm listening.
Iduna!
- What are you reading, your Majesty?
- Some new Danish author.
King Runard, I'm sorry,
I don't understand.
Grandfather!
We bring Arendelle's full guard.
But they have given us no
reason not to trust them.
The Northuldra follow magic,
which means we can never trust them.
Grandfather?
Magic makes people
feel too powerful,
too entitled, it
makes them think
they can defy the
will of a king.
That is not what magic does.
That's just your fear.
Fear is what
can't be trusted.
You see, the Dam will weaken their lands,
so they will have to turn to me.
♪ ..for you, dive down deep into her sound ♪
♪ But not too far or you'll be drowned ♪
They will come in celebration,
and then
we will know their
size and strength.
As you have welcomed us,
we welcome you,
our neighbors, our friends.
King Runeard, the Dam isn't strengthening
our waters, it's hurting the forest.
It's cutting off the North...
- Let's not discuss this here.
Let's meet on the fjord, have tea,
find a solution.
No!
Anna!
Which lucky tunnel do we choose?
You see, the Dam will weaken
their lands,
so they will have to turn to me.
King Runeard, the Dam is hurting the forest!
Elsa's found it.
- What is it?
- The truth about the past.
That's my grandfather,
attacking the Northuldra leader
who wields no weapon.
The Dam wasn't a gift of peace.
It was a trick.
But that goes against
everything Arendalle stands for.
It does, doesn't it?
I know how to free the forest,
I know what we have to do,
To set things right.
Why do you say that so sadly?
We have to break the Dam.
But Arendelle will be flooded.
That's why everyone was forced out,
to protect them from
what has to be done.
Oh! Oh.
Are you okay?
I could really use a bright side, Olaf.
Bright side? Umm...
Turtles can breathe through their butts?
Huh?
And I see a way out.
I knew I could count on you.
Come on, Olaf.
Elsa's probably on her way back
right now, we can meet her and-
Olaf?
What's this? - Are you okay?
- I'm flurrying?
Wait, no, that's.. that's not it.
I'm flurrying, away...
The magic in me is fading.
What?
I don't think Elsa's okay.
I think...
she may have gone too far.
No, no.
- Anna.
I'm sorry.
You're gonna have to do
this next part on your own.
Okay?
-Wait, come here.
I've got you.
That's good.
Hey Anna.
I just thought of one thing that's permanent.
-What's that?
Love.
Warm hugs?
I like warm hugs.
I love you.
Olaf, Elsa.
What do I do now?
♪ I've seen dark before ♪
♪ But not like this ♪
♪ This is cold ♪
♪ This is empty ♪
♪ This is numb ♪
♪ The life I knew is over ♪
♪ The lights are out ♪
♪ Hello darkness ♪
♪ I'm ready to succumb ♪
♪ I follow you around ♪
♪ I always have ♪
♪ But you've gone to a
place I cannot find ♪
♪ This grief... ♪
♪ has a gravity, it pulls me down ♪
♪ But a tiny voice ♪
♪ whispers in my mind ♪
♪ You are lost ♪
♪ Hope is gone ♪
♪ But you must ♪
♪ Go on ♪
♪ And do the next right thing ♪
♪ Can there be a day ♪
♪ beyond this night? ♪
♪ I don't know anymore what is true ♪
♪ I can't find my direction, I'm all alone ♪
♪ The only star that guided me was you ♪
♪ How to rise from the floor ♪
♪ When it's not you I'm rising for? ♪
♪ Just do the next right thing ♪
♪ Take a step ♪
♪ Step again ♪
♪ It is all that I can, to do.. ♪
♪ The next right thing ♪
♪ I won't look too far ahead ♪
♪ It's too much for me to take ♪
♪ But break it down to this next breath ♪
♪ This next step ♪
♪ This next choice ♪
♪ Is one that I can make ♪
♪ So I'll walk through this night ♪
♪ Stumbling blindly toward the light ♪
♪ And do the next right thing ♪
♪ And with the dawn, what comes then? ♪
♪ When it's clear that everything
will never be the same again? ♪
♪ Then I'll make the choice ♪
♪ To hear that voice ♪
♪ And do... ♪
♪ The next right thing ♪
Wake up!
Wake up!!!
That's it!
Come and get me! Come on!
Over here!
Okay, that's right!
Keep coming!
That'll work.
This way guys!
No, no-no, she's leading
them to the Dam.
- Kristoff!
- I'm here.
- What do you need?
- To get to the Dam.
You got it.
- Thank you.
- Help me up!
- We'll meet you around!
- Lieutenant Mathias.
- Your Highness.
- What are you doing?
- The Dam must fall.
It's the only way to break the
the mist, and free the forest.
But we've sworn to protect
Arendelle at all costs.
Arendelle has no future
until we make this right.
King Runard betrayed everyone.
How do you know that?
My sister gave her
life, for the truth.
Please.
Before we lose anyone else.
Look out!
Destroy the Dam, come on!
Throw your boulders!
That's it.
I've got her.
Anna!
Hang on.
I'm sorry I left you behind.
I was just so deperate
to protect her.
I know, I know, it's okay.
My love is not fragile.
Look at the sky.
I just didn't realize there
was so much of it.
34 years.
5 months.
And 23 days.
Is it really you?
Anna.
- I thought I'd lost you.
- Lost me?
You saved me.
Again. - I did?
And Anna.
Arendelle did not fall.
It didn't?
The spirits all agree.
Arendelle deserves to stand with you.
Me?
You did what was right,
for everyone.
Did you find the fifth spirit?
You are the fifth spirit.
- You are the bridge.
- Well, actually, a bridge has two sides.
And mother had two daughters.
We did this together,
and we'll continue
to do this together.
Together.
Elsa! You're okay!
You look different.
Did you cut your hair or something?
Or something.
Oh.
Anna, I need to ask you a question.
Okay.
Do you wanna build a snowman?
What?
Thank goodness, water has memory.
Anna, Elsa.
Kristoff and Sven.
You all came back!
I love happy endings.
I mean I presume we're done,
or is this putting us in mortal danger
situation gonna be, a regular thing?
No, we're done.
- Actually...
There is one more thing, Anna..
You are the most extraordinary
person I've ever known.
I love you with all I am.
Will you marry me?
Yes!
Arendelle's okay.
- What?
Ahtohallan is beautiful.
Hello.
- You know,
you belong up here.
I took an oath to always do
what's best for Arendelle.
Luckily,
I know just what that is.
I still don't know what
transformation means.
I feel like this forest,
has really changed us all.
Presenting, her Majesty,
Queen Anna of Arendelle.
Oh! Oh!
Hi!
Sven, don't you look nice.
Oh my goodness! Olaf!
Charmed?, I'm sure.
- Charming.
- Your Majesty.
Kristoff.
Oh, did you boys get all dressed
up for me?
It was Sven's idea.
One hour, you get
this for one hour.
That's okay, I prefer
you in leather anyway.
I'm shocked you can last
an hour, that was brutal.
Hm, the things we do for love.
What is this crazy magic called again?
A photograph.
- Photograph... hm.
Really good.
Halima, General Mathias.
Ah Your Majesty. I'll be right back, you
can look at our photograph while I'm gone.
I'm just kidding,
How'm I doing? - Fantastic.
Our lands and people,
now connected by love.
Hi Gale, you like it?
Oh, do you mind?
I've got a message for my sister.
Thank you.
Charade's Friday night, don't be late.
And don't worry,
Arandalle is doing just fine.
Keep looking after the forest.
I love you.
I love you too, Sis.
Hey Gale, we're going for a ride,
wanna come?
Are you ready?
Ahhheeeooo...
Show yourself!
Right now!
Elsa, be who you are.
Oh, I will mama, I will.
Elsa's dead. Olaf's dead.
Anna cries.
And then, a bunch of important
things happen,
that I forgot, but all that matters
is I was right, and water has memory,
and thus... I live.
And so do you.
Ohhhh... we live!
We Live!!
Ahhh..oho...
Good story!