Agent Rick Dicker
interrogating.
State your name, please.
Uh, Tony.
Tony Rydinger.
Tell me about
the incident.
Well, there's this girl,
um, in my class.
I saw her at the track meet.
You're, uh, Violet, right?
That's me.
I sort of knew her,
but she'd changed.
Relaxed.
She was more sure of herself.
Cool, cute.
I asked her out
to a movie.
So, Friday?
Friday.
And I went to watch
the track meet.
Not long after, this
thing happened in the parking lot.
Behold! The Underminer!
I am always beneath you,
but nothing is beneath me!
As if things aren't weird
enough,
I look over and I see these
boots.
You two, stay here.
Wait.
Should we be doing this?
It is still illegal.
They looked like superheroes.
We're gonna lose him.
Oh, all right.
One of you patrol
the perimeter,
keep the crowds
back and safe.
The other,
watch after Jack-Jack.
But I thought
we were gonna
go with
You heard your mother.
Trampoline me.
I call perimeter!
You're not going anywhere,
you little
maggoty creep!
I see my chance
to get out of there.
But there's something
familiar about
one of the kids' voices.
The girl, she's upset
and she throws down
her mask
and it's her!
Oh. Tony!
Hi.
Uh, this isn't
what you think it is.
It was just getting
too freaky.
I couldn't handle it
and ran off.
I feel kinda bad about it.
Maybe I should've said
"hi" or something?
It's not her fault
superheroes are illegal.
And it's not like
I don't like strong girls.
I'm pretty secure
manhood wise.
What is that?
Have you told anyone else about this?
Your parents?
No, they'd only think
I was hiding something.
You know what I mean?
Sure, kid.
I like this girl,
Mr. Dicker.
I'm supposed to go out with her
Friday night.
Now, things are just gonna
be weird.
I wish I could forget
I ever saw her in that suit.
You will, kid.
You will.
*INCREDIBLES 2*
Come on!
Consider yourself
undermined!
Ooh.
Underminer!
Oh!
We meet again Huh?
Oh, great!
Now,
he's on the agenda.
Incredible!
Meet Jack Hammer!
Buh-bye!
No, no, no!
Everybody, stay back!
Okay? Stay back!
You're not sticking me
with babysitting!
I can't steer it or stop it.
And the Underminer's escaped!
We'll have to stop it
Bob! The monorail!
Frozone!
Yeah!
We have to stop
this thing
before it gets
to the overpass!
I'll try to keep it away
from the buildings!
Hey, lady!
Thank you so much,
young man!
What?
Violet!
Oh, oh. Ahh!
Stop!
Everybody, stop!
Ah, hah!
Heads up, Dad!
Dash!
Violet!
Who's watching Jack-Jack?
Dash is watching him!
Violet,
here, you take him!
It's headed for City Hall!
Mom needs help!
They're out in public again!
This is our chance!
Follow them,
follow Frozone!
Bob!
Help me with the boiler!
That should do it!
What are you kids doing?
Get out of here!
This thing's gonna blow!
There's no time!
We did it!
Freeze, Supers!
Oh, what did we do?
Excuse me,
Mr. Zone?
Sorry,
but I'm not really supposed to be here.
Which seems wrong
doesn't it?
Perhaps you'd be interested in
changing that law?
Superheroes including Frozone,
Mr. Incredible,
and Elasti Girl
caused further damage
to the city.
The Underminer
remains at large.
We didn't start
this fight.
Well, you didn't
finish it either!
Did you stop the Underminer
from inflicting more damage?
No.
Did you stop him
from robbing the banks?
No.
Did you catch him?
The banks were insured.
We have infrastructure
in place
to deal
with these matters.
If you had simply
done nothing
everything would now be
proceeding
in an orderly fashion.
You'd have preferred
we do nothing?
Without a doubt.
You weren't much help.
Do you want
out of the hole?
First you gotta
put down the shovel.
Well, that went poorly.
Dad, this is probably
not the best time
to tell you about this
but something else
happened today with a kid
and my mask.
Oh, hey, Rick.
Violet thinks a friend of hers,
a kid named Tony
might have seen her
in the outfit,
without her mask.
Talkative type?
Don't know.
Last name is Rydinger.
Tony Rydinger.
I'll check it out.
Bob, Helen
a word
if you don't mind.
Uh, the program's been
shut down.
What?
Politicians don't
understand people
who do good simply
because it's right.
It makes 'em nervous.
They've been gunning for Supers
for years.
Today was all they needed.
Anyway
I'm done.
I'm afraid two more
weeks in the motel
is the best
I can do for ya.
It ain't much.
You've done plenty, Rick.
We won't forget.
Well, it has been
a great honor
working with
you good people.
Thanks for everything,
and good luck.
Yeah.
You, too.
Did you wash your hands?
With soap?
Did you dry them?
What?
Is this all vegetables?
Who ordered all vegetables?
I did. They're good
and you're going to have some.
Are we going
to talk about it?
What?
The elephant in the room.
What elephant?
I guess not then.
You're referring
to today.
Yeah, what's the deal
with today?
We all made mistakes.
For example,
you kids were supposed
to watch Jack-Jack.
Babysitting,
while you guys did the important stuff.
We talked about this.
You're not old enough
to decide about these things.
We are old enough
to help out.
Yeah!
Isn't that
what you tell us, Dad?
Yeah, well,
"help out" can
mean many different things.
But we're supposed to help,
if there's trouble. Aren't you glad
Well, yeah, but
we helped today?
Yeah, I know but
You said that you were
proud of us.
Well, yeah,
I was. Am!
We wanna fight
bad guys!
No, you don't!
You said things
were different now.
And they were,
on the island.
But I didn't mean
that from now on
So now, we've gotta go back
to never using our powers.
It defines who I am.
We're not saying
you have
What?
Someone on TV said it.
Can we just eat?
The dinner, while it's hot?
Did we do
something wrong?
Yes.
No.
We didn't do
anything wrong.
Superheroes are illegal.
Whether it's fair or not,
that's the law.
The law should be fair.
What are we teaching our kids?
To respect the law!
Even when the law
is disrespectful?
If laws are unjust,
there are laws to change them!
Otherwise, it's chaos!
Which is exactly
what we have!
I just thought
it was kinda cool.
What was?
Fighting crime
as a family.
It was cool.
But it's over.
The world is what it is.
We have to adapt.
Are things bad?
Things are fine.
May I be excused?
How much longer
in the motel, Dad?
Uh
Not much longer, honey.
What are we gonna do?
I don't know.
Maybe Dicker will find something?
Dicker is done, Bob.
Any thought we had about being
Supers again is fantasy.
One of us
has gotta get a job.
One of us?
You did a long stint
at Insuricare.
Hated every minute of it.
I know
it was hard on you.
Maybe it's my turn
in the private sector
and you take care of the kids
No, I'm doing this.
I need to do this.
You know where my suit
and ties are?
Burned up when
The jet destroyed our house.
Yeah.
We can't count
on anyone else now, Bob.
It's just us.
We can't wait for
No lifeguard on duty!
Swim at your own risk.
Oh, where'd you go today?
I noticed
you missed all the fun.
Don't be mad because
I know when to leave a party.
I'm just as illegal
as you guys.
Besides, I knew the cops
would let you go.
Yeah, in spite
of Bob's best efforts.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I heard
the program shut down.
How much longer
are you in this motel?
Two weeks.
Now, you know
the offer still stands.
You're very generous,
but there are five of us.
We wouldn't do that
to you and Honey.
Well, door's always open.
You know,
the news isn't all bad.
While you guys
were being detained
I was approached by a dude
who represents this tycoon.
Winston Deavor.
Wants to talk
with me, with you two,
about hero stuff.
I checked him out.
He's legit.
Trained under Dicker.
He wants to meet.
Ah, jeez!
More superhero trouble.
We just came from
the police station, Lucius.
When?
Tonight. I'm going there now.
You enjoy,
I'm sitting this one out.
He wants
all three of us.
Honey, let's just at least
hear what he has to say.
You got the address,
I'll meet you guys there.
Go in our Supersuits?
Yeah.
Might wanna wear
the old Supersuits.
Got a feeling
he's nostalgic.
Where are you going?
The fresh air
is especially good tonight.
If Jack-Jack
wakes up
I know the drill.
Your security badges.
Please, this way.
Hey, listen,
you're my biggest fan.
Good to see you.
I'm your biggest fan.
Shoot!
I love superheroes!
The powers, the costumes
the mythic struggles.
Winston Deavor.
You can call me Win.
Genuine pleasure
to meet you.
Frozone!
It's good to see you.
Elasti Girl.
Nice to meet you.
Mr. Incredible!
Hello.
Mr. Incredible,
Incredible
Catching the bad guys
Pow, pow, pow
Who's the cat
Who's always chill
When survival odds
are close to nil
Frozone
Yeah!
Can't tell you what a thrill this is.
And this
Oh, hello there, superheroes.
I'm so sorry I'm late.
is my tardy sister,
Evelyn.
And I'm
I'm scolding myself
so you don't have to, Winston!
Spectacular.
My father was so proud
that I was even remotely
connected to you guys.
He used to call you
the last line of defense.
He was
your top supporter.
He donated
to superhero causes.
He raised money
for the
Dynaguy statue
in Avery Park.
He got to know
many Supers personally.
Even installed a phone
with direct lines
to Gazerbeam and Fironic
in case of emergencies.
He loved that,
showed it off to everyone.
He was heartbroken
when you were all forced
to go underground.
Father believed
the world
would become more dangerous
without you.
He didn't know
how right he was.
There was a break in.
My father called Gazerbeam.
The direct line.
No answer.
He called Fironic, no answer.
Superheroes had just been
made illegal
The robbers discovered him
on the phone
and shot him.
So
It must've been hard.
Especially for Mother.
She died a few months later.
Heartbreak.
If superheroes had not been
forced underground
it never would've happened.
Or Dad could've taken
Mom to the safe room
as soon as he knew
there was
trouble.
I disagree strongly!
But we're not going
into it right now.
The point is
nobody expected us
to be able to actually
run Dad's company.
But with Evelyn as designer,
and myself as operator
uh, we threw ourselves
into building DEVTECH
into what it is today.
A world class
telecommunications company.
Bigger than ever.
Perfectly positioned
to make
some wrong things right.
Hence, this meeting.
Let me
ask you something.
What is the main reason
you were all
forced underground?
Ignorance.
Perception.
Take today for example,
with the Underminer.
Difficult situation.
You were faced
with a lot of hard decisions.
Oh, tell me about it.
I can't.
Because I didn't see it
neither did anyone else.
So, when you fight bad
guys like today
people don't see the fight
or what led up to it.
They see what politicians
tell them to see.
They see destruction
and they see you.
So, if we wanna change
people's perceptions
about superheroes
we need you
to share your perceptions
with the world.
How do we do that?
With cameras.
We need you to share
your perceptions with the world.
How do we do that?
We embed tiny cameras, like those,
into your Supersuits.
Wow, so small.
And the picture
is outstanding.
Thanks!
Designed 'em myself.
We've got resources, lobbyists,
worldwide connections
and very important,
insurance.
Insurance is key.
All we need now
are the superest superheroes.
It needs you three.
Come on!
Help me make all Supers
legal again.
This sounds great!
Let's get this going.
What's my first assignment?
That enthusiasm is golden.
Now hold on to it.
But for our first move
Well, Elasti Girl
is our best play.
Better than me?
I mean, she's good.
Really, a credit to her
You know.
With great respect
let's not test the whole
"insurance will pay for everything"
idea
on the first go 'round, okay?
Wait a minute.
You're saying what? I'm messy?
Well, Evelyn did
a cost benefit analysis
comparing all your last
five years of crime fighting
before going underground.
And Elasti Girl's numbers
are self explanatory.
Well, it's not
a fair comparison!
Heavyweight problems
need heavyweight solutions.
Of course!
We're gonna solve
all kinds
of problems together.
After the perfect launch
with Elasti Girl!
So, what do you say?
What do I say?
I don't know.
What do you mean,
you don't know?
A few hours ago,
you were saying it was over
and being a superhero
was a fantasy.
Now, you get the offer
of a lifetime
and you don't know?
It's not that simple, Bob.
I wanna protect the kids!
So do I.
From jail, Bob!
And how do you do that?
By turning down a chance
to change the law
that forces them to hide
what they are?
They haven't decided what they are.
They're still kids.
Kids with powers,
which makes them Supers
whether they decide
to use those powers or not.
This will benefit them.
What? It's not a good time
to be away.
Dash is having trouble
with homework
Vi is worried
about her first date
with that boy she likes,
Tony
and Jack-Jack
Jack-Jack?
What's wrong with him?
Okay, nothing's wrong
with Jack-Jack.
But even a normal baby
needs a lot of attention.
I'm just not sure
I can leave.
Of course
you can leave.
You've got to.
So that I
we can be Supers again,
so our kids can have
that choice.
So you can have that choice.
All right, yes!
So I can have
that choice.
And I would do a great job!
Regardless of what Deavor's
pie charts say or whatever
But they want you.
And you'll do a great
job
too.
Well, that was excruciating to watch.
I can't lie to you.
It's nice to be wanted.
Flattering, you know,
but
But what's the choice?
One, do this right,
get well paid,
we're out of the motel
and things get better
for all Supers,
including our kids.
Or two
I find a job in two weeks
or we're homeless.
You know
it's crazy, right?
To help my family,
I gotta leave it.
To fix the law, I gotta break it.
You'll be great.
I know I will.
But what about you?
We have kids.
I'll watch the kids,
no problem.
Easy.
Easy, huh?
You're adorable.
Well, if there is
a problem,
I'll drop this thing
and come right back.
You won't need to.
I got it,
you go do this thing.
Do it so
I can do it better.
Deavor here.
This is Elasti Girl.
I'm in.
Mr. Deavor,
it's wonderful
but it's too generous.
Nonsense!
That's the least we can do.
We're partners now!
Can't have my partners
living in a motel.
But whose house?
Is it a house?
It's my house.
I have several.
I'm not using that one.
Stay as long as you need.
I don't know
what to say.
How about "thanks"?
This is our new house?
Okay, easy, tiger.
It's being loaned to us.
This is homey.
Look at this place.
Deavor bought it from
an eccentric billionaire
who liked to come and go
without being seen
so the house has
multiple hidden exits.
Good thing
we won't stand out.
Wouldn't want to attract
any unnecessary attention.
It's got a big yard!
Isn't this a bit much?
Near a forest!
Would you rather be
at the motel?
And a pool!
What exactly
is Mom's new job?
The important thing is
we're out of the motel.
I like Mom's new job!
Oh, ho, ho!
Whoa.
Well, check out
the water features.
Oh!
Wow.
Wicked cool!
Hey! Dash! Stop it!
Not the couch! Stop it!
No! Dash!
Stop!
Don't touch the buttons!
The couch!
Dash!
No!
No, no!
Oh, no. Oh, boy.
This isn't me.
I'm not all dark
and angsty.
I'm Elasti Girl.
I'm, you know,
flexible.
I mean, look at this.
E designed this?
No, some guy named
Alexander Galbaki.
Glad it's you and not me,
'cause you're gonna
hear from her.
This note came with it.
What?
A new Elasticycle.
Elasticycle?
I didn't know you had a bike.
Hey, I had a mohawk.
There's a lot about me
you don't know.
Yeah, but
A mohawk?
Ah, you didn't miss anything.
Oh, yeah!
This one's electric.
What's that mean?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Means it's torque-y.
I'll get the hang of it.
You will be great.
I will be great.
And you will, too.
We will both be great.
Bye, sweetie.
Wait a minute!
Is that Elasti Girl?
I think that's Elasti Girl.
Hey! Elasti Girl!
Marry me, Elasti Girl!
Here comes Elasti Girl
No theme songs
Stretching her
or I'll turn this bus
right around!
Look at that.
New Urbem.
You wanna make a big
crime fighting statement
you go where
the crime is big.
Strange thing to be
excited about, Winston.
It's like
a superhero's playground!
No Sugar Bombs
on my watch.
Where's Mom?
She's up and out.
She's at her new job
doing hero work.
But I thought superheroes
were still illegal.
They are, for now.
So Mom is getting paid
to break the law?
She's not breaking
She's an advocate
for superheroes.
It's a new job.
So, Mom is going out
illegally
to explain why
she shouldn't be illegal.
Hey Hey!
The bus is here!
Whoa! Grab your stuff quickly!
Go on, get on the
Put your homework
in your pack!
Bye-bye!
We're gonna get along
just fine
'cause you don't ask any hard questions.
All right. All locations,
we need to know
where you want us.
Stand by.
Seems strange
to wait for crime.
Relax.
You're smack in the middle
of the worst crime area in the city.
It's perfect.
It's a superhero's playground.
"It's a superhero's
playground." Right.
You know,
after we went underground
my husband used to listen
to a police scanner
waiting for something
to happen.
And I got mad at him
for it.
Oh, I'm such a hypocrite.
All units.
Something's up.
We've been picking up
some chatter about
potential disruptions to the
hovertrain's opening ceremony.
Disruption or threat?
Both.
Station's at Fifty Fourth
and Nottingham.
A potential threat!
Perfect!
Fifty fourth and Nottingham.
Go, go, go!
Hey, Vi! I want you
back here by 10:30.
11-ish?
10-ish,
heading for 9:30-ish.
10:30-ish it is.
Enjoy the movie.
"In the county of Noddoff
"the Frubbers of Freep
"are all giving in
to the sweet succor of sleep."
We will control the horizontal
we will control the vertical.
That's not the way
you're supposed to do it, Dad.
They want us
to do it this way.
I don't know that way!
Why would they change math?
It's okay, Dad.
Math is math! Math is math!
I'll just wait for Mom
to get back.
What?
She won't understand it
any better than I do
The Outer Limits.
"All over Doozle Dorf,
"the Fribbers of Frupp
are going to sleep
"'cause they just
can't keep up.
"All over Doozle Dorf,
Doozles are dozing.
"Eyelids so heavy,
they're drooping.
"Closing! The point is:
"Everyone,
everyone's hitting the sack!
"Everyone's getting the sleep
that they lack."
Mayors often brag
about their cities
and I'm no exception.
And I'm willing to admit
that New Urbem
is not the only city
Are you sure the police are
gonna be okay with this?
Sure. You're making
life easy for them.
They still haven't
forgiven us
for the last time we made
life easy for them.
I know the Chief of Police.
There won't be a problem.
With all due respect
if you alone had handled
the Underminer
things would have
been different.
I'm just saying.
on budget
and ahead of schedule
to launch our magnificent
new hovertrain.
It can get you
where you need to go
at ridiculous speeds.
The future is open
for business!
Wait. The train has stopped.
It's going
the wrong direction.
It's going the wrong way.
I'm going after it.
This thing's really moving.
100 and climbing.
How much track is built?
About 25 miles.
No one can shut
this thing down?
They've tried. No-go.
Is that Elasti Girl?
Overrides?
They're locked out
of the system.
What about a fail safe?
Not enough time.
Someone's calling!
Switching over.
Hey, Mom.
I can't find my high tops
and Dad
can't find them either.
But he won't call you
and ask, so I am.
Do not call your mother!
Dash, honey.
Can't talk right now.
Look under your bed, okay.
How much time?
Less than two minutes!
There's a shortcut. Cut
through the culvert up ahead.
I don't know
if I can stay with it.
What the heck was that?
Is everybody all right?
Is anybody injured?
Are you all right?
Your story better be good.
Hey. Hey!
What happened?
Honey, why are you
Don't say anything.
It's Dad.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
I don't wanna talk about it.
Tony didn't even call?
Oh, honey
Dad!
If you want me to feel better,
then leave me alone.
Please?
See, there's nothing
a cop hates worse
than a missing child.
My kid brother's son.
Today is his first birthday.
Oh, but if anybody
can find that child, it's you, Roman.
Because you're
a wonderful policeman.
This is a holdup.
All right, get your hands up,
turn your back.
Put your hands behind
your heads
and keep them there!
Don't move!
Drop that.
All right, now get over there.
Watch the door.
You think I'm kiddin'?
Now.
I said now!
I got it!
Come on, I tell you, come on!
You wanna get killed?
Uh-oh.
No, no, no!
No!
No, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
You have powers!
Yeah, baby,
and there's not
a scratch on you!
Did you go through
the locked door?
Are those your powers?
Who can multiply
like rabbits
and go right through
any solid
Oh, my God!
Hello?
Hey, honey.
You weren't gonna call me?
Oh, hey!
No. I mean, yes, yeah
I just didn't wanna wake you.
The strangest thing just
happened out in the yard.
Sounds like I just
woke you up.
No, no.
It's just, Jack-Jack
He had an accident!
I knew it!
I'm coming home right now!
I never should have
No, no, no, accident.
Stay there and finish your mission.
You never should-should
wh-what?
You don't think I can do this?
No, no.
Sorry. I misspoke.
Do you need me
to come back?
No, no. No, I've got this.
Everything's great.
What happened
with Jack-Jack?
Nothing.
He's in excellent health.
Well, that's good.
How was Violet's date?
Uh
That was tonight, right?
Yes. Good.
All fine and good.
And Jack-Jack went down
with no trouble?
Fine, yes, no trouble.
And Dash got
his homework done?
All done.
So, things haven't
spiraled out
of control
the moment I left?
Amazing as it may seem,
it has been
quite uneventful in fact.
How about you?
I saved a runaway train!
It was so great!
The mayor was there to cut
the ribbon on this new train.
Elasti Girl pursued the train
and was able
to successfully activate
Blah, blah, blah. He says a
few words, cuts the ribbon
and the train starts pulling
out of the station
backwards
track of its brand new hovertrain
hovertrain malfunctioned
thanking Elasti Girl
..deemed to almost
Superhero Elasti Girl
Elasti Girl
Boom! No casualties!
specialized motorbike,
saving all of
the passengers
One thing leads to another
and suddenly,
I go after it!
I'm telling you, honey,
it was a saga!
That's fantastic, honey!
And on your first night!
I am so proud of you, really.
I'm proud of you, honey.
I know you want to get out
there and you will soon.
And you'll be amazing.
I couldn't have done this
if you hadn't taken over so well.
Thanks for handling
everything.
It's nothing.
I love you, honey.
I'll be back soon.
Sweet dreams.
Sweet dreams, honey.
"Hey, Dad, it's okay.
"I'll just wait for Mom
to get home."
As if she could
I know how to
I can do math.
Oh, brother
Wait for Mom!
What am I,
a substitute parent?
It's not my fault
they changed math.
Come on, buddy.
Come on.
I think I understand
your math assignment.
We still have some time
to finish it before your test.
So first, you wanna put
all the numbers
by themselves on one side.
you change the sign.
That means a plus becomes
a minus and a minus
You got it?
Yeah, baby!
Oh. Uh, hello.
We're in a new house.
I did write my address
on your locker
in permanent ink.
Oh, is that what that is?
Did you forget?
Forget what?
That's funny.
Points for funny.
Oh, was it
the weird outfit?
Because there's a reason.
I'm in a drama class
and they just wanna do
Shakespeare
but they're like,
"Try to make it relevant for the kids."
So, like, "Oh, superheroes!
Kids love superheroes."
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
You wanna wear
one kind of tights
and then they're like,
"No, wear these
other kind of tights."
Do I know you?
Many say your speech
today is critical.
Both sides just want the
best for their people.
We are so close to finally
getting peace in the region.
I haven't done this
in a while.
This is good.
The train gives us momentum.
Just go out there and
be your charming self
and capitalize on it.
Ms. Elasti Girl,
they're ready for you.
Hey, stretch a leg.
Thank you, Chad.
It was fun.
Ambassador, your documents.
We're moving to the rooftop.
Oh, Madame Ambassador,
hello!
Oh, you are Elasti Girl!
This is why now
I'm shaking your hand.
It was so sad
when you went underground.
I am glad to see you back
in your shiny outfit.
That means so much
coming from you.
Good luck with your speech.
This way, Ambassador.
Uh, uh. Bring lasting peace!
I will,
when you defeat evil.
Okay.
Three, two
For over 15 years,
superheroes have been
in hiding.
Forced into it
by a society
no longer willing
to support them.
That may soon be changing
due to a growing movement
to bring the Supers back.
Here, fresh on the heels
of her own
heroic save
of a runaway train
and sporting a new look,
is the superhero, Elasti Girl.
Welcome!
Hello, Chad.
All the polls are going
in your direction.
That's true.
Things are good
Hello.
Uh, hello?
Do I have your attention?
Yes, Chad.
Of course I do.
I'm appearing
on your screen.
Reading the words I'm saying
off of another screen.
Screens are everywhere.
We are controlled by screens.
And screens
are controlled by me
Screenslaver.
Hey!
I control this broadcast
and this idiotic anchorman
you see before you.
What's wrong with him?
The signal's been hijacked.
I'll check it out.
Don't look at any monitors.
I could hijack
the ambassador's aerocade
while it's still airborne.
Right, Elasti Girl?
Nearest window!
Where's the nearest window?
Oh, what's going on?
Where's Elasti Girl?
Which one?
Elasti Girl!
What are you doing here?
The ambassador is in danger.
Which chopper is she
Look out!
Follow them
and get me close!
Get out of the sky,
and touch down safely!
Stand down! It's Elasti Girl.
Stay in your seat, ma'am!
We're under attack!
Quick, go!
Protect the ambassador!
Open the door!
Do as she says!
Can you all swim?
Yeah.
No!
We're gonna have
to slingshot! Hang on!
Are you all right, ma'am?
I'm perfectly fine
Ah! Ooh! Ah! Oh!
Boys are jerks
and superheroes suck.
Good morning!
He takes one look
at me in that suit
and decides to pretend
he doesn't even know me.
Well.
He's protecting himself.
If he really did see you,
it's best that he forget.
It's better for you, too.
Um. I can't I can't tell you
how many memories
Dicker's had to erase
over the years
when someone figured out
your mother's
or my identity.
It was Dicker!
You told him about Tony!
Honey
You had me erased
from Tony's mind!
I hate superheroes!
And I renounce them!
I renounce them!
Is she having adolescence?
A new report out today shows that,
when it comes
to decision making
people have more trust
in a monkey
throwing darts than Congress.
What's going on, Tommy?
A protest?
They're here in support.
Support?
Support of what?
Well, in support of you.
Wow. Oh, hey
Thanks for coming out.
Hi.
Oh, my goodness.
Thanks so much.
Oh, hello.
What does your sign say?
Ka-boom! Ka-pow!
Supers should be legal now!
Talk to ya.
Oh, what do ya know!
Ellenwood.
Oh, now you wanna
return my calls
about superheroes, huh?
Oh. I'll have to
call you back.
Oh, that felt good.
Felicia, hold my calls,
please.
Eh! Hey!
It's working!
Hey, the ambassador
made a big speech
about superheroes today.
Turns out
saving someone's life
makes a good impression on them.
Who knew, huh?
I'm getting calls
from all over the world.
Media awareness
is up 72%.
The push
for superhero legalization
is becoming
a worldwide movement!
I have big plans
for our next move.
We're gonna have
a summit at sea.
We'll use our ship
we'll gather leaders
and Supers
from all over the world.
That's great.
I'm happy.
I'm happy
the numbers are up.
I'm happy the ambassador
is pro superhero
and I'm happy
you're happy.
I'm hearing that you're happy,
but
why am I not feeling it?
Because I didn't get him!
Screenslaver
is still out there.
All I did was play his game
and win this round.
He's gonna want more
and as long as
he gets to play, he wins.
One thing
I've learned in business?
Smell the flowers.
They don't bloom that often.
What do you want
on your tombstone?
"She worried a lot"?
All right, stop talking.
Show her.
This is just so exciting, isn't it?
Huh?
Oh, wow. Uh
Wow! Elasti Girl,
there you are.
Hello.
I didn't
Wow!
Come on, get yourself
together, Karen.
Hi, my superhero name
is Voyd.
I just wanna thank you,
for, like, for being you!
I'm just no, I just like the
Okay, what I can do,
um, is this.
Yeah.
That is impressive.
Very interdimensional.
I felt like
an outcast before.
But now, with you being
you, I feel like
Yay, me.
I flew them in
from all over.
They've all been
in hiding.
They have powers,
secret identities
and names
they've given themselves.
I'm Screech.
It's a pleasure.
I've always considered you
the gold standard
for superheroes.
Well, thanks.
You're too nice.
I am called Brick.
Nice to meet you, Brick.
Uh, where are you from?
Wisconsin.
Oh. Elasti Girl.
I assume your powers are
You know,
zapping things electrically
charging things, bolts of lightning,
that kind of stuff.
Name's Reflux.
Medical condition or
superpower, you decide.
That's a little line
I say just to put
people at ease.
Hope I don't offend.
Oh, no, no, no.
Reflux. Love it.
Well, I do look forward
to working with you.
Yes, that is impressive.
Keep practicing.
Ow!
Well, I'm beat. Congratulations.
Big day.
Good night, ladies.
I will see you tomorrow.
Good night.
Must be nice for you,
being out front
after all this time.
Out front?
Well, it's been a while
since your superhero days
and even then,
you were kind of
in Mr. Incredible's
shadow.
Nah, I beg to differ.
I'm not I'm not
saying you weren't big.
No, you were,
and are, a superstar
but you have the stage
to yourself now.
And people have
to pay attention.
Oh, you mean,
"It's a man's world" and all that?
Well, what world
do you live in?
Your brother runs DEVTECH.
I don't want his job.
I invent, he sells.
I ask you,
which of us has the greater influence?
Which side of me
are you asking?
The believer or the cynic?
The cynic
Would say selling
is more important, because
the best sellers
have the most buyers.
Doesn't matter
what you're selling.
It only matters
what people buy.
This is true.
If I discovered the
origin of the universe
my brother
would find a way
to market it as a,
uh, foot massager.
So, what would
the believer say?
The believer would tell you
to make your mark.
Don't wait for permission,
assert yourself
and impose your will
on the status quo.
Sounds like my brother.
What?
You sound like my brother.
Well, he's not wrong.
There is an art
to getting a reaction
Oh! I know how to get him.
My brother?
No. Screenslaver!
You're tech savvy.
I need to lock onto a signal
and trace its origin.
How fast
can you slap something together
and meet me at the airport?
Airport?
Need to go
out of town, pronto.
I can get your contraption
together by 5:00 a.m.
I need to get on TV.
Chad!
I'll get my brother to set up
an exclusive with him
tonight on the newscast.
Finish our interview by phone!
Promote the hell out of it.
Independence
from Screenslavery!
Chad tonight.
Boom!
Dicker.
Yeah, hey, Rick.
You remember that kid
I mentioned to you?
Tony Rydinger.
Mind wipe?
Yeah, nice kid.
Well, you also wiped out
the Friday night date
my daughter had with him.
In fact,
you wiped out my daughter.
Oops.
Not an exact science, Bob.
Rick, you gotta help me here.
Violet hates me, and you,
and superheroes.
I gotta fix this.
What do you know about Tony?
Um
Not much.
Seems like a good kid.
Popular,
plays sports, music.
Parents own The Happy Platter,
kid works there part time.
Happy Platter?
Why did we drive
all the way across town
for The Happy Platter?
We'd like a booth over there,
near the philodendron.
Good, right?
Near the philodendron.
This platter doesn't look
all that happy to me.
It looks bored.
Ha-ha!
The Bored Platter!
I thought Vi would want
a change of pace
from drive in food.
I like drive in food.
Does this mean vegetables?
A balanced diet
means vegetables, kiddo.
Get used to it.
Good evening, everyone.
Oh, no!
Is she all right?
Violet, are you okay?
Nothing to see here.
Yeah, more napkins would be good.
I'm fine,
I'm fine.
It happens all the time here.
Mops it right up.
Normally, she doesn't
ever drip like this.
Would you like water, sir?
Yes.
Yes, I would.
This is my daughter
who you must know, right?
God. Stop.
Hello.
Violet.
Hello, Violet.
Hey, Vi, say hi to
Don't push it, Dad.
I'm Dash,
her little brother.
Hello.
Mmm.
This is really good water.
It's very refreshing.
Spring water, is it?
I don't know, sir.
I think it's tap.
Well, it is very good.
Excellent tap.
Excuse me.
Well, nice to meet you.
Where'd she go?
Mmm.
To find a good place
to be angry?
Tonight, we go now
to a special remote interview
with Elasti Girl.
How you feeling, Chad?
You doing all right?
I'm fine.
The doctors checked me out.
I have no memory of the event.
I gotta tell you,
it's pretty strange
to see a recording
of yourself
the night before
and have no recollection.
I don't think
anyone needs to worry.
We've taken many precautions
tonight though.
Where are you right now?
On a case, in a secure
undisclosed location.
I wanna talk about you
starting with your save
of a runaway train.
Here's an exclusive
unedited clip
from your own suit cam.
Roll the clip.
This thing's really moving.
100 and climbing.
How much track is built?
About 25 miles.
The Screenslaver
interrupts this program
for an important announcement.
I'll be damned. She knew.
Let's see
if your gadget works.
Don't bother
watching the rest.
Gotcha!
Elasti Girl doesn't
save the day.
She only postpones
her defeat.
And while she postpones
her defeat
you eat chips and
watch her confront problems
that you are too lazy
to deal with.
Superheroes are
part of your brainless desire
to replace true experience
with simulation.
You don't talk,
you watch talk shows.
You don't play games,
you watch game shows.
Travel, relationships, risk
every meaningful experience
must be packaged
and delivered to you
to watch at a distance.
So that you can remain
ever sheltered
ever passive
ever ravenous consumers
who can't bring themselves
to rise from their couches
break a sweat
and participate in life.
You want superheroes
to protect you
and make yourselves ever more
powerless in the process.
While you tell yourselves
you're being looked after.
That your interests
are being served.
And your rights
are being upheld.
So that the system can
keep stealing from you
smiling at you all the while.
Go ahead,
send your Supers to stop me.
Grab your snacks,
watch your screens,
and see what happens.
You are no longer in control.
I am.
Find anything?
Sorry!
What happened?
What happened is
you destroyed my evidence.
What's going on?
What did I do?
What did you guys do to me?
That's right, punk.
Blame the system.
Your tracker worked
like a charm, Evelyn.
You're a genius.
Aw, shucks!
I'm just the genius
behind the genius.
Hey, Dad.
We're doing fractions
and denismals and percentages
and I don't get 'em.
Aren't you
Didn't we get all caught up?
Yeah, we were caught up
and now we're doing fractions
and percentages and demicels.
Decimals.
the addition of the Incredibile,
the super car
once driven by superhero,
Mr. Incredible.
It's the kind of thing you buy
when you have everything else.
They said it was
beyond repair.
Hey, it was in perfect condition.
You used to
drive that?
They said it was destroyed.
Long thought lost
or destroyed,
the famous car
turned up at private auction.
They said it was
That's my car!
Stupid water feature!
This car is just loaded
with amazing gadgets.
Care to demonstrate?
I'd love to, but we haven't figured out
how to make them work yet.
Wow! It works?
Huh?
What are you doing?
This is not a toy!
That's a rocket launcher!
Sweet! Which one launches
the rocket?
Hey!
This is not your car!
It's not your car, either!
It is so!
It's the Incredibile.
Why's that guy have it?
He shouldn't!
Launch the rockets!
I'm not
launching anything!
Launch the rockets!
Do you think I want an angry
I wanna blow it up!
Rich guy coming after me
right now
when I'm trying not to
I'm not sure
what's happened here, Mark.
..distract
But everyone here has scattered
..your
and I'm afraid I'll need to move
..mother.
At any minute.
Rich guy got my car.
So, you're not gonna
steal your car
back from the rich guy?
What the heck is that?
Jack-Jack has powers?
Well, yeah, but
You knew about this?
Yeah.
Why didn't you tell us?
I don't know.
We're your kids.
We need to know
these things.
Did you tell Mom?
No. Your mother
Why not?
You'd want us to tell you,
wouldn't you? Is not talking
Why would you not tell Mom?
Because I didn't wanna
What? Come on, man.
Because it's not the time.
Why?
Because So uncool!
Because I'm formulating, okay?
I'm taking in information,
I'm processing!
I'm doing the math,
I'm fixing the boyfriend
and keeping the baby from
turning into a flaming monster!
How do I do it?
By rolling with
the punches, baby!
I eat thunder
and crap lightning, okay?
'Cause I'm Mr. Incredible!
Not Mr. So-So
or Mr. Mediocre Guy.
Mr. Incredible!
We should call Lucius.
No. I can handle it.
There's no way I'm gonna
Dada.
I'm calling Lucius.
Looks normal to me.
When did this start happening?
Since Helen got the job.
I assume she knows?
Are you kidding?
I can't tell her
about this,
not while she's doing
hero work!
Mama!
Girls, come on.
Leave the saving the world
to the men?
I don't think so.
Mama!
I've got to succeed!
So she can succeed.
So we can succeed!
I get it, Bob!
I get it.
When was the last time you slept?
Who keeps track of that?
Besides, he's a baby.
I can handle it,
I got this handled.
So, you good then?
You got everything
under control? Right?
What the?
Cookie!
Cha Cha want a cookie?
Num-num cookie?
Cha Cha wanna num-num?
Num-num cookie! Cookie!
You're not
Cookie!
Oh, my God!
Dada! Dada. Dada.
Whoa.
Okay! Okay.
So, he can still
hear you
from the
From the other dimension, yeah.
That is freaky.
I mean, that's not like
Not like our other kids.
No, it is not.
Full powers, totally random.
So now, he's what?
Is he good?
Yeah, you'd think so,
right?
Obviously,
I can't keep giving him cookies!
Uh-uh?
But if I stop
Ahhh! He is freaking!
Again, he is freaking!
No biting the daddy!
What the?
No biting!
Okay.
I think I just need
a little bit of me time.
Then I'll be good to go.
Oh, you need
more than me time, Bob.
You need
major life realignment
on a number of levels.
Starting with
baby superfreak here!
You need some solid
outside the box thinking.
Galbaki?
Elasti Girl's supersuit
is by Galbaki?
Explain yourself!
Oh, my God.
You're worse than I thought.
It's the baby.
I brought the baby.
Oh, highly unusual.
You look ghastly, Robert.
I haven't been sleeping.
I broke my daughter,
they keep changing math
we needed double-A batteries,
but I got triple-A's
and now we still need
double-A batteries.
I put one red thing
in a load of whites
and now
everything's pink.
And I think
we need eggs.
Done properly,
parenting is a heroic act.
Done properly.
I am fortunate that it has
never afflicted me.
But you do not come to me
for eggs and batteries,
Robert.
I design herowear
and Elasti Girl
must have a new suit.
Actually, it's Jack-Jack.
You also wish
a new suit for the baby?
I would hardly classify
this as an emergency.
Well, he's a special case.
Worth studying.
If I could just leave him
with you
for a while
Leave him? Here?
I am not a baby person,
Robert.
I have no baby facilities.
I am an artist.
I do not involve myself
in the prosaic day-to-day to
day.
Fascinating!
AA-Are you seeing this, Robert?
Dada.
Oh, my God.
Yes!
Of course you can leave
the baby overnight.
I'm sure filling in
for Helen is challenging,
and you are very tired
and the other children
need you
and miss you,
and you must go to them.
Auntie Edna will take care
of everything
so, drive safely and goodbye.
I enjoy our visits.
"Auntie Edna"?
Attention. Attention.
I wanna thank everyone
that came out tonight
in support of superheroes
and bringing them
back into society!
You all made it happen.
The need for this
has been made
crystal clear
in recent days
with bad actors
like the self proclaimed
Screenslaver
threatening our peace.
His reign was short, huh?
And thanks to this woman
a great super. You love her.
You missed her.
Welcome back, Elasti Girl.
Come on up here.
Don't be bashful.
Come on. Get up here.
I want you to have this.
A memento.
Thanks, Winston, Evelyn,
and everyone at DEVTECH.
I am forever in your debt.
And thanks to all of you,
your pressure
changed all the right minds.
We've made amazing headway
in a very short time
which leads me
to an important announcement.
Just now,
at a worldwide summit
leaders from
more than a hundred
of the world's
top countries
have agreed to make
superheroes legal again!
We'll gather superheroes
and leaders
from all over
the planet
on our boat,
the Everjust
for a televised
signing ceremony at sea.
Now if you'll excuse us,
we got a ship to catch!
So good to see you.
Thanks for coming out.
Hey.
Hi, it's me, again.
Um, there's, uh, something
I've always wanted to ask you.
Yeah, how do you balance
the superhero stuff
with the life stuff?
I know I can handle
the superhero stuff.
Uh-huh, uh-huh. Oh.
Would you please
excuse me a moment?
Oh. Yeah, okay, see you later!
Good talk!
Hey, Vi.
Hey.
Where's Jack-Jack?
E's taking him
for a little bit.
Edna is babysitting?
Yeah.
And you're okay with this?
Yeah. I don't know why,
but yeah.
I wanted to say
something to you.
Sorry about Tony.
I didn't think about Dicker
erasing his memory
or about you having to pay
the price for a choice
you never made.
It's not fair, I know.
And then, I made it worse
at the restaurant
by trying to
Anyway. Anyway
I'm sorry.
I'm used to knowing
what the right thing
to do is
but now,
I'm not sure anymore.
I just wanna be
a good dad.
You're not good.
You're super.
Are superheroes allowed
to drink on duty?
I'm definitely not on duty.
Ignore the costume.
I know
I should be up there
but I had to step away from
the grip and grins, you know?
Gotta get away to keep it pure.
I know I do.
What are you getting
away from?
Eh, you know, company stuff.
My brother, mostly.
But you love him,
you two are this company.
Yin and yang.
Yeah,
I invent the stuff,
he's good at people.
Pleasing them, engaging them,
figuring out what they want.
I never know
what people want.
What do you think
they want?
Ease.
People will trade quality
for ease every time.
It may be crap,
but hey, it's convenient.
Yeah. Kind of
like this case.
What?
The Screenslaver?
Yeah, something's not
sitting right.
It was too easy.
That was too easy?
Wow.
Funny.
What?
Look at that.
One of Screenslaver's monitors
is tuned into my suit cam.
What?
Isn't the suit cam
closed circuit?
It is.
Then
how come
Screenslaver has it?
Maybe he hacked it?
So, he's sophisticated enough
to do that
but he has simple locks
on his doors?
Maybe he wanted you
to find him.
He wanted to get caught?
He wanted you
to win.
That makes no sense.
He's a brilliant guy.
If he's smart enough
to conceive
of technology like this
he's smart enough to think
of something to do with it.
The guy we put in jail
delivered pizzas.
So? Einstein was a patent clerk.
Look, you won.
You got the guy who
Wait. All Screenslaver
needs to do
to hypnotize someone
is get a screen
in front of their eyes.
But what if the screen
doesn't look like a screen?
What if the pizza guy
is really a pizza guy
but he was controlled
by the screens
built into his glasses
You are good.
Look, the robot!
It's taking off.
I'm not getting a reading yet.
Press "fire"?
Now!
More power.
Oh, I hope this works, Dad.
I thought it was best
to just let you sleep.
Seventeen hours.
How do you feel?
Super.
You got it, Dad.
Hurray!
I can't tell you
how much I appreciate
you watching
Jack-Jack for me, E.
Yes, I'm sure your gratitude
is quite inexpressible.
Don't ask me
to do it again, darling.
My rates are far too high.
Oh, uh
I am joking, Robert.
I enjoyed the assignment.
He is bright
and I am stimulating.
We deserve each other.
Your child is a polymorph.
Like all babies,
he has enormous potential.
It is not unknown
for supers
to have more than one
power when young
but this little one has many.
Yes, you have many powers.
I understand
your lack of sleep
and coherency, Robert.
Babies can be anything,
and your child
is no exception.
He has pure,
unlimited potential, Robert.
He slept while I worked
in a creative fever.
Auntie Edna stayed up
all night
making sure you look
fabulous in your many forms.
What are you You're
putting him in the
In the chamber, Robert.
He is part
of the demonstration
and will be fine.
Your challenge
is to manage a baby
who has
multiple powers
and no control
over them, yes?
Huh. That sums it up.
I often work to music
and I noticed the baby
responds to it as well.
Specifically, Mozart.
I blended Kevlar
with carbyne for
durability under duress
and cotton for comfort.
Interwoven with these fabrics
are a mesh of tiny sensors
that monitor the baby's
physical properties.
Oh, Lord!
What What is he doing? What is he doing?
Well, it's Mozart, Robert.
Can you blame him?
The important thing is that
the suit and tracker
anticipated the change
and alerted you.
Oh, no. Cookies.
I gotta get cookies!
You do not need cookies.
As I learned quite painfully
last night
any solution involving cookies
will inevitably result
in the demon baby.
"Combustion imminent"?
What does that mean?
It means fire, Robert,
for which the suit
has countermeasures.
I suggest you extinguish
the baby's flames
before he trips
the sprinkler system.
The flame retardant
is blackberry lavender,
darling.
Effective, edible,
and delicious.
Well, what do you know?
That is useful.
Although, I have doubtlessly
exceeded your expectations
for a single night's work
the suit
and device contain
a few more features
we need to discuss.
Thanks again, E,
for everything.
How much
do I owe you for
Pish-posh, darling.
Your bill will be covered by my fee
for being Mr. Incredible,
Elasti Girl,
and Frozone's
exclusive designer
throughout the known universe
and until the end of time.
But babysitting this one
I do for free, darling.
I would
resist the temptation to stretch.
The temperature around you
is well below freezing.
Try to stretch
and you'll break.
So, you're
the Screenslaver.
Yes and no.
Let's say,
I created the character
and pre-recorded
the messages.
Does Winston know?
That I'm the Screenslaver?
Of course not.
Can you imagine
what Mr. Free Enterprise
would do
with my hypnosis technology?
Worse than
what you're doing?
Hey, I'm using
the technology
to destroy
people's trust in it.
Like I'm using superheroes.
Who did I put in jail?
Pizza delivery guy.
Seemed the right height,
build.
He gave you
a pretty good fight.
I should say I gave you
a pretty good fight
through him.
But it doesn't bother you
that an innocent man
is in jail?
Eh, he was surly
and the pizza was cold.
I counted on you.
That's why you failed.
What?
Why would you count on me?
Because I built you a bike?
Because my brother
knows the words
to your theme song?
We don't know each other.
But you can
count on me anyway.
I am supposed to,
aren't I?
Because you have
some strange abilities
and a shiny costume
the rest of us are supposed
to put our lives
into your gloved hands.
That's what
my father believed.
When our home was broken into,
my mother wanted to hide.
Begged my father
to use the safe room.
But Father insisted they call
his superhero friends.
He died,
pointlessly, stupidly
waiting for heroes
to save the day.
But why would you
Your brother
Is a child!
He remembers the time
when we had parents
and superheroes.
So, like a child,
Winston conflates the two.
Mommy and Daddy went away
because supers went away.
Our sweet parents
were fools
to put their lives
in anybody else's hands.
Superheroes keep us weak.
Are you gonna kill me?
Nah.
Using you is better.
You're gonna help me make
supers illegal
forever.
Dada. Dada.
Ready?
Laser eyes.
Stop.
Wow!
Yeah!
Yay, Jack-Jack!
Yeah, baby!
And that's not all.
Watch this.
Jack-Jack, blaster ready?
No way.
That is crazy cool.
My turn.
I get to blast him first!
Let me try. I want him. Give him to me.
Hey, I'm just demonstrating.
No firing the baby around
the house, you understand?
This is potentially
dangerous
and we're trying to teach him
to control his powers, okay?
Stop. See the screen.
He vanished!
That's really cool!
Okay, good. Use the thing.
See that.
That's the current readout.
Click it. See the readout?
Dimension four.
See the shape?
That's the room.
See where he is in relation?
So, where is he?
He's there!
Okay. Come out.
Num-num cookie?
Yay, Jack-Jack!
Yeah, Jack-Jack!
That's really cool.
Hello?
Elasti Girl's in trouble.
What? What happened to her?
Sorry to tell you
on the phone.
Meet me on our ship
at DEVTECH.
The ship at DEVTECH.
I'll be there in 15 minutes.
What's at the ship
at DEVTECH?
Lucius? Bob.
Helen's in trouble.
I need someone
to watch the kids.
Suit up. It might get weird.
I'll be there.
ASAP. Fifteen tops.
W here are you
going ASAP?
You better be back ASAP!
And leaving that suit.
I gotta go.
I'll be home soon.
Lucius will be here sooner.
No firing the baby
around the house, okay?
What's at the ship
at DEVTECH?
And why are you
in your Supersuit?
Is that Mom's supersuit?
She may need it.
You never know.
What's going on?
I don't know,
but Dad called Lucius
after getting a call
about Mom
and then left.
I thought you renounced
superheroes.
Yeah, well,
I renounce my renunciation.
Put that on.
Hello there, little fella.
Hello.
You kids aren't safe.
The Deavors sent us
to take you
Well, isn't that redundant?
The Deavors just sent me here
to guard the house.
'Cause the kids aren't safe.
I get it,
managerial screw up.
Tell Winston
I handled it.
You understand,
Ms
Voyd.
Ms. Voyd.
Drive safely.
The thing is, he wants us
to bring you, too.
Hey.
That isn't gonna
hold them long.
Dash, grab the baby!
Spread out!
Whoa!
Oh!
Dash!
We gotta get to my car.
What? What's going on?
Little fella!
It worked!
Incredibile, windows down!
Dive in!
Incredibile,
set voice identification.
Loudly, say your names.
Violet Parr.
Dashiell Robert Parr.
Lucius!
Incredibile, escape!
Fill me in!
Good news and bad news.
We found her.
She seems physically fine
but she's had an encounter
with Screenslaver
and she's acting
kind of strange. In here.
Strange how?
Helen?
Helen, what are you
Helen, it's me.
Incredibile, pull over.
We can't go to E's.
You saw those goggles
they put on Lucius.
They were
wearing them, too.
They're all under
someone's control.
They've probably done
the same to Mom.
Okay. Bad guys after us.
No Mom, no Dad.
No Lucius.
But we have our powers,
this car
and what?
Incredibile,
take us to DEVTECH.
The kids have escaped
in a tricked out car,
but we got Frozone.
Bring him to the ship
at DEVTECH immediately.
Aw, we missed 'em!
Oh, I wish the Incredibile
could follow that boat.
What did you do?
I don't know.
I didn't do anything!
Wow, this car does
anything I say.
We didn't plan this well.
What do you mean?
We're here, aren't we?
Yes, we're here.
We need to be up there.
Hey
What if the Incredibile
has ejector seats?
Wait, what? No.
Yeah, baby!
No, don't say any more
Max power! Launch!
Come on.
Hello!
Glad you could come.
Welcome to the conference.
Good to see you.
Our stars, where are they?
The event's about to start.
They didn't want to upstage
the others.
They'll join for the signing.
Welcome, guests!
You're in for a treat.
This ship is the largest
hydrofoil on the planet.
So, hold onto something
because we're going
to open her up!
We need to find Mom and Dad.
Stay here.
I'm gonna search for them.
Wait! Who's gonna
watch Jack-Jack?
Suck it up.
I won't be long.
Wait. Wait, but, but wait!
This is important.
They are in trouble.
It's up to us.
To us, understand?
Keep him amused but quiet!
Ugh.
Shh! Quiet!
Huh?
Jack-Jack?
Jack-Jack!
The mesmerized supers
know we're here
but I found Mom and Dad
Where's Jack-Jack?
You lost him?
I gave you one thing to do!
The tracker.
Use the tracker.
He's going up?
He's in an elevator.
Let's go!
Hey, little baby.
Where are your parents?
And here they are, folks!
The supers who started
this whole thing.
I told you
they'd be there in time.
Hey, did you make them
new masks?
Yeah. Night vision,
et cetera
They look good, right?
So simple, even he can do it.
And we're back live in
three, two, one
This is
a momentous occasion.
We've all managed
to accomplish
something extraordinarily rare
in today's world.
We agree on something.
We agree to undo
a bad decision.
To make sure a few extraordinarily
gifted members
of the world's many countries
are treated fairly.
To invite them once again
to use their gifts
to benefit the world.
I thank all of you
for representing your nation's
commitment to superheroes.
With special thanks
to Ambassador Selick.
Yeah, it's okay.
Let her hear you.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Thank you, Ambassador,
for your early
and very crucial support.
I can't think of anyone
more deserving than you
to be the first signature
on the International
Superhero Accord.
There it is!
Holy cow!
I know he's on fire.
Just put him out.
They're coming.
Is it okay
to give him that?
I wasn't hearing
any better ideas.
No!
Come on, Jack-Jack.
We have to go.
Cookie num-num?
Mama, Mama.
I see him. He's getting away!
Stand back.
Darn it!
He's heading for Mom.
It is done.
The world is super again.
Group photo. Come on.
Group photo, everyone.
Squeeze in. That's it.
Historic occasion.
Everyone, smile.
Go on phase two.
Years of mandated
hiding and silence
have made us bitter.
You bring us out
into the light
only to clean up the messes
your lack
of discipline creates.
Your bodies
and your character are weak.
Your promises are empty,
and you will pay for it.
We no longer serve you.
We serve only us.
May the fittest survive.
Well, we, um
Some very alarming
moments there
before the, uh,
technical difficulties.
Please bear with us.
What?
Mayday! Mayday!
Mayday!
Hold! Let him talk.
Superheroes have forcibly
taken the bridge.
Repeat.
Now.
A little further.
Little further. Stop.
What the A baby?
Mom and Dad.
Uncle Lucius?
My mama.
Jack-Jack, no!
A super baby?
No, no, no!
Put him down!
Grab her!
No!
Hold Jack-Jack.
Hey, it's me!
Yeah, that's what
I thought last time.
Kids, what are you Wha
You came for us?
Don't be mad.
Oh, sweetie,
how could I be mad?
I'm proud.
Not to break up
a tender moment,
but where are we?
Is this DEVTECH's ship?
Evelyn Deavor
controls the Screenslaver
and until a second ago, us.
Where's the crew?
Collision detected.
Correct course.
Uh-oh.
Did I do that?
Mom, the suit?
Try this.
Phase Three.
Go on Phase Three!
Why are the kids here?
You didn't go to the house?
I went to the house.
You didn't escape?
How did you not escape?
Hey!
We just saved you!
Escape? Escape from who?
Those guys!
What the?
Jack-Jack has powers?
We know.
Fight now, talk later.
Jack-Jack.
Laser eyes!
Ah-ha!
Ugh.
Come with me, Winston.
Did I faint?
You'll be safe here.
Safe? Safe from what?
Where are the diplomats?
The supers?
Still hypnotized.
What have you done?
Evelyn, she's escaping.
Well, go after her.
Finish your mission.
I can't just go!
What about the kids?
Jack-Jack, who's gonna
Mom!
Go. We've got this.
Voyd, come with me.
I'll go shut down
the engine.
I'll try to slow the
ship from the bow.
Wait, someone's missing.
Where's the crusher guy?
Strap in now!
It's for your own good.
No!
This is.
We're too late.
Get me up to the jet.
Hey, you did this.
Can you undo it?
You want me to un-crush?
What?
No one's ever asked for that?
No. To un-crush is silly.
Why un-crush?
To get into the engine room.
Oh, forget it.
We don't have enough time.
What if I said
to un-punch someone?
What do you do?
Welcome aboard, Elasti Girl.
Although
we haven't yet reached
our cruising altitude
feel free to roam about
the cabin.
Or just relax
and let the cabin roam
about you.
I can't get
to the engine room!
We gotta do something!
Because trying to
slow it down ain't working.
Hey! What about
turning the boat?
The steering's been destroyed!
Dash means from the outside!
Yeah!
If we break off
one of the foils
and turn the rudder
we can veer the ship
away from the city!
That might work.
I'll turn the front,
you turn the rear.
Using the rudder?
That's underwater.
How am I supposed to get
All right.
Come on, kids.
Dad, I know
this is going to work.
But if it doesn't,
and we crash
my shields are probably better
protection than the ship.
I should stay here.
With Jack-Jack.
That's my girl.
Remember, Bob,
we're both turning right!
You know what's sad?
If it weren't
for your core beliefs
I think we could have
been good friends.
At least
I have core beliefs.
We have breaking news
While there is
still no radio contact,
the ship
has changed direction
and is heading towards land
at a high rate of speed.
So, Dash
I am going to the rudder.
Once I turn the ship,
you hit the pull up button.
Okay, Dad.
Now lower me down
The reputations of
superheroes are ruined.
You will never
become legal. Ever.
Never?
No.
Ever?
Not even a little
smidgee widgee?
Oh, hypoxia.
When you don't have
enough oxygen,
things seem really silly.
Things get sillier
and sillier
and then you die.
I don't wanna die.
Ah, nobody does.
Really.
Not such a bad way to go.
Everyone, we need to get
to the back of the ship.
All supers,
protect your ambassadors!
Follow.
Dad's been underwater
for too long.
We gotta pull him up.
Wait. It's too soon.
I'm gonna press the button!
Not yet!
It's turning. It's working.
Now!
Dash, now!
Save yourself. Make a chute.
Make a chute. Make a chute.
Make a chute!
Helen! Brace yourselves!
Crash positions!
Whoo.
I missed Jack-Jack's first power?
Actually, you missed
the first 17.
Oh!
The fact that you saved me
doesn't make you right.
But it does make you alive.
And I'm grateful
for that.
I'm sorry,
but she'll go to prison.
Well, I'm sorry she's rich
and will probably get no more
than a slap on the wrist.
First of all, Violet,
I like you.
And who knows what the
future may bring
but I have a good feeling
about all of you.
Hmm. Good feeling.
Should we be worried?
You guys got the next shift.
I'm beat. Oh!
I saw what you did back there.
That was incredible!
No pun intended.
Sorry I had to punch you.
Yeah, baby! My sweet ride!
And in recognition
of the extraordinary service
they have demonstrated
the legal status
of superheroes
is hereby restored.
You don't know me,
do you?
No, I don't
Wait.
Are you the girl
with the water?
I'm Violet Parr.
I'm Tony.
Okay.
You split up into separate
groups and stuff
Tony, this is my mom.
Pleased to meet you.
This is my dad.
Oh, we've met.
And this is embarrassing.
Charmed, I'm sure.
My little brother, Dash.
And the baby is Jack-Jack.
I tried to limit it
to one parent.
We're all going to a movie,
too, Tony. Don't mind us.
We'll be sitting on the
other side of the theater.
Not watching you.
He's kidding.
They are only dropping
us off at the theater.
They have
other things to do.
So, you guys are close,
I guess.
Yeah, I guess.
We can get closer.
Bob.
Stop! Let us out!
Here, large popcorn,
small soda.
Save me a seat, center,
about eight rows back.
I'll be back before
the previews are over.
Here comes Elasti Girl
Stretching her arms
Elasti Girl
No one's beyond her reach
Ah, Elasti Girl
Here comes Elasti Girl
Stretching her arms
Elasti Girl
No one's beyond her reach
Ah, Elasti Girl
Who's the cat
who's always chill
When survival odds
are close to nil?
Frozone
Always chill
Ah
Frozone
So chill
Talk about Frozone
Frozone
Mr. Incredible
Incredible
Catching the bad guys
Pow, pow, pow
Pow, pow, pow, pow, pow
Mr. Incredible
Incredible
Punching the bad guys
Pow, pow, pow, pow, pow