- Hello.
- Hello, sweetie.
Daddy. lt's early.
l know. l just wanted you to know,
l'm sending you something.
- Does it smell nice?
- No, but it's sparkly.
- Does it have a receipt?
- l'm sending it to you from the store.
Come by. We'll have some breakfast.
lt would be a long trip.
l'm in Venice.
With your parole officer's approval?
l like the guy, Stella,
but we never really connected.
So l think l've paid my PO his last visit.
What are you into? Don't break
my heart. You said you were through.
After this, l am. l swear to you.
- ls Charlie there?
- l'm on a cellphone.
l'll call you tomorrow from a landline.
l love you. Go back to sleep. Bye.
Dad?
l love you, too.
- l sent it.
- You're supposed to shop after the job.
l feel so optimistic. How do you feel?
- Fine.
- Fine?
- You know what fine stands for?
- Yeah, unfortunately.
- Freaked-out...
- lnsecure...
- Neurotic...
- And emotional.
- See those columns behind you?
- What about them?
That's where they strung up
thieves who felt fine.
Well, after you.
- For after the haul.
- Hope l'll get to fire it up.
No word from the garbage men?
No. They don't show, prep's wasted
and you're out of retirement for nothing.
This is fun. You've taken over the reins,
the worries. l'm just along for the ride.
Glad you're enjoying yourself, John.
Police boat can get to us in seven, so
you've four minutes to work your magic.
- You told me ten and said l'd have five.
- When?
Do not mess with me.
- l will kick your ass.
- Yeah? Take your best shot.
What?
Come on, let's go.
What is it this time?
Da Vinci. Architect, engineer, painter.
- Fascinating.
- Check this out.
''Learn the language of poetry,
art, romance, sex...''
Unlike you, my friend, l don't need
a guidebook. Can we go?
- Right, guvnor.
- Make yourself useful. Untie that line.
- Today.
- Yeah.
Yeah, Gilligan, if you don't mind.
We set?
Yeah. The viewing matrix
tracks the Cartesian coordinates
and altitude angles
to give the exact position of our baby.
- We're in ltaly. Speak English.
- Steve, how we looking?
Papa took the boat at 8.1 5,
so the garage is empty.
Mama left with daughter at 8.30
for pre-school, as usual,
so for the next 45 minutes,
we own this place.
Still no word from the garbage men?
Who got you the Budapest beekeepers?
You can trust these guys.
How many times must l tell you?
Trust everyone,
but not the devil inside them.
We're in.
Just tell me where to paint.
- Your men still not in position?
- They will be.
You don't know that. We should abort.
l think that's Charlie's call now.
Our baby's being taken away tonight.
This is our only shot.
- Charlie?
- Keep going?
- lt's up to you, kid.
- Let's go.
OK, Steve.
From the west wall,
measure 1 4 feet 8 inches.
- Got it.
- 8 feet 5 inches from the north wall.
That's the northwest corner of our baby.
- Got it.
- Well, it's right above you.
Now, paint. 2 feet 9 inches wide,
2 feet 5 inches deep.
OK, Left Ear, you're up.
1 4 feet 4 inches from that west wall.
The garbage men are in position, John.
They've got the safe in the boat!
Someone just called it in.
The police boat's heading your way.
Seven minutes and counting. Let's go.
We've got four minutes. Let's go.
Hey, you guys. Come here.
l want to propose a toast.
To us!
And l want to propose a toast to Charlie.
We just stole 35 million dollars worth
of gold without even holding a gun
because he planned this down to a T.
Nobody else could've done that. Charlie!
So, come on. Shopping lists. Who's
doing what? Spare no dirty details.
Come on, guys. Take a lesson from
an old man. Don't spend it. lnvest.
- ln what?
- ln gold.
- Let's get out of here first.
- What are you getting, Rob?
l don't know.
There's a lot of things you can buy.
l'm thinking of naked girls and leather
seats. l'll get the Aston Martin Vanquish.
There's little a girl
won't do in one of those.
l'm getting a NAD T7 70 digital decoder,
70-watt amps and Burr-Brown DACs.
lt's a big stereo with speakers so loud
they blow women's clothes off.
$35 million and you can't get more
creative than that?
l'm going to Andalusia, south of Spain,
get me a big house, a library
of first editions, a room for my shoes.
- What about you, Steve?
- l haven't decided yet.
You haven't decided yet?!
ls it the mountain air?
l liked what you said.
l'll take one each of yours.
Well, two of everything for Steve.
l loved the toast. But you could've
pulled this off with your eyes closed.
You were just incredible.
You saw the whole picture
and covered all the angles.
Charlie, there are two kinds
of thieves in this world.
The ones who steal
to enrich their lives,
and the ones who steal
to define their lives.
Don't be the latter. You miss out
on what's really important in this life.
What are you talking about?
You've been a good father.
Sitting in prisons
doesn't make you a good father.
l've spent half my kid's life in prison.
Don't get to my age with only this.
Find somebody you want to spend the
rest of your life with. And hold on to her.
Hey, let's go. l'm freezing my ass off.
- Steve's getting cold. You, too?
- l'm all right.
- l love you, kid. You did really great.
- Thanks, John.
Let's go.
Rob was driving that boat
like Don Johnson!
- Yeah, from Brixton.
- What do you know about Brixton?
Look at this idiot
in the middle of the road.
What's this?
Who the hell are these guys?
- Take your hands off the wheel.
- Steve.
Just do it.
No, John.
- What the hell are you doing?
- Made a few plans of my own.
There's nowhere you can go
we won't find you.
l think that's probably right.
Go! Go!
We've got to go, Charlie.
- Do you always work in the dark?
- Makes me feel l'm alone.
Not bad, Stella.
- Purley couldn't crack that safe.
- Neither could Spears.
- You know who to call first.
- You're expensive.
Those guys cut us a break
on subpoena jobs, goodwill...
l do it for the money.
l'll send you a bill.
- Don't you want to see inside?
- l never look inside.
Have a good day. Hey, George.
- How long to crack it?
- Four minutes, 43 seconds.
- You're the man.
- What's in the line-up?
Todd Millikan called. He has
a prototype lock he wants you to test.
He added two false contact points
on the tumbler.
l'll pretend to be stumped
for a second or two.
And there's a Charlie Croker in your
office. Says you know each other.
- Charlie Croker.
- Hi, Stella.
Didn't l tell you
l never want to see you again?
lt was when you told me my father died
after you pulled him in for one last job.
We found him, Stella.
He's in Los Angeles.
The gold bricks he stole from us had
a Balinese dancer stamped on them.
My contact, Skinny Pete, says an LA
dealer's been buying those bricks.
- How do you know it's him?
- Skinny Pete sent me this.
Steve changed his last name to Frizelli.
- Why tell me this?
- l checked high-end safe companies.
Steve had a Worthington 1 000
delivered to his home office.
You install a Worthington 1 000 only
if you've got something big to guard.
No one on my crew can handle it.
l need somebody l can trust.
l'm a safe technician. l'm not a thief.
lt's not about the gold, Stella.
John was like a father to me, too.
l'm sorry. l can't move on
until l've set things right.
l've moved on.
Come on, then, Charlie. Come on.
l want to see his face
when his gold is gone.
He took my father, l'm taking this.
- She's in.
- That's a good thing?
She can crack the Worthington 1 000
without flinching.
l'm not sure
hiring a civilian's a good idea.
- She's got the skills and the motivation.
- Exactly.
She's emotional.
You know what happens then.
Don't kid yourself. We're all
emotional on this one. Let's go.
- Are you ready?
- Course l am.
You're not ready.
- That was quick.
- Where are they?
We're a little early.
l didn't expect us to get here that fast.
There. That's Lyle.
He's my computer genius.
He's who really invented Napster.
At least, that's how he tells it.
Said Shawn Fanning was his college
room-mate and stole his idea.
l think it's his first time
riding that bike, though.
- You OK?
- Yeah.
That's Left Ear.
Demolition and explosives.
When he was ten he put too many
M80s in the toilet bowl.
- Cool! How did you do that?
- What?
- How did you do that?
What?
Lost hearing in his right ear.
Blown stuff up ever since.
Handsome Rob. Premier wheelman.
Once drove from LA just so
he could set the freeway chase record.
He got 1 1 0 love letters from women
who saw him on the news.
And you? l never heard
how you got your start.
Me? Well, l've been a thief
since l had baby teeth.
- OK, you both know what to do.
- Cough it up now.
Watch it, spas!
What's your problem, man?
- Hey, Charlie.
- Good to see you.
Good to see you.
- Hello, Charlie.
- You good?
Guys, Stella Bridger.
- Nice to meet you.
- Phones.
They're all clean, with internal chips.
Change daily, we will get heat online.
lDs?
James Hymen?
One time give me a cool name.
- 1 40 pounds? Try 1 65.
- Try lifting some weights.
- Try lifting up these.
- We leave tomorrow, all right?
- Handsome, help him with the bike.
- Help Knievel set up his next jump.
Out of all the places for a thief to hide,
this joker picked Hollywood.
He's a punk, but he ain't stupid.
We need a way to make a blueprint
of the inside of Steve's house.
- l want phone surveillance.
- l want to try something.
l'll fool the phone company into
thinking there's a legal tap on the line
and re-route the copies of the calls to us.
Been doing it to my ex for years.
How long...will it take? Not, how
long have you been doing it to your ex?
- l'll have it running by morning.
- Sorry l'm late.
We gotta get Steve out of the house.
How much time do you need?
- Five minutes flat.
- Don't be cocky.
lt's not the same as opening a safe
for the police.
Perspiration on your fingertips, heart's
pounding. Whole different ball game.
l appreciate your concern. l'll be fine.
This is the easy part.
The getaway can get us caught.
- What's the schedule?
- Drive to Union Station.
Car goes onto the train. We need to
know exactly how long to Union Station.
- Oh, great. Carson security system.
- How good is it?
Carson's hold an annual contest.
$50,000 if you can bypass the system.
lt's a who's who of ex-cons.
Five years running, no one's been paid.
Here's the status.
An anti-scaling fence,
hardened electro-plated steel.
l'll have to paint that up
with some nitromon.
- Security?
- A little rent-a-cop with a 9 mm.
That security booth looks prime
for a chemical grenade.
Nitromon, chemical grenades?
That stuff's hard to come by.
Yeah, Lyle, it's a bear market... Shit!
This dude got dogs. l don't do dogs.
l had a real bad experience.
- What happened?
- l had a bad experience. l'm deaf?!
''Turn in your badge
and your weapon...'' Crush.
''l don't want you anywhere
near this investigation.
''...your badge and your weapon.
''l don't want you
anywhere near this investigation.''
Oi! lt's a green!
Green!
Unbelievable.
There he is.
Let's get to work.
lt's either bad traffic, peak traffic
or slit-your-wrist traffic.
Five people died from smoking
between traffic lights.
You could always use the metro.
That would be ideal for carrying
a tonne of gold.
What's your guesstimate?
From 20 journeys, l got an average
of 32 minutes and a top time of 50.
But with green lights,
we could do it in 1 4 minutes.
What, you couldn't get through traffic?
You could do anything
with green lights all the way.
l'll see what l can do.
You're right on time.
These people putting their savings
in banks, S and Ls, mutual funds...
Do they think when the collapse comes
they can depend on the government?
- l don't think so.
- Are you taping me?
Of course not. l never tape you.
See for yourself.
Governments are nothing more
than puppets on strings.
ln a world where NAFTA can
overrule the Supreme Court,
like my cousin Mashkov always says,
''This is our only refuge, baby.''
Gold.
Every time l look at these engravings...
She's so beautiful.
- Where did you say you got these?
- l didn't.
A little ''walking around'' money.
- l'm not walking as far as l thought.
- l can only buy two today.
- That wasn't the agreement.
- l'm just middleman.
- l'll buy the other two on Wednesday.
- Don't waste my time, Yevhen.
So, what does a man with 35 million
dollars worth of gold do at night?
He watches his big-ass TV.
That's our in.
Jesus!
- How did you get in here?
- l knocked but you didn't answer.
- So you just let yourself in?
- l was checking you were OK. l'm sorry.
Don't look.
OK.
You've got a lot of stuff.
Your dad was old school.
- Did the whole thing by touch.
- lt worked for him. This works for me.
Technology guarantees
speed and accuracy.
There's no guarantees in this business,
Stella. Why the headphones?
Just training myself. Ambient noises,
you know. Just in case.
- What do you want?
- We're knocking out Steve's cable.
- Then we send in a repair man.
- To get your video blueprint?
Yeah. The problem is
Steve thinks we're all dead.
Except me.
l'll do it, Charlie. l'm in all the way.
Whatever it takes.
- All right. l'll set it up.
- OK.
You want to get a drink with me
before l go back to my room?
l should finish this stuff up.
Get it all done tonight.
- Yeah. Sorry l scared you.
- lt's OK.
Goodnight.
Bye.
Then he's the media darling,
on all the magazine covers.
l should've been on
Wired magazine's cover.
He said he named it Napster because
of his nickname, his nappy hair,
but it's 'cause l was napping
when he stole it from me.
- He didn't even graduate.
- l think it's time to move on, don't you?
They shut him down.
l wish they'd do the same to you.
Here. Here we go. Cable chick.
Becky. Nice name.
l wonder what she calls the other one.
lt's such a mystery
why you don't have a girlfriend.
All we need is a service truck
like that, a work-shirt like hers...
- Think Stella can pull it off?
- l have my doubts.
There's no talking to Charlie, though.
You think he's mixing business
with pleasure?
He should know better.
Only l'm allowed to do that.
Right. Where are you going?
The work-shirt and the service truck.
Are you kidding me?
How does he do that? How do you
do that? What are you saying?
''Hey, how are you?''
''l'm good.''
''Nice to meet you,
l'm Handsome Rob, and you are...?''
''My name's Becky. lt's on my shirt.''
''l need your shirt and your truck.''
''Perfect. Would you like
my virginity as well?''
''lf it's on the menu.''
''You're so witty. Take advantage of me.''
''You're not too bright, are you?''
''No.'' ''Perfect.''
- Yes, Mr Frizelli.
- The cable's out.
The TV, the modem, everything.
Get somebody up here quick.
Netcom Cable.
l'm at 3320 East Skyway
and the cable's gone.
- l have a Thursday between 9 and 3.
- That's good. Thank you.
Guard just called the cable company.
- What time's the appointment?
- Thursday between 9 and 3.
l'm calling from Netcom Cable.
You set up
an appointment for Thursday?
We have a technician
who's free earlier than expected.
- Will somebody be there for an hour?
- Sure.
Our technician will see you then.
Have a nice day.
Here's all the paperwork you need.
Just get him to sign and date it.
Let's check out the camera.
Stella, you'll be going patriotic today.
Walk slowly or the image'll streak.
- l'm sorry.
- lt's OK.
Couldn't pin the corsage
on my prom date, either.
- You had a prom date?
- lt was his cousin.
There's cable in the kitchen,
living room, bedroom and the office.
You need to locate the safe in the office.
l think you're very brave going in there.
- l second that.
- lt's going to be fine.
What?
Fine stands for freaked out, insecure...
...neurotic and emotional.
- You'll be great.
- Yeah.
Good morning. Can l see some lD?
- Thanks for coming so soon.
- That's part of the job.
Aston Martin Vanquish.
So that bastard took my car.
Nasty-ass dogs.
Cease!
Relax, Jesus Christ!
Come on, they won't bother you now.
Come on. House!
Go on, get out of here.
l'm used to running
into animals on my job.
- Want to show me that problem?
- Of course. This way.
- You've a really nice house.
- 1 922. All the original tiles.
Every stone in that courtyard
from some monastery in Seville.
- What a tactic.
- Monastery for punk-ass creeps!
You're not impressed?
lt's just that lugging rocks from one
place to another isn't that interesting.
- lt doesn't quite do it for me.
- What does do it for you?
TVs.
l have a monster TV.
- lt's not working right now...
- l should check the cable modem.
Yeah? OK, right. Over here.
l paid thirty grand for some punk kid
to install it. One day it just goes out.
l'm going to have him strung up.
- Here we go.
- There's our baby.
- Oh, man.
- We got him.
- Got any wiring coming through here?
- There's no wiring in here.
lt's just right here?
Look at that. That's my NAD T7 70.
That's my stereo.
l bet people are surprised
when they expect the cable man
and find you standing there.
He's hitting on her.
There's no problem here.
l should just check the TVs.
You know what? l'm blowing this shit
right off the mountain right now.
- ABM processor.
- Only the best.
Check the box.
l'm just going to reset your system.
Sometimes these things
just get jammed up, you know?
- That should do it.
- lt's fixed?
- Turn her on. Let's see.
- Now.
Perfect.
Becky, huh? Have we met before?
No, l don't think so.
lf you can just sign there.
lf l asked you to dinner, would l be
the first customer to do that?
Did you ask your last cable guy out?
No, but he was 300 pounds
with a handlebar moustache.
- Not my type.
- lt's not a good idea.
- ls that some cable company rule?
- No, it's my rule.
l don't go out with strange men.
We just met five minutes ago.
l guess l have to sabotage my cable
until we get to know each other.
- Have a nice day.
- l'll be a perfect gentleman.
l won't even ask for your number.
l'll meet you. Anywhere you want to go.
Come on, break your rule. Once.
Just dinner.
ls that a yes?
You OK?
Yeah.
He touched my hand.
He came on to me.
Hey, at least l created
a window of opportunity, right?
When he goes out Friday night, we go in.
By the time he realises you've stood
him up, we'll be gone with that gold.
Shuffle them cards this time, Left.
Lyle, what's the distance between
the front door and the vault?
- Quit dealing while my back's turned.
- You've got loser's paranoia.
He only answers
to the Napster now, Charlie.
- l'm not calling you the Napster.
- You call him Left Ear.
- And him Handsome Rob.
- Because he is Handsome Rob.
- Well, you can call me the Napster.
- They were at college together.
- Why are you encouraging this?
- lt is verifiable.
He was my room-mate.
He stole my ideas. l am the Napster.
All right, what is the distance between
the front door and the vault, Napster?
- Farther than you want to carry it.
- So, how do we get the gold to the car?
How wide is the hallway...Napster?
6 feet.
OK, you've got your gold.
We need more cars to handle the weight.
l'll need help with the custom work.
l know a man for the job.
l modified the camera with LlDAR
so we can create hi-res digital maps...
- Who's that?
- Rob's mechanic friend.
- Charlie, this is Wrench.
- What's up?
Rob says you're talented.
l need some bodywork done.
We need to pack
2,700 pounds in these Minis,
with enough suspension and
horsepower to outrun anything chasing.
- 2,700 pounds of what?
- Whatever.
- What do l get from this mystery?
- 1 0,000.
All right.
We didn't get a chance to meet yet.
Wrench.
- Ham and cheese.
- That's cold. Damn, that's cold.
You want all greens?
'Cause you got 'em.
Welcome to LA's Automated Traffic
Surveillance and Control Center.
They use video feeds
from intersections and algorithms
to predict traffic conditions
and control traffic lights.
l created my own kick-ass
algorithm to sneak in
and now we own the place.
- Want to do a dry run?
- Thought you'd never ask.
See red light? Green light.
- Danielson, what's up with grid 34?
- Let's check it out.
Oops! Did l...? But it's awesome.
ls that not awesome?
Can you change it back?
Lights are working fine.
lt's just an accident.
That's good.
- What are those?
- Unnecessary parts.
l lost your smog controls
and 200 pounds of fat.
You got a sweet ride now, Charlie.
Know what l'm thinking about right now?
The look on Steve's face.
- You're early.
- l'm in a hurry.
You know that the Florida vote-rigging
was a ClA and mob operation?
Which is not so different from when JFK
won an election with his father's help.
- You're uncomfortable l mention JFK?
- No, l don't like making two trips.
You Americans, you love your heroes.
A holiday for Columbus?
He makes the wrong turn
and wipes out an indigenous people.
- Know what he was looking for?
- Tell me.
Gold, supposedly for Queen lsabella.
Don't think the Medicis didn't want some.
What did ltaly need gold for?
The long-distance slave trade,
based in Venice.
Venice. That's where these bricks...
- You were saying something?
- No.
Don't stop. l'm interested.
Please, l'm confused. My English...
What do you know about my gold?
- l don't...
- Don't even think about lying to me.
OK. l heard a rumour
about a heist in Venice.
35 million, in bricks,
with a Balinese dancer imprint.
- Who have you told?
- No one, l swear to God!
- You swear to God?
- You're crazy. l swear to God, l didn't.
Well, then, l guess l believe you.
Let's putt it. Putt, not drive.
Very good. You can get it.
l know you can do it.
- Here to see Skinny Pete.
- He's over there.
Thanks, man.
Don't stare.
He doesn't like people staring.
Stare at what?
That was good. Try that one.
l know you'll get that one.
- That was great.
- Skinny Pete.
- Yo, Charlie.
- What's up, man?
Was l right about the gold?
l'm not here for that.
We need some supplies.
Baby, go relax. Go relax!
- Supplies.
- What's wrong?
Some nitromon...
- Some nitromon primer.
- What's wrong?
Nothing, l'm cool. l'm great.
l just need a big can of...
...nitromon primer, detonating cord,
two triple-charger chemical grenades
and a launcher.
- Right, like l had told you earlier.
- All right.
- Cost you about five Gs.
- Done. Thanks. Sorry about that.
- All right, man. Peace.
- Come on.
Get out.
There.
Vance has something to tell you.
Go on.
A couple of weeks back...
...l was working in your cousin's shop.
A guy come in asking about gold
bricks with Balinese dancer on.
- What did you tell him?
- That l'd seen the bricks.
- l'm sorry.
- What did this man look like?
He had long black hair
with tattoo on his neck.
He must have weighed
at least 400 pounds.
l know that guy.
Baby, go relax.
- Do you know who l am?
- You're Mashkov.
Right. You were asking about the gold
bricks with the Balinese dancer on.
Why?
Steve just confirmed
his eight o'clock dinner reservation.
- Let's go over it.
- Gas the guards. Doors open, 8.1 5.
- Safe popped by 8.25.
- Loaded, 8.35. Out, 8.45.
Straight to Union Station.
Only green lights, rest of city's red.
Cops stuck in traffic.
Train leaves at 1 0. Cars must be
aboard by 9.30. Timing must be exact.
- Let's get ready.
- Let's get it.
Wow, that is a nice car. Sorry, Rob.
Coast is clear, guys.
This is it. Moment of truth.
What the hell is this? Shit!
Steve's neighbour's throwing a party.
- Are you here for the Baker party, sir?
- No.
We're not blowing any gates tonight,
guys. Too many witnesses.
- Stella.
- l know...
l'm late for my date.
You've got to be charming. We need
him to ask you out again. Sorry.
Let's get out of the street.
- l can't imagine you doing that.
- What's that mean?
Well, you don't really seem
the adventurous type, you know.
Don't let the cable uniform throw you.
l wasn't making assumptions.
- l've made some about you.
- Oh, really? And...?
You're just going to have to wait and see.
Why wait? Let's go back to my place.
No assumptions.
Not tonight. lt's late. l should go home.
- You have a cable company curfew?
- No.
l've made some bad calls in the past.
We should take this slower.
Lovely dinner, sparkling conversation.
Still don't trust me?
l trust everyone. lt's the devil
inside them l don't trust.
That's an interesting saying.
Where'd you pick that up?
- Can't remember.
- l knew a guy who said it just like that.
- Really?
- Yeah.
He's the only person l've ever heard
say that. His name was John Bridger.
- You're hurting me.
- He had a daughter about your age.
Let go.
l knew there was something familiar
about you.
You're exactly like your old man.
l liked him, too.
l liked him right up
until the minute l shot him.
Who are you working with?
She's with us.
- The gang's all here.
- The only thing worse than a thief...
...is a coward.
Then you should've seen the way
your daddy begged for his life.
- He's not worth it.
- Put a leash on your cat.
Not bad, Charlie.
You have no idea how hard it is
for me not to kill you now.
You know better than that.
You can't let emotion into these things.
lt wasn't emotion
when you shot John and left us?
That wasn't about emotion.
lt was about a lot of gold.
Anything you think you deserved,
you didn't.
Don't talk about right and wrong
with me. l don't give a shit. OK?
You got your cards, l got mine.
We made our play, l came out on top.
lf you want to start the game
up again, that's fine with me.
What is your play here, really?
Come on, what do you think?
You'll try to take out my guards?
l have five that you don't know about.
You'll have Lyle hack the system?
l'll change it tomorrow morning.
What was your final move? Have
Bridger's daughter try to crack my safe?
That's very poetic, but l just don't
think she'll get anywhere near it.
Same old Steve.
Always thinking defensively.
That's why you're always number two.
- How's that?
- You've got no imagination.
Couldn't even decide what to buy.
Bought what everyone else wanted.
- Try this. That gold is already gone.
- Bullshit.
lt's over, Charlie.
l'm trying to move the last two bricks.
You want to come after me over
a couple of lousy bricks? Be my guest.
But you're off to a bad start because
you just blew the element of surprise.
Surprised?
lt's over when l say it's over.
Are you all right, sir?
How you doing?
Good.
Considering the fact l'm doing
all of this for a man l barely knew.
You know what bothered me
all those years?
lt was that whenever he'd call me
to tell me he was on some job,
l knew you were right there with him.
You got to know him a lot better
than l did.
Doesn't mean he wasn't
thinking about you.
- Would be nice if it was true.
- lt is.
He always regretted not having been
a good enough father to you.
- How do you know?
- Because he told me.
What did you do to your hand?
- l punched Steve.
- Why do you get to punch him?
'Cause those hands
are way too valuable.
You OK?
There'll be nothing left of that
if you keep rubbing it.
Tell Mr Frizelli we'll see him at eight.
- He's flying the coop.
- When?
His security guard
called for a helicopter at 4 p.m.
and an armoured car at five.
There's a cargo plane, departing LAX
at 8 p.m. to Mexico City.
What if he's moving
the safe as a diversion?
- We crack it, the gold's somewhere else.
- Steve won't let it out of his sight.
lt'll be in that truck
and he'll watch it from the helicopter.
- The gold's headed to Mexico?
- Who knows...?
- Slow down. This is good news for us.
- What do you mean?
Now the safe has come to us.
We're going to boost it in transit.
He could take a dozen routes.
We don't know which. We can't take
out an armoured truck at rush hour.
We're already set up to do it. Gridlock
every route except the one we choose.
Force that truck
to go where we want.
Where do we want it to go?
We'd lose a shoot up.
We do it like The ltalian Job.
- Why'd you do it?
- Do what?
- Yevhen. You didn't have to clip him.
- We didn't clip anybody.
Yevhen's cousin is
under the impression you did.
Why?
Because you wanted
to know about the gold.
You told him that?
One thing l know,
never mess with Mother Nature,
mother-in-laws,
or mother-freaking Ukrainians.
Look, l need a favour.
Had a hiccup last night. Need some help.
More hands-on. lnterested?
Could be, but l don't like
to be kept in the dark. lf l'm in, l'm in.
- OK, you're in.
- All right.
- What do you think?
- This'll work. Let's go.
You're amazing. lt's a work of genius.
- You OK?
- Just give me a moment.
- Now?
- l'm inserting this pin into the detonator.
lf the brass touches the sides, we'll
both be the last people we ever see.
Take all the time you need.
- Hey, Charlie.
- What?
l love you, man.
l love you, too.
He's going to be on train 59
for New Orleans.
You sure the source is good?
l'm sure.
Check positions. Napster?
l'm in position.
- Handsome Rob?
- ln position. Everything's quiet, Charlie.
Wrench?
Set.
We've got an uninvited visitor. There's
a motorcycle guard following the truck.
We'll deal with it.
- Who are they?
- What's wrong?
You won't believe this.
He's brought in three armoured trucks.
lt's a shell game now.
l can't re-route
if l don't know which to re-route.
Follow the one Steve
follows by helicopter.
He'll never
let that gold out of his sight.
Unless he's playing us. And he is.
OK, let's go! Move it out!
Here we go. They're pulling out.
Napster, pull up the traffic
cameras you're watching.
Where's the first camera they go past?
- Vine and Yucca.
- See which one's riding low.
First in line...
First two are the same, so...
Houston, we have our truck.
Number 1 28.
We're moving out.
Three Kilo Bob to Two Fox Mike,
we're heading to the airport.
OK, guys, truck 1 28
has turned right heading west.
Gridlock time.
We've crashed.
lt's not a crash.
- We've got power.
- l can't log in.
They're about to hit a detour
and be sent your way.
You'll never shut down the real Napster.
What's your problem?!
- Truck 1 28, what is your progress?
- Traffic's out of control.
We've got to look for another route.
Check the police band.
OK, l'm opening up a space
on Highland.
- Get us out of here.
- l'm trying.
And he's taking it.
Police are saying computers
are down at traffic control.
Nice, Charlie. What are you up to?
Go back.
l now command you to turn left.
Come on, take the left.
Yeah, you did. You did.
Give us the flag.
Metro just passed through the station.
You are clear for 90 seconds. Go.
Come on, Steve.
30 seconds and counting.
1 5 seconds, you're blocked in
or you're paint on the train.
Come on, come on!
Stay on me. This'll be tight!
- Go, go, go.
- You're going to stop there.
- OK, guys, coming into position.
- Stay cool.
Ten, nine...
...eight, seven...
...six, five...
...four...
- Don't lose him.
- ...three...
...two, one...
What...?!
Damn.
What the fuck happened to my truck?!
- lt blew through the street.
- Get under there.
- We have another problem.
- What?
- This isn't the Worthington 1 000.
He switched safes on us.
- Can you do it?
- lt's lsraeli made.
lt's got a glass relock system.
There's a pane of glass here.
lf l don't drill perfectly, steel rods
snap into place and we can't open it.
Then we're up shit creek.
l think l just cracked the glass.
l don't think it broke, though.
l can't drill it again.
l have to do it by touch.
l can't get through.
The train's blocking the tunnel.
- Where does the Metro Rail emerge?
- Eleventh and Fig.
Meet at Eleventh and Figaro and double
back to Hollywood and Highland. Hurry.
Baggage for train 22
now available at carousel 4.
l can't do this. l need a drill
or a borescope to get in there.
- Come on, Charlie.
- You can do this.
Slide.
- Don't you want to see inside?
- Absolutely.
Napster, 1 3 across, 4 high, 4 deep.
- That's 208 bricks.
- How much?
- 2.7 million.
- What?!
No, it's 27. That's 27 million.
That's 27 million dollars worth of gold.
Got the Holy Spirit.
You should get on it, it's a good train.
What do you think, John?
- 27 million.
- Say it again.
We've got two motorcycles
on us, Charlie.
Three Minis heading east
towards the LA river.
Stop them
before they get to the street.
Shit!
Here we go.
Open your door.
Come on, guys. We're moving.
There!
Hey, come on. Get down!
Come on!
Where are you going?
l'll take Steve. Go to Union Station.
l'll meet you there.
Stay on him.
l'm opening up a spot on Lower Grand.
l know it's you, Charlie.
Take your next left.
Nice move, Steve.
Get out! Get out!
l said get out!
- You got Mini Coopers in there, right?
- Look, man...
Don't worry about them. l'll give
you five grand to put me inside.
Buy your girlfriend something nice.
Half now, half when you help me unload.
l've got to hand it to you.
You played this one pretty smart.
Decoy trucks, you switched safes,
the helicopter routine. Pretty good.
Now l've got the gold,
you've got nothing.
l've got this, so cut the crap
and give me my goddamn gold!
- Who are you?
- l am Mashkov.
- You killed my cousin Yevhen.
- You've got to have some insurance.
He was already dead when l arrived.
He dealt with unsavoury people.
- This guy's trying to play you.
- You were right. No imagination.
There's a lot of gold in there. Only we've
got guns. l'll make you a good deal.
l've already made my deal.
- What do you want?
- You know this was never about gold.
Whatever helps you sleep at night,
sweetheart.
Bitch. Charlie, come on, Charlie!
That l loved.
l'll double whatever he's given you,
just don't shoot me.
Don't worry, l'm not going to shoot you.
l'm going to take you to my workplace.
l think you'll be interested
in my machinery.
Oh, come on.
Guys, l want to make a toast.
To John Bridger. The most brilliant
master planner of all. Father and friend.
Stella was right.
lt wasn't about the money.
Of course, that didn't stop the guys
from having some fun.
Handsome Rob got his Aston Martin.
Took it for a ride to break it in.
He got off with a warning.
Left Ear got his dream house in Spain
with a room just for his shoes.
Lyle finally made
the cover of Wired magazine.
- Are you really the Napster?
- Yes, l am.
And he got that kick-ass stereo
he wanted.
Would you listen to something?
With speakers so loud they could
blow a woman's clothes off.
lf you would.
And me?
l took John Bridger's advice.
l found somebody l want to spend
the rest of my life with,
and l'm going
to hold on to her forever.