PREVIOUSLY ON "KODIAK"...
GET DOWN, GET DOWN,
GET DOWN!
THE SEASON IS COMING TO AN END.
THIS BEAR
IS TWICE AS AGGRESSIVE.
THESE BEARS EAT RED MEAT,
AND WE'RE RED MEAT.
AND THE FAMILIES ON THE ISLAND
HAVE BEEN PUSHED
TO THEIR LIMITS.
I'M SORRY.
THIS IS THE FIRST TIME
EVER IN MY LIFE
I'VE HAD TO SIT DOWN
WITH MY DAD.
I NEARLY
GOT KILLED TODAY.
SURE YOU STILL
WANT TO DO THIS?
THE HOLLAND BOYS GET
THEIR FIRST TASTE OF GUIDING.
He should be right on the edge
of that forest.
You got him now.
BUT AS THE SEASON WINDS
DOWN, THE PRESSURE RAMPS UP.
LATER, KYLE.
EITHER YOU **** GET
IT WRAPPED AROUND THAT MOTOR,
OR WE'RE GONNA RIP
THAT WHOLE **** DEAL OFF.
YEAH, I DON'T GIVE A ****
IF YOU GOT TO CHEW A TREE DOWN
WITH YOUR **** TEETH
TOMORROW.
YOU NEED TO GET
SOME ****DAMN WOOD IN HERE.
YOU'RE SURE
YOU WANT TO DO IT?
'CAUSE ONCE YOU TAKE A LIFE,
YOU TAKE A LIFE.
DO I WANT TO BECOME A GUIDE?
SOMETIMES I THINK YES,
AND OTHER TIMES, NO.
MY GOD!
THERE'S A **** WHALE
RIGHT THERE.
That bear saw us.
Get down, get down, get down!
OH! I'M JAMMED.
- Captions by VITAC-
CAPTIONS PAID FOR BY
DISCOVERY COMMUNICATIONS
PUDDLES ARE FREEZING.
IT'S COLD.
ICE ON THE BEACH THIS MORNING.
WE GOT TO START
WINTERIZING THIS PLACE.
WINTER IS COMING
TO KODIAK ISLAND, ALASKA.
BEAR SEASON IS OVER,
AND ALL OF THE HUNTERS
HAVE LEFT THE CAMP.
FROZEN SOLID.
THE WEATHER COULD GET BAD.
IT COULD FREEZE UP IN HERE,
AND I MIGHT NOT SEE THIS PLACE
FOR FOUR MONTHS.
BOB MAY AND HIS CREW HAVE
ONLY DAYS TO PREPARE THEIR LODGE
BEFORE THE ENTIRE ISLAND
IS ENTOMBED IN SNOW AND ICE.
FROM THIS DAY ON,
WE'RE GONNA LOSE RUNNING WATER
TO THE BUILDING AND EVERYTHING.
THERE'S PLENTY OF RUNNING WATER,
YOU JUST GOT TO RUN AND GET IT.
AND WHAT'S WORSE,
THE ISLAND'S NAMESAKE,
KODIAK BROWN BEARS,
ARE STILL
ON THE HUNT FOR RED MEAT
AS THEY BULK UP FOR HIBERNATION.
TROY.
YEAH?
SEE WHAT THE BEAR DID?
OH **** YEAH.
YEAH,
HE DIDN'T QUITE GET IN,
BUT THEN
HE BROKE OUT THIS WINDOW,
TRIED TO GET IN THERE,
AND THEN DECIDED BETTER OF IT,
BUT WE GOT TO COVER IT UP.
SEASON'S COMING TO AN END,
AND TROY AND KYLE
HAVE DONE A GREAT JOB.
THEY OBVIOUSLY WANT
TO BE GUIDES,
AND I'M STILL A LITTLE
ON THE FENCE,
BUT THEY'RE STRONGER TOGETHER
THAN THEY ARE APART.
WE GOT TO GET THIS PLACE
SHUT DOWN.
HOW MANY MORE WINDOWS
DO WE GOT TO DO?
A LOT.
WINTER'S HERE.
GOT TO GET THIS DONE BEFORE
THERE'S THREE FEET OF SNOW.
BUT NEXT YEAR, HOPEFULLY,
I WON'T BE
AN APPRENTICE DOING IT.
THAT ONE'S IN.
GO HANDLE
YOUR **** COMPASS.
YOU'RE ON YOUR OWN.
ALL RIGHT.
THANKS, BUD.
YEP.
I'M ABOUT TO BE A GUIDE -
ME AND KYLE, YOU KNOW,
SIDE BY SIDE.
WE'RE GONNA DO THIS TOGETHER.
I FEEL LIKE, YOU KNOW,
WE'RE AT THE LIGHT
AT THE END OF THE TUNNEL.
CUT THESE SLICES SO THIN
IT'S LIKE I'M MAKING PAPER.
I KNOW IF TROY AND I GET
OUR SHOT AS GUIDES,
WE ARE GONNA BE AS GOOD
AS BOB CUSACK, BOB MAY,
AND MY DAD, ERNIE,
TAUGHT US TO BE.
AND THEY'LL MAKE UP
THEIR MINDS
BEFORE WE CLOSE THIS CAMP
FOR THE WINTER.
WE BETTER HURRY.
THE TIDE'S FALLING.
IF WE CAN GET THIS THING TOWED
A LITTLE WAY, THAT'D BE GOOD.
COME ON, DOGS. OUT.
COME ON, ABBY.
I DON'T HAVE A LOT
OF REAL CLOSE FRIENDS,
BUT THE FRIENDS I HAVE
LIKE ERNIE AND BOB,
I CHERISH THEM.
YEAH, LET'S TRY AND GET THIS UP
HERE JUST A LITTLE WAYS.
GET IT STARTED.
TO BE A BEAR GUIDE HERE
ON KODIAK,
YOU BETTER KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
AND WE'RE ALL
PRETTY DAMN GOOD AT IT.
YOU KNOW, I MEAN,
WE'VE KNOWN EACH OTHER FOREVER.
YOU CAN'T FIND BETTER PEOPLE.
THEY'RE AWESOME.
IT'S LIKE HAVING FAMILY HERE
ALL THE TIME.
PROBABLY WOULD'VE BEEN
A LITTLE EASIER
IF WE TOOK THE MOTOR OFF,
BUT...
YEAH.
...WE'LL LET THEM YOUNGINS
DO THAT.
LISTEN, SO, HOW ARE KYLE
AND TROY DOING OUT THERE?
WHAT DO YOU GUYS THINK?
ARE THEY READY
TO BECOME GUIDES?
GOT A NEW YEAR COMING UP
NEXT YEAR.
I THINK
THEY'RE PRETTY GOOD.
YEAH.
I THINK THEY'RE PICKING UP
THINGS PRETTY FAST.
THINK THEY NEED
MORE EXPERIENCE.
IS THAT BECAUSE
THEY'RE YOUR KIDS?
PROBABLY.
KYLE AND TROY WERE KIDS,
ALL THEY WANTED TO DO
WAS BE LIKE DAD
AND BE A BEAR GUIDE.
YEAH, SEE YOU LATER, TROY.
GOOD LUCK HUNTING.
THE SCARIEST THING -
SCARIER THAN ANY BROWN BEAR
OR ANYTHING -
IS LOSING ONE OF MY KIDS.
EVERY TIME
YOU STEP INTO THESE WOODS,
THERE IS A PROBABILITY
THAT YOU'RE GONNA DIE.
THEY NEED TO...
BE TOUGHER.
WHY DON'T WE JUST SEND THEM OUT
WITH ROBERT,
HUNTING THAT DAMN ELK?
SURE AS HELL WOULDN'T HURT
FOR THEM
TO SPEND A LITTLE MORE TIME
DOING SOME
OF THE NON-DANGEROUS GAME.
YEAH, SOMETHING LIKE THAT -
I THINK THAT'S A GOOD IDEA.
IT'S BETTER THAN NOTHING.
IT'S MORE EXPERIENCE.
I CAN SEE THAT ERNIE
LOVES HIS BOYS AND THAT
AND CONCERNED ABOUT THEM,
BUT JUST SEEMED
TO COME AROUND A LITTLE BIT,
YOU KNOW?
WELL, LET'S JUST PLAY
A LITTLE GAME HERE
AND HAVE ROBERT BE THE CLIENT
AND THEY'RE THE GUIDES,
AND THEN AT THE END
OF THE HUNT,
WE'LL HAVE ROBERT
ASSESS THEIR PERFORMANCE
AS IF HE WAS A CLIENT.
I'D FEEL GOOD ABOUT IT.
LET'S FINISH GETTING
THIS THING UP
SO WE CAN HAVE A BEER.
SOUNDS GOOD.
CRANK AWAY.
COME HERE.
PUT THIS BAD BOY ON.
WE'RE GONNA SEE IF YOU CAN
PACK OUT SOME MEAT.
WE'LL MAKE SURE
YOU'RE WORTHY.
NEW PACK?
I'LL TEST THE STRUCTURAL
INTEGRITY OF THIS THING.
THOUGHT WE WERE GONNA LOAD IT UP
WITH SOME WOOD OR SOMETHING.
NO, ME,
'CAUSE I'M ABOUT
WHAT YOU'RE GONNA BE
PACKING OUT.
ALL RIGHT.
WHAT DO YOU WEIGH?
180.
TROY AND I HAVE AN
OPPORTUNITY HERE TO TAKE ROB OUT
AND GUIDE HIM ON AN ELK HUNT,
AND I AM BEYOND EXCITED.
WE BECOME ONE.
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
OKAY, YOU READY?
YEAH, ARE YOU IN THERE?
I'M ALL ON THE PACK.
ALL RIGHT.
HOLD ON TIGHT.
MY FIRST DEAR HUNT,
I WAS PROBABLY 11 YEARS OLD.
BOB BROUGHT ROBERT OUT,
MY DAD BROUGHT ME OUT,
AND WE WERE KIDS
GOING OUT HUNTING,
NOT REALLY TAKING THINGS
THAT SERIOUS.
BUT, YOU KNOW, OUR DADS,
BOB AND ERNIE,
DEFINITELY PROBABLY KEPT
A WATCHFUL EYE ON US BACK THEN.
BUT NOW, WE CAN GO OUT
AND HUNT ON OUR OWN.
I GOTCHA.
YOU'RE IN THERE.
BEAR SEASON'S OVER NOW,
AND MY DAD,
HE ASKED ME TO GO ELK HUNTING
WITH KYLE AND TROY,
AND I'M GONNA PUT 'EM
TO THE TEST,
YOU KNOW, SEE WHAT THEY CAN DO
AND WHAT THEY CAN'T DO.
OKAY, SET ME DOWN.
YEP.
ALL RIGHT, I THINK
YOU'LL BE ABLE TO HANDLE IT.
YEAH,
YOU'RE NOT SO BAD.
JUST HOPE
EVERYTHING GOES ALL RIGHT
AND WE MAKE IT BACK SAFE.
BOYS HAVE BEEN WORKING
PRETTY HARD AROUND CAMP, YOU KNOW?
AND I DON'T THINK
I HAVE A BETTER WAY
TO TEST THE METTLE OF THESE BOYS
OTHER THAN SENDING THEM OUT
ON AN ELK HUNT WITH ROBERT,
AND BESIDES THAT,
WE CAN GET SOME MEAT
IN THE FREEZER, YOU KNOW?
GRAB ME SIX ROUNDS,
KYLE.
THIS IS OUR CHANCE
TO PROVE OURSELVES
THAT WE CAN ACTUALLY HANG
IN THIS BUSINESS.
I'M A LITTLE BIT EXCITED,
A LITTLE BIT NERVOUS.
I'M READY FOR THE CHALLENGE.
I'M READY TO STEP UP.
HEY, MOM. HOW ARE YOU?
BEFORE HEADING OUT
ON THIS ELK HUNT,
I DECIDED TO CHECK IN
WITH MY MOM
ON THE EMERGENCY
SATELLITE PHONE.
YEAH, WHAT DID THEY SAY?
STARTING WHEN?
SHE TOLD ME THAT SOMEBODY TRYING
TO GET AHOLD OF ME,
BEEN E-MAILING ME FOR THE LAST
- I DON'T KNOW - FEW WEEKS,
AND WONDERING IF I HAD FALLEN
OFF THE FACE OF THE EARTH,
'CAUSE I HAVEN'T HAD
ANY CONTACT.
AND I GUESS I HAVE
A JOB OFFER COACHING SOCCER.
EVERYTHING THAT I'VE WORKED FOR
ALMOST MY WHOLE LIFE
PERSONALLY AND PROFESSIONALLY,
IN SOCCER,
KIND OF CULMINATING
IN THIS ONE OPPORTUNITY.
BUT I ENJOY BEING OUT HERE
SO MUCH
WITH MY DAD AND MY BROTHER
THAT I...
MAN.
IT'S...
WELL, MY DAD AND MY BROTHER
WOULD BE PRETTY HEARTBROKEN
IF I WERE TO TAKE OFF,
AND, YEAH,
I'M REALLY CONFLICTED
IN WHAT TO DO.
AND I NEED TO TAKE SOME TIME
TO THINK ABOUT IT.
AH.
WAITING ON KYLE.
I KNOW THAT THERE'S,
WHAT, ABOUT TWO OR THREE BEAR
THAT ALWAYS HUNT
THAT HERD UP THERE,
ESPECIALLY WHEN THEY'RE OUT
ON STEEP CAPE.
YEAH.
SO...
THEY'RE GOING UP TO A PLACE
WHERE THE BEARS
FOLLOW THE ELK HERD,
AND THAT'S WHAT THEY'RE EATING,
AND SO IT CAN BE
DANGEROUS BEAR-WISE,
BE DANGEROUS WEATHER-WISE -
ALL KINDS OF THINGS
THAT CAN HAPPEN
THAT ARE BAD MOSTLY.
YOU MADE IT.
WE ALMOST LEFT WITHOUT YOU.
WITH THIS ELK HUNT,
I JUST AM HOPING FOR THE BEST.
HAVE A GOOD ONE.
WE'LL BE BACK.
KYLE, TROY, AND ROB
ARE TRAVELING
15 MILES NORTHWEST OF THE LODGE
TO UPPER MALINA LAKE.
HERE, THE REMOTE FERTILE VALLEYS
SUPPORT LARGE HERDS
OF ROOSEVELT ELK.
FINE WEATHER.
LIQUID SUNSHINE.
THE GROUP WILL BE CUT OFF
FROM ALL UTILITIES
AND COMMUNICATION
UNTIL THE PLANE RETURNS.
WHOO-HOO!
WE'RE GOING ELK HUNTING!
THEY'LL HAVE
TWO FULL DAYS TO HUNT AN ELK.
WELL, LET THE HUNT BEGIN.
BUT WHERE THE ELK RUN,
THE KODIAK BROWN BEARS
LIE IN WAIT.
THIS SPOT IS AWESOME.
WELL, THERE'S DEFINITELY
ALWAYS A DANGER OF BEAR.
BEFORE YOU'RE EVEN
SETTING UP CAMP,
THEY KNOW YOU'RE THERE -
THEY'RE SMELLING YOU.
DOES THIS LOOK LIKE A BEAR
HAS BEEN DIGGING IN HERE?
YEAH.
REALLY?
YEAH, LOOKS LIKE
HE JUST KIND OF SWEPT OUT
ALL THE CONES
AND THEN JUST
DUG HIMSELF OUT
A NICE, LITTLE BED IN HERE.
SLEEPING
OUT IN THE WOODS WITH TROY,
WHEN WE'RE IN BEAR COUNTRY,
WE KEEP OUR .500 PISTOLS
JUST RIGHT ABOVE OUR PILLOWS
JUST IN CASE WE NEED TO REACH UP
AND SQUEEZE OFF A SHOT,
BUT A BEAR CAN BE ON TOP OF YOU
BEFORE YOU EVEN HAVE TIME
TO BLINK YOUR EYES.
I'LL SEE YOU GUYS
IN THE MORNING.
SEE YOU IN THE MORNING.
WE'RE GONNA HIKE
TO THE TOP OF THAT RIDGE
AND LOOK IN THE VALLEYS
FOR THOSE BIG HERDS OF ELK.
YOU'RE THE GUIDES.
YOU TELL ME.
I'M KIND OF LIKE THE
CLIENT, AND THEY'RE GONNA BE GUIDES.
THERE'S NO TIME FOR ERROR.
AND THESE BOYS
BETTER PROVE THEMSELVES TO ME,
OTHERWISE I'LL GIVE THEM
A BAD REPORT.
HURRY UP, TROY.
WE GOT TO STAY WITH ROB.
ELK UP HERE IN KODIAK,
THEY'RE ROOSEVELT ELK,
AND THEY MOVE SO QUICKLY.
THEY CAN BE
IN THESE DRAINAGES FORAGING,
AND THEN THEY CAN BE
ON THE OTHER SIDE OF A RIDGELINE
IN PROBABLY ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
SO HUNTING THEM UP HERE
IS REALLY, REALLY DIFFICULT.
KEEP AN EYE OUT FOR BEARS.
THE IDEA IS .500-GRAIN BULLET
WITH A SOLID COPPER
POINT HOLLOW TIP,
WILL STOP A BEAR, HOPEFULLY.
DOESN'T ALWAYS TURN OUT
THAT WAY.
IF YOU THINK
THAT'S RIGHT, LET'S GO.
THE ROLE OF A GUIDE
IS TO TAKE CARE OF THE CLIENT.
YOU KNOW, SAFETY'S NUMBER ONE.
TRACKING DOWN THE ANIMAL,
GETTING OUR CLIENT
INTO POSITION,
AND MAKING SURE
HE LEAVES HAPPY -
ALL OF THOSE THINGS
ARE KYLE AND MY PROBLEM.
SEE ANYTHING MOVING?
NO, NOTHING.
WE SHOULD MOVE ON.
LOOK AT THAT!
WHAT IS THAT?
THAT WAS A BIG BUCK.
A BIG BUCK WOULD BE NICE,
BUT WE CAME HERE FOR SOME ELK.
WHICH WAY SHOULD WE GO?
We need to look
for a game trail.
Makes the hiking way easier.
WITH KODIAK, IT ALWAYS MAKES YOU
WORK FOR WHAT YOU WANT.
**** DAMN IT.
Holy ****
RIGHT THERE -
THE ONE SINGLE.
YEP.
I GOT EYES ON IT.
COME ON, STOP.
IT'S A TOUGH SHOT, MAN.
YOU'RE GOING UPHILL
AT 300-PLUS.
OH, FORWARD COW.
FORWARD COW.
YOU GOT HIM, MAN.
YOU **** GOT HIM.
THAT'S A HIT.
THERE SHE GOES.
ROB'S AN ANIMAL, MAN.
HE TOOK A SHOT, GOT IT DOWN,
BUT I THINK HE GOT
THE BIGGEST ELK OF THE HERD.
WE'VE GOT ELK MEAT.
OHO-HO-HO!
THAT THING IS HUGE!
HOLY ****
**** HEY!
- HUH?
- GOOD SHOT, MAN.
NICE.
YOU SAY YOUR THANKS?
NOT YET.
- NO?
- LET'S DO IT.
THANKS FOR THE EXPERIENCE.
THANKS FOR GIVING LIFE
TO CREATE LIFE.
WE APPRECIATE IT.
YOU'LL FEED MANY MOUTHS.
THANK YOU.
GOOD HUNTIN'.
WE'RE GONNA HAVE
TO DIG INTO THIS,
GET IT SKINNED OUT,
GET THE MEAT OFF OF IT.
WE NEED TO GET ON THE BALL
AND GET THIS THING
IN OUR PACKS AND ON THE ROAD,
SO OUR GUIDE SKILLS ARE
REALLY GONNA BE PUT TO THE TEST.
SUN'S GOING DOWN. WE'RE LOSING
DAYLIGHT BY THE MINUTE.
WE STILL GOT A LOT
OF GROUND TO COVER.
THERE'S BEARS
ALL OVER THE PLACE.
THAT FOLLOW THESE HERDS
THAT HUNT THEM YEAR 'ROUND,
AND WE GOT TO GET GOING FAST.
YOU GOT AN EYE
UP THE HILL?
YEAH.
WIND'S STARTING TO PICK UP.
HOW LONG HAVE BEEN HERE
ON THIS?
I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S GONNA BE A LOT OF BLOOD
IN THE AIR.
SCENT OF THIS GUT PILE
HAS PROBABLY TRAVELED
QUITE A DISTANCE.
ONCE BEARS COME ON A CARCASS
AND THEY ESTABLISH
THAT'S THEIR MEAT,
IT'S OVER THEIR DEAD BODY
IS BASICALLY THE ONLY WAY
THAT WE'RE GETTING OUT OF THERE.
SO YOU DON'T WANT
TO LET YOUR GUARD DOWN.
YOU HEAR A STICK, BRANCH SMACK,
YOU KNOW,
YOU'RE CHECKING THAT OUT.
YOU'RE WONDERING WHAT DID THAT.
BOB SAID THAT WE NEED
TO BEAR-PROOF THIS PLACE.
SO IF YOU WANT
TO GRAB SOME WOOD,
I'LL GRAB THE DRILLS
AND SOME SCREWS,
AND THEN
WE CAN WORK ON IT.
YEP.
GOOD?
IT'S THE END
OF THE HUNTING SEASON,
SO THERE ARE A LOT
OF CHORES THAT NEED TO GET DONE.
AND ONE OF THE BIG CONCERNS
WITH LEAVING THE HUNTING CAMP
EMPTY FOR THE SEASON
IS THAT THERE'S A LOT OF FOOD,
AND YOU NEED TO BEAR-PROOF IT,
MAKE SURE THE ANIMALS
AREN'T GETTING INTO IT.
THERE YOU GO.
SO, WHAT WE HAVE TO DO
IS GET THESE SCREWED IN,
AND THEN WHEN THE SCREWS STICK
OUT THE OTHER SIDE,
AND THEN WE FLIP IT OVER,
AND IT'LL BE A LITTLE WARNING
TO ANY BEARS
THAT TRY TO GET IN THE CABIN.
I THINK
I'VE REALIZED THAT I NEED
TO MAKE ALASKA
A BIGGER PART OF MY LIFE,
AND I THINK THAT MAY MEAN
LEAVING MY FARM,
LEAVING SAN DIEGO,
AND TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
HOW I CAN
SPEND MORE TIME UP HERE.
I MEAN, I REALLY DON'T EVEN
WANT TO LEAVE.
ALL RIGHT.
I THINK THAT'S GOOD.
I CAN'T GIVE UP ALASKA.
I'VE SPENT SO MUCH TIME HERE
EVERY YEAR OF MY LIFE,
THAT IF I DON'T COME HERE,
I FEEL OUT OF BALANCE.
PERFECT FIT.
NICE. WE DID A GOOD JOB.
WAS THAT FUN?
OKAY. CAREFUL.
FALSE ALARM.
THOUGHT I HAD A BEAR.
WE GOT TO GET THIS **** DONE
AND GET GOING QUICK.
THERE YOU ARE.
HOLY ****
THAT WEIGHS A LOT.
SIT IT
SO THAT SIDE'S UP.
THIS IS GONNA FEED
BOTH OF OUR FAMILIES
PROBABLY
THE WHOLE WINTER,
AND WE'RE GONNA HAVE THIS
WELL INTO THE SPRING.
EACH TIME WE LOAD SOME
MEAT INTO ONE OF THOSE GAME BAGS
AND LIFT IT UP THE HILL
AND SET IT DOWN,
ALL I'M THINKING IS,
"HOLY ****
THAT IS A HEAVY BAG."
AND JUST LIFTING IT LIKE THAT
AND DROPPING IT DOWN,
YOU CAN ONLY IMAGINE
WHAT IT'S GONNA FEEL LIKE
WHEN YOU GET IT
LOADED UP ON YOUR BACK.
NOW WE HAVE THE ARDUOUS PROCESS
OF FIGURING OUT
HOW THREE OF US ARE GONNA
PACK OUT AN ANIMAL
THAT'S FAR TOO LARGE
FOR THE THREE OF US TO PACK OUT
IN ONE TRIP.
WE HAD 10 GAME BAGS,
AND I'M JUST LOOKING
AT THIS LIKE,
"**** THAT'S A LOT OF MEAT."
I'M NOT TOO STOKED ON THIS PACK.
THIS PACK'S GONNA BE A ****
THERE AIN'T NOTHING ELSE
TO SAY ABOUT IT.
SO, ROBERT SHOOTS
AN 800-POUND ANIMAL.
THAT'S ABOUT
600 POUNDS PACKED OUT.
THERE'S THREE OF US.
THERE'S GONNA BE 200 POUNDS
OF ANIMAL ON MY BACK.
OKAY.
I WEIGH ABOUT 155.
TROY WEIGHS LESS THAN I DO.
AND HE'S A STRONG KID,
BUT WE'RE NOT ANTS.
HE'S UP.
YOU'RE LOOKING
A LITTLE WOBBLY.
HE'S GOOD TO GO.
ALL RIGHT, BOYS.
ALL RIGHT.
THERE'S NOT TRAINING SYSTEM
IN THE WORLD
THAT IS GONNA PREPARE YOU
FOR DOING A HAUL LIKE THIS.
AW ****
AAH! ****
TRY AND STAY ON YOUR FEET
AS LONG AS YOU CAN.
DUDE, THIS THING'S WOBBLING
ALL OVER THE **** PLACE.
****
WE REEK LIKE ELK MEAT.
YOU'RE COVERED IN BLOOD.
AND IF WE DO RUN INTO A BEAR,
IT'S MINE AND KYLE'S JOB
TO PROTECT ROB.
YOU KNOW, HE'S THE HUNTER.
IF WE GOT TO TAKE A BEAR DOWN,
WE GOT TO TAKE ONE DOWN.
DAMN, THIS IS THE MOST
UNCOMFORTABLE **** PACK.
WHOA. THIS SUCKS.
WE'RE PACKING OUT THIS MEAT.
IT IS JUST
THE MOST GRUELING THING
THAT I HAVE EVER EXPERIENCED.
THIS IS PART
OF THE GUIDING BUSINESS.
BUT THIS IS PAINFUL,
AND THIS SUCKS.
****
YOU ALL RIGHT?
YEAH.
I WAS JUST
COMING DOWN THAT HILL,
SLIPPED, LOST MY FOOTING,
TURNED MY ANKLE OVER.
IT'S THE SAME ANKLE
I HAD SURGERY ON.
I NEED TO
SIT DOWN AGAIN.
WHEW,
I'M **** CRAMPING UP.
TELL YOU WHAT, MAN,
THOSE HILLS
ARE PUSHING ME TO MY MAX.
OH, MY.
****
OHH!
GUYS, WE ARE NEVER
GONNA MAKE IT AT THIS PACE.
WE'RE RUNNING OUT OF DAYLIGHT,
AND IF WE GET STUCK OUT HERE
IN THE DARK, WE'RE SCREWED.
LET'S LEAVE
HALF THE MEAT UP HERE.
HAVE TO COME BACK FOR IT
IN THE MORNING.
IF THAT'S WHAT
YOU THINK IS BEST, ALL RIGHT.
IF WE LOSE HALF THE MEAT,
WELL, THAT'S BETTER
THAN LOSING OUR LIVES.
THE SAFER THING TO DO IS THROW
HALF THIS MEAT UP IN THE TREES.
THAT WAY, IF WE DO
RUN INTO SOMETHING,
WE'RE NOT OVERWEIGHTED
WITH SO MUCH WEIGHT.
BLACK BEARS CAN CLIMB TREES,
BUT KODIAK BROWN BEAR,
THEY'RE JUST TOO DAMN BIG.
THEY CAN'T GET UP THOSE TREES.
YOU GOT THAT?
YEAH, JUST TIE IT OFF
RIGHT THERE.
LET'S KEEP EYES OUT
FOR BEARS.
WHAT WAS THAT?
LET'S KEEP EYES OUT
FOR BEARS.
WHAT WAS THAT?
IT'S NOTHING.
YOU GOT THAT?
YEAH, JUST TIE IT OFF
RIGHT THERE.
COME BACK IN THE MORNING
AND THERE'S A BEAR
UNDERNEATH THE TREE,
IT'S A DANGEROUS SITUATION.
YOU KNOW, THAT'S HIS TERRITORY,
THAT'S HIS MEAT,
HE'S DETERMINED THAT,
AND HE'S GONNA DIE
TRYING TO PROTECT IT.
ALL RIGHT, BOYS.
HOPEFULLY, THAT MEAT'S
STILL THERE IN THE MORNING.
WORKED TOO **** HARD
TO GET IT THAT FAR
TO LOSE IT.
IT'S TWO MORE RAVINES.
COME ON. JUST KEEP MOVING.
THE DROPPING
TEMPERATURES OF LATE FALL
TRIGGER A SURVIVAL INSTINCT
IN KODIAK BROWN BEARS
THAT MAKES THEM RAVENOUS
FOR RED MEAT.
THEY HUNT BOTH DAY AND NIGHT
TO FATTEN THEMSELVES
FOR HIBERNATION.
WHEN A KODIAK BROWN BEAR
SMELLS BLOOD IN THE AIR,
THEY'RE COMING FOR IT.
THEY SMELL FRESH KILL,
THEY WANT IT.
I'LL FEEL BETTER
ONCE WE GET BACK INTO CAMP.
OH! LAST HURRAH.
WE MADE IT, BOYS.
YES, WE DID.
HEY, TROY,
WILL YOU HELP ME HANG THIS MEAT?
THEN WE GOT TO
START A FIRE.
YOU KNOW, WE'RE PRETTY HAPPY
TO GET BACK INTO CAMP
WITHOUT ANY BEAR INCIDENTS,
BUT WE STILL HAVE
A LOT OF WORK TO DO.
YOU CAN'T
LEAVE THAT MEAT SITTING DOWN.
ROBERT'S
GONNA HOP UP IN THE TREE
AND THEN START HEAVING THOSE
120-PLUS-POUND HIND QUARTERS
30 YARDS UP JUST TO MAKE SURE
THAT THE BEARS
AREN'T GETTING INTO IT.
WITH ALL OF THAT MEAT
UP IN THE TREE,
WE'RE PRETTY MUCH BEAR BAIT.
THERE'S EVERY SINGLE WORRY
GOING THROUGH MY HEAD.
THIS IS NOT GOOD.
ONE, TWO, THREE, GO.
IS THAT THE LAST ONE?
YEP, THAT'S IT.
CALL IT GOOD.
I'M **** EXHAUSTED.
YOU'RE A DIFFICULT
FIRST CLIENT -
TRYING TO REIN YOU IN
AND KEEP YOU CORRALLED,
SO TO SPEAK.
I LOVE DOING THIS
ALMOST AS MUCH
OR IF NOT MORE
THAN COACHING SOCCER.
BEFORE NOW,
I WOULD'VE BEEN REALLY EXCITED
AND JUMPED AT THE OPPORTUNITY,
AND RIGHT NOW I'M JUST HAVING
SECOND THOUGHTS.
I DEFINITELY DON'T WANT TO
DISAPPOINT TROY.
I KNOW THAT HE WOULD RELY ON
HAVING ME OUT HERE TO HELP HIM,
AND I DON'T KNOW
WHAT I'M GONNA DO,
AND I'M REALLY TORN UP INSIDE.
BUT RIGHT NOW
ALL I'M THINKING IS,
"WE'RE GONNA BE GOING OUT AGAIN
IN THE MORNING
TO GO AND GET THAT SECOND LOAD."
SO I NEED TO MAKE SURE THAT
MY HEAD'S IN THE RIGHT PLACE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
THE CHANCES ARE
THAT WE'RE GONNA COME ACROSS
A BEAR SITTING ON THAT MEAT?
THERE'S A PRETTY GOOD
CHANCE.
ABBY, WANT TO GO DUCK HUNTING?
WANT TO GO DUCK HUNTING?
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GO.
WITH ALL THE CLIENTS
GONE, BOB, ERNIE, AND CUSACK
HAVE TIME TO GET IN
ONE LAST HUNT
BEFORE WINTER SHUTS THEM DOWN.
THIS TIME OF YEAR,
IT'S TIME TO PUT SOME MEAT
IN THE FREEZER.
THE BOYS ARE OUT HUNTING,
SO GO OUT WITH ERNIE AND CUSACK
AND SHOOT A FEW DUCKS.
KIND OF LIKE OLD TIMES,
YOU KNOW?
THAT'S A DOGGONE FINE DECOY
THAT'S OUT THERE RIGHT NOW,
MISTER.
NOW WE JUST GOT TO WAIT
FOR THE DUCKS.
- HERE'S A DUCK.
- HERE WE GO.
ALL RIGHT, BOB.
WONDER HOW THE BOYS
ARE DOING.
TROY AND KYLE,
THEY'VE GOT THE BEST MENTORS
THAT YOU COULD EVER HAVE
IN GUIDING -
BOB MAY AND BOB CUSACK.
HERE THEY ARE COMING IN.
YOU CAN'T MEET
A MORE INTERESTING PERSON
THAN BOB CUSACK.
HIS GUIDE'S LICENSE
IS NUMBER 72, FOR GOD'S SAKE.
I MEAN, HE WAS THE 72nd GUIDE
LICENSED IN THE STATE OF ALASKA.
WHAT, THIS GUY
DID 45 YEARS UP HERE.
HERE WE GO.
SOMETHING COMING UP.
BOBBY MAY HAS MENTORED ME
IN THE GUIDE BUSINESS.
I APPRENTICED UNDER HIM
FOR THREE YEARS HERE IN KODIAK,
AND THEN I STAYED
FOR ANOTHER 10.
AND TO THE LADIES.
THAT'S NOT ALL RIGHT
TO SAY THAT.
COOKED
THIS WONDERFUL MEAL.
I HAVE TO REALLY GIVE HIM CREDIT
FOR A LOT OF THE SKILLS
THAT I HAVE NOW IN THE WOODS
AND THE SKILLS THAT I HAVE,
YOU KNOW, BROWN BEAR HUNTING.
WELL, I HEAR A DUCK.
I HEAR A DUCK.
HERE'S A DUCK.
TAKE HIM.
TOUGH SHOT.
I GOT MY GUIDE'S LICENSE
UNDER BOB.
KYLE AND TROY ARE GOING THROUGH
THAT SAME APPRENTICESHIP.
AS LONG AS YOU GOT ENOUGH DUCKS
TO EAT, I'LL BE HAPPY.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT ROBERT'S
GONNA SAY ABOUT IT.
WE'LL JUST HAVE TO SEE.
KYLE, TROY, AND ROB
ARE TRAVERSING
THE THREE MILES BACK
TO THE PLACE WHERE THEY LEFT
300 POUNDS OF ELK MEAT
HANGING IN A TREE.
THEY MUST GET THE MEAT AND
HURRY TO THE RENDEZVOUS POINT
WITHIN TWO HOURS,
OR RISK MISSING THEIR PLANE
BACK TO THE LODGE.
JUST GOT TO KEEP MOVING.
FOR THE PAST EIGHT HOURS,
THE SCENT OF THE HANGING MEAT
COULD'VE DRAWN IN
EVERY BROWN BEAR
WHO HAS BEEN STALKING
THE ELK HERDS IN THIS AREA.
WE GOT A BIG TASK - WE GOT TO
GO BACK OUT IN THE FIELD,
POTENTIALLY CHASE OFF A BEAR
FROM THE PRIZED MEAT
THAT WE JUST WORKED SO HARD
GETTING.
SCARY.
ARE THOSE THEM -
THESE TWO JUST RIGHT ABOVE
THE HORIZON?
YEAH, I THINK IT IS.
THAT MEAT'S BEEN UP IN THAT TREE
ALL NIGHT.
PLENTY OF TIME FOR A BEAR
TO COME AND THINK IT'S HIS.
WE MAKE IT BACK TO THE MEAT.
YOU KNOW, WE DON'T KNOW
IF THERE'S A BEAR THERE,
SO WE GOT TO APPROACH IT
REALLY CALMLY.
YOU KNOW, THERE COULD BE
A SLEEPING BEAR
UNDERNEATH THE TREE.
GUYS, LET'S MAKE A BUNCH
OF NOISE AS WE GET CLOSER.
WE DON'T WANT TO SNEAK UP
ON A BEAR.
HEY! HEY!
HEY, BEAR!
COO!
NICE. THERE'S THE MEAT.
IT'S STILL HANGING.
NO **** BEARS
GOT INTO IT.
DROP YOUR PACKS,
TRY TO GET UP THERE.
ALL RIGHT,
I'M GOING UP TO GET IT.
COVER MY ASS.
WATCH OUT FOR BEARS.
HURRY UP, TROY.
THERE YOU GO.
THOSE BEARS CAN BE ULTRA-SILENT.
THEY'LL SIT THERE.
THEY COULD AMBUSH YOU
IF THEY REALLY WANTED TO.
GOOD TOSS.
ALL RIGHT, I GOT IT.
LET'S GO.
LET'S DO IT.
LET'S ROLL.
IT'S NOT HEALTHY
TO BE OUT IN THE FIELD
WITH BAIT ON YOUR BACK
IN BEAR COUNTRY.
THEY CAN SEE US,
AND WE CAN'T SEE THEM,
SO THEY HAVE EVERY ADVANTAGE.
THAT PLANE
HAS A SMALL WINDOW TO GET US,
SO WE GOT TO HAUL ASS.
I'M DEFINITELY WORRIED
ABOUT GETTING LEFT ON THIS ISLAND.
WE'RE BASICALLY
AT THE PILOT'S MERCY.
WE'RE NOT CELEBRATING YET.
SOMETIMES -
I KNOW THOSE FLOAT PILOTS -
THEY DON'T LIKE LANDING
IN WHITE-CAPPED WATERS,
AND THERE'S SOME CAPS
THAT ARE CAPPING OUT THERE.
CAN YOU HEAR IT?
THERE'S THE PLANE.
YEAH, HERE HE COMES.
THAT'S HIM.
LET'S GO, BIG BOY.
FEELS GREAT, YOU KNOW?
FINALLY, THE HUNT IS A SUCCESS.
AND THE FACT THAT ME AND KYLE
MADE IT TOGETHER -
I'M THRILLED.
I'M PUMPED.
I'M EXHAUSTED, BUT I'M PUMPED.
FINALLY. IT'S HERE.
OH, MAN, THAT'S A SWEET SIGHT
RIGHT THERE.
OH, BOY,
AM I GONNA BE HAPPY
WHEN WE GET ALL THIS
BACK TO CAMP.
I KNOW OUR DADS
ARE GONNA BE REALLY PROUD OF US
THAT WE WERE ABLE TO
GET THIS ELK OUT SUCCESSFULLY -
NO INJURIES, NO MISHAPS.
NOW I NEED TO MAKE A DECISION
WHETHER I'M GONNA TAKE
THE JOB COACHING OR STAY
AND DO THE GUIDING BUSINESS
WITH MY BROTHER.
HERE THEY COME.
YEAH.
YOU DID.
HEY, BUD.
WHAT'S UP, DAD?
HOW'S IT GOING?
IT'S GOING GOOD.
HOW'D IT GO, ROBERT?
GOOD.
DID YOU GET ANYTHING?
GOT A COW, YEAH.
YOU'RE KIDDING ME.
OH, MAN. AWESOME!
THERE YOU GO.
KYLE AND TROY ARE BACK,
AND THEY HAD A GREAT HUNT,
BUT I'M MOST HAPPY
TO SEE THEM WALK OFF THE PLANE
AND BE SAFE AND SOUND.
WELL, GOOD JOB.
ALL RIGHT,
I'M PROUD OF YOU GUYS. GOOD JOB.
GOOD JOB, ROBERT.
I HOPE BECAUSE
OF THE SUCCESS WITH THE HUNT
THAT THE BOBS AND MY DAD,
YOU KNOW, SEE THIS AND THEY SAY,
"HO, DAMN. THOSE GUYS
CAN HOLD THEIR OWN, YOU KNOW?
I'D HIRE THOSE GUYS ANY DAY."
WELL, THE ELK HUNT
WENT PRETTY GOOD.
KYLE AND TROY ARE BACK,
AND THEY HAD A GREAT HUNT.
NOW WE GOT TO SEE
WHAT ROBERT HAS TO SAY ABOUT IT.
SO, HOW'D THE BOYS DO?
THEY WERE ALL RIGHT.
THEY DID GOOD, YOU KNOW?
I THINK TROY'S GONNA BE
A HELL OF A GUIDE SOMEDAY.
COOL.
KYLE - HE SEEMED LIKE HE HAD
A LOT ON HIS MIND,
BUT, YOU KNOW,
HE DID WELL IN MY OPINION.
WELL, THANKS
FOR TAKING THEM HUNTING.
YEP.
THAT'S MY REPORT TO YOU
GENTLEMEN.
YOU GUYS
HAVE A GOOD EVENING.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
WELL,
YOU KNOW HOW I FEEL.
WHETHER OR NOT TO GIVE
BOTH MY BOYS THE GREEN LIGHT
IS GONNA BE ONE OF THE HARDEST
THINGS I'VE EVER DONE.
WELL, WE GOT TO WORK
ON THE BOAT HERE.
HAD SOME FUEL PROBLEMS.
THAT'S NOT A GOOD SIGN.
THERE AIN'T NO FUEL IN THIS.
HOPE THE FUEL LINES
AREN'T FROZEN.
LIVING HERE ON KODIAK,
YOU GOT TO BE SELF-SUFFICIENT.
YOU'VE GOT TO HAVE
YOUR OWN SET OF SKILLS
AND BE ABLE TO UTILIZE THEM.
RUNNING.
SOUNDS PRETTY GOOD.
YOU'RE A MECHANIC ONE DAY,
FIXING MOTORS.
THEN THE NEXT DAY,
YOU'RE BUILDING A CABIN,
INSULATING IT, PUTTING UP WALLS.
YOU NEED TO BE ABLE
TO FLY AN AIRPLANE.
YOU NEED TO KNOW HOW TO SET UP
A SHELTER WITH NOTHING.
YOU DON'T KNOW HOW TO FIX A GUN,
YOU SHOULDN'T BE OUT HERE.
IF YOU DON'T KNOW
HOW TO CATCH FISH,
YOU SHOULDN'T BE OUT HERE.
YOU HAVE TO FIGURE THINGS OUT.
YOU BETTER KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE DOING ON KODIAK,
OR YOU'RE GONNA BECOME A VICTIM.
I'M ACTUALLY GLAD
YOU GUYS ARE IN HERE.
I'VE BEEN ON THE FENCE
ABOUT WHETHER
I'M GONNA TAKE THE JOB COACHING
OR BECOME A GUIDE,
AND I'VE MADE MY DECISION.
I HAVE A JOB OFFER
TO GO COACH SOCCER.
IT'S SOMETHING
THAT I'VE BEEN WORKING
A REALLY LONG TIME TOWARDS,
AND I FEEL LIKE, YOU KNOW,
THIS IS SOMETHING THAT I NEED TO
DO AND I WANT TO DO AND...
AT THE SAME TIME, I DON'T
WANT TO LET YOU DOWN, YOU KNOW,
'CAUSE I KNOW DAD WANTS US
TO GUIDE TOGETHER AND...
YEAH. SORRY TO KIND OF JUMP YOU
WITH THIS NEWS, BUT...
SO, WHEN DO YOU LEAVE?
UH, SOON ACTUALLY.
SOON? HOW SOON?
TOMORROW.
TOMORROW?
THAT'S A SURPRISE.
IT'S A MIXED BAG.
KYLE -
I'M REALLY HAPPY FOR HIM.
BUT NOW I GOT TO DEAL
WITH TROY OUT THERE BY HIMSELF.
HE'S CAPABLE, HE'S READY TO GO,
BUT IT'S TOUGH FOR ME.
I'M HAVING A HARD TIME WITH IT,
BUT BOB AND I MAKE THE DECISION,
AND I HAVE TO LIVE WITH IT.
YOU KNOW, I'M KIND OF
MAKING A SELFISH DECISION
TO HEAD OFF TO GO COACH
AND PURSUE MY DREAM, BUT...
IT'S THE JOB OF A LIFETIME,
AND I HAVE TO GO TAKE IT.
ALL RIGHT, PUT THAT DOWN
AND GIVE ME A HUG.
HE'S GONNA LEAVE?
THANKS FOR EVERYTHING.
YEP.
IT'S BEEN AWESOME.
TAKE CARE.
OKAY.
TROY.
LATER, BROTHER.
BE SAFE, ALL RIGHT?
I WILL.
YOU KNOW, I GOT TO SUPPORT HIM.
IT'S WHAT HE WANTS TO DO.
BUT I HOPE
IT DOESN'T AFFECT, YOU KNOW,
MY CHANCES OF BECOMING A GUIDE.
MAN, THANKS, BOB.
ALL RIGHT.
I APPRECIATE EVERYTHING.
YOU DID A GOOD JOB.
THANK YOU. THAT MEANS A LOT.
OH, I GOT TO GO.
ALL RIGHT.
TAKE CARE.
SEE YOU, KYLE.
ALL RIGHT, GOOD.
THAT'S GOOD.
LET ME SHOW YOU GENTLEMEN
HOW US KODIAK BOYS LIGHT A FIRE.
OKAY.
WHAT'S THAT?
DON'T MISS.
OH ****
BE CAREFUL, BOB.
WHOO!
HEY, THERE WE GO! YEAH!
HO! HEY!
FIRE DANCE!
ALL RIGHT. COOL.
WHOO!
LAST NIGHT FIRE, BABY.
WELL, TROY, MY BOY,
EVERYBODY LISTEN UP HERE.
EVERYBODY LISTEN UP.
PLEASE DON'T TALK ABOUT
MY CHEST HAIR.
WE GOT A LITTLE CEREMONY
TO DO HERE.
BEEN DOING PRETTY GOOD GUIDING,
BEEN DOING YOUR CHORES,
BEEN DOING PRETTY GOOD.
WE DECIDED IT'S TIME
THAT YOU BE ACCEPTED INTO
THE BROTHERHOOD OF GUIDES.
ALL RIGHT.
YOUR FIRST RESPONSIBILITY
IS TO A CLEAN KILL
OF THAT ANIMAL.
RESPECT THE LAND.
RESPECT THE HUNT.
NEVER FORGET
THE RESPONSIBILITY
THAT YOU HAVE
TO THAT HUNTER AND THE HUNT
AND ALWAYS RESPECT
THAT HUNT.
AND THIS
IS SO YOU DON'T FORGET.
I WON'T FORGET THAT.
NOW YOU GOT TO WEAR
THIS SILLY ****DAMN HAT
THE REST OF THE NIGHT.
AW. I DID NOT THINK
THAT WAS GONNA HAPPEN.
GOOD JOB, MAN.
THANKS, BOB.
YOU BEEN DOING GOOD.
AWW!
GOOD JOB, BUD.
THANKS, DAD.
YOU'RE WELCOME, BUD.
LOVE YOU.
I GOT MY GUIDE HAT.
PRETTY PROUD OF THIS.
THANK YOU, BOB.
WE'LL TURN YOU LOOSE
ON A FEW BEARS HERE.
I HOPE.
YOU KNOW, KYLE'S NOT HERE,
AND IT'S TOUGH.
BUT HE DID THE RIGHT THING,
AND IT'S JUST GREAT TO SEE TROY,
YOU KNOW, GROW INTO A MAN
AND GET HIS DUE.
RIGHT,
I'M GONNA MISS YOU BOYS.
YEAH, BUBBA!
KIND OF HATE TO SEE IT END.
WE'VE ALL HAD A DAMN GOOD TIME,
BUT THAT'S THE WAY LIFE IS,
YOU KNOW?
I'M GLAD THAT YOU GUYS
BROUGHT US OUT HERE,
SHOW US THE ROPES.
EASY DOES IT NOW.
YOU KNOW, ANYMORE,
IT'S HARD TO FIND YOUNG GUYS
THAT REALLY WANT TO
GET THEIR HANDS DIRTY
AND BE ASSISTANT GUIDES.
IT'S NOT EASY.
YOU KNOW, YOU'RE NOT
GONNA GET RICH AT IT.
AS HARD AS IT IS,
I MEAN, IT'S LIKE A BROTHERHOOD.
THANKS.
OKAY.
THANKS, BOB.
OH, YEAH.
YOU KNOW?
SURROUND YOURSELF
WITH THE RIGHT PEOPLE IN LIFE,
THINGS GO SMOOTH.
I MEAN, WITHOUT ERNIE, BOB,
AND THE BOYS, I'M NOTHING.
YOU CAN'T REPLACE PEOPLE
LIKE THAT.
YOU KNOW, I'M WAITING
FOR THE NEXT BEAR SEASON NOW.
MAKES ME WANT TO JUST GET OUT
THERE AND KICK ASS.