- Goodnight, John.
- Goodnight, milord. Goodnight, milady.
- Goodnight.
Excuse me, sir. Is that
Lord Glenarvan's yacht?
- It is.
- Well, we'd like to see him, please.
Oh, would you, now?
He'll be horribly hurt to know...
you didn't arrive
for the start of the party.
We didn't even know about it.
I bring news of one of his ships,
disappeared at sea.
A message from Captain Grant
of the Britannia.
Captain Grant?
Why, he's dead, isn't he?
And just how would he get
a bottle where he's at?
- Go on. Get on with you.
- Captain Grant's our father,
and he's not dead.
I'm Mary Grant,
and this is my brother, Robert.
Oh, no offence intended, miss.
He was a good man, he was.
The best this line ever had.
It's just that it's, uh, hard to take
serious. The note in the bottle, I mean.
Still, l-I suppose
it could happen.
And that's why we just have to
see his lordship before he sails.
Oh, I'm sorry, miss.
I've had my orders.
Nobody aboard
except invited guests.
But we've come all the way from Plymouth
today. It has cost me my last franc.
And we haven't
had a thing to eat.
So that's it.
Another trick, is it?
Get out of here with your wild tales,
your hard-luck stories.
You almost had me taken in for a minute.
Go on. Stand clear of the gate there.
Come on, Robert.
- Lovely.
- Goodnight to you.
You two, come back here!
Come back, I said.
You children,
come here at once.
- Did you hear me?
- Good evening.
- Come back, I said! Come back at once!
Come out now, matey,
wherever you are.
You wouldn't want me to lose
my bloomin' job now, would you?
- How do we get past this one?
- Goodnight, sir.
Oh, very simple.
Just walk nonchalantly...
up the plank backwards.
Yes, with all the confusion...
he won't be able to tell you
from the departing guests.
Go on, now. Go on.
Goodnight, sir, madam.
Goodnight, sir.
- Come on.
- You now.
Go on. Go on, go on!
Goodnight, sir.
Goodnight.
Little boy, would you be so kind
as to get my wrap for me?
- I think I left it in the salon.
- You children, what are you
doing there?
- Stop those children!
- Evening.
- Come back, you two!
- Good evening. Good evening, sir.
Come back. Stop, you two!
Come on. Stop!
Come back, you two.
Come back!
- May I give you some more turkey?
- Thank you.
Not too much.
The salmon is delicious.
I hear Lord Glenarvan is going
to Venezuela again this year.
Yes. He so much
enjoys the seasons.
How long does he plan
to be away this time?
He seems very proud
of this new, uh, steamer.
Good evening.
Uh-Uh, cloves from Madagascar.
It is not bad for English ham.
Oh, excuse me, madam.
There's someone
under the table! Look!
There they are!
Head them off the other way.
Steward! Steward!
Up there on the deck!
- Oh, let me go!
- Why?
Come back, you two! Come back!
Oh, come here.
Come here now, then. I got you!
- I got you!
- Oh, let me go!
- You leave him alone!
- Oh!
Oh. It's you, your lordship.
- Isn't it?
- I daresay, but who are you?
- Oh, please, your lordship,
we must speak to you.
- We've come all the way from Plymouth.
- I'm Mary Grant, and this is my
brother. Our father's Captain Grant.
- On the Britannia.
- And he's alive. And you must send
a ship to bring them back.
- With two of his men.
- As quick as you can.
- Now, just a minute.
Come along.
We'll talk it over.
Now, then, how do you know
your father's still alive?
- He put a note in a bottle.
- And a French professor...
- Monsieur Paganel, he found it.
- Oh-Oh, that again.
- What do you mean?
- My dear children, ever since...
I posted the reward
for news of your father's ship...
people have been turning up with notes
they claim to have found in bottles.
- How many is this, John?
- Uh, 22, Father.
If I had my way,
every last one of the culprits
would be hanged from the yardarms!
Exploiting human misery,
that's what it is.
Nothing more vicious,
more treacherous.
But it is from my father.
I can tell.
Monsieur Paganel, show them
the note you found in the bottle.
Voilà. Oh, I'm-I'm sorry.
Wr-Wrong bottle.
Ah, this is the one.
First question always,
where'd you find the bottle?
Well, y-you see, milord,
l-I went fishing with some students.
And I suppose you cut open a fish
and found the bottle inside.
Oui, oui, milord,
a 220-pound shark!
Osborne, throw this man off the ship
before I turn him over to the police.
- No, your lordship.
- But it is the truth, what I tell you.
Ridiculous. Why should a shark
want to swallow a bottle?
Oh, what was in his mind,
l-l-I don't know.
l-I tell you only what
was in his stomach.
You make a career of this,
do you, exploiting children?
I am Jacques Eliacin
Francois Paganel.
Professor of geography,
Université of Paris.
My credentials, milord. Oh!
Forged, I imagine, like the note
in the bottle. All right, Steward.
Come along.
- Oh, no, your lordship, you can't!
- Monsieur Paganel's our friend.
Just a minute, children.
I have something to say to you.
If we could be
alone for a moment.
Take your hands off me, messieurs.
Never have I been thrown
from anyplace in my life.
Let's not set a precedent.
My dear children, don't you think
I'd be the first to respond...
if I thought there was the slightest
chance of finding your father...
or any of his crew alive?
I'd go to the ends of the earth,
and that's no idle boast.
The Glenarvan motto:
"Persevero".
It's been the family creed
for 800 years.
But it's not a hoax. I saw the note
myself, and I know my father wrote it.
The way he makes his letters.
I can tell.
Just a little more clever
than the rest, that's all.
When you consider the odds, it would be
fantastic just finding the bottle.
But this business about it
being swallowed by a shark...
Well, what would my father have to do?
Come back here himself and say...
"Yes, I wrote the note.
Now come and find me."
Did I understand you to say
you came all the way from Plymouth?
Tell Osborne to get cabins ready
for 'em. We'll drop them
off there on the way.
- Very well.
- But what about Monsieur Paganel?
- We can't go off here and leave him.
- Now, my dear, I'm only doing
what's best for you.
Now, then, how'd he get past you
in the first place?
Well, how did he get past you,
if it comes to that?
Now, wait a minute.
Oh, here's his lordship's wine.
- And about time too.
- A bit late, aren't you, Charlie?
It'll be a pretty rough trip
if his lordship doesn't get his wine.
Uh, follow me, please.
This way, miss. Cabin number five
on the starboard side.
Of course, Richard's
a lot older than you.
Maybe not actually in years, but...
Oh, he's been around more.
I don't know what
you mean by that.
After all, there's probably
nobody else in the world my age...
who's made as many trips
to the Mediterranean as I have.
Well, that's just it! I mean...
have you ever been to, oh,
South America, for instance?
As a matter of fact, no.
- Pacific Ocean. Ever seen that?
- It's only an ocean.
Perhaps you should have waited
and had breakfast with my father.
He's the one
who'd have to give the order
to change course for South America.
Oh, he would go.
Nothing could stop him...
if it were for something
you could really believe in...
and not this note in a bottle.
Let me ask you something. If you were
a castaway and you had a bottle...
wouldn't you put a note in it
and throw it into the sea?
Oh, I don't think so. After all,
it's such a small chance, isn't it?
Well, what would you do, then?
Just sit there with the empty bottle
until you died or something?
All right. I suppose I would try it.
But I wouldn't expect someone
to find it inside a shark.
Well, if that's where
they did find it...
you wouldn't expect them
to just forget about you, would you?
You never saw that Frenchman before
in your life...
did you, until he showed up
with the bottle?
And yet, you believe
every word he says.
And no matter what he says, you
and your father refuse to believe him.
Suppose I told you that I'd found
a bottle with a note in it.
- Would you believe me?
- Well, did you?
- Yes.
- And what did it say?
It said:
"Disregard first message."
Oh, I suppose you think
that's funny, don't you?
You've got your father,
so to you this is just a big joke.
Now, wait a minute.
I'm not making a joke of it.
- I'm just trying to show you.
- Please, do you mind?
- I'll make you an offer.
- What kind of an offer?
I don't necessarily believe this story
about the shark swallowing the bottle.
But I am getting a little fed up
with these infernal trips
to the Mediterranean.
Down, boy. Good old boy. I'll bring
you a bone or something later.
That's a good boy.
Oh, uh, bonjour.
In case you've emptied
your own pockets.
And just don't let any shark
get this away from you.
Thank you.
I assure you, mademoiselle,
your case shall be properly presented.
After all, Father,
suppose it was you cast away.
Do you think I would give up
if I had even the slightest clue?
I'd live up to all the legends
of Glenarvan. Persevere,
if I had to move heaven and earth.
- Why don't we try Corsica for a change?
- Father, will you listen to me?
- Haven't been there for years.
- Suppose you were a castaway
and you had a bottle.
You wouldn't just sit there
staring at it until you died
or something, would you?
You'd at least try
putting a note into it.
And suppose for some strange reason
it did get swallowed by a shark.
- Most unlikely, I'd say.
- Very well, then.
If you won't listen, I shall be getting
off at Plymouth with Mary and Robert.
- Oh, come, come, come, come.
- I feel very strongly about this,
Father.
My dear boy,
if that's the way you feel about it,
let's have a look at the blasted note.
- Where is it?
- In the bottle.
- Well, where's the bottle?
- The Frenchman has it.
- Confound it, where's the Frenchman?
- You had him thrown off
the ship in Glasgow.
- That's a fine thing.
When I really want something,
no one takes the slightest notice.
- If I happen to drop a casual remark...
- Casual remark?
"Throw him off the ship
before I call the police!
We ought to hang him
from the yardarm."
Now we're in a deuce of a fix.
That Frenchman might be anywhere by now.
Where's Captain Mangles?
Tell Captain Mangles to... Oh!
- Oui, milord?
- Good gracious, the Frenchman!
- I thought...
- Oh, but I give you my word,
I was put off the ship.
Fortunately, I do not let
such things upset me.
The note, milord.
Well, this is useless. There's
practically nothing of it left.
Ah, but with a little study,
a little intelligence...
it is possible
to make out what is said.
You will see one thing
w-without question.
Their location is given
as 37 degrees...
11 minutes, southern latitude.
That's no good
without the longitude.
Consider first, milord,
on the 37th parallel...
there are only a few places
they could be.
That's what I've always said.
If Captain Grant's anywhere at all,
he's in Australia.
It's only logical if you know
anything about shipping and commerce.
Use the head, milord.
The note makes reference
to being captured, no?
And you can make out the word
"Indian" or "Indians".
So where on the 37th parallel
would they be captured by Indians?
- Australia, of course!
- Aboriginals, yes. Indians, no.
By George! I've got it. South America.
Couldn't be anywhere else.
And if he was captured by Indians,
he'd be on the West Coast.
It's a matter
of simple logic, monsieur.
We'll go there and follow
the 37th parallel over the Andes...
until we find Captain Grant.
Osborne, find Captain Mangles!
Tell him I'm going to change course.
- Thank you, milord! Thank you!
- Oh!
- Now, just a minute.
Don't forget that
it was me who arranged...
- Thank you!
- Thank you, milord!
Oh, please!
I'm an Englishman, you know.
There, milord, is where we must go.
The pass of Antuco.
Then follow the parallel
until we find Captain Grant.
Ha, jolly good trick to throw
a bottle into the ocean
from up there, I must say.
Ah, but could he not put
the bottle into a river?
And would it not flow
down to the sea, eh?
No, no. Grimpons.
- Grimpons.
- That means "let's climb".
It is the French recipe
for the good life.
Whatever you want to do, don't be
afraid to do it for fear of failure.
Don't be afraid
of the beautiful and high mountain
- Let's climb, let's climb
let's climb, let's climb, let's climb
- Let's climb, let's climb, let's climb
Don't be afraid of
the beautiful and high mountain
Let's climb, let's climb, let's climb
Let's climb, let's climb
And if we fall, crash, bang
And die a terrible death
Never mind, we've had thejoy
thejoy of the climb
Oh, don't be afraid of
the beautiful and high mountain
Let's climb, let's climb, let's climb
let's climb, let's climb
Let's climb, let's climb
Oh, look! Look!
Straight down that valley there.
- Where?
- Do you see it, milord?
A river into which
one might throw a bottle.
- By Jove, yes!
- And an Indian village.
I'd say, this could be just the place,
couldn't it? Have a look, my dear.
Better make camp here tonight
and get an early start in the morning.
Hey, you, make camp.
Stay here tonight.
- No stay.
- Huh?
- What's the fellow talking about?
- Ah, it is not Spanish.
It must be a local Indian term.
Hey, hey, hey.
What means trango peeray?
Oh, l-l-l-l-I think
he-he wants to tell us...
it gets, uh,
terribly cold up here.
Oh, we build a fire,
no matter how cold.
No matter how trango peeray,
we stay in hut.
- No stay.
- Listen to me.
I tell you when to go
and when to stay.
- No stay.
- We stay here tonight!
- You stay. We go.
- Don't you dare to try and tell me!
I think the fellow
really means it.
Well, that's done it.
Without the horses, we're helpless.
- We'll never make it.
- Well, can't we still go on on foot?
But of course, mademoiselle.
The Araucanians have...
crossed these mountains on foot
for hundreds of years.
- Even drive their sheep.
- Oh, good!
- When do we start?
- We're not gonna start.
I'm not gonna go
leaping about like a...
like a confounded
mountain sheep, thank you.
- Oh, please, your lordship, please!
- No, no, mademoiselle. Uh, he's right.
Uh-Uh-Uh, we-we'll, uh, return
to the ship with the Indians...
and get some crewmen
who are younger.
- Age has got nothing
whatever to do with it.
- I'll take over
and lead the-the expedition.
You-You-You can remain
in your deck chair.
You lead the way? Ridiculous! Have
the whole lot of you lost in no time.
On the other hand,
with me in command...
it would take a great deal more than,
ha, trango peeray to turn us back.
- That's right, isn't it?
- Right, your lordship.
Monsieur Paganel, do you think
we might have one tonight?
When you are in the poultry yard, it is
a good time to wish you catch the egg.
See? Look at this. See?
Any slight tremor of the earth,
and it starts to swing.
But if you're asleep,
how could you tell?
Oh, maybe all night I sleep,
uh, with one eye open.
Perhaps his lordship
will sleep better...
if we do not tell him
before tomorrow...
what trango peeray means, eh?
Your pleasure, mademoiselle.
Castaway, castaway
Trust in your star
You know I will find you
Wherever you are
Though all your dreams
May be tossed by the tide
Cling to your hopes
Never cast them aside
Castaway, castaway
Though you may be
Lost in the wilderness
Over the sea
I will discover
Your castaway shore
Then you'll
Be a castaway
No more
You'll be
A castaway
No more
It's my father's favourite.
E-Ever since I was a little girl,
I've always thought it sad.
Not the way you sang it.
Oh, it's just the way I feel
tonight, I suppose.
Oh, it's all so exciting.
We're up here.
Father's down there.
The stars pointing the way.
It's almost like
being in heaven.
- I know.
- Ah, there you are, my boy.
Better get some sleep, you know.
Got an early start.
- We're too excited to sleep.
- Mm, so I see.
You'd better come along with me,
just the same.
Wait. I want to make a wish
on that star.
What could you wish for
that you haven't got?
That my father would go
somewhere and get lost.
Just for a little while,
you understand.
- What on earth are you doing?
- This is to wake me up.
- Wake you up?
- Yes, in case...
- In case what?
- Oh, nothing.
- And what is this, may I ask?
- My watch, milord.
Perhaps I want to look at it
during the night.
How very peculiar.
Oh, Robert, really.
Do put those things away.
But if there's an earthquake,
I want to be sure and see it.
Earthquake? Who said anything
about an earthquake?
Oh, I'm so stupid, milord.
I didn't realize it until later.
The Indian, when he did,
uh-uh-uh, that, you see?
He did not mean
it was cold. No.
He meant trango peeray...
earthquake!
- This is the land of many earthquakes.
- Gracious me.
In the whole world,
no place has such big...
such beautiful, such magnificent
earthquakes as right here.
But it is one chance in a million
we should be so fortunate.
Yes. Yes. Yes, of course.
Quite right.
Besides, this place looks as if
it's been here for hundreds of years.
Doesn't it?
I mean, uh, it's safe to assume...
that it will last
one more night, eh?
- Oui, monsieur?
- Oui, milord.
And I'll wake you up
if one comes, your lordship.
- It worked!
- Oh, Robert, do be quiet.
An earthquake
of the first magnitude.
I say, do you have
to shake the whole place?
By Jove, it's an earthquake!
Outside, everybody!
Oh! Oh, magnificent!
This is an experience that makes
our entire expedition worthwhile.
By Jove, that was
a narrow squeak! Oh!
I say, this is
getting rather dangerous.
Then we attempt to change course.
Everybody to port.
- It worked!
- That's better. Much obliged.
- Look out! Look out!
- This way, everybody, quick!
To the port, quick!
- What the... Port, quickly!
- No, starboard!
- Port, I say!
- Starboard!
Where are we going now?
- Perfect timing.
- Oh!
- Abandon ship!
- No! Wait!
- There's a hole in the ice!
- But we don't know where it goes.
We'll soon find out.
Alpine-type glacier.
Drift minimum.
We'll never get
out of here alive.
The ice melts and gets out.
Why can't we?
- Isn't it beautiful!
- Oh!
They'll never believe us
when we get home. If we get home.
Look out, everybody! Duck!
Where...
Where're we going now? Ooh.
Try starboard, I tell you!
- This is most peculiar.
- Look out!
- That was close.
- Oh!
Come on!
- Where's Robert?
- Here's his hat.
Robert! Robert,
can you hear me?
Not down there.
I'm up here.
Oh, a giant condor.
A Sarcohamphus gryphus.
Robert, hold on!
I don't have to.
She won't let go.
This is true. She will not let go
until she reaches her nest.
- Reaches her nest?
- Yes, high in the mountains.
No doubt she has
little ones that must...
Hang on, Robert.
We're coming!
- Robert!
- I got dizzy coming down...
but it was a jolly good view
from up there.
- Oh, thank goodness you're all right.
- I wonder who fired the shot.
Perhaps he did.
A Patagonian. Magnificent!
It's like turning back
the history book hundreds of years.
Hope he's not dangerous.
Permit me. l-I've learned
a few primitive words.
Anyway, even if you
don't understand...
l-I want to thank you for
saving my brother's life.
- Happy could do.
- Heavens, he speaks English.
First-class shooting, sir.
First time, right through the heart.
No. Shoot through heart...
bird go limp, drop small boy.
But shoot back of head...
bird go stiff, wings go up.
He circle down, land boy safe.
Y-You mean, you-you purposely...
i-induced motor paralysis
through damage on the medulla?
- Not understand.
- Neither do I.
- Can you tell us where our father is?
- He was captured by Indians.
- On the 37th parallel.
They were kidnapped,
washed up on the shore, captured.
Three white men.
Indians hold them
for ransom money.
- You very slow to come.
- Are they all right?
Last time I hear, they are well,
but very tired of being prisoners.
Just a minute. What do you mean,
"last time you hear"? Don't you come
from the village where they're held?
No. I'm an Araucanian chief,
Thalcave.
My people do not rob, do not steal,
do not hold prisoners for ransom.
- Well, where are they?
- Far away, at the foot of the mountain.
Great plain reaches
far as you can see.
- Many days to cross.
- The pampas.
Well, couldn't you take us there?
First we stop at my village
for horses and supplies...
then Thalcave will try
help you find them.
Much rain there.
You sleep in tree. May come flood.
Flood? By George,
that's a good one.
A giant ombu tree,
Phytolacca dioica.
- Magnificent specimen.
- Oh, please, may we sleep in it?
You can sleep where you like,
but I certainly don't intend to roost...
in a tree
like a confounded sparrow.
Pitch my tent just here.
You in tree, listen!
Flood come. Much water.
You stay in tree. I bring help.
- My father?
- I wake him.
To be safe, we tie things
so they do not fall.
Flood come. You go quick to tree.
I ride for help.
Not even raining.
Just like on a ship.
Make ready for the storm.
Look! The flood!
- Father! Father!
- John, be careful!
- Father, hurry up! Come with me!
- Now what's going on?
Can't a fellow get
a decent night's rest in this place?
- Come on, Father!
- Oh!
Come on.
They've got it!
Hold on!
Highly irregular, flood like this...
and not even raining.
With some food in your stomach, milord,
the world will feel a lot brighter.
- Oh! Look out below!
- Oh!
Sorry, milord.
Why cry about bad weather
Enjoy it
Each moment is a treasure
enjoy it
We're travellers
on life's highway
Enjoy the trip
Each lovely twist and byway
Each bump and dip
If there's a complication
enjoy it
You've got imagination
employ it
Then you'll see roses
in the snow
Joie de vivre
will make them grow
Voilà, that's life
Enjoy it
Since I must do the cooking
I'll enjoy it
This ombu tree smells gorgeous
You'll enjoy it
A hurricane comes your way
enjoy the breeze
You're stranded in thejungle
enjoy the trees
If there's a complication
enjoy it
You've got imagination
employ it
This tree's a cornucopia
Why, it could be...
- Utopia
- Voilà, that's right, enjoy it
Why cry about bad weather
- Enjoy it
- No, enjoy
Oh, each moment is a treasure
Enjoy it
- That's better. Enjoy it.
- We're travellers on life's highway
Enjoy the trip
Each lovely twist and byway
each bump and dip
- Good.
- If there's a complication
- Enjoy it
You've got imagination,
employ it
Employ it
From eggs and herbs au naturel
Omelette ombu a la Paganel
Pour vous, milord
Enjoy it
Voilà!
Robert, can you
see anything...
that looks like an Indian
on horseback coming to our rescue?
- Only some birds.
- Only some...
Only gone down
half an inch in two days.
We'll be here for ten years
at this rate.
Cheer up, milord.
We pay no rent.
Mother Nature
sets the table for us.
And, fortunately,
we have plenty of water.
That's very fortunate,
I must say.
- Very fortunate.
- My father will never
trust another Indian.
But Thalcave's different.
He said, "I bring help".
- And he will.
- If he got through.
Don't even think such things.
All right.
But if I may paraphrase...
what a wise young girl
once said to me many years ago:
"If you were marooned
in an ombu tree...
and you had some logs
and something to tie them into a raft...
you wouldn't just sit there
until you died or something, would you?"
That's very good.
For a girl, I mean.
I suppose most girls are taught
embroidery and things.
But Mother died after Robert was born.
And Father, being a sea captain...
When we first met,
I had a different impression.
Most girls can be rather silly.
Do you know what I mean?
- No, I don't.
- Well, you're different.
- How different?
- I don't know how to say it.
I had it all worked out last night.
Sounds rather silly now, though.
- What does?
- Well, you don't expect things
of a girl, certain things...
like climbing mountains, going
through floods, making the most of it.
You know what I mean?
Don't think I do.
Well, I want to say that...
I think you've been just fine,
for a girl.
Oh, what I really mean is that
if we get out of here alive...
and when we're old enough...
- John!
- Mary!
There's the log
you've needed for your raft.
That's it, just what we need.
Perfect!
Got it.
- Oh!
- Keep out of the way!
- It's a tiger!
- No, no, it's a jaguar. Felis onca.
Get that beast out of here!
It's probably as frightened
of us as we are of it.
- Just a big cat, milord.
- Well, get rid of it. Get rid of it.
Can't stand cats
at the best of times.
Confounded things
always make me sneeze.
Go on! Get out of here!
- Go on! Get out!
- Don't, John! The poor thing.
Do not move, not an eyelash.
"Marooned in ombu tree.
Latitude, 37 degrees south.
Longitude, 66 degrees west.
Send help immediately."
One, two...
three, four, five...
six, seven.
More than two kilometers away.
My father always told me,
never go near a tree in a thunderstorm.
One, two, three...
four, five.
I think it's getting closer.
Yes. At 35 degrees centigrade...
sound travels
at approximately... one...
Great heavens,
the tree's on fire. Look!
We'll beat it out.
No time for that sort of thing.
Get out of the way!
You see? It's too late now.
The oil in the ombu tree, milord,
it has a remarkably low flashpoint.
- Onto the raft. It's our only chance.
- Look out!
Oh, no!
- I'll get it.
- No, don't!
Apparently, we have our choice:
eaten raw down there...
or roasted alive up here.
Hold on, everybody. Mother Nature
comes to our rescue. A waterspout!
Ahoy!
We're still several degrees
off course, you know.
Hurry up with the canvas.
There's a breeze coming up.
Aye, aye, Captain!
You're strangely quiet,
aren't you?
- Sorry, milord. I was thinking.
- I don't know which is worse, by George:
having you so happy you sing all the
time, or so glum you won't even talk.
"The ombu tree is gorgeous.
Enjoy it." Huh.
I am stupid!
Stupid! Stupid!
I know, but that hasn't
worried you till now.
- It is better they do not hear.
- Better they don't hear?
What are you talking about?
It is something
I remembered in the night.
- How could I be so stupid?
I don't know, but the shark I caught...
- Land ho!
with the bottle,
it was a mako shark.
- It...
- Ahoy!
And as well as I know anything
in the world, I should know that
the mako shark lives only in...
Be quiet! Ahoy there!
Ahoy. Ahoy there!
I think I see it. There.
- A canoe!
- Ahoy there! Aho...
Good heavens. It's an Indian war canoe.
This is a fine fix.
We're completely unarmed.
- It's Thalcave! He did come back!
- What? Thalca...
Ho-ho. Thalcave, my good man.
Delighted to see you.
- I bring news.
- News? What kind of news?
You come in canoe.
We go fast to village...
where they hold prisoners,
three sailor men.
Three sailor me...
Oh, monsieur, we've found them!
It's like a miracle.
Thank you, my lordship! Thank you!
Oh, I say, I say. Careful. Come along.
Let's get aboard. Careful, now. Careful.
You're a welcome sight, sir,
believe me. Is this thing safe?
Forty-six, forty-seven,
forty-eight...
forty-nine, fifty.
Oh, now it's come,
I can hardly believe it.
- We're saved!
Stop it! Stop it! Who the devil
are these people? Where's Captain Grant?
These not right men?
It's all my fault.
How could I be so stupid?
It's what I started to tell you,
milord, about the mako shark.
- What about the blasted thing?
- It lives only in and
around the Indian Ocean.
That's what the-the word "Indian"
means in the note...
not that they were captured
by Indians.
If you knew this, why didn't you tell me
before I paid out all that money?
I kept hoping, milord,
that maybe somehow I could be wrong.
This can mean only one thing:
Captain Grant is in Australia.
Australia? That's where
I wanted to go in the first place...
only, I was stupid enough
to let you talk me out of it.
Oh, my dear children, I'm so sorry
it all had to end like this.
Listen! Thalcave speak.
For many years,
my people hunt...
trail game many miles.
Sometimes sneak up,
but game not there.
But Indian knows
if game not there...
it somewhere else.
Keep looking; otherwise,
Indian die out many years ago.
"Keep looking."
He's right, you know.
Now we know
where Captain Grant really is.
And by Jove,
we'll go and find him.
Oh, thank you, Thalcave.
Thank you.
- How does she look to you?
- Just what we need.
- Ain't a ship hereabouts
could overhaul her.
- What about the steam?
- We can learn.
- The old man wants to know
what happened to the Britannia.
- Maybe I should tell him.
- You're not serious, now, are ya?
Maybe I should tell him.
The very spot, your lordship,
where she sank beneath the waves.
Now, it's me own dear brother
who lost his life...
tryin' to put out in a small boat
to save some of the crew.
- It was shockin'.
- All right, Osborne. Pay 'em off.
- Very good, milord.
- Thank you, lordship.
Much... Much obliged.
- I don't wanna see any more.
- Very good, milord.
Look at that!
Ridiculous! Preposterous!
How can the same ship go down
in a dozen different places, sometimes
500 miles apart? Answer me that.
Ah, confounded wharf rats! Lie to you,
take your money, cut your throat
if you give 'em half a chance.
How the dickens can I tell
where to start, eh? What do you want?
- Mr Frederick Ayrton
to see you, milord.
- I told you I didn't want
to see anybody else.
- This is a gentleman, your lordship.
- I do hope I haven't arrived
at an awkward moment.
I'm sorry I couldn't get here sooner.
I would've warned you not
to offer a reward.
- Well, as a matter of...
- I'm afraid you'll find very little
integrity...
among some of the men
who frequent our waterfront.
And it so happens that
I have the very information you require.
- About my father?
- Ah, so this is the daughter
of Captain Grant.
Well, if I can reunite this delightful
child and her gallant father...
that is the reward I'm interested in.
Were you ever in Plymouth?
Plymouth, England?
No, I haven't had that pleasure.
May I inquire, sir, as to the nature
of your information?
Oh, well, two years ago,
I was caught in a violent storm
in the Tasman Sea.
We picked up a poor fellow,
badly battered and half drowned...
- just off the coast of New Zealand.
- New Zealand?
He said he was from the Britannia,
and that she'd gone down with all hands.
He died during the night, and our ship
combed the area the following day.
You know, until I read that piece
in the paper about the message...
in the bottle, I had no idea that
there were any survivors.
But why wasn't the sinking reported
when you reached your destination?
Well, I assumed that it was. I was only
a passenger on the ship, you know.
Heavens. If he landed in New Zealand,
he must've been captured by the Maoris.
I'll report this to the authorities
at once. Osborne!
- I'm afraid it isn't as easy as that.
- Why ever not?
You haven't had my experience
in dealing with our colonial government.
Eventually, you learn to get along
in spite of them.
They talk endlessly,
and they need authorization from London.
You'll be lucky
if they're ready in a year.
But anything could happen
to him in a year. What do you suggest?
Oh, l-I can't afford
to get mixed up in this.
I've told you all that I know, and...
and I've got my own estates to run.
Sir, the lives of three men
are at stake.
I'd like to speak
to this gentleman alone, please.
The trouble is,
New Zealand is not in the Indian Ocean.
There is something strange,
very strange.
I don't care what it is.
I've seen that man before.
- Oh, you're just imagining it.
- No, I'm not.
Anyway, I can't stand people
who look at me like that.
"Delightful child,
gallant father."
Perhaps it's a good sign that neither
of you take to him...
because it seems that everything else
that you've welcomed with open arms...
has turned out dead wrong.
Please understand I don't wish
to do anything against the law.
- Oh, certainly not.
- But at the same time, I don't intend...
to leave Captain Grant in the hands
of those bloodthirsty cannibals.
So, uh, I appeal
to you as a man with experience...
and knowledge of local conditions
to help us before it's too late.
All right. I'll gather up some men
who know the Maoris...
and who can
handle any kind of situation.
By Jove, you mean we just, uh, go in
and have it out with them?
Oh, good heavens, no. We'll
take along some supplies to barter...
and then if Captain Grant and his men
are still alive, we'll buy them back.
Capital idea. I can't tell you
how grateful I am to you.
- I need hardly remind you that we must
be discreet about what we plan to do.
- Ooh, of course, of course.
- Don't want to be tied down
by a lot of confounded red tape, do we?
- No.
Just my son John and Captain Mangles.
Otherwise, not a word to a soul.
Yes, just as it should be.
Get this crate down
in the hull, would ya, lads?
Motley looking lot of fellows
you've got together.
Well, when you look for men
to go into Maori country...
you don't choose them
from among the socially elite.
Jolly well put.
But I must say, I didn't realize
you'd require quite so much merchandise.
Ooh, I'm afraid the days are gone
when one could impress the natives
with a handful of coloured beads.
And if they choose
to sell their prisoners dearly...
we'd better be prepared.
I see.
John, you've got to tell me.
What's going on out there?
Ah, mademoiselle,
you are far too beautiful...
in the new gown to worry your
pretty little head about such things.
But what's in all those boxes?
I would've thought if my father wanted
you to know, he would've told you.
Every man out there looks like
a fugitive from the penal colony.
John, you've got to do something. Don't
let this man make a fool of your father.
Just because he calls you "a delightful
child" and you don't like it...
you think he's trying
to make a fool of my father.
It is better that we think it, monsieur,
than to give him the opportunity
to prove it.
All right. Let me tell you something,
both of you.
Maybe my father
huffs and puffs a little bit,
and we've all smiled at him just in fun.
But I don't think anybody's going to
make a fool of him quite as easily as...
well, certain people I could name.
And now, if you'll excuse me.
Patience, dear.
We shall see what we shall see.
I'll wager she's faster than any ship
in the Royal Navy.
Good. You know,
I'd say that...
steam was the coming thing if it
weren't all so complicated to handle.
Well, you don't have to complicate it.
Actually, it's quite simple.
- Yes?
- Pardon, milord. Uh-Uh, Could I talk...
to you sometime before too long?
- Certainly. What about?
- No matter how much I think about it,
it is always the same.
Captain Grant is in Australia.
There is no possible way the note
could mean he's in New Zealand.
Oh, my dear fellow,
don't worry about that beastly note.
Mr Ayrton knows precisely where
the Britannia went down, don't you?
- Of course.
- Milord, I'd be the happiest man...
in the world if it turns out
that once again, I'm wrong.
- I've no doubt you will be.
- If it's not too much trouble,
I'd like to see the engine room.
Oh, my dear fellow, delighted.
Take you around myself.
I think you'll find
there's nothing complicated about steam.
It's a beautiful day. Why not enjoy it,
let bygones be bygones?
Now that we're at sea, I can let you in
on our secret, if you're interested.
Those boxes you were wondering about.
Would you like to know what's in them?
Trinkets. Trade goods.
They're for barter with the Maoris so
that we can buy your father's freedom.
- Who told you this?
- Mr Ayrton.
- And you believed him?
- All right, Miss Suspicious.
If it'll make you more companionable,
I'll take you below and show you.
Well, here you are.
All right, Pandora.
Which box do you want me to open?
- That one.
- You sure you don't
have a guilty feeling?
After all, it is rather
like spying on someone...
especially when they've gone
out of their way to be so nice to you.
- Open it.
- I will.
Nothing is too much trouble
if it satisfies your curiosity.
Voilà, mademoiselle.
"Trade goods. Trinkets", he said.
So that's his game. He's using
my father's ship as a gunrunner.
Pity you did that.
Wilcox, down here!
We've got to warn the others. I'll lead
them off, then you make for the door.
- There he is!
- I see him!
- Ooh! Oh!
- Now, is that a nice way to behave...
when we're taking you
to meet your father?
Come on.
Make no noise. Just stop the paddles.
Anything else, and I'll shoot.
Ever been to New Zealand before?
Yes. Twice.
Do as I tell you, and perhaps
you'll live to make it three times.
- We're stopping.
- That is most strange.
- Raise the hands quietly.
- Do as he says, Robert.
Help! Pirates!
Lord Glenarvan, help!
Come quickly!
Lord Glenarvan, help! Pirates!
Lord Glenarvan!
I thought
I heard the boy call for help.
You did. Now, give me that gun,
and no harm will come to him.
Wait.
I say, you can't put us out there
without oars. It's not human.
Oh, the current will carry you to
the shore, if that's any consolation...
but I'm afraid we'll have
to keep your crew on board...
until they've taught us the fine points
of using steam.
We're unaccustomed to such luxuries
in the South Pacific.
- You'll pay for this.
- You've got it backwards, old man.
We have been paid for it, and
quite handsomely. Cheer up, Frenchie.
You promised you would
be the happiest man in the world...
if you were wrong about Captain Grant
being in Australia.
And you were. Brown and Riley,
lay aloft and stand by to make sail.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- You were in Plymouth!
My father signed you
on the day he sailed.
As third mate. What a memory.
You'll hang for this, you know.
I'll see to it personally.
I'll make a full report
to the admiralty.
You do that.
And here's a bottle to put it in.
Let's hope it isn't swallowed
by a shark. Lower away!
You'll never get away with this.
That's what Captain Grant said
when we put him over the side...
at this very spot with
his two rather foolishly loyal mates.
If you're lucky, you might all end up
in the same stewpot.
If anyone is interested,
I might explain.
It is the influence
of the west wind drift...
playing against
the east Australian current...
that might drive us
right up onto the shore.
Yes, yes, yes.
That's the second
of my ships he's got.
First the Britannia,
and now my beautiful new steam yacht.
It's all clear now.
It was a mutiny.
There's no reason why I should lie about
it. My father was set adrift here...
Then he must be a prisoner
of the Maoris.
What did he mean, we might all end up
in the same stewpot?
Not to change the subject, but our
reception committee seems to be waiting.
Maoris, hundreds of'em.
Deuce of a fix.
No trinkets to bargain with.
What have we got to offer, huh?
Just us, I suppose.
- Good gracious!
- You come as a stranger,
and I take ye in.
I have prepared a place for thee
in the presence of thine enemy.
- It's all right, my dear.
I'm sure he's harmless.
- What think ye now?
I be crazy, eh?
Not a bit of it.
I be smart. Mark ye well
the words of old Bill Gaye.
Bill Gaye! Weren't you the mate
on my father's ship?
Depends entirely
who your father was.
What was his ship?
And who you be, for that matter?
You see, I be smart.
Makes a difference who she is.
I'm Mary Grant. My father's
Captain Grant of the Britannia.
Well, why didn't you say so before?
Fine ship, she was.
I walked her decks
across the seven seas.
Woe be onto thee, oh, Moab,
for thy sons are taken captive.
- Who is he?
- Fantastic, he seems to be the mate
from the Britannia.
Do you know where he is?
Can you tell me?
Where is Captain Grant?
Have you no eyes?
Can you not see?
- He's gone.
- Where?
Same as before. Diane's Inlet.
- Did the Maoris take him?
- He be smart too.
He learns the way to keep alive, for
they need him when they get more guns.
Guns? Then it must be Ayrton.
Aye, that's who it be.
Somehow the devil has got another ship.
- Were there three of you?
- Aye, three of us there were.
Captain Grant, McNabb
and old Bill Gaye...
against Ayrton
and all of his mutinous crew.
- The scoundrel!
- Bonjour, Monsieur.
My father, Captain Grant... Did he and
McNabb go together to Diane's Inlet?
Nay, my child.
I say unto you:
McNabb, he was not smart.
He was caught
when he tried to escape.
Odd devil.
- What's he laughing at?
- For this, child, I have prayed.
And the Lord has granted my petition,
which I asked of Him.
This is the night
the Lord hath given us our salvation.
What think ye? Could a man
force himself through there...
even a man who has gone without food
to make himself as thin as a man can be?
Nay. I say unto you,
it is impossible.
It is easier for a camel
to go through the eye of a needle.
Robert, do you think you
could crawl through there?
Maybe if I tried very hard.
- You be smart too.
- Even if he could,
what good would it do?
I'll show ye now. The Lord helps them
that helps themselves.
Two years we took to make it,
from the hairs of our heads...
from the garments we wore,
from a thousand things we gathered.
Absolutely preposterous. What could
the boy possibly do all by himself?
There be more to it than that,
for this be the night of the haka.
Bide ye your time
till the night be well begun...
and the horns sound
and the flames leap upward...
and the devil hath
seized the souls of our captors.
Then I will show the way.
- Nobody's looking. Now's your chance.
- Right. Up you go. Up.
- It looks awfully small.
- Go on. Go on!
I'm stuck.
Let out all the air.
Pardon my soul, I don't know
which is worse: a crazy man...
who thinks he's smart
or a Frenchman who admits he's stupid.
- Hold that.
- Oh! Ooh-ooh!
Now, to get the pendulum swinging.
Oh, do be careful!
Lower away.
I have the unhappy feeling we're going
out of the frying pan into the fire.
He can't get over!
The rope's not long enough!
Lower away!
- He still can't do it.
- Go on! Lower away!
That's all there is!
Then let her go!
He did it!
Tie that down there.
Go down it.
Go. Bye.
- Deuce of a fix this is.
- Off we go to the mountain.
We'll never outrun these fellas.
By Jove, I never
saw a rope burn like that.
Gunpowder. It's woven in
like a fuse.
Aye, what say ye?
Who be'st smart now?
"Vengeance is mine.
I will repay", said the Lord.
Father, come on!
If this is the sacred volcano
of the taboo, they dare not follow.
You know of such things,
even though you be a stranger?
Aye. I be smart too.
Aye. We be two of a kind.
- By Jove, they've stopped.
- What think ye now of old Bill Gaye?
Be he crazy or be he smart?
They dare not set foot here,
for all this is taboo.
I say, that's splendid,
isn't it?
- But they're moving on again!
- A slight miscalculation, milord.
- I'm afraid we're on the wrong volcano.
- Just as I thought.
- Out of the frying pan, into the fire.
- Don't worry, milord.
Come help, please!
- What are you planning to do?
- Uncork the bottle
and let the genie free.
Oh, I've got it!
Everybody, push!
- Lucky shot, that. Chance in a million.
- At the university, milord...
I'm considered the wizard
of the croquet court.
Come ye, where we'll be safe.
- Oh, it's horrible!
- Have no fear, mademoiselle.
The Maoris can run faster
than the lava. Enjoy it!
And now, Mr Gaye,
to Captain Grant.
Aye, to Captain Grant!
Follow Bill Gaye!
He's got it all planned out!
All right, Grant.
Tell them there are six more boxes...
nearly 200 rifles
still in the hold.
I'll send the whole lot ashore
as soon as they hand over the money.
And how do I know the rest
are as good as this one?
- I give you my word.
- That's what you offered last time...
when you unloaded a pile of junk.
Now, really, Grant.
Every time I do something charitable,
I live to regret it.
Like putting you ashore alive.
And I intend to stay alive by not
recommending rifles I haven't examined.
My beautiful, beautiful yacht.
If they've done anything
to damage her...
I'll have them strung up
by their thumbs.
How did you know
where she was going to be?
This be where
they always unload:
in Diane's Inlet.
In Diane's Inlet? Oh!
In the note, what I thought said
"Indian" was really...
Oh!
I'm stupid, stupid, stupid!
Cheer up, my friend. Your stupidity may
turn out to be of divine inspiration.
Mr Gaye, I thought
we were going to find Father?
We be. We be. Look ye now.
It's Father!
He looks well, thank goodness.
- They're all getting into boats.
- They're comin' here.
We have but little time
to prepare our reception.
- I come to see thy ship.
- No one can come aboard.
Surely ye be not afraid
of old Bill Gaye?
- Bill Gaye?
- "The hoary head is a crown of glory."
Know ye not that?
- How many do you want, Lucky?
- That'll do.
How many cards do you want?
- So where's mine?
- I gave you them.
What a hand here. Right.
How do we get past him?
Excuse me, sir,
but is this Lord Glenarvan's yacht?
Well, sonny, I guess...
Here. Wait a minute. Ain't you the boy
that's with that lot? Come back here!
- Your lordship.
- We haven't got the keys, Captain.
We'll have to break the door down
best we can.
- Put out your decks, gentlemen.
- I'm busted.
- See if Thompson'll play.
He's got money.
- Yeah. All right.
- Your deal, Bob.
- Right. Here you are.
Riley, come here quick!
- The brig!
Know ye not what the Good Book says? "He
that diggeth a pit shall fall into it"?
Send him over to me.
Ooh, got him! Quick.
I suppose we'll have to open every box.
Put the best ones on top.
Ayrton, you scoundrel!
Don't move. You may
live long enough to hang.
Hello, Glenarvan.
Welcome aboard.
Well, here we are.
This makes us even, doesn't it, uh?
You've got your ship back,
and I'm bringing you Captain Grant...
so, uh, why don't we, uh...
Captain, take him below
with the rest of the scoundrels.
Aye, ye've sown the wind...
and I say to you,
you shall reap the whirlwind.
Back, you dogs! Back, I say!
Bill Gaye! What on earth...
- Father!
- Mary! Robert!
You think I be crazy, don't ye?
See now,
how are the mighty fallen.
- How on earth did you find me out here?
- Monsieur Paganel.
- He's a French professor.
- He found a note in a bottle.
- Lord Glenarvan took us on his yacht.
- And we've been all around the world
looking for you.
- South America.
- And we were captured by Maoris.
- Maoris!
My dear children.
Oh, how I've prayed
for this day.
- I was beginning to give up hope
that I'd ever see you again.
- I must be catching a cold.
And now you're suddenly here, and I'm
able to hold you both close in my arms.
I can't find words to
express my gratitude to all of you.
We would've been here months earlier if
I hadn't been so stupid about the note.
- The note?
- Yes. The-The note in-in the bottle.
The note in the bottle?
What think ye now? It was I
put that note in the bottle.
And put the bottle in the sea.
"Cast thy bread on the waters...
for thou shall find it
after many days."
But they seemed so sure
it was their father's handwriting.
- It was, wasn't it?
- Now you know my secret...
why I ran away to sea.
The voice is the voice
of a God-fearing man...
but the hands
are the hands of a forger.
- Oh, my word!
- Bill, you scoundrel!
Just think. If he hadn't
put the note in the bottle...
and if Monsieur Paganel
hadn't caught that shark...
And if you hadn't tried to slap my face
that morning on the way to Plymouth...
I wouldn't have talked my father
into making this trip.
- Funny how things work out, isn't it?
- Isn't it?
Here we are, all of us together.
All of us.
Did you ever see so many stars?
Once, on top of a mountain.
Did you know that down there, out of the
light, you can see the Southern Cross?
Southern Cross?
So, that's my little girl.
By george, they do grow up.
Uh-Uh, I was just thinking
to myself.
No matter
where you are in the world...
it is always different,
but it is always the same.
In English, you would say...
"All climates
are the same for love."
There it is.
The Southern Cross.