Liftoff!
Go, man.
Go, man... go.
You're doing fine, Charlie...
just fine.
That's it.
Just hang on up there, Charlie.
Keep up the good work.
Heart's still strong,
pulse rather fast,
respiration rapid...
otherwise, normal.
Slowed up a bit
mentally, general.
Probably a little swacked.
I wish I were.
Joe, give me an alert when
the wire radar picks him up.
Yes, sir.
Gulou, this is mcchord.
Give me an e.T. On acquisition.
Thank you, major.
Congratulations, general,
congratulations.
Thank you.
Mr. Secretary,
this is a great day
for your air force...
a great day.
Where is he? Still on the moon?
Not on the moon, senator...
around the moon.
What's the difference?
It's a space-race victory.
Not yet.
Orbiting the moon is one thing.
Getting him back alive
is another.
Of course, of course.
But he's all right, isn't he?
Sure.
He's a little bit
hypoxied, that's all.
What?
Stoned...
drunk as a skunk.
Did he say "drunk"?
He means "space drunk"...
a combination of isolation,
oxygen, and fear.
Haven't you read our booklet...
"simple science for senators"?
I didn't have time.
Besides, my kid said
it was juvenile.
Hawaii has acquired him, sir.
Get me hickum.
Yes, sir.
Any time you're set, Joe.
W-why's everybody so nervous?
Starfire just completed
the third moon orbit.
Oh.
They're about
to shoot him down.
Shoot him?
Space jargon, senator.
I wish you fellas
would be more careful
with that kind of language.
Words like "drunk"...
can't you see the headlines...
"billion-dollar space bender"?
And in an election year.
Ready, general.
Bring him in.
Start re-entry procedure.
Man: On my mark, it will be
"t" minus five seconds.
Go.
What happened?
Engine restart successful.
I'll tell the press.
He's not home yet...
just rounding third,
and home plate is a few
hundred thousand Miles away.
Hickum, sir.
Vanneman speaking.
Charlie's on his way home.
Turn it over
to the recovery group.
From here on in,
it's up to them.
Good luck, Charlie.
It's coming in fast now,
fellas...
any second now.
Man: There he is... 12:00 high!
Careful, sir!
Give me that leash!
We lose a lot of
visiting firemen that way.
Are you all right?
Yeah. Thanks.
Pilot to crew chief...
get ready, fellas.
Here she comes!
We got it!
Recovery, sir.
Yee-haw!
Ha ha ho!
Well, reel him in
as soon as you can!
Yes, sir.
Pull her in!
Hickum control,
this is recovery five.
Starfire picked up.
Air recovery successful.
They're bringing him in now.
What about Charlie?
Is he still alive?
They'll know soon.
Man: Bring it straight back.
Straight back! Straight back!
Easy... easy, now!
That's enough!
Easy.
Crew chief to pilot...
the hatch is off, sir.
Soon as you find out,
let me know.
How is he?
He's alive!
Yeah hoo hoo hoo!
Hurry up... bring him out.
Hey, Charlie boy, how are you?!
Oh, man, it's good to see you.
Gentlemen...
Gentlemen,
we're gathered here tonight
for a double purpose...
to honor our friend and mascot,
airman Charlie...
first chimpanzee
to orbit the moon.
Charlie, you put us
on the threshold.
On the threshold of what?
A man around the moon.
Now, just a minute.
We were under the impression...
if a chimpanzee can survive,
so can a man.
After all, there's practically
no difference between them.
Oh, no?
Do chimpanzees have the vote
in your state, general?
Senator, sometimes I wonder.
As I was saying, gentlemen,
we stand ready
for the big jump.
The only question is...
Who's going to be
the lucky man?
Now, I know you're all
fully qualified,
but I can't make a choice
without letting myself open
for a charge of favoritism.
Therefore,
I'll ask for a volunteer.
General...
A point of information, sir...
is this shot still scheduled
for next march?
Changed...
we have
till the end of this week
to catch the moon in its
present proximity to earth.
Otherwise, we have to wait
three months.
This week, sir?
Right.
Now, that's a tough decision
on short notice.
But Washington...
Washington wants
its answer tonight.
We're not the only nation
shooting for the moon.
Now, then...
Who's it gonna be?
You have any doubts,
just take heart from
our friend Charlie here.
How is it up there,
Charlie boy... fun, huh?
Pbbbt!
Sorry, sir.
What's the matter with you?
Gentlemen...
I'd welcome a show of hands.
As I said before,
we're not pressuring anyone.
Take your time!
Hah!
There's my man.
That's him, senator.
Congratulations, boy.
Congratulations.
Very nice.
Frankly, gentlemen,
captain Talbot
was my personal choice
right from the beginning.
Excuse me... thank you, sir.
He's young, unmarried,
physically fit,
specially trained
in bioastronautics,
with a fine future.
In short, gentlemen...
perfect for the mission.
Captain, what state
are you from?
Yours, sir.
That's what I was afraid of.
Well, we best get going.
We got a great deal to do,
and only a couple of days.
That won't give me
much of a leave.
No, I suggest that...
what was that?
I said, that won't give me
much of a leave, will it, sir?
Leave for you is out.
But...
no one sets foot off this base
until you're in that bird
and on your way to the moon.
But, general...
even I have to stay here.
But, sir, you see...
no one outside this base knows
except the president.
But, sir, the only...
there's no time for
personal interest, captain.
We can't risk a failure.
Secretary: Not a public one,
at any rate.
Not in an election year.
We're not going to yell
for the whole world to watch
and then fall
flat on our faces.
No.
General,
I wouldn't tell anyone.
Gentlemen.
Try to understand, captain,
leave for you is out.
All I want to do is go home!
Do you have a mother, captain?
Well, yes, of course
I've got a mother.
That's why I want to go home.
Now, uh,
you wouldn't want to worry
your mother, would you?
Oh, I wouldn't tell her
a thing.
You wouldn't confide
in your own dear, sweet mother?
Not in a case like this.
You think I want
to scare her to death?
She'd worm it out of you.
I know mothers. I had one.
They're all psychic.
Oh, not mine.
She believes
anything I tell her.
You're not going to be
difficult, are you?
Yes, sir.
Is this an ultimatum?
You won't ride in the bird
unless we let you go home?
That's about the size
of it, sir.
I guess maybe now you'll be
wanting somebody else?
I've already informed
the white house.
Senator: John,
you've got to let him go.
If it ever got out
that we shot this fine
American boy around the moon
without letting him
say goodbye to his mom...
Oh...
If I can, sir,
I'd like to get started
first thing in the morning.
It will take me
a day each way by bus...
bus!!
Did you say "bus"?
Well, actually, sir...
I don't really care
that much about flying.
You don't care much abou...
and you're going to take
a trip around the moon?
Never mind!
He volunteered, senator!
You did volunteer,
didn't you?
Well, you see, sir...
Yeah. Yes, sir.
All right, Talbot, you can go.
You mean I'm... Replaced, sir?
No... you have
three days' leave!!
Oh.
Oh! Well, thank you, sir.
Senator, thank you.
Mr. Secretary,
I knew you'd understand.
Ha!
Hey, Charlie.
Hey, listen...
how did it feel up there, huh?
What was the worst part...
the blastoff, the going up,
or the coming down?
Oh, boy, Charlie,
I sure would give more
than a penny for
your thoughts right now.
If you could only give me
some idea, some sign.
Aw, charli...
Charlie!
What did you do that for?
Ch...
Charlie!
Now, Charlie.
Come on, now, Charlie.
Charlie, put that down.
Hey! Charlie!
Crazy?! How can you tell
when a chimp's crazy?
Aren't they all?
Oh, no, sir. He's changed.
Charlie was friendly,
and now he's mean and wild.
Wild!
I tell you, sir,
he got moonstruck up there.
You know...
luna... moon... lunatic.
Ha!
Frankly, sir, I wouldn't
want that to happen to me.
W-would you, sir?
Will you sit down, captain?
I can understand
your natural anxieties,
but I can be
a lot more objective.
You've supervised all
of Charlie's flight reactions.
Now, what was his conduct
at that time?
He was right out
of the jungle then, sir.
And wild...
like he is now, hmm?
Then you put him through
the old air force basic...
discipline,
regular habits, huh?
Turned him into
an a-number-one astro chimp?
You might say, sir...
that's it.
Charlie's not loony.
He's overtrained.
That flight to the moon
brought him back normal.
The same thing's
gonna happen to you.
You've been working too hard.
You need to get away,
rid yourself of these
anxieties, tensions.
I envy you, boy, you know that?
Sir?
If they'd let me do it,
I'd fly in that bird myself.
Now...
I've got your round-trip
air routing in San Francisco.
There you are.
I'll give you a few orders
and instructions
before you leave, however.
When you climb in that capsule,
you're going to be
in tiptop shape.
From this minute on,
you're not to touch
tobacco, alcohol,
or stimulants of any kind.
Questions, captain?
No, sir. Major.
You will eat
nothing else than this.
It is a highly concentrated,
nourishing paste...
the same thing that will
sustain you in outer space.
Couldn't this have waited?
After all,
my mother's a good cook.
Your stomach must be
pre-shrunk, captain.
Your system must have time
to get adjusted.
Mind, now...
no food of any kind...
not even a teeny-weeny bite.
Gen. Vanneman:
Any more questions?
No, sir.
Captain.
You body and brain, sir,
need absolute calm
for the ordeal ahead.
So there must be no...
pardon me, captain.
Major... Would you mind?
Thank you.
As I was saying...
You need absolute calm
for the ordeal ahead,
so there must be no emotional
upsets or involvements.
I'm not sure I follow you.
What he means is no dames.
Oh... That.
Exactly.
Well, you don't have to worry.
I don't have a real
steady girlfriend anyway.
Don't have
an unsteady one either.
Understand?
Yes, sir.
Good. One thing more,
and remember it...
don't talk to strangers.
Types like Uncle Willy
and aunt bessie can be spies.
The enemy never sleeps!
Yes, sir.
Good luck, rich.
Enjoy yourself.
Yes, sir. Thank you, sir...
But how?
Sandwich?
Coffee, tea, or milk, sir?
No... Thanks.
Sir, would you care
for a sandwich?
My stomach
just isn't air-minded.
Would you care to try
one of these?
It will make you feel better.
Please... you look to me pale.
It won't help. It never does.
This will.
It's never been known to fail.
An infallible cure?
That'll be the day.
You must not be
so professionally cynical.
Professionally?
Thank you.
Oh, please, keep them.
You may need them again.
Gen. Vanneman:
Don't talk to strangers.
They might be foreign spies.
No... uh... What's her name?
Her?
Yeah... the girl in the seat
across from me.
Against regulations.
This is urgent.
I think I've been poi...
I'd rather not say.
4-a...
Name's lyrae.
Lyrae?
L-y-r-a-e.
Lyrae what?
Just lyrae. That's all.
Oh?
Does it say where she's from?
No.
Is she alone?
Not anymore, she isn't,
apparently.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
This isn't what you think,
believe me.
I wouldn't have
the slightest interest.
Huh. Well, give me
your honest opinion...
how does she strike you?
Does she seem
a little, uh... Unusual?
Well, frankly,
she looks like a beat.
Beat?
A beatnik... oddball...
unsquare... you know.
Oh... A beatnik.
Sir, are you sure
you couldn't use
a cup of coffee?
Oh, no, thanks. I feel fine.
Hey, I do.
I really do!
That pill must have worked!
Pill?
Yeah. I feel just fine now,
and, uh, thanks.
Hmm...
I wonder where she is from.
Why?
Why, becau...
huh?
Why do you wish to know
where I am from?
I didn't say a word.
Oh, excuse me.
I thought you did.
I must talk to you, captain.
Fasten your seatbelt, sir.
Return to your seat.
We'll be landing
in just a few minutes.
Captain? How did she know?
Gen. Vanneman:
Remember, Talbot...
the enemy never sleeps...
Sleeps... Sleeps.
Woman: All incoming passengers,
please claim your baggage
at the street entrance.
Hey, Walt!
Hiya, rich.
How are you?
Hello!
Come on. Let's get out of here.
Please, captain,
you must listen to me!
Keep on going.
Ohh!
Hey, what's this?
You trying to shake
a little sky-side romance?
You just drive.
Is that all you air force guys
have on your minds?
Never mind, little brother.
Hey, what's new with you?
You are addressing the new
assistant second foreman
of Daisy fresh frozen foods.
Ha ha! Still the same old
go-getter, huh?
I'm gonna own that company
in 30 years.
I should live so long...
I hope.
Hey... If I work a few angles,
maybe I can get you
a place at Daisy fresh.
Thanks, but I think
the offer's a little late.
Not to change the subject,
Walt, but, uh...
Hey, what are you doing
tonight?
I got a date.
Want me to fix you up?
Forget it.
I'll spend the evening
with mom.
Mom! Richie!
Hi, mom! How are you?
Richie, darling, why didn't
you let me know earlier?
It was all kind of sudden.
I could've delayed dinner.
Well, don't worry about it.
I'm on a diet, anyway.
A diet?
Oh, and you're so thin
and peaked.
Same old mom.
I'm so glad you're back,
Richie.
I've been waiting for you.
Oh, Richie.
Hey, how about my best girl
taking in a show
with me tonight?
Oh, I'd love to, Richie.
That's a wonderful idea.
Oh...
Oh, I forgot...
it's Wednesday,
and my bridge club
always meets
on Wednesday night.
Oh.
So it does.
I am sorry,
but when you surprise
people like this...
your stuff's upstairs, rich.
Look, I've got to hurry.
I'm gonna be late, okay?
Hey, Walt...
see you tomorrow morning!
Psst!
Mom!
Oh!
Oh, Richie, darling, come in!
You... you girls all know
my son Richmond, don't you?
Hello.
Yes, dear?
Mom, I think I'll stroll
around the old neighborhood
and take a LA... take a look.
Go right ahead,
but don't be too late.
See you later, mom.
Woman: Celia, please.
All right.
Uh, 2, spades.
Whew...
oh, boy, that's
a long, long way from home.
Woman: Captain!
How did you...
what are you doing here?
I came to warn you.
To warn me? About what?
About what your air force
is planning to do with you.
Air force? E... pi...
Oh, you must have me
mixed up with somebody else.
No, captain Talbot.
They intend to send you
around the moon in a rocket.
How do you know th...
I mean, no, they're not!
There is no reason
to be alarmed.
Now, see here.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Your people have left out
a very important element.
If you ever expect
to get back...
I don't even know you!
And this about rockets...
now, get this straight...
my name's not Talbot,
and you got the wrong sucker,
so stop following me, see?
Please, captain,
you must listen to me!
Go away.
Go away,
or I'll call the police.
I have it right here
if you only want to see.
Please!
Please, captain!
Hey, watch where you're going!
On, uh, second thought,
where are you going?
Would you, uh, like a lift?
I checked.
$10.
$10...And $20.
I'll get it, captain.
General.
This I gotta see.
General vanneman's quarters.
It's for you, John.
I'm out.
Three Jacks...
Three kings, senator.
...and two aces.
What?
Yes. Put him on.
Oh.
It's Talbot.
Talbot?
Sir, I'm sorry.
I've got to talk to you.
What's up? You're not
supposed to check in till...
sir, I'm being followed.
You what?!
A spy... everywhere I go.
I can't seem to shake her.
Her?!
Yes, sir. She's a woman.
Describe her.
Well, she's... she's young...
early 20s, maybe.
Dresses kinda funny,
like one of those...
like one of those beatniks.
She's got an accent.
What kind?
I couldn't tell, sir.
We can pretty well guess,
though, can't we?
Oh.
You know her name?
Yes, sir...
lyrae... l-y-r-a-e.
A-e.
Hmph. Naturally,
that's not a real name.
They're too smart for that.
How can they know?
How can they possibly know?!
She was on my plane, sir.
Then the leak must be
right here on this base.
Well, no doubt about it, sir.
I knew it from the start!
I never should have
let you go, Talbot!
Oh, no, no, no, sir.
I'm all right.
My only problem is this girl.
What'll I do, sir?
Do?!
Get out of there,
that's what you do.
Take the first bus
to San Francisco.
Does your family know?
No, sir.
Good. Don't let them.
Don't tell them anything.
Don't you talk to anybody...
not even federal security!
Federal security?
Are they here?
They will be.
All you have to do
is take that bus.
You understand?
No, sir, but I'll do it.
Good.
This woman's not alone,
you know.
But, sir, if she knows...
touch in the dark...
war of nerves.
We can play
that little game ourselves.
Now, all you have to do
is pack up
and get out of there...
alive!
Believe me, general...
I'll sure try.
Captain Talbot?
Fed...
federal security.
Mcclosky.
Well, we missed her.
We flung a net over the town,
but she got through.
Either that,
or she's still holed up
there somewhere.
We're gonna need
some more details.
Like what?
Now, what happened
on that aeroplane?
Nothing much.
She gave me some pills.
I still got the bottle.
You didn't take any?
One.
Oh? Any after-effects?
Yeah. I felt better.
Could be a delayed reaction...
like a time bomb.
Why is she tailing you?
I haven't the faintest idea.
You big with the air force?
No, Mr. Mcclosky...
small, very small.
Secret mission?
No. I was just home on leave
visiting my family.
You don't have to clam up
with me, captain.
We're on different teams,
but we both work
for the same coach.
What the opposition
wants from you
is part of the same game.
I can get blown out of
the stadium as high as you.
I rather doubt that.
Come on, captain.
This isn't marbles.
This is the big game.
Well...
When you come right down to it,
all I saw was one girl,
and all she wanted to do
was tell me something.
Tell you what?
Well, she knew
that I was going to...
gen. Vanneman: Don't tell them
anything... Anything...
Anything!
Go on! Go on.
What did she know?
I'm not talking.
Hey, Mr. Mcclosky!
Mr. Mcclosky!
What's the...
let's go. Come on.
Any word?
One man says he saw a woman
answering her description...
almost ran her down.
Did he talk to her?
Tried to give her a lift.
What happened?
That's what the fella
can't remember.
When he came to,
it was 3:00 A.M.,
and he was 4 Miles outside
of town walking in circles.
Does this info check out?
All except the last part...
I don't know about that.
But you see what I mean?
They're clever.
Here...
Send this to the lab.
Tell them to rush it.
Soon as you got a report,
send it to me.
If there's any antidote,
bring it to me pronto.
Right.
You made sure
we won't be bothered?
Yes, sir.
You're in the bridal suite.
Now, everything's secure,
brown?
Buttoned up tight.
Relax, captain.
Those spies of yours
couldn't have the remotest
idea where you are.
I don't doubt it.
I don't know where I am myself.
Hey, who are you calling?
Mcchord air force base...
on orders. Any objection?
Okay. Okay.
Don't get touchy.
Oh, sorry.
I want to place a call
to general vanneman,
mcchord air force base.
That's right.
Make it collect.
Who, me?
I'm captain Talbot.
You and your detail spell
each other standing guard.
I want a man here at all times,
at every entrance.
I mean every delivery
entrance and mousehole.
Gotcha.
¶ Hmm da-doo-doo
hmm-hmm hmm hmm hmm ¶
this is a private call.
Do you mind?!
Sorry.
I'm under orders, too,
you know.
I'd know anyway.
It's bugged.
¶ Hmm-hmm hmm hmm ¶
¶ hmm-hmm hmm hmm-hmm ¶
I don't care
whose toes we step on!
I want another security check
brought on everybody!
And this time, include me!
Does that make it
clear enough, colonel?
Yes, sir.
General.
Vanneman!
That's all.
Yes.
Talbot?
Yes, sir.
Where are you?
Uh...
Park Lane hotel.
Gen. Vanneman:
What about the spy?
Well, we've finally
shaken her, sir...
at least, I think we have.
I've turned the base inside out,
I'm having checks rerun...
be careful, sir,
this line's tapped...
federal security.
Tapped?!
How dare they do that?!
This is official
air force business!
Would you like
to tell them, sir?
One of them's
standing right here.
Yes. Put him on!
General vanneman.
Mcclosky speaking.
Mcclosky, as of right now,
captain Talbot is the most
important man in this country.
You understand?
No, general, I don't.
I'd appreciate it if...
I don't got time to chat.
Get this straight...
if you'd give me an idea...
guard him with your life...
with your life, sir!
See that he's not disturbed.
Yes, sir, but I feel
that I have the right...
keep him quiet
and perfectly relaxed.
I'll let you know later about
getting him back to the base.
Whatever you say, general.
But just between...
right! Put Talbot back on.
Uh, say, general,
what about my leave?
Canceled!
But, sir, you promised.
You've gotten us into
enough trouble, Talbot.
There'll be no more.
But, general, sir,
you promised me...
you have 6 hours and
23 minutes of leave time left.
Use it wisely.
Wisely?
Go to bed and stay there.
That's an order!!
Yes, sir.
The general didn't take time
to elaborate,
but I get the impression
he's leaving it up to you.
Hmm?
Leaving what?
Filling me in.
What is this all about?
I may be bushed, Mr. Mcclosky,
but I'm not that bushed.
We're entrusted
with the security
of the entire United States,
and they don't tell me a thing!
Oh.
Talbot!
Yeah?
Come and get it.
Okay.
Oh.
Excuse me.
It's good. Dig in.
Major: Mind, now...
no food of any kind...
not even a teeny-weeny bite.
Gen. Vanneman: Talbot!
Remember the rules.
What's the matter...
yours tough?
I got my own food.
What's that stuff?
Lunch!
No, that's dinner.
Oh... ulcers?
Mnh-mnh.
Ohh...
Medical experiment...
like survival food, maybe?
Maybe.
All right, don't tell me!
I'm sorry if I can't talk,
Mr. Mcclosky.
It's nothing personal,
you know.
Listen to this...
"captain Talbot,
please do not avoid me again.
"Your very life is at stake.
The girl on the plane."
The girl on the plane?
She's here!
She can't be.
She can't be!
Stay put and lock the door!
And don't leave
until I get back!
Hey!
I thought you said
she'd never find us!
How's that for luck?
Walked right into our trap!
The girl on the plane.
Captain Talbot...
Captain Talbot!
Ooh-hoo!
Captain Talbot,
I must talk to you.
Captain Talbot...
Whoo-hoo!
I do not always mean
to startle you,
but there is so little time.
Where did you...
how long have you been here?
Not long.
How did you get in?
From the next room.
It is not occupied.
That door was locked.
I checked it myself.
Yes. I know.
Okay.
We've got you now.
You're all washed up.
Washed up?
Yeah... finished.
Federal security's
tearing this hotel apart
looking for you.
Your spying tricks
won't work with us,
you understand?
You speak too fast...
don't play
sweet and dumb with me.
Where are you from?
How'd you find us here?
It does not matter.
The only thing is...
no, you don't.
I am only trying to help!
Well...
All right.
Maybe you're one spy
who doesn't carry a gun.
A spy?
Yes... an enemy spy!
But no!
What do you mean, "but no"?
I am no enemy.
You're a friendly spy?
A spy is someone
who seeks information.
Is that not so?
Well, that's one way
of putting it.
Then I am no spy.
I am here to give you
information,
not to seek it.
Well, that's a switch.
A switch?
Yeah. A switch...
yes?
Oh, never mind.
Captain Talbot...
I wish only to save your life.
Now, look...
How did you find out
I'm going to the moon?
I did not say you were going.
I said you would try.
And you will fail unless
you follow our instructions.
Our?
Mcclosky:
Open up, Talbot, it's me.
Believe me, captain,
what happened to Charlie
will happen to you!
The poor little thing is...
how do you say it?
Out of his head?
Yes.
You did not protect him.
It is not your fault...
you are not as advanced.
Talbot, you all right?
Just a second!
How could you possibly know?
You will come with me, yes?
Yes.
Where?
How about the park
right out there?
When?
Who's in there with you?
Open up!
Soon as I can.
Oh, that is good.
Talbot, you let me in,
or I'll break the door down!
Get in here... quick!
Open up!
Talbot, you let me in,
or I'll break the door down!
Break it down!
What's going on?
Ow!
Where is she?
She?
Ohh.
Come on. Come on.
Woman: I'll tell you
how you can get it...
Where did she go?
Where did who go?
Don't you give me that!
I heard a woman's voice
in this room!
Uh, you...
You must have heard that.
Woman: ...Frankie, don't look
at me like that.
Baby, I love you. No... oh, no!
Please, Frankie!
Why did you take so long
to open the door?
Uh, t-to open the door?
Yes.
We got the whole staff
rounded up in the kitchen.
I'll be right with you.
Why don't you get dressed
and come on along
and see if
you can identify her?!
I will. I will.
Tuxedo 5-0711, and be quick.
Drake! Send this to the lab.
Tell them to rush it.
Tell those men in the lobby
to get up here fast.
We don't want any slip-ups.
Hurry up, will you?!
Hello, Harris? Mack.
Say, uh, I think
we've got that girl
trapped right here
in the hotel.
Right.
Well...
Break out files
on all female spy suspects
and stand by for action, sir.
Thank you.
Oh...
Ready?
With that convention...
with that convention crowd
in the lobby,
we'll have to keep
close tabs on our boy.
There will be no slip-ups.
Uh, Mr. Mcclosky,
what if we don't find the spy?
Well, if we don't find her,
what do we do then?
Captain, we never quit
until the file is closed.
Don't worry...
this one's closing with a bang.
Say, uh, Mr. Mcclosky...
uh, Mr. Mcclosky, uh...
When this is over,
if you don't need me,
I was wondering
if I could get away
for about a half an hour?
Uh...
Not even to look up
an old friend?
Absolutely not.
Excuse me.
Hey.
Hey, don't I know you?
No.
Ted Jones! Of all the...
you got the wrong fella.
I'll see you.
No, come here!
You're the spit and image
of your dad.
Hey, fellas, look who's here!
Come and meet my family.
Now...
When we get in there, we...
who...
Talbot!
Where is he?! Get him!
Cover the exits!
You... you...
Gen. Vanneman: Talbot!
Don't talk to anyone.
They're rough. They're clever.
Talbot, you've gotten us
into enough trouble.
Captain Talbot.
Don't do that!
I am happy
that you could get away.
Yeah. H-how did you...
how in the world
do you always manage to...
oh, boy.
Now, are you alone?
Oh, yes.
Where shall we go?
Nowhere. We'll...
Come on. We'll sit over there.
Come on.
Listen, I'll give you
exactly one minute
to explain how you know
about Charlie and me,
or I'm gonna turn you in.
Tsk.
"Coat the rocket
with beryllium and cesium
"and proportion
3 to 5 respectively.
"This to be infused
with aniline and talvadine
at a temp... "
what's this supposed to do?
Protect you
from the proton rays.
What happened to Charlie...
will happen to me.
You said that before.
Your air force must give
you this protection.
Beryllium and cesium
infused with aniline...
aniline?
Chemistry is not
my special field,
but I know a little.
We've been using vanadium
in combination with...
that is not good enough...
not where you'll be going.
The way Charlie was acting up,
you may have a point.
You think this is the answer?
I know it is, captain.
You must not lose
another moment.
It will take time
to coat the rocket.
All this time
I've been running away
thinking you were an enemy.
Oh, yeah, that is funny...
a big, strong man like you
and a weak little girl like me.
I can just see vanneman's
face when I tell him...
By the way,
what am I going to tell him?
Where did you get this formula?
It is a confidence.
It's better I do not say.
But if I'm gonna make sense
with the general,
I'm gonna have to answer
some questions, like...
by the way, where are you from?
Please, do not ask me that,
captain Talbot.
Why not?
It has nothing to do
with the formula.
Nothing?
Oh... tell your general
you thought of it yourself!
He knows I'm not that smart...
not in chemistry, anyway.
Then tell him nothing.
Only make him test it,
and he will see for himself.
We have been using it
for years.
We? Who's we?
Promise me you will insist
on the protection, hmm?
Now, look...
You tell me who you are
and where you're from.
You would not believe me.
Why wouldn't I?
All right...
If there is no other way.
I am from betalyrae.
Beta what?
Lyrae.
Where's that?
Up there.
Which hotel?
Not a hotel, captain...
a planet.
Oh, a planet.
A planet?
You cannot see it now.
Even at night it's difficult.
You mean you think
you're from...
It is beyond the star
that you call Andromeda.
Oh, boy.
It was bad enough when
I thought you were a spy.
Now you think you're...
I knew
you would not believe me.
What did you expect?
Then why did you
make me tell you?
That was not very bright.
And I am not a space-age kook.
How did you know
I was thinking that?
You earth people
are so conceited.
You think you know everything!
You can read minds.
When it is necessary, yes.
Can you tell fortunes, too?
Captain...
If I prove to you
I am what I say,
would it help?
Look, don't you think
this has gone far enough?
I will try to show you
something of your future.
Sometimes the vision
is not very nice.
I never know
what will materialize.
You are not afraid?
No, go right ahead.
My future couldn't look
any worse than it does now.
Look, I've given you
just about every chance I can,
but spy, astronaut,
or just plain kook,
it's time I had you
checked out with security.
Hello.
Are you lost, fella?
Unh-unh?
What's your name?
Richmond.
Richmond?
Richmond... Richmond?
He's got the same name as me.
Huh?
You better run along, fella.
Wait.
Whose little boy are you?
Yours.
Mine?
I told you, I never know
what will materialize.
Ours?
Huh?
Did I do it all wrong?
It's unbelievable.
Oh, you do not believe me?
Come on.
We better go call the general.
Every highway and bridge...
every airport,
railroad station,
bus depot, and taxi stand.
I want complete coverage,
a list of all suspects,
instant reports
on the slightest rumble.
Right? Right.
Mac.
Oh, denis.
Chief says I'm to be
your good right arm.
What'll you have?
Plenty of police cars,
both standby and cruising,
and I want
every man you can spare.
They tell me this is
top-security stuff.
My orders are coming
straight from Washington.
For an air force captain?
The guy must be hot.
What's he do?
Sorry...
I'm not at liberty to say.
A man as important as that
should have been guarded.
He was.
Oh, no! What rookie
handled that goof-off?
The bird flies
at 1000 sharp on schedule.
Keep the countdown going.
We'll do our best, sir.
You'll do better than that.
We have no control
over technical bugs, sir.
We have them every time.
Then make this a first!
No scrubs, no bugs,
no red lights, and no excuses!
I'll have Talbot
back here in time
for final briefing
and blastoff.
He goes up on schedule,
or we'll go down in history
as failures.
And I'll write the book myself!
Did he like it?
He wasn't there.
He left the base,
and he's on his way
here to get me.
Oh, that is good!
You will tell him then.
It's in the meanwhile
that I'm worried about.
There is nothing to do
but wait.
So, will we wait?
Oh, thank you.
Why, uh...
well, how come you went
to all this trouble?
Hmm?
Why should you care whether
our moon shot works or not?
We want to be friends.
With us?
But of course.
Yeah?
We've been watching you
for centuries.
No fooling?
It has taken you
a long time to...
how do you say it...
to advance to us?
Um, catch up with you?
Yes, catch up...
So that you could hear us
and talk to us,
and it will come.
Now you are in space with us.
We would like to help.
Oh...
You laugh at me.
No.
It struck me funny, that's all.
Funny?
Yeah. Well, no,
not funny exactly.
It's more like...
it's more like wonderful...
crazy, mixed-up... Wonderful.
What is?
Well, you, me...
just the thought that
there are people like you
up there.
I mean... oh, man,
that's something!
Wait till I tell
those other guys.
They'll never believe it...
never in a thousand years.
What is wrong?
Well, how do you expect
the general
to ever believe
a thing like this?
But you believed me.
Well, sure I did,
but look what you had to do.
I mean, well...
You can't just go around
materializing children
out of thin air
for guys like
the general or mcclosky
or anybody else
who happens to come along
and want some proof.
It wouldn't be decent.
But I could not materialize
for them...
...only for you.
Uh-huh, uh-huh.
I want the entire
neighborhood fine-combed!
Right!
Excuse me.
Say, whatever happened
to that couple that was...
general vanneman.
Where is he?
I'm glad to meet you, sir.
My name's mcclosky.
Trot him out, mcclosky.
He'll be here directly, sir.
Won't you have a seat?
Thank you.
I don't have much time.
What do you mean, "directly"?!
In a minute, sir.
You mean he's not here?
Oh, of course he is.
Can't I order you a drink?
No, thank you.
Room service!
Wouldn't you like a sandwich?
Say, what's going on
around here?!
"On," general?
Yes!
Who are all these people?!
It looks like
a field headquarters!
Oh, this... this is just
ordinary routine,
that's all... yes.
Routine for what?
Well, when we do a job, sir,
we do it thoroughly...
yes, sirree!
Where is captain Talbot?
He'll be back
within the hour, sir.
You, uh... you have my word.
He's gone.
Don't you concern yourself,
general...
you lost him!!
Just temporarily,
that's all, sir.
There was a bit of a mix-up,
wasn't there?
But we're hot
on the scent, sir...
hot on the... Scent.
I thought...
I talked to him!
You had him right here!
Yes, sir...
right here in this very room.
You let them grab him
out from under your noses.
Shows what kind of experts
we're up against, huh?
Experts?!
Of course they're experts!
What's so difficult
about being expert
when you're dealing
with amateurs?!
Let's be careful
about the language, huh?
Don't tell me to be careful!
You should have been!
Hold on! We're only human.
Anybody can make a mistake.
Even we can.
Don't give me platitudes,
just get me back my officer!
And talking of mistakes...
if he's so important to you,
why did you let him out
in the first place?
That has nothing
to do with you.
I have a right to know!
Why is he so important?!
Sorry... top security.
General, I am security!!
Oh, yes.
Mr. Mcclosky...
Captain Talbot
happens to be the pilot
who is going around the moon.
Around the moon!
Shh!
Like Charlie the chimp?
Yes.
Well, what do you know!
I'd never have guessed it...
not the captain.
The captain happens to be
our lucky volunteer.
Just think...
All this time,
we had a man
right here in our midst...
a man who'll go down
in history,
like Columbus,
and we didn't even know.
We didn't...
why wasn't I told?!
Does that imply, sir,
that your efforts left
something to be desired?
My job is just as important
to me as yours is to you.
I'm in charge of this search,
and right now you're in my way!
Is that clear?
Ha!
Mac.
Yeah.
What?
Search all of those joints.
I want every female beatnik
in the town brought in.
I want to see
that spy dame behind bars!
Right.
Mcclosky, I've changed my mind.
I'll have that drink.
What if he just plain refuses?
Then you must make him do it.
With generals, you don't
make them do anything.
He's not a reasonable man?
Well, it all depends upon
what he calls
a "reasonable" request.
Then refuse to go.
Oh, sure, I can see
the headlines now...
"moon pilot chickens out."
I'd rather be dead
the easy way, like a hero.
If the moon shot fails,
your president would be
very angry with him.
You don't realize he has to
go through with it,
and so do I, protection or not.
Oh, you are so stubborn.
Nope.
I'm just a guy who does
what he has to do.
Right now, I'm more worried
about what's gonna happen
to you.
What is gonna happen
when I'm up there?
Please, don't worry.
Will you be going back to...
I don't know.
If the general turns me down,
is that gonna mean trouble?
Do not even think of that.
I have to.
Maybe I'll decide
I won't even call him.
You must.
It is your duty
to your country...
I know.
...to the whole universe...
To me...
our future together.
Yeah...
Our future.
Richmond...
I wish always to be
where you will be.
For me there is
no one else but you.
It's like I've been
lonesome all my life,
and now, all of a sudden...
lyrae...
What was that?
Hmm?
What did you do?
I kissed you.
So that's a kiss?
You mean to say
you didn't know about it?
I have heard about it,
and I have tried to understand,
but it is not the same
as doing, is it?
I guess not.
Would you do it again?
Mmm. That is nice. Oh, yes.
I don't think you quite
got the hang of it.
I cannot become skillful
with one lesson.
I must have time
to consider
what I have learned.
Hey, uh...
What do they do on betalyrae?
Do?
Yeah. I mean, if they don't...
What do they do?
Yike!
You don't like?
Well, no. It's just
a little unexpected,
that's all.
Yeah. As a matter of fact,
I do like.
Are you expert?
Hmm? Expert?
With kissing.
Oh...
Yeah, maybe.
With you,
I will become expert, yes?
With me?
Yeah.
I believe I am getting it.
Now, will you call him?
Hmm?
Your general.
The general.
Yes.
Oh, the general?
Yeah, you bet I'll call him,
and I'll convince him, too.
Brown speaking.
It's for the general.
Washington?
Hello.
Hello, general,
this is captain Talbot.
It's Talbot... it's Talbot.
Talbot...
Talbot!
Trace this call.
Hook me in.
Talbot, where are you?
I'm in town, sir.
Where?! Where?!
Where? Where... where in town?!
I'm at a pay phone, sir.
What's the matter,
can't you talk?
Oh, yes, sir.
That's why I'm calling.
Gen. Vanneman:
Where did they get you?
They?
The spies. The spies!
What's the matter
with you, Talbot?!
It's from the dock area.
I'm going after him.
Keep him talking.
Don't let him hang up.
Captain...
Have you been brainwashed?
Brainwashed?
I'm sorry, sir.
I'm afraid I don't follow you.
Tell... tell me one thing...
are you free to come and go?
Oh, yes, sir... free as a bird.
Then what are you doing
on the phone?!
If you're such a free bird,
get your tail up here!
Uh...
Yes, I will, sir...
As soon as I have your promise.
Promise?!
About something
very important, sir.
Listen to me, Talbot...
no, you listen to me!
What?!
Sir...
I'm sorry, sir,
but this is important.
Have you got a pencil, sir?
Yes, I've...
blast you, Talbot,
I'm gonna have you
up for court-martial!
No, you won't, sir,
because I gotta go to...
I've gotta go to the moon,
and I would like this shot
to be a success, sir,
wouldn't you?
Ahh.
Uh, wouldn't you, sir?
I've...
Wouldn't you, sir?
You're doing fine.
We've almost got it traced.
Captain Talbot?
I'm still here, sir.
Correct me if I'm wrong.
Are you trying to make
another little deal?
Yes, sir, I am.
That's mutiny!
He's coming around.
Captain, are you familiar
with the articles of war?
Ye...
you realize this is treason.
I'm gonna run you up
in the morning...
Talbot?
Talbot,
are you listening to me?!
I beg pardon, sir?
You heard me.
Humor him. Keep him on.
All right, talk.
I'm listening.
Brown, you got him
pinpointed yet?
Great.
Fisherman's wharf.
Beryllium and cesium?
Talbot: Yes, sir.
You see, cesium's
a soft silvery substance...
I know what it is.
I also know
we've been using vanadium.
What makes you think
your formula's better?
W... uh, uh...
Well, let me ask you one
first, sir.
Uh, how's Charlie?
Charlie?
Well, uh, let's see, now.
At last check...
he's worse.
His mind's been affected, sir.
Look, all I'm asking
is that you make these tests.
After all, it's my brain
and my life.
Is that too much to ask, sir?
No, I suppose not.
Well, then, will you write
this down, sir?
All right, talk.
Cut your siren.
Cut sirens.
Converge on middle wharf.
That's right, sir...
at a temperature
of 845 degrees centigrade.
You got that?
Got it.
Is there anything else
you'd like me to do
for you, captain?
I would like your promise
to test this formula, sir.
Of course!
Anything to keep you happy.
Well, thank you, sir.
We're in, sweetheart. We're in.
Thank you very much, sir,
and I'll be right Al...
let's go, sweetheart.
Search the area.
Pick up witnesses.
Hey! Now, wait a minute.
Where are you taking me?
To police headquarters.
You can't do that.
I gotta see the general.
You'll see him.
Well, well, captain...
Awfully nice to see you again.
Yes, sir. It's, uh,
good to see you, sir.
Your little escapade
all over now?
Yes, sir.
No more deals and conditions?
No, sir.
Let's get out of here! Out!
Not so fast, general.
I'm not through with him.
I can't help that, sir.
I'm running out of time.
Sorry.
We're shooting him
to the moon, remember?
He stays until
he tells me about the spy.
Here's a witness for you, Mac.
Witness for what?!
What's your name?
Cristoforo battaglia.
Sit right down here,
Mr. Battaglia.
Now, tell me...
Have you ever seen
that man before?
Oh, sure.
Mcclosky: Where?
At... on the Fisherman's wharf.
When? This evening.
What was he doing?
Well, uh, he was talking
a long time on the telephone.
Uh-huh.
Was he alone?
Oh, no... with a lady friend.
Describe her.
A good-looking lady...
very pretty.
Ah, it's nice to be young
and make love, eh?
Would you care to tell us
exactly what they were doing?
What would you be doing
with a pretty girl?
Uh, just answer the question.
Well, uh, he kiss her,
and she kiss him.
Are you sure of this, sir?
Senza dubbio.
They kiss not one time,
not two time, but many time.
Mcclosky: Thank you,
Mr. Battaglia.
You ready for the lineup?
Yeah, run them in.
Mr. Mcclosky, look, um,
if it were this girl,
and you found her,
what would you do to her?
Well, this is a spy.
Most nations shoot them.
We pamper them.
Come on... quit stalling
and tell the truth.
Are you protecting her?
Did you sell out, huh?
You handed over
some rocket secrets?
What do you think I am?
I don't know!
Will you tell me?
You think I'd betray
my country?!
Benedict Arnold did.
Easy!!
No excitement, captain.
No excitement.
Mr. Battaglia, when they
line these people up,
I want you to try to identify
this girl you told us about.
And, captain, I hold you
honor-bound as an officer
in the United States
air force to do the same.
I am following an old gray cat,
who is following
a little gray mouse.
We all live together happily
on the shores of the catatonic.
Knock it off.
I am a waterlily on dry land...
What in heaven's name do
you see in weirdos like that?
Believe me, sir, I'm not
as bad as I'm painted...
mcclosky: Pay attention.
Any of them look like her?
Woman: ...Faded society.
We are all symbols
searching for a status.
We are all known...
all right, next bunch.
...and silent trees...
Take them out.
All right, down the steps.
...we are all symbols
searching for status.
Yeah.
We are all known only...
woman: Hey, wait a minute.
Only to the darkened silence.
Get in here.
Knock it off!
Get... Up... There!
All the way over there...
and you, too!
All right... on over.
Come on... all the way up.
Yeah?
No, no, no, no.
The other was, uh...
Affectionate...
che paradiso di Fiore.
Darkness!
Like, way out there!
The crazy quiet!
Quiet, man!
Nothing but gone peace,
but I mean out-on-a-limb quiet!
Dig that bottomless pit!
Fallen!
Nothing but gone peace!
Mac, here's the lab reports.
Woman: Go up there...
all the way across.
I hate machines...
all machines...
tape machines,
the wish machines,
and the washing machines...
all machines.
I hate 'em, I hate 'em,
I hate 'em!
Blah!
Woman: ¶ ...A-hangin' ¶
¶ a-hangin' from a tree... ¶
cowards of conformity!
Protectors
of the organization man!
Away with the dollar bills
that chain men to managers!
And away with blue uniforms
and grey flannel suits!
And keep your hands off of me!
Away with conformity!
Look at you all!
You think I don't see you
out there?
I see you!
What does it all mean?
Is it something we can take home
and discuss later?
With your blue suits!
Why does it have to be blue?
Man: Mac?
Yeah?
Oh... uh, is there
any more back there?
Uh, two or three, maybe.
All right, run them in.
¶ Nobody can avoid the void ¶
¶ nobody can avoid the void ¶
¶ you can't ¶
¶ I can't ¶
dig!
¶ Neither could Sigmund Freud ¶
¶ scoo-ba-Dee-doo-bee ¶
¶ doo-bee doo ¶
that does it, Mac.
You want them held?
No. Send them back
to their coffee cups.
All right.
That'll be all. Thanks.
Thank you.
A very nice show... oh, yes.
Yes. Well, if you don't mind,
mcclosky, we'll...
just a minute, general.
I have here a lab report
on those pills
the girl gave you on the plane.
They analyzed them with
every test known in the book.
You know what they found?
"They contained no elements
known on earth."
And the same goes
for the bottle.
It wasn't made
of plastic or glass
or anything that
had ever been seen before.
That's very interesting.
Isn't it, sir?
Very interesting.
Just a minute, captain.
We also analyzed the note
she sent you this morning.
The composition
of the paper and the ink
was totally unfamiliar.
And take my word for it...
when we can't break down
a piece of paper,
nobody can!
Your point, sir?
The point is that...
I don't have any.
Do you?
No.
You're free to go, captain.
Thank you.
Oh, Talbot...
Sir?
I want a straight answer
from you...
yes or no.
Did you break any of the rules?
With a beatnik, sir?
Yes or no.
Oh, no, sir.
Oh, uh, captain.
Hey, uh...
Where did you say
that girl was from?
I didn't say.
Uh-huh.
Bye, Mr. Mcclosky.
No element known on earth...
No, no... Couldn't be.
Man: "T" minus 27 seconds
and counting.
All recorders
and oscillographs to "fast."
Ready your start.
Man: ...Pressurized.
Man ♪2: ...Pressurized.
Status check...
range safety arm light on?
Affirmative.
Range ready?
Ready.
Water system ready?
You comfortable, rich?
On my mark, it will be
"t" minus five seconds.
4...
3...2...
1...0.
Man: Going good.
Going good, boy... going good.
Keep going, boy, keep going.
Go, man. Go, man.
Go.
Any time now, sir.
Separation.
Mcchord to starfire.
Come in, starfire.
Can you read me, starfire?
Starfire to mcchord.
Good to hear you, rich.
Oh, boy...
don't think it isn't good
to hear you, sir.
Are you all right?
Yes, sir.
But that first stage
was sure a Lulu.
Take over anytime you're ready.
Yes, sir.
The prettiest countdown
we ever had.
It's a beautiful day!
Oh, boy, I wish
you could see this, sir.
What a sight!
Any abnormal sensations?
I do feel
a little... Lonesome, sir.
I shouldn't wonder.
Everything's working
great, rich.
How do you feel now?
Fine, sir.
Keep alert.
Keep alert, rich!
Yes, sir, I remember.
Oh, lyrae...
If I ever needed you before,
I need you now.
If only you were here with me.
But I am with you,
Richmond, darling.
Mmm...
Lyrae...
How did you get here?
We have ways
of doing things, darling...
That I will teach you.
His voice is changing.
It's affecting his mind.
M-mcchord to starfire.
Talbot?
Darling...
What?!
Wherever you go, I go, too.
Good heavens, general,
that sounds like a woman!
Impossible!
Talbot...
Talbot: But I'm going
around the moon.
Answer me!
Yes, but your moon is so dull.
Huh?
Why don't you first come
with me to betalyrae, huh?
Gen. Vanneman: Talbot,
if you don't answer me, I'll...
you will like betalyrae.
¶ Exa luna bot ¶
exa luna what?
¶ Exa luna lot ¶
exa luna lot?
¶ There are seven moons ¶
seven?
¶ Off betalyrae ¶
betalyrae...
¶ Seven moons ¶
seven?
¶ All made for love ¶
yeah?
¶ Exa luna bot ¶
exa luna bot.
¶ Exa luna lot ¶
exa luna lot.
¶ Seven moons above ¶
seven... yeah.
¶ Seven times the love ¶
Uh this is starfire to mcchord.
Are you still there?
Well, of course...
of course we're still here.
Where have you been?
Well, sir, I just wanted
to let you know
I'll be a little late
getting back.
You'll what?!
Well, sir, I've got
something to do first
before I go around our moon.
What are you talking about?
I've got a lady here
who's gonna take me
to her planet.
They've got seven moons,
and they're all made for...
Love.
Love?!
Shut up! Talbot!!
Don't you dare cut me off!
Oh, yes... tell my mom
I'll have a big surprise
for her when I get back.
Bye, now.
Say goodbye
to the general, lyrae.
Goodbye, general, dear.
Mcchor... firefly to...
to, uh... I mean, Talbot!
Talbot!
¶ There are seven moons... ¶
Talbot, talk to me.
Talbot!
Talbot, please talk to me!
Talbot, what's going on
up there?!
¶ ...seven times the joy ¶
gen. Vanneman: Talbot!
You listen to me...
¶ For a girl and boy ¶
¶ seven moons above ¶
what's going on up there?!
¶ Seven times the love ¶
blast you, Talbot!
I'll have you up
for court-martial!
That's mutiny!
Talbot, please talk to me!
Talbot!