Help! Help!
Somebody, help!
- Help! Help!
- Help! Get us out of here!
- We're trapped!
- Francis?
Help! Help!
- Help! Help!
- Help!
- Somebody get us out!
What happened?
She's hit something.
Have mercy!
I can't get it open. It's jammed.
You first, Fritz.
Ernst, help your mother.
Captain Wilhelm?
Anybody here?
Anyone there, Fritz?
If anybody was here,
they'd have heard us long before this.
It's just as I was telling you.
If they've abandoned the ship,
they've got no right to claim it.
It's ours by maritime law.
I can't believe that they'd go off
and leave us here.
Something must've happened.
Something's happened, all right.
They thought the ship
was gonna sink in the storm.
It was every man for himself.
It was carrying too much sail.
I heard the captain and mate arguing
down below.
If I'd been captain,
I'd have fought the pirates,
instead of running into the storm.
All right, Mother.
What a mess.
At least we're not too far from land.
Then there's hope.
Maybe when we get to shore
we can get some help,
make her sail again.
She'll never sail again.
Maybe we could build a raft.
We've got enough wood.
Fritz is right.
The sooner we get ashore, the better.
Hey! Look what I found.
Look!
Oh, those poor things.
They must have had a worse time of it
than we did.
How's it look?
Are we solid on the rocks?
I don't know. No, I'd say we're...
Well, we're here at least
until the turning of the tide.
Help me, somebody, help! Help!
No!
Look what I found! The captain's dogs!
And are they glad to see me! Whoa!
- He's all right.
- Duke, Turk, get off me.
Better make a start. Come on.
Come on, give me a hand.
Now suppose it's a deserted island.
Now I can work out right where we are
soon as I learn how to use this.
All right, take it along.
It still works.
There's no time for that now.
Why don't we put up a distress flag?
Don't you think
we look distressed enough?
Ernst, anyone who sees
a ship stuck on the rocks,
might possibly guess it's in trouble.
Now you look after them, Turk.
You too, Duke.
But I don't see how
we can take all these animals.
We're not taking them.
But we can't leave them here,
Father, they'll die.
When your mother and brothers
are safe on land,
then you can talk to me
about the animals, not before.
Francis, get them out of there.
- We don't want this one or that.
- Wait a minute!
Or that.
Wait a minute, they wanna go too.
We don't want any of them.
All right, Fritz.
Put it over your head. That's it.
All right, I'm fine.
Just hold tight. Grip the rope here.
Ernst.
- All right.
- Come on, Mother.
Now, Mother, don't worry.
We'll take care of you.
- Right, Mother, now don't worry.
- Right, Fritz.
- Come on.
- Now.
- Sorry, Mother.
- You all right?
Hey, Fritz! The dogs!
He forgot the dogs!
They're not coming with us.
- Cast off, Fritz.
- They're my dogs! I found 'em.
Francis, sit down.
They weigh more than any of us.
We'd sink in no time at all.
- All right, Fritz?
- All right.
All right. Watch that wreckage!
Here comes the dogs, going to swim it.
Come on, Duke! Come on, Turk!
You can make it!
Come on, boys! Keep swimming!
Straight between those rocks.
That side, Ernst, that side!
Never mind that side!
Come on. Help me push over here!
Come on, boys!
You can make it! Keep swimming!
Look out, Ernst! Watch those rocks!
- Your side, Ernst!
- Push off!
Come on, Turk! Come on, Duke!
Look out! Look out!
Do something! They'll drown!
We can't take any more chances.
Look!
Come on, boys! Come on!
Good boy, Turk! Well done.
Keep them in the middle.
That's right, in the center.
You see, they didn't sink us.
Let's get to shore.
I wouldn't dare pray for any
more miracles, not in one day.
Fritz, the wave in the front there.
Hey, Turk, Duke! Wait for me!
I'm coming too! Hey! Wait for me!
Francis, come back! Stay in your tub.
I'm coming! Hey!
I'm coming! I'm coming, Duke!
Francis, come back here!
Tie it around the tree stump.
- Come on, let's go.
- Francis!
Francis, come back here!
See ya later.
First thing we've got to do is
to unload the raft.
Then...
put up some sort of shelter
for the night.
Not the first thing.
Fritz. Hold it, Fritz.
We are not making any progress.
I know it, Father.
It's got to hang down even
on both sides.
Aren't very good.
We're lucky to have them.
Pull your side down.
Right, I've got my side.
- Hold it down, Fritz.
- Right.
Come on.
You're very lucky to have them,
you know.
Fritz, I think tomorrow,
if the ship's still there,
you and I and maybe Ernst
ought to go out
and try and bring in the animals
if we can,
anything else we might need.
How long do you think
we'll have to stay here?
Well, I don't know, Mother. I just...
I just think we ought to
do everything we can.
What's going on?
Powder was wet.
Aren't you coming to bed?
You have to have some sleep.
Besides it's going to rain.
No, I'm all right.
No one can ever go back
and undo what's already done but...
Well, I...
I want you to know that...
Well, I'm sorry things didn't work out.
Not the way I wanted them to.
I know.
It would have been so much better
if we'd just stayed in Bern.
I'm not so sure of it,
not with Napoleon Bonaparte
trying to grab up more and more.
Fritz and Ernst might both be in a war,
maybe even you.
No, it would have been better
to stay and face things
rather than just...
running away.
Is it running away
to try to find a new life
in a new colony?
To try to give our sons
a chance to live,
a chance to be free?
Is that running away?
I keep thinking about all the men
who work in those other
offices along the Marktgasse.
They go on working at the same old jobs
and manage to find opportunities
for their families
without running off
to the other side of the world.
I thought we settled all this
before we left home.
It was a good thing we set out to do.
We were right.
All that hasn't changed just
because we were shipwrecked.
You're always right, aren't you?
We'll get there, I'm sure of it.
I'm sure of it!
Sooner or later,
there's bound to be a ship.
I'll pray for it
with every breath I take.
It's... It's a big land, New Guinea.
For hundreds of years,
there've been new colonies,
a great new world to build.
No limit to what a man can do.
Just because we're
a couple of months late
getting there won't matter.
We're not too badly off, are we?
We've got each other.
We've got the family.
- Food to eat.
- And even a tent to keep the rain off...
If we had sense enough to use it.
Oh, the dogs.
- Here, Duke!
- Try to keep covered up.
Now, don't worry.
Try to go back to sleep.
I'm soaked!
Having trouble?
Oh, I'll get it down,
but it may take a while.
Easy.
- Easy.
- Fritz, wait a minute.
Hold him. Hold him.
Easy!
I keep trying to tell her
it's for her own good.
- A ship!
- What?
- There's a ship!
- Come on!
Ahoy! Ahoy there!
I think they've seen us. Ahoy!
Ahoy! Ahoy!
Ahoy!
Take a look, Fritz.
There's something
on the sail. I can't...
I knew it. It's the pirate ship
that chased us into the storm.
Get down. Ernst, get down!
And I deliberately tried
to get their attention.
At least this time we have something
to fight back with.
- Do you know how to fire it?
- I think so.
Let's pull it back.
I'll get a keg of powder.
See if you can find some rags
we can use for wadding.
I know. I'll be right back.
We only have one shot.
Let's wait till we can't possibly miss.
What's happening?
They're leaving. They're going away.
Do you think they saw us loading
the cannon and got scared off?
Pirates scared off
by one cannon and three people?
Do you know what they're up to, Father?
- What's that?
- That? Oh, that's a quarantine flag,
warning that there's black death aboard.
How did you know that?
Well, I do a bit
of reading too, you know.
Come on, Fritz.
- Pull those new lines tight, Ernst.
- Right.
There, that's it. There.
Oh, no. What's the matter with you?
Not that way, stupid, this way.
Maybe we tried too much for one trip.
We had to try.
Sharks. Sharks!
- You got one!
- Watch that one coming in!
- There's another one!
- I'll get it!
I hit it!
Here comes another one!
Get out of here.
Got them.
Look out, Ernst! There's another!
No, it isn't. It's a turtle.
Probably disturbed him with our shots.
I think we scared them away.
He's pulling us.
It's better to use your head
than break your back, I always say.
Francis, see if you can find the...
Francis, where are you?
Here, Duke, Turk. Here, boys!
Francis?
Where's Francis? Go find him.
Now, you wait just one minute
and I'll have some sugarcane for you.
Now, come on, little fella,
I won't hurt you.
Now just let me fix this.
Here, little elephant. Come here.
That's right.
Come on, little elephant.
I wouldn't hurt you.
Come on, little fella.
I have some nice fresh
sugarcane for you.
Come on, come on.
Come on. Come on.
Just a little closer.
That's right.
Come on, little fella.
Francis, where are you? Francis?
Now you just put your foot right there.
Come on, little elephant,
a little closer.
Just a little bit closer.
Right...
Now, stop pulling!
What's the ma...
Francis! Francis!
You, get outta here!
Francis!
Francis, where are you?
You get away from my elephant!
Get out, he's my elephant!
Duke! Turk! Come on!
You beat him enough.
- Oh, good old Duke.
- Good boy.
Did I tell you
you could leave the beach?
Don't you know you
might have been eaten
wandering off that way?
Well, what do you have
to say for yourself?
I'm sorry, but...
But what?
Can I keep the baby elephant anyhow?
Now, I'll keep ya.
Come on, Rocky, get going.
All right, Francis, hold it.
Slack off a bit.
Come on, Rocky, back up.
Good fella, back up.
Right.
Hold it.
- That was a good idea of yours, Ernst.
- Thanks, Fritz.
Come on, boy.
Come on. Come on.
Here.
Fritz, no more full planks,
just some odds and ends.
I think we got enough here, Father.
Well, what do you think of it?
I'd like it a lot better if I knew
tigers couldn't climb trees.
They won't climb this one
by the time we're finished with it.
You've probably never seen
such a house as this is going to be.
I'm sure of that.
The world is full of nice,
ordinary little people,
who live in nice, ordinary little houses
on the ground.
But didn't you ever dream of
having a house up in a treetop?
No, mostly I dream of having
a house in New Guinea.
You must think we're going to be here
for quite a long time.
This I have no way of knowing.
But we can't sit on the beach
just waiting for a ship to come by.
But there could be a ship.
Of course.
Then I think we ought to try
to light the signal fire.
Just forget about the pirates?
Maybe they won't come back.
Maybe we could get away with it.
We can't take that chance.
Right now being alive is more
important than being found.
Don't look down.
All right, Mother, I've got you.
Well, what do you think?
Fritz, can I sleep with you tonight?
What an idea.
It isn't exactly built for two, Francis.
- But I'll give you a swing.
- Oh, good!
Fritz, be careful. Take this rope...
And tie it around his waist!
Mother!
- Getting on, aren't we?
- Yes.
Oh, no, Fritz, you let me out.
No, Fritz. No.
Here, I want to show you something.
Oh, faster, faster.
Look, this is our room.
You're not going to get me
to go up there
unless you make some sort of railing.
But you don't understand.
It's going to be like a real house.
You know, enclosed.
This is your own circular stairway.
Let's go back down before
someone falls off the edge.
- Come on, Francis.
- He'll be all right, Mother.
Let me go first.
Come on, little fella,
I wouldn't hurt you.
I just want to pet you.
Come on, come on.
Francis!
Francis! Hold him, Ernst!
I've got him!
- He caught it!
- You all right, Francis?
- Yes, he's my new pet.
- Aw, look at him.
- Don't let him go.
- Hey, you should feel his heart beating.
Mine could match his beat for beat.
Supposing I hadn't just
happened to insist
that he have this rope
tied around his waist?
Until you get some sort of railing
put up or something
I don't want Francis back up here and
I assure you I won't be up here either.
I'm sorry, dear.
I don't blame you for being upset.
You don't seem to understand
what we have in mind.
- No, but won't you trust us?
- Do what you like about this place.
Just see that Francis is on the ground
and I assure you I won't be back up here.
All right, all right, we'll do that.
You stay back in camp.
And when we've got everything fixed up
just the way we want it,
then we'll bring you back,
see how you feel about it.
Don't you think
you can talk to me like that.
But how much further do we have to go?
Hurry, Mother.
You're gonna love this new house.
Now this way, Mother,
wait'll you see what we've done.
I really think you're gonna like it.
You just wait.
We must be there now.
Wait till you see this, Mother.
- I can't wait.
- Take off the blindfold.
I can hardly wait.
Oh!
Oh. Just a moment, please,
old Swiss custom.
- Carry the bride across the threshold.
- Father.
Duke, Turk, get outta my way.
How's this?
All the latest innovations,
running water,
genuine imported tortoise shell.
And not forgetting the cooler.
This is Ernst's contribution.
He invented it. He and Fritz built it.
See how it works, Mother. Look,
big wheel turns the little wheel up there.
The cup pours the water into the shell.
It runs down the bamboo,
and feeds the sink and the cooler.
I... I can't believe it.
Darling, thank you.
I'm second. I go after Mother.
Hey.
- Thank you.
- Up you go.
Up there's the boys' room.
And look.
This is something I worked out.
When you're in for the night,
turn the wheel.
Pull up your stairs.
Not only keeps out wild animals,
but any neighbors who might
become a nuisance, you know,
always wanting to borrow.
We'll be troubled so much by them.
Hey, get me down.
Oh.
Remember this? I built it for us.
Don't tell me you,
you pull this to ring for the butler!
Here, I'll show you.
Now, you can lie here
and look at the stars.
Don't you remember?
That summer we went to Interlaken?
You said that someday
if you could have your wish,
you would sleep each night
so you could see the stars.
What is it? What's wrong?
These curtains don't belong in here.
Well, they're from the captain's cabin.
We thought you'd like them.
It's so wonderful. I don't deserve it.
I can't believe it.
Don't worry about the curtains.
If you don't like them,
I know a woman who can fix anything.
Oh.
My heart was an island
On a stormy sea
'Til my golden ship
Of dreams came to me
La, la
La, la, la
Filled with the wildest dreams
Of love...
Here it is. "Tiger.
"Panthera Tigris. Native of Asia.
"Ranges north to Siberia
"and south to India
and the Malay peninsula."
That can only mean one thing,
a land bridge.
That's how there came to be
so many different kinds of animals
on one island.
Well, how do you know it's an island?
Why couldn't it be a peninsula?
Well, why don't you let us
try and sail around it?
You know how your mother
feels about that.
Well, it's just as I was telling Fritz.
Now, I think there used to be
a land bridge between here and Asia,
and this is all that's left of it.
Now that would explain
how so many different types of animals
came to be trapped here.
What do you think, Fritz? Do you agree?
Well, I suppose there could have
been one a long time ago.
There's only one way to find out.
Why don't you ask Mother again, Father?
Maybe she'll change her mind.
After all, mother wants to get to
New Guinea as much as we do.
There might be something there,
a village or an outpost,
someplace where ships come in.
Well, if the occasion presents itself,
I might possibly bring it up again.
What's this, spelling competition?
"Tiger, bear, elephant."
That's the list of animals
we've identified so far.
"Hyena, monkey, lizard."
Ostrich.
Help!
- Francis!
- Help!
Francis, let go!
I can't let go or he'll get away!
Let him go anyway. We'll catch him.
Francis!
Head her over this way!
- Are you all right, Francis?
- Yes, I'm all right.
Are you all right, Francis?
Not a mark on him that won't wash off.
- Grab his neck!
- We can learn to ride him.
Ride him? Let me try,
somebody help me up.
I think we'd better
get him trained a bit first.
- Let me try it then.
- All right, all right.
I get to try next.
I got him. I got him. Hold on!
Hold on! Hold on!
Oh, you sillies.
Here I go! Whee!
Watch out for that rock.
Yeah!
No fair stopping.
You gotta keep swinging.
Francis, come on.
Come on, everybody. Follow the leader.
Fritz.
Come on, I'll race you down.
Mother, look at me!
Go ahead, Father. You can do it.
Me? Well, of course, I can.
Whoa!
Here I come!
Where're we going, Ernst?
Wait and see.
Come on!
Hey, look at the monkeys, look!
- What?
- Oh, yeah. Look at 'em swinging.
Look at that one.
Well, I can do that.
- I bet you can't.
- Well, let's see you try.
Anyone can change hands.
- Now steady, Fritz.
- Go on, Fritz.
He's done it!
- My turn next.
- No, no, it's my turn.
After me, after me.
Are you all right?
Never better. See what I mean?
You really are very graceful.
Thank you very much, Mother.
Don't you sometimes feel
that this is the kind of life
we were meant to live on this earth?
Ya-hoo!
Everything we need,
everything's right here,
right at our fingertips.
You know,
if only people could
have all this and be satisfied,
I don't think there'd be any
real problems in the world.
Or any future generations.
There isn't everything we need
right at our fingertips.
Now what are you talking about?
This, it's wonderful for today, I know,
but what about tomorrow?
What about our sons?
What future is there here for them?
Now don't worry about tomorrow.
It'll take care of itself.
Suppose we should
never get away from here.
They'd never know what
it was like to... To be married.
Yes, it... Yes, that's right.
Now you come to mention it,
there aren't many girls around here,
are they?
It's not anything to joke about.
Suppose they never have a chance
to know what it's like to have a family.
What you're trying to say is,
we ought to make every possible effort
to get away from here.
- Exactly.
- Right.
Then I'll tell the boys we've decided
to let them sail around the coast.
- See what they can find.
- That's not what I said at all.
Sooner or later,
we're going to have to face it.
But what do they know about
sailing and outrigging and...
Do you think it's safe?
We can't hold onto them forever.
Come on, Rocky, you can pull it faster.
Come on, pull!
- Straight ahead. Straight ahead.
- Pull. Come on.
Fritz, grab ahold. That's it.
We'll be back soon and
maybe we'll find a ship to take us away.
- Oh.
- Don't worry, Mother.
Oh, be careful, Fritz.
Drop it, Ernst.
Francis, get Rocky clear.
Back up, back up.
Well, it's gonna be up to you, Fritz.
If you run into a storm
or trouble of any kind,
I'm relying on your judgment,
your good sense.
Make sure you both get safely back.
Come on, come on, Rocky, let's go.
- Good-bye, Ernst.
- Good-bye, Mother.
- You got nothing to worry about.
- Remember to use your head.
Yippee!
Ya-hoo!
Good luck.
Don't worry.
They'll be back before you know it.
I hope we are doing the right thing.
- Letting them go.
- I'm sure we are.
Perhaps we ought to have
let 'em go sooner.
We might have been
in New Guinea by this time.
Bye, Fritz. Bring me back a crocodile.
- Good-bye.
- Bye.
Oh, Fritz, I wish Mother could see
this place. She'd love it.
You know what I'd like?
I'd like to see some
real mountains once again.
Walk the Oberland.
Stand looking up at Jungfrau
when a storm moves in.
Remember how you could
sort of smell the snow in the air?
Yeah. Fritz, do you ever
think about where you'd be,
what you'd be doing
if you'd have stayed in Bern?
Sometimes.
I think about Herr Kobel. What he said.
That I should attend the academy.
Fine chance you would have had.
Well, you can't tell.
It might have worked out.
I'll tell you
where I'd really like to be.
Walking down the Nydeggasse
like on a Sunday after church...
And all the girls stroll past
all dressed up.
Any one in particular?
No, nobody special.
Maybe you don't even know them,
maybe you don't speak.
But you look and they look
and you just know they're there.
Fritz, listen, do you think
when we get to New Guinea,
if we ever do,
there'll be any girls our age?
By the time we get to New Guinea,
we won't care what age they are!
Ernst, get the sail down quick!
Keep down!
What's the matter, Fritz?
What happened?
Quick, give me the glass.
There's something moving
over there, on the beach.
Pirates!
I'm sure it's the same one we scared off
with the quarantine flag.
- Let's try to sneak in a little closer.
- Oh, yeah!
If we stay behind the rocks,
they won't be able to see us.
- Ernst, bring the bow around.
- I'm trying!
That chest they just opened,
it belonged to my first officer,
God rest his soul.
I wish they'd fight
and kill each other off.
You let me do any talking.
No, no. No, no, leave him!
Put him down!
Kuala, listen to me. Kuala?
You, boy? You born how long?
He is 14 years.
Leave him alone. Leave the boy alone.
Kuala, wait!
You will want me to write a ransom note.
I write.
My people send money if you let me go.
You send plenty money.
Then you go.
Wait! Leave the boy with me
or I not write ransom note.
No boy, no note.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry, Bertie.
Sorry to have gotten you into this.
We'll... We'll get out of...
Out of this somehow.
Now keep as still as you can.
You'll only make things worse.
Now they'll have to decide which crew
is going to take us.
Ernst,
I think we could sneak in there
and free the old man and the boy
before the others knew
what was happening.
All right.
It's now or never.
Come on!
At least I think
they'll keep us together.
Don't make any noise.
Who are you?
We've come to help you.
If only we had a knife.
Quick, don't bother with me.
Get the boy free first.
Well, go on!
They won't harm me.
I'm valuable for ransom.
Get Bertie free.
Get away if you can.
If they ransom me,
I'll get a ship and come back for you.
I won't leave without you.
Get away quickly.
Don't waste time on me. Go on!
- Run!
- Run, Ernst! Run!
No, I won't go!
Go on, leave me! Leave me!
Come on!
I can't go on another step.
In here.
Pirates took your ship?
What were you, cabin boy?
You mean the old gentleman back there
is your grandfather?
Come on.
Who are you anyway?
Where did you come from?
We were shipwrecked...
Ernst? Ernst!
Run, run!
- Come on.
- Come on!
They're leaving. They're going away!
It could be a trick
to get us to come back...
You know, like the Greeks
and the Trojan horse.
I think we'll stay here until daylight.
Probably save a lot of time
cutting across the island
instead of going back around the beach.
There's no question about it now.
This is an island.
What about me? What am I going to do?
I guess you'll come with us.
Right about that direction
should take us home.
But my grandfather?
If they release him, he's bound
to come back here to look for me.
Well, don't worry about it.
He knows you're with us.
If we're not here,
he'll just sail around the island.
He couldn't get a ship past our place
unseen even if he wanted to.
Come on, Bertie.
You can have the middle.
Come on.
I'll just sit up. Not sleepy.
Fritz? Fritz!
Do you imagine we've changed a lot
since we first landed here?
- In what way?
- Well, lots of ways!
Like getting stronger,
more sure of ourselves, things like that.
I suppose so.
Remember the first night we came here?
Everything scared us...
All those strange noises.
How could I forget.
We must've been helpless.
That I'd have to agree with.
Fritz, listen. You don't think
we were something like him?
I don't think so.
- Did you get a good look at his hands?
- I'll bet he's never done anything.
A wealthy family,
probably an only child.
Sometime,
get a look at the way he walks.
I did.
And back home, we used to call
Jean Monteau a sissy.
Do you remember the other afternoon we
were wishing we could see some girls?
Yeah?
I don't think we could have
come much closer to getting our wish
and still miss it completely.
That direction!
That's the way we've gotta go, Fritz.
Right. We'll cross here.
Doesn't look as though
it'll be over our heads.
Do we have to cross just here?
It's easy. Take off your clothes.
Carry them over your head.
It's better than walking around
for hours in wet clothes.
It's just until we get across
the deep part here.
I can't swim.
I don't think you'll have to.
Now come on, get started.
I'm going back to the beach
to wait for my grandfather.
Don't come any closer!
- Are you out of your mind?
- Stay back!
That's my gun!
You've got no right to take it.
I'm sorry, Ernst, but I have
more need of it than you have.
I'll see my grandfather
makes it all right with you.
Wait!
You keep his attention.
I'll slip around behind him.
I'll keep his attention!
You, Bertie!
Put that down or I'll let this go!
Drop it!
Don't do that, Ernst. I'll shoot!
I don't want to shoot you, Ernst.
Now put that down!
Let go of me!
Stop it!
Let me take him on, Fritz!
I'll teach him to shoot at me.
It was my fault the gun went off.
She didn't mean to fire.
I don't care. I could've been...
What did you say? "She didn't..."
It's a girl!
Why would a girl dress up like that?
It was because of the pirates.
My grandfather made me cut my hair
and dress like this because...
Because he didn't want them to know.
At least now you can wash your face.
Well, it will be nice
to be called Roberta again.
I'm... I'm sorry, but if we would've known
you were a girl, I mean,
- we wouldn't have...
- We'll try to make it easy for you.
As much as possible.
Careful.
- Give me your hand.
- Thank you.
- Careful... Roberta.
- Watch your step.
Oh.
Thank you, Fritz.
Variations and deviations
are two completely different things.
Well, like here, Roberta.
You see, variations can be
compensated for mathematically.
But deviations, you never know
when they're going to happen.
Wait till my grandfather
gets to know you.
He'll put you to work
navigating one of his ships.
Would you like that?
Maybe. Someday.
I'd like to finish school first, though.
Do you like the sea, Fritz?
I like things you can depend on.
The sea? You can never be sure of it.
Well, that's the fun of it,
not being sure of things.
"The winds aloud howl o'er the masts.
"And sing through every shroud.
"Pale, trembling, tired,
"the sailors freeze with fears.
"And instant death
on every wave appears."
Homer's Iliad.
Oh, I think that's one of the most
beautiful things ever written.
The first night,
when we were caught in the storm,
I was thinking of those lines
over and over.
Do you read a lot, Fritz?
Who? Him?
He practically doesn't even read at all.
Never really needed to. Sooner or later
Ernst tells me everything he knows.
I think we're getting off course, Fritz.
We should bear more to the right.
It's all right. He won't hurt you.
It's gone.
- Oh.
- Come on.
Stay close to me.
Get out of it quick!
Ernst, do something!
The knife! Get the knife!
Ernst, the knife! The knife!
Ernst, hurry.
Hurry, Ernst!
Hit the head!
I can't find it!
Here, here, here!
Here. I'm holding it.
Now!
I'm sorry I took so long to find it.
It was horrible.
Let's go back.
Please let's go back!
It keeps getting worse and worse.
I think the worst is behind us now.
Here, give me your hand.
Oh, no! My compass, it's gone!
I don't even know where to look!
I guess we'll have
to get along without it.
Get along without it?
We wouldn't have a chance.
We need that compass.
We don't necessarily need a compass.
I think I can do
just about as well without it.
You think?
You could be wrong, you know?
All right, I don't think it. I know it.
And from now on, Ernst, you're
just going to have to trust my judgment.
Come on.
How's it feel now, Roberta?
I don't care what he says.
I can't go on day after day.
We have to go on.
We've got no other choice.
We're lost, Fritz, and you know it.
We're not lost. We're not going to be.
Fritz, if you want to go on, go ahead.
Ernst and I have decided not to.
You've what?
Well, we can find the river
and follow it back to the coast.
Anyway, it's two against one.
I wouldn't care
if it were ten against one.
I'm the one who's got to get us back
and I'm going to.
Look, just because you're older
doesn't mean you're always right.
What are you doing?
I'll just take charge
of the pistol for a while.
I seem to remember
it being appropriated
once before when somebody wanted
to go back to the beach.
You give me back my pistol!
Watch yourself!
Oh, Fritz, Ernst, stop it!
All right,
you can have your pistol back.
But you know
you only have a few shots left.
How far do you think you'd get?
There isn't any decision to make.
We've got to keep going.
I suppose we'd better go with him.
Do you think you can?
I'll try.
Hey! Hey, hey!
Run! Get out! Hey!
Get away!
Go on! Go away, go away!
Go away! Go on!
Get away! Go on!
You really got yourself into a mess.
All right, boy. I won't hurt you.
Easy, boy, easy. We'll get you out.
- Oh!
- If we can get him out of here,
maybe you won't have to walk
all the way.
Not that way. You'll never get him out.
I'll get some more branches,
make a path for him.
Now, at a time like this,
you gotta use your head.
- Come on.
- Here you are.
Oh, Christmas tree
Thy leaves are so unchanging
Not only green when summer's here
But also when 'tis cold and drear
Oh, Christmas tree
Thy leaves are so...
Must've got wet coming over.
I don't see how you ever
managed to get it ashore.
Well, I couldn't have done it alone.
Fritz and Ernst helped. I...
Merry Christmas.
Are we ever gonna open up
these other packages?
Those are for Fritz and Ernst.
But suppose they don't come back?
Suppose they got "et" up?
Francis, it's been a long day
and it's past your bedtime.
But it's Christmas.
Merry Christmas, sweetheart.
- I'll come up and say good night.
- All right.
How often has the Christmas tree
Afforded me the greatest glee
Oh, Christmas tree
Much pleasure thou canst give me
It's Fritz and Ernst!
What've you got there?
But also when it's cold and drear
Did you bring my crocodile?
Oh, Christmas tree
Thy leaves are so unchanging
What've you got there?
We thought you got "et" up
or something!
- Hey!
- Merry Christmas!
Merry Christmas!
- Francis.
- Merry Christmas.
- What is it?
- A zebra.
- Merry Christmas!
- Ernst, happy Christmas.
Mother! Merry Christmas!
Fritz! Happy Christmas.
Oh, Christmas tree
Thy leaves are so unchanging
A zebra!
Oh, Christmas tree
Thy leaves are so unchanging
I think I need that razor after you.
Let's see, Ernst.
Yes... Got it!
Well, it's a good thing
you boys have done,
a very good thing.
And I'm gonna try and
make sure it's not wasted.
How do you mean, Father?
The pirates know
you took their prisoner.
They also know
you're somewhere on this island.
Do you think they're likely
to forget about that?
Well, they didn't know she was a girl.
They thought she was a cabin boy
on the old captain's ship.
They wouldn't come here after us.
What've we got?
We've got their prisoner here.
Pirates?
If they come here, I'll shoot them.
I'm afraid it'll take more
than a crossbow.
The cannon. We can bring the cannon
back from the ship.
It's useless, Ernst.
It's rusted right over.
It's my fault.
I should've covered it up.
Now let's not waste time
looking backwards.
Thank you, Father.
First thing tomorrow morning,
we'll go out to the ship,
take off everything else
we might possibly need
and then blow her up.
You mean with gunpowder?
Well, what for?
They already know it's there.
I'm hoping that with hundreds of islands
and thousands of reefs,
they won't remember
exactly where we are.
Father's right,
we'll have to blow it up.
We're ready to fight,
but not too proud to hide?
Just a sip now.
That's enough.
It must've taken great courage
to pack off and set off for a new colony
and leave your whole world behind you.
With my husband and my three sons,
I wasn't leaving
my entire world behind me.
Well, you couldn't know
what you were getting into.
There might have been
all kinds of hardships.
I mean, think of the things
you might have had to do without.
Take a look.
It's beautiful.
I've always wanted a daughter,
someone I could dress up
and make clothes for.
I just didn't expect her for Christmas.
Thank you.
How about this? We get some trees,
bend them down, make some snares.
The pirates step in the snares,
they trip the mechanism
and whoosh, they're caught.
But how can we defend this place?
I think what we need is a hill
so they have to come up to us.
- I got an idea.
- What is it, Francis?
Well, we could dig some big pits.
And then we could put some lions
and tigers and snakes
and all sorts of animals in there.
Then when the pirates
come along, they fall in.
Well, I don't know whether we could
manage the lions and tigers,
but I think a few pits
might be a very good idea.
Nyaah!
You look very beautiful, my dear.
Come and join the family.
Allow me, Roberta.
Well... May I have the pleasure
of the first dance?
Whee!
There you are. What did I tell you?
Anything we really need,
the island will produce it, even a girl.
A girl? But we have three sons.
Excuse me, Fritz.
Hey!
I'll dance with you, Fritz.
I'll rest a while, if you don't mind.
What's the matter?
I was just thinkin'.
We gotta have those lions and tigers...
Or else... Well, that's the whole idea.
Well, I guess
we'll just have to have them then.
Yeah.
Since you have a partner,
I'm sure you won't mind.
It might have been simpler
if I'd left the dress
in the bottom of the chest.
Keep playing.
Oh, thank you.
Come on, Francis.
May I have the pleasure?
Yippee!
Something must've
gone wrong with the fuse.
Well, we're not going back to find out.
We'll have to pick up
every scrap of lumber.
We can't leave any evidence.
Must be getting close.
Kaboom!
Kaboom! Kaboom!
I used to dream that somehow
we'd find a way to make her sail again.
Now...
Well, we can be sure of one thing.
If the pirates do come,
we're going to be outnumbered
maybe ten to one.
But up here if we prepare
everything in advance,
I think we'll be able to give
a very good account of ourselves.
We'll be just like medieval knights
defending the castle.
We'll keep the muskets
for our final defense.
And I'll give the order
when to use them.
Of course,
if anything should happen to me,
then Fritz will take charge, then Ernst.
And then me.
Yes, then you, Francis.
We've only got a small army.
We can only afford one general.
Now, that's our weak point.
And this is where
they'll try to come up.
This is where we could've
used the cannon.
Well, we'll have to do the best we can
without it.
Now down there, we'll put our pits
and then our snares
and our entanglements.
Maybe we could plant some gunpowder
and touch it off with fuses from the top.
You know, anything we can think of
to hold them up.
You can rely on me, Roberta.
I've got it all worked out.
And I take care of the lions and tigers
and things.
Right, Francis.
- You're in charge of the tigers.
- Oh, good.
Now the thing about me is that
I'd like to be something in the world.
That's why I want to go to school.
You'd love it in London anyway.
There are concerts, parties, dances,
ladies in beautiful gowns,
elegant men in tall hats.
Did you ever own a tall hat?
- No.
- I can't wait to see you in one.
You'll be quite handsome.
I think that's what I miss most of all,
the color and the excitement.
I know I'd especially like it
if you were there.
I'll be there.
As long as I live, I don't think
I shall travel any further from home
than an occasional trip to the seaside.
Thank you, Roberta.
There must be something
my grandfather can do for all of you.
Herr Kobel used to say,
"For some boys, school is a punishment,
"for others, a reward."
There must be something, though,
my grandfather can do.
Francis, don't!
If you drop that,
you could blow us all to pieces.
Oh, that wouldn't set it off, just to
drop it. You'd have to light the fuse.
Even then I'm not so sure.
You don't think they'll work?
Well, they may make noise,
keep the pirates confused.
That's about all they're good for.
Just because Papa thought
of them instead of you!
Hey, what's all this?
More pirate alarms?
Yes, for over there on the steep side.
You and your pirate alarm. Ha!
What about your tiger?
Have you caught him yet?
No, because until Fritz
and Ernst dig the pits,
I don't have any place to keep him.
Ernst, Roberta!
One of you give me a hand, will you?
- Oh, it's all right. I'll go.
- Don't bother.
Up there, pull the knot
as tight as you can.
Francis, put that down!
Is that all right?
Good.
There we are.
What are you doing?
He was just showing me how it will work.
I feel sorry for any pirates
who come creeping around here.
Well, it was my idea, don't forget.
If you'd like,
I'll show you what else I had in mind.
Pirates. They're here.
Into the fort, everybody.
Come on, Mother, quick.
- What is it?
- Francis? Where is he?
You know those coconut bombs?
You don't have to worry about them.
They work right well.
Come down here.
Don't you know
you might have been killed?
If you had stayed
where you were supposed to, Ernst,
this wouldn't have happened.
You can't tell me
what I'm supposed to do.
- I just did.
- That's enough.
I don't care.
He thinks he can just give orders
and get anyone to slave for him.
Ernst, I said that's enough!
This incident's closed.
Now let's get back to work.
And I don't want to hear
another word about it.
If you really don't want to go to school,
and your mind is made up,
maybe my grandfather
could give you a job.
It'll be a good job, Fritz,
perhaps in the counting house.
What if he doesn't get back here
for one reason or another?
What if we have to stay on this island
for 10 or 20 years?
He will come back, I know it.
He's probably out there now
headed this way
in one of his fastest ships.
You'll take the job if he offered it
to you, wouldn't you?
It's not that I wouldn't appreciate it,
but it's just not for me,
cooped in an office
counting somebody else's money,
doing the same thing day after day.
What would you like to do?
Well, if we get off this island,
I'd like to do
what we started out to do,
go on to New Guinea
and become part of the new colony.
Maybe take up some land in my own name.
Why?
Well, because it's a good thing.
You've got a chance to build
with your own two hands.
It's the beginning of a new country.
That's what I like about it.
Well, I'm going to London.
Ernst was very flattering.
He said he'd like to be there if I was.
Well, wouldn't you like
to see me in London?
I don't know
that I'll ever be in London.
I don't see how anybody
can shoot a thing like this.
Fritz, why don't you teach me
how to shoot?
It might be important
if there's a battle.
All right. Come on.
Well, first,
you pull the gun
tight into your shoulder, like this.
And...
Well, here. Tight into your shoulder.
And,
well, right hand near the trigger.
No, no. Here.
Left hand out to support it.
A little more. Right.
No. No, no.
You have to use this hand to support it.
Now you sight along the barrel here.
I hope you don't mind.
Why do you think
I wanted you to teach me?
Roberta, where are you?
I'm over here.
May I have this next dance, milady?
You said that's what
you missed most of all.
I thought maybe I could
make you feel at home.
Wherever did you get that, Ernst?
You wish the name of my tailor,
my good man?
Go two blocks past the town square,
take the first street to the left.
I thought you were supposed
to be covering the pits.
Yes. And I thought you were supposed
to be working on the bridge.
He was teaching me how to shoot.
I asked him to.
Fritz?
Come here a minute.
I wanna show you something.
If you'd like to learn how to shoot,
Roberta, I'd be happy to teach you.
I think I have the general idea.
You know, Fritz, the ol' tiger,
he'll come along here like this at night
after the pit's been all covered up.
And he'll sniff the meat,
and he'll start to circle the pit.
And he'll come around here like this.
And he'll think,
"I think I just might grab
that big hunk of meat."
So he gets down like this...
And he gets like this and then...
I think you better just tell me, Francis,
not show me.
Otherwise you'll be in there
before that tiger of yours.
Well, anyhow, he'll jump for the bait...
- And that's how I'll catch my tiger.
- Ha!
Do you honestly think a tiger's
going to fall for something like this?
You're wasting your time.
You talk about wasting time, Ernst.
How many hours did you spend
making that silly hat?
That's none of your business.
You're not my boss.
No. Now look, Ernst, we've got more
important things to do
than try to amuse Roberta.
The trouble with you is you're jealous.
Jealous? Of what?
Why don't you grow up?
That's enough, Ernst.
Fight, fight! Now you hit him, Fritz!
Come on, Fritz, get him!
Get him, Fritz!
Fight, fight!
Come on, Ernst, you can get him!
Fight, fight! Get him, Ernst! Come on!
Get him, Ernst, get him!
Oh, what a beauty!
Now your turn, Fritz.
Come on, Fritz, get him. Your turn.
Come on.
Fight, fight!
Are you afraid of him, Ernst?
Poke him one!
Come on, Fritz.
Get him, Ernst. Come on!
Fritz! Ernst!
What's this all about?
Nothing.
Who started it?
You know...
I think this is probably my fault.
I think I've been pushing everybody
just a bit too hard.
It might do us a lot of good
to relax for a change.
So here's what we're gonna do.
Tomorrow we are going to observe...
The first national holiday
in the history of New Switzerland.
A holiday?
You mean like Christmas?
Now let's get on with the work.
Get ready for it?
Yippee!
A holiday!
We're gonna have a holiday, Roberta!
Where did we get these flags?
I got 'em off the ship.
Allow me.
Thank you.
How do you like this
for the winner of the race?
I better try it on for size?
Not going to argue?
Just conceding that I'll win?
Fritz, about this afternoon...
I know why you and Ernst were fighting.
It was my fault and I'm sorry.
It wasn't your fault, Roberta.
Everything that's happened here lately
is because you brought me
back with you,
even the danger we're in
from the pirates.
I don't recall your asking
to be brought back here.
As a matter of fact, it seems to me
you had quite different ideas,
remember?
Poor Ernst.
The hours he must have spent
making that silly hat.
He didn't mean to neglect his work.
He was just trying to be nice to me,
that's all.
I know that.
I never dreamed he'd do that.
I did hope I could repay your family
in some way.
And all I've achieved so far
is to cause trouble between you.
I didn't want to do that.
Don't.
Roberta... I'm not much at saying
things, you know, but...
It's no good.
Fritz, when we leave here,
you're going on
and I have to go back to London.
Let's not make it difficult.
Well, you talk about when we leave here.
How do you know
we're ever going to leave?
We might be here...
My tiger! I bet I got him!
Francis, come back here! Francis!
Come on.
Look out, Ernst. Look out.
He might be anywhere.
Let me go.
Francis, wait till we get there.
Wait a minute.
- Francis, wait!
- It's my tiger. Let me go!
Mind the pit.
Where is he?
Well, I never believed it!
Well done, Francis.
Let's hurry and cover it up
with palm leaves
so he'll go to sleep
and the pirates won't know he's there.
No, you better run off
and tell your mother.
We'll cover up the pit.
Oh, yes.
You don't have to worry anymore.
I got my tiger.
He's got his tiger.
Everybody back behind the starting mark.
Everybody out of my way!
Stay back.
Come on! Come on, Rocky, turn around.
Hang on. Hang on.
Mother, you hold Duke, will you?
Now remember,
you go around the first pylon
and then over to that one,
then back and forth three times
and here to the finish.
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
to the winner...
Good.
This gorgeous culinary creation,
which all of us will eat.
Bravo!
Quiet. And serving as our official starter,
the loveliest lady of the canton.
- Whoa! Whoa!
- Wait!
- Quick, Mother, fire.
- Wait for me.
- Come on!
- We're winning!
Faster!
Come on! Come on, Rocky. Get goin'!
Come on, Duchess. Round you go!
- Wait!
- That way. Come on, Rocky!
Let me get on. Give me a chance.
Now we're off.
No, Turk, get out of here.
You're ruining everything!
Get out. No, Turk, the other way!
Look out! Look out!
Wait a minute, Ernst.
Oh. Oh. Oh, no, not that way.
Hold it, Clementine. Hold it.
What's the matter with you?
Try to jump on.
Come on, boy! Go. Good boy, Lightning!
Hey!
You're going the wrong way, Roberta.
Come on, Rocky!
Stand still!
Come on.
Now we're gonna win!
It's not good
if you can't stay on him, Fritz.
Turk! Get away, Turk!
No fair, Ernst. You have to ride him.
Come on, Rocky. We're gonna win.
Come on, Lightning.
Straight, Clementine.
Oh, no, not that way. The other way.
No, the other way!
Come on! Get away! Now.
Come on!
Turk, get out of here.
Run, run, run!
Oh, I give up. Come on, Clementine.
Whoa! Whoa!
Come on! Don't just walk!
- Out of my way!
- Keep out of the way, Clementine.
Come on.
I'm gonna ride you
if it's the last thing I do.
Quick, the tape! The tape.
Quick!
Turk, mind now. That's not the way
you're supposed to go.
Wrong way, Roberta. Come back.
Roberta, come back here!
Come on, Clementine.
Wrong side.
Hurry, Rocky. Come on, Rocky.
Come on, Rocky, we're winning. Come on.
- Francis, come on!
- No fair, Roberta. I was winning.
You're not hurt?
- Pirates on the beach.
- What?
There's pirates right here on our beach.
- Up the hill, everybody. Quick.
- I'll get the muskets.
Come on, quick, quick.
Come on, Roberta. Come on.
- Remember your orders?
- Yes, sir.
- Well, get started.
Come on. Come on, Francis.
Duke, Turk, come back!
No time now. They'll be all right.
Come along, Mother.
Come on, Francis.
You just stay quiet.
Quick, quick.
Francis!
They see us.
They've seen us.
Fritz, Ernst, the bridge, quick!
All right, Mother?
Here, Duke. Here, Turk.
Good boy. Good boy.
- Ready, Ernst?
- Ready.
Now!
Fritz, Ernst, come up.
Come up, Fritz.
They must be getting near it now.
Over this way a bit.
My tiger. He got 'em!
Number three.
Don't light it till I tell you.
Now!
The idea, my boy, is to judge it
so that the flame reaches the powder
at the same time as the pirates.
See what I mean? Give me the torch.
Bull's-eye!
Look at 'em running!
- Now the coconut bombs.
- No, no, no. Not yet. Not yet.
- They're coming around this way.
- Don't fire yet.
Get back. Get back.
We've got 'em on the run!
Right. The coconut bombs.
Oh, good!
Nah.
Kaboom!
That's it.
- Keep throwing.
- We did it!
We haven't stopped them.
Use the rifles.
Try and pick off the leaders.
Where you going, Father?
- Hurray!
- It worked!
Watch those logs mow 'em down.
Look at 'em!
Hurray! There's a man getting squashed.
- We're saved! We're saved!
- Yippee! Hurray!
Hurray!
Kuala make talk.
You hear?
We hear you.
You take boy belong Kuala.
Give us boy. No more fight.
You hear?
You want the boy, you come and get him.
We're ready for you.
And you can put away your white flag.
Maybe it would be better to agree.
Don't worry. He wouldn't bargain with us
if he thought he could beat us.
Send the boy down the hill.
Kuala take boy.
Get plenty money.
Nobody hurt. You hear?
You make Kuala fight long time!
Then you die...
And Kuala take boy all the same.
It's true. You can't possibly
hold them off forever.
You don't look like
a boy anymore, Roberta.
You know what will happen
if you give yourself up now?
Do you know what might happen
to all of you if I don't?
Nothing's going to happen to anybody.
He must think we're mad.
Roberta, don't listen to such nonsense.
My pirate alarm!
They're comin' up that way!
- Quick!
- Down! Down!
- Look out, Ernst!
- Father, look out!
Ernst, look!
Roberta, stay back.
Get down, Roberta!
- How many rounds have we got left?
- Five.
Five.
Not getting very close.
They're running away.
They're running away!
It's a ship, a merchantman!
They're firing on the pirates!
It looks like
one of my grandfather's ships.
I knew he'd come for us.
Yippee! Here we are, up here!
Can I see your hat, please?
- This? Of course, my boy.
- Thank you.
No, no more, thank you, no.
That was delicious.
Well, there's nothing to it, my boy.
I've been making donations
to that college for years.
About time I asked for something.
Well, Roberta and I
have talked about school,
but a university... I never dreamed!
I'm going to a university!
And as for the rest of you,
I won't try to influence you.
But if you'd like to return to Europe,
well, I think I could make things
interesting for you
and give you a fresh start.
But if you still want to go on
to New Guinea,
I'll be happy to take you there.
I think that since
we have to decide forever,
that my husband and I would...
Rather stay here.
Are you sure that's what you want?
It's been a good life for us here.
Of course, as Roberta says,
there are some few things
you have to do without.
But it's surprising
how unimportant they seem
when you don't have people
stopping by feeling sorry for you.
You mean I don't have to go?
- Yippee!
- Fritz and Ernst will go with you.
I think we should keep Francis here
for a few years.
I'll be back.
Of course you won't be
without neighbors, you realize.
This is a new island.
There'll be a new colony,
a new governor.
They might make you governor, Father!
More than likely, I should say.
- Hello.
- Oh.
It's funny, isn't it,
how you can change your mind
about what's important.
What it is you really want.
Take your parents.
All of this time they've been wanting
to get to New Guinea.
And now when they really
have their chance,
they find out everything they want
is right here.
You mean they're not going?
I can understand how they feel.
I do too.
Two people, if they have each other...
What more could they want?
I guess... Just to be alone.
Fritz? Roberta?
It's time to go now.
- The captain wants to sail with the tide.
- Just coming.
Well, surely you'll want to go
and see him off.
Anyway, I'll have to
explain to my grandfather.
- Bye, Ernst.
Come back next year. Good-bye!
Good-bye, Mother. Good-bye, Father.
Good-bye, Fritz. Good-bye, Roberta.
- Good-bye, everybody.
- Good-bye, Ernst.
God be with you.
Hey, wait for me. Duchess, Clementine!
Turk!
Duke, wait for me!