It was in that time of year
called Indian summer,
That season when the Canadian wilderness...
Is touched with Autumn's mystery.
It's a time when change is in the air,
When migration is in the blood...
And the homing instinct
is strong in the heart.
It's a time of busy comings and goings,
Of constant commotion
and unexplained restlessness.
Yet, as each day ends, nature sleeps again,
And the night brings a peaceful calm.
It was in this uncertain season,
In this same wild section of Canada,
That this story had its beginnings.
One evening, a man named John Longridge...
Was passing the time with some old friends.
They were good company, these three.
For a bachelor, almost like
having a family around.
Washing will be done on the floor.
Yet, things weren't
as perfect as they seemed.
It so happened, this wasn't
the animals' true home.
And this man, for all
his hospitality and kindness,
Wasn't their real master.
And that accounted for the lonely look...
In the young retriever's eyes.
Hello.
I'm sorry, I can't hear you.
Mrs. Oakes?
Yes, it's me, Mr. Longridge.
Can you hear me?
I hear you.
I wanted to know what time
you'd be leaving in the morning.
About seven.
Trouble is, I can't make it by then.
Sorry, Mrs. Oakes,
I've lost you again.
I think it's somebody else on the line.
If that's you, Winifred,
you get off this minute.
Do you hear me?
Winifred?
- You're still there.
- I can tell.
What I was trying to
tell you, Mr. Longridge,
I can't get there until nine o'clock.
That's quite all right.
You're sure now?
Nine o'clock...
Is all right?
Of course, and before
you get here I'll take...
The 2 dogs and the cat...
Hello?
Mr. Longridge?
The joys of living in the country.
Well, that was your friend,
Mrs. Oakes.
Now, how about a run?
Come on, you two.
For a man who'd never kept pets,
Longridge had learned the ropes quickly.
He knew the animals expected and enjoyed...
Their nightly romp outdoors.
He'd learned not to worry about them.
They'd be back in their own good time.
"Dear Mrs. Oakes,"
"we are out of coffee."
"Please order more."
"I'll be taking dogs..."
"and Tao, too, of course,"
"out for a morning run...
"before I leave.
"Don't worry yourself too much over them.
I know they
will be fine."
No bears out tonight?
Rabbits? Skunks?
No other cats?
Come on, Luath.
You're letting in the cold.
At bedtime every night,
The retriever liked to get off by himself,
So he slept in the kitchen.
The comfort-loving siamese
chose the hearth...
In front of the fire.
But the bull terrier wouldn't
settle for anything less...
Than the master bedroom.
Old Bodger had his own basket,
his own blanket,
And his own sly plans.
The moment the man dropped off to sleep,
The dog would sneak out of his own bed...
And then climb into the big one.
He practically never missed his chance.
But tonight for some reason,
the man stayed awake.
He was calling to mind again,
How he'd come to have
3 remarkable animals...
Belonging to somebody else.
It was one weekend at
professor Hunter's house.
The Hunters were his closest friends.
He was godfather to the daughter,
And sort of an unofficial uncle to the son.
This, somehow, gave him a
special interest in their pets.
Come on, Bodger, jump!
Get the ball!
On this Sunday, as usual,
he was invited to dinner,
And this happened to be the day
the exciting telegram came.
I've been offered a visiting
fellowship at Oxford.
Here's what they say.
"A series of 12 lectures.
Lodging for family available.
Hope you will accept."
It's wonderful news!
You are going to accept?
Well, it does mean a lot to my career...
And Nancy's willing.
Nancy was more than willing.
In fact, everybody was thrilled,
And in their excitement had
forgotten something important.
What will we do about Tao while we're away?
Hey, that's right.
What about Bodger?
I must confess, this is
a problem I'd overlooked.
Don't worry, we'll find a
good kennel and board them out.
But mother, not Tao.
You know how he hates to be cooped up.
He wouldn't be that cooped up.
He'd be with other cats.
But he hates other cats.
Might do him good.
Sometimes, I think, he thinks he's a dog.
Well, suppose we settle this later.
No need to bother John with the problem.
Ah, but I have the answer.
There I am rattling around
that big house of mine, right?
I know the animals.
The animals know me.
So there's no need to board them out.
They will stay with me.
About the time everyone else was in bed,
It was the cat's habit
to wake up and go prowling.
A shadow, a moth, a beam of moonlight,
His curiosity took him everywhere.
On this particular night, his exploring...
Would sort of miscarry.
Without his knowing it,
he had opened the door...
For the incredible journey.
Next morning, as he'd planned,
John Longridge got off to an early start.
For as long as he could remember,
He'd never missed
the opening day of duck season.
Here it was, that time of year again.
Luath,
Young fella,
You'd like to come along,
but I'm afraid it wouldn't do.
You couldn't leave your friends,
Now, could you?
Why, Luath.
This is the first time.
You charmer, you.
Well, young fella, you're the steady one,
So you'll look after the other two.
Won't you?
Au revoir.
Now, the animals were alone,
And for all they knew, completely deserted.
Silence fell upon the scene,
Silence that seemed to stretch
away to the ends of the earth.
Then voices spoke.
Wild geese called,
Wild geese going home.
Somehow, this was an urge
the young dog could understand.
For in him, the homing
instinct was strong, too.
Among these three, the bond
of friendship was binding.
Wherever one would go,
the others would follow.
So it was,
The animals set out for home.
They couldn't know it was 200 miles away.
They only knew that it was
somewhere off to the west,
So they would follow the sun.
The incredible journey had begun.
That's funny.
I don't see the animals.
They're always out to welcome us.
Probably Mr. Longridge
left them inside...
Knowing you was coming. I s'pose so.
Bring the vacuum cleaner,
Will ya, Bert?
Now, where do you s'pose they've gone to?
Bodger, Luath?
Where could those rascals be?
Probably gone up to the school.
There's no note at all.
He goes up there sometimes
to play with the kids.
Where's the cat?
He wouldn't go up there.
Luath, Tao?
Here puss, puss, puss.
Bodger?
Here, boy.
Here, boy!
Luath? Tao?
Bodger?
They're not outside.
Probably hunting.
The cat, maybe. I never saw
such an animal for hunting.
But the dogs, they wouldn't go off.
Quit stewing.
They'll show up.
Where do you want this plugged in?
Right there, in front of your nose.
Oh, for heaven's sakes.
Here's a note from
Mr. Longridge, after all.
That's funny.
"I'll be taking the dogs
and Tao too, of course."
Now what do you s'pose he means by that?
Just what it says.
He's got the animals.
Why didn't he say so on the phone?
Don't ask me.
Wait a minute.
I remember now.
Last night when the phone went dead,
Mr. Longridge was just about
to tell me something.
Then, don't worry. He's got
the dogs and the cat, too.
You've got nothing to fuss about.
Well, all I can say is that...
It sure beats me how some people
can change their minds.
As it turned out,
not a single person concerned...
Would know of the secret departure.
By this time, the animals
were well on their way.
From the very start,
The travelers had adopted
a certain marching order.
The young dog became the natural leader,
For he was the one driven
by the desire to get home.
The old dog was more of a follower,
Quite satisfied to
let someone else show the way.
He wasn't too sure he could make it,
But he'd try for his friends' sake.
The cat, meanwhile, was everywhere;
Sometimes in front, sometimes far behind,
Sometimes off on side trips of his own.
As the little procession went along,
The dogs were the dedicated ones,
And the cat
the happy-go-lucky one...
Ready for anything, especially hunting.
Along about mid-afternoon
of that first day,
The animals were getting a little tired...
And beginning to feel
the effects of their long walk.
They put their heads together a moment,
And even the ambitious
young leader seemed to agree...
It was time to stop.
When he'd had his fill,
the retriever led off again.
He took it for granted that
the rest periods would be short,
That they'd immediately push on.
It seemed, though,
That his partners weren't of the same mind.
Old Bodger's feet hurt.
The truth of the matter was,
This was almost too much for an old dog...
No longer in his prime.
The others would just have to
wait while he took a moment out.
The cat was agreeable.
Especially since
he'd stumbled onto something...
Well worth waiting around for.
Car coming!
Might be someone who would
recognize them, and this was...
The last thing they wanted.
The scare over,
it was time to get going again.
If the old terrier
had been alone at this moment,
He probably wouldn't have bothered.
He was stiff in every joint, and
definitely feeling his years.
Much more of this and he'd be through.
By morning of the second day,
Bodger was definitely
beginning to slow down.
It was becoming more and more apparent...
He'd soon have to rest.
But the young leader
couldn't bring himself to stop,
Not this early in the game,
And he kept urging his friends to push on.
As the leader,
It was the retriever's job
to choose the way.
He seemed to have an uncanny knack...
Of always knowing where west was.
So far as he was concerned,
There'd be no such thing as obstacles.
He would keep going in a straight line.
It was up to the others to follow.
For Bodger, it wasn't quite that simple.
His sore feet were beginning
to give him real trouble,
And his pace was getting slower and slower.
Many miles farther on,
Near mid-afternoon
of the second day,
The weary old terrier had
just about reached his limit.
The collapse, when it came, was total.
His legs simply folded up under him.
The young dog hated to stop,
yet he knew he had to.
He couldn't leave his friend.
There was nothing else to do...
But wait until Bodger
could get his second wind.
And if possible, somewhere,
somehow, something to eat.
In fact, all of them were getting hungry,
And before much longer,
Would need something
more to go on, than water.
If food was to be found,
It was likely the cat
would be the first to find it.
Suddenly, the chance popped up
right in front of him.
Old Bodger stayed put,
glad for the chance to rest.
As yet, he wasn't aware that
he was a celebrity of sorts.
Somehow the news had got around about him,
And now the curious came to look him over.
These two decided not
to be standoffish about it,
But to give him their greeting in person.
Bodger, perhaps,
Could have done with a little
less of the personal touch,
But he was much too tired to object.
Pretty soon the cubs had had enough, too.
To their way of thinking,
This dull stranger wasn't much for fun.
In another moment,
They'd invented a game
with a lot more action in it,
Action...
And noise.
From a distance, it sounded
like a really vicious fight.
Alarming enough to raise a mother's fears,
And make her come a runnin'.
Thoroughly aroused,
The she-bear needed a target.
Somebody'd been hurtin' her cubs,
And somebody would have
to suffer the consequences.
It had been a near thing for Bodger,
Weak as he was and almost helpless.
But now the cat would cheer him up.
He would bring the meal so badly needed.
Within a few minutes...
The old dog was quite himself again,
Revived and refreshed,
and ready for the road.
By the end of the first week,
The animals had learned
to travel after sundown.
For then, they stood
less chance of being seen.
Generally, they steered around settlements,
But one night they decided
to break their rule.
An old sawmill looked
deserted enough to risk it,
And they chose the shortcut.
Everything went along all right...
Until Bodger got wind of the cook house.
Being shot at was something new
for the old terrier.
It sort of shook his faith in human nature.
But worse than that,
It made him look foolish
in front of his friends.
He could sense it in their accusing looks.
After 10 days on the trail,
The animals were weak with hunger,
And had begun to get discouraged.
Even the determined young leader.
By now,
They were ready to stalk
any wild game they could find.
The cat, of course, was a natural hunter,
But the dogs were ready to try, too,
Though neither of them
was a true hunting breed.
Chasing rabbits was a bit
strenuous for the old terrier,
And instead, he rested.
Then, suddenly, he heard singing.
It was old Jeremy, the hermit,
Recluse, and philosopher.
Slightly odd, people said,
But kindly, and very friendly to animals.
Oh, ho!
Good day to you.
Old Jeremy lived close to nature...
In a world of his own.
His friends, the wild
creatures of the forest.
Instinctively,
Bodger felt this was a man
who might help them.
When the retriever returned
and fell in step,
He was sort of lukewarm about it.
This was all against his better judgment.
He wasn't sure...
They wanted to get
mixed-up with people.
At the hermit's cabin
the young dog hung back,
Still not convinced this was a good idea.
Come in, my dear, around this way.
Presently, maud, presently.
It was the appetizing smell of the stew...
That finally won the dog over.
However, he would put his rabbit...
Where he could find it later.
Oh, come in, old chap.
Glad to have you aboard.
So the retriever joined his friends,
Prepared to accept
the old man's hospitality.
Now, their host went about
setting the table.
From long habit, he got out only one plate.
But wait,
Today there would be places for 3 more.
Oh, Maud, you must learn
to control yourself.
At last,
the half-starved animals...
Were about to enjoy
a home-cooked meal.
How lucky that Bodger had
spied this friendly old hermit,
And how kind of him to bring
them to his bountiful table.
For what we are about to receive,
May the lord make us
truly thankful. Amen.
Do sit down.
At the familiar command, the animals sat...
On the floor,
Where most pets have been trained to sit.
All except cats.
Cats, of course, will sit where they please.
Oh, not hungry?
Oh, picky.
His own plate finished,
The old man moved to the
next chair and the next serving.
Since no one was eating it,
This seemed the most logical thing to do.
Gradually, it began to dawn on the dogs...
That they might be about to
lose out on a good thing.
The last chair, the last plate,
Their last chance.
In the end, it was the crow...
That roused the old man
from his daydreaming.
Oh, Maud,
Time for our nap, is it?
Good-bye, old chap.
Nice you could come to dine.
Remember me most kindly to your mother.
Disappointed, but too polite to show it,
The animals carried out
their part of the make-believe,
And took themselves off,
Like the well-behaved
guests they were.
Delightful people, eh, Maud?
We must have them over again very soon.
Yes.
As it worked out, their luck wasn't all bad.
This rabbit
wasn't make-believe,
So they wouldn't starve.
It was to be expected
that the wilderness, itself,
Would give them a problem or two.
Now they had one.
At moments like this,
The retriever had a decided
advantage over his friends.
For him, being an
out-and-out water dog,
Crossing a river was nothing.
In fact, he sort of enjoyed a nice swim.
The bull terrier didn't
take to it quite so naturally.
Still, once he got over his fear,
He turned out to be...
A pretty good water dog, too.
But when it came the cat's turn,
it was a different proposition.
For the first time on the trip,
He got his back up.
He wouldn't even dip his toe in.
He could face a bear, maybe,
But he couldn't bring
himself to face a river.
This was asking too much.
As it turned out,
The cat wouldn't have to
get his feet wet, after all.
There was a bridge the beavers had built.
It had a stick or two missing,
But not so much but what
the cat couldn't jump over.
He'd crossed many a creek wider than this,
And the dogs were confident he could do it.
The cat was gone, no two ways about it.
Their friend had disappeared.
Instinctively, the dogs
knew a sense of loss.
They missed their partner,
missed him very much.
They tried to console each other
in their common sorrow.
For hours afterward, they stood by...
Refusing to leave.
They seemed to feel that
somehow, by hook or crook,
The clever cat would find a way to get back.
If they'd stay just a little longer,
They'd see him comin' along...
As sleek and spry as ever.
But it was a forlorn hope,
And finally, they seemed to understand that.
Now they'd have to forget
their best friend and provider,
And push on, just the two of them.
Miles downstream, pure chance
would play a part in things.
For in the cat's moment of greatest need,
A helping hand happened to be near.
Papa!
Come and see.
There's a funny looking animal.
See, papa?
Is it a weasel?
No, I don't think so.
No, it's a cat.
Or...
It was a cat.
It's moving.
It's still alive.
Poor thing.
What can we do?
I don't know.
Helvi, you run and get a dry towel,
And I'll heat some milk.
Put some brandy in it, too.
Be careful.
Don't squeeze too hard.
He swallowed half the river.
That poor thing won't
need a drink for weeks.
Olga, see if he'll take
a little milk and brandy.
Oh, look.
He's moving.
Keep him warm and quiet for awhile.
I've got chores to do.
Will he be all right, papa?
Maybe, maybe not.
Hard to tell just yet.
And so it was,
that a half-starved cat...
And a lonely little girl
struck up an acquaintance...
That brought comfort
and companionship to both.
Good night, mama.
Sleep well.
You, too.
Papa, one little song...
For my cat?
♪ Ol kaunis kesa ilta ♪
♪ Kun laaksossa kavelin ♪
♪ So tun tee ni voitti ♪
♪ Ja hei tyi syommeni ♪
♪ so tun tee ni voitti ♪
♪ Ja hei tyi syommeni ♪♪
Later that night, the cat came to the girl,
As though to tell her something.
He was trying
to say good-bye.
Something out there was calling him,
And he knew what it was.
He knew he must find the 2 dogs.
Next morning, the cat located the place...
Where the dogs had waited,
And soon had picked up their trail.
Now that he was alone, he could travel...
At his own pace, in his own way,
His natural stealth his protection.
He was almost as much
at home in the wilderness...
As the creatures of the wild themselves,
And often watched them pass...
Without their knowing he was anywhere near.
As he went deeper and deeper
into the forest,
The cat began to get uneasy.
He had a strange feeling...
He was being followed.
There was nothing in sight,
Yet his senses told him
there was something back there,
Something evil.
Evil it was, for it was the lynx,
A wild and wanton killer.
Suddenly, another hunter appeared.
Not as savage as the lynx, perhaps,
But equipped to deal out death,
just the same.
When all seemed quiet, the cat went on.
Faster now, to make up
for the time he'd lost.
One morning, not long after,
The dogs heard a peculiar call.
It was a cry to stop them in their tracks,
For it sounded like a siamese cat.
The young dog let Bodger
be the first to greet the cat.
He understood that there was...
Something special about this friendship.
Then both dogs offered the cat
their affection.
They seemed to want to tell him
how much they'd missed him.
Every step of the way,
the animals had known hunger,
And by the end of the third week...
Were desperate for food.
By this time, they'd taught themselves...
To chase anything that moved.
Especially if it looked
fat and easy to catch.
Now, a porcupine could only mean trouble,
But the dogs weren't
experienced enough to know that.
The retriever was struck...
Before he quite knew what had happened.
Something else he didn't know...
Was that the sharp quills
were barbed like fishhooks,
And would work their way in deeper.
Instinctively,
The retriever turned to
his friends for help,
But Bodger, not knowing what to do,
Only succeeded in making things worse.
When the pain started,
The dog went to water
to cool his burning face.
It wasn't a cure, but it was a relief.
It was the only thing he knew to do.
Every few hours,
He found it necessary
to repeat the treatment.
And so it was, that he happened
to be at a nearby lake...
When the first flight of mallards came in.
Surprised though he was,
the hunter was interested, too,
For he could see that the
retriever had been well trained.
He was james mackenzie,
fancier of fine hunting dogs...
And a man to admire one when he saw it.
Good dog!
Well done.
Now bring it to me.
Poor laddie.
You've got mixed-up with
a porcupine someplace.
Where's your master?
Ahoy!
Or don't you have one?
Whose ever dog it was,
Mackenzie's mind was made up.
The animal must have immediate attention.
The retriever went along without protest.
He seemed to realize...
He needed help,
And must return to the world
of humans to find it.
And so, the kindly man led the dog home.
He couldn't know there were
others of the party around,
That he might even have touched one...
If he'd known he was there.
Nell, look what I found.
And look what I found.
Another one.
This poor dog's nearly starving.
Aye, so is this one.
Worse than that, he's hurt. Hurt?
Porcupine quills.
You can see for yourself.
Will he let you touch him? I think so.
That is if his partner, here, will let me.
Funny, how they seem to know each other.
It's more than that. I think
they're traveling together.
Where do you suppose they came from?
I don't know.
Lost from a car
traveling cross-country,
It's hard to say.
The main thing is...
This retriever needs help.
When did you find Whitey?
Oh, he found me.
I guess he smelled the bacon cooking.
He came to the door
like an old hobo, begging,
And I really mean begging.
I heard this scratching,
and there he was carrying on...
Just like he's doing now.
You old clown.
Now, laddie, hold still.
I know this hurts.
Unfortunately, it's got to be done.
There, there, laddie.
It's not as bad as all that.
See if you can get him on the porch.
How?
Food, food.
Your intentions are good,
but you're getting in the way.
Shall I go out there with him?
No.
There, I'm through.
Let the other one in.
I can't get over
the affection these two show.
Do you think we can find who they belong to?
When I drive into deepwater in the morning,
I'll inquire around,
maybe put an ad in the paper.
Meanwhile,
The one person who should have
been the first to know,
Would be the last to hear...
Of the events of the past several weeks.
Welcome back,
Mr. Longridge.
Thank you.
I've been watching out for you all morning.
This came the first of the week.
The hunter family...
Will be flying back the day
after tomorrow. So I see.
Was it a good trip? Yes, marvelous.
And the animals, did they have a good time?
The animals?
Why Bodger, and the cat and Luath.
You mean, all this time...
They haven't been with you?
Of course not. I left them here.
But they're not here!
I haven't seen them in 3 weeks.
3 weeks?
When I came, the morning you left,
The animals were nowhere in sight.
And then, I found this note,
Saying that you were taking them with you.
But this is only half of it!
That's all there was,
Mr. Longridge.
Do you suppose they could
have been hit by a car?
Or poisoned?
Or stolen?
One of them, maybe,
But not all 3 together.
Yet, they couldn't just vanish.
The retriever,
I keep remembering the look in his eyes.
You know,
On the morning I left,
For the very first time,
he offered me his paw.
Mrs. Oakes,
they've gone home.
Home?
Home!
The retriever has taken them home.
He was the unhappy one,
So he's simply gone back home.
Someone would have seen them.
Not necessarily.
They wouldn't be where
anyone would see them.
You see, traveling by instinct,
They'd simply go west,
Straight across country...
And over the Ironmouth Range.
Over the Ironmouth!
Then there's no use hoping anymore.
Don't let's fool ourselves.
You know old Bodger couldn't
last more than 10 miles.
I wouldn't give much for
the cat's chances, either.
Operator?
If they did make for home,
there's a good chance...
That the big powerful dog,
like the retriever,
Would get there.
But it's a long way,
Mr. Longridge.
Yes, I know.
Operator, would you please
get me the chief ranger...
Of lands and forests
up at the Ironmouth station?
Glad to,
Mr. Longridge.
I'll pass the word on to
the game wardens tomorrow.
Yes, sir.
No trouble at all,
Mr. Longridge,
But the reporter that knows that area...
Is up at Windigo covering a plowing contest.
But he'll be in tomorrow,
and I'll have him call you.
Yes, Mr. Longridge,
I have maintenance crews
all through that country.
I'll be in touch with them in the morning.
Tomorrow, tomorrow.
I gotta know today.
How do you find a dog...
In 200 miles of backwoods country?
That same evening,
James Mackenzie was providing
bed-and-board for his guests.
He'd decided to keep the dogs
locked up until he could...
Inquire around and find out
who they belonged to.
There you are, now.
Spend a quiet night.
The third member of the party,
Whose presence Mackenzie
was still unaware of,
Had watched these goings-on
with great interest.
He now knew where the dogs were.
He knew they were all alone.
This was his chance to join them.
Neither latch nor lock could
keep him from his friends.
The worst thing is,
we haven't got a single clue.
Hello.
Yes, this is John Longridge.
Yes!
Yes, that's right.
2 dogs and a siamese cat.
It's the operator at Lintola.
She says a little girl
rescued a siamese cat.
Oh, it disappeared.
2 weeks ago.
Get me the map.
No sign of the dogs?
Well, thank you very much for calling.
Please let me know
if you hear anything more.
Good night.
It's not much to go on,
But apparently the cat
got as far as Lintola.
It's about 100 miles from here.
100 miles? There it is, right there.
Lintola.
How could the cat get that far,
And nobody's seen the dogs?
If it was our cat.
What could have happened to those dogs?
Poor old Bodger.
I don't think we're going to
solve anything more tonight.
Come on, mother.
We'd better get home,
And let Mr. Longridge
get some sleep.
He's gotta be on that plane in the morning.
Yes.
When the hunters get home,
I've got to be there.
That's the least I can do.
But I don't know how I'm going
to face up to the children.
At sun-up
the next morning,
The retriever was eager to be up and doing.
The old restlessness had returned.
It was time to press on.
For a moment,
His determination seemed to weaken.
He was grateful for the kind
treatment he had received.
Yet, the homing call
was stronger than gratitude,
And he knew he must answer it.
Ahead lay the Ironmouth Range,
Rugged, forbidding, and uninhabited.
Now, the animals were beyond all human help.
And worst of all,
A biting edge of cold
could be felt in the air.
Already ice had begun to form in the stream.
Before many more days, the
river's voice would be still,
And this land frozen under winter snows.
At the hunter's house, meanwhile,
The telephone had been
kept busy day and night.
Thank you for calling.
Good night.
That's the best bet, yet.
A man named Mackenzie, who lives in Conrad,
Says he actually had
the dogs only 3 days ago.
Had the dogs?
Yeah. He didn't
know about the cat,
But the dogs answer our description.
Why didn't he keep them?
He must have known
they belonged to somebody.
He did. He locked
them in his barn,
But they managed to get away.
He figures they're headed through here.
Through the primitive area.
Then there's no hope.
There might be, jim.
They made it this far.
It's only 40 miles more.
But 40 miles of what?
The worst kind of country!
Nancy, as you can guess,
I've regretted that day when I
offered to take the animals.
Nonsense, John.
None of that.
It wasn't your fault.
Oh, sure.
But try to tell the youngsters that.
They'll get over it, in time.
Peter doesn't say much.
I think he knew from the beginning...
That an old dog wouldn't stand a chance.
I think he's accepted the fact
that poor old Bodger's gone.
And Elizabeth?
Elizabeth's a strange one.
She's just the opposite.
Firmly convinced in her own mind...
That her cat's going to show up.
Just has faith that her old
Tao cat will come walking in...
As sassy and independent as ever.
The grownups wished they could
share the child's belief,
But they knew it was too much to hope for.
It was better to forget what had happened...
And look forward to happier occasions.
♪ Happy birthday, dear Peter ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪♪
Bravo!
Blow them out.
Did you make a wish?
I don't feel much like it, really.
Not the wish I'd like to wish.
Peter, I was going to wait
until you opened your presents,
But I think this is the right
time for you to have this.
Happy birthday.
What is it?
Registration papers
from the Kenmore Kennels.
They're holding a puppy in your name.
Well, Peter.
Another bull terrier.
How nice of you, John. What's his name?
He's properly named, as tradition says,
Starting with a "b."
Champion Birmingham...
Brigadier of Brocton.
What's his color?
White, of course.
And so much like Bodger,
I just couldn't believe it!
Peter, darling, can't you say thank you?
Thank you, Uncle John.
Suppose we serve the cake now, hmm?
Elizabeth, would you
get the ice cream, please?
All right. Very nice of you, John.
Listen.
Listen, everybody!
What is it?
I hear a dog barking.
I don't hear anything.
I do.
Daddy, it's Luath!
Oh, Liz, please don't.
But I'm sure of it.
I know his bark.
I think I hear it, too,
Up on the hill.
It's probably just somebody out hunting.
You know, James, Luath might
have been able to make it.
It could be Luath, dad.
Try calling him.
For a magic moment,
James Hunter was as a child again,
Hoping against hope.
It is!
It is Luath!
Look at him come!
Come on, Luath!
Come on, boy!
Good boy, Luath.
I can't believe it.
Luath!
In the general excitement,
everything else was forgotten,
Peter, Bodger, and the cat.
Quite ignored until Elizabeth...
Heard a familiar voice.
Mother, it's Tao!
He's back!
Tao!
I can't believe it.
I know it's true,
But I can't believe it!
I'd never have bet on it.
It was hard to believe, yet there he was...
Safe in Elizabeth's arms.
Her cat was home.
Peter, I'm sorry.
Oh, it's all right.
Hi there, Luath.
I'm glad he's back, dad.
And Tao cat, too.
I knew all along Bodger wouldn't make it.
He was just too old.
But Peter, you're not old,
and he's the same age.
I feel old.
And with dogs it's different.
Look!
Bodger!
Miraculous as it seemed, it was Bodger.
Champion Buracastle Brigadier of Doon,
Coming as fast as he could.
Come on, boy.
Hurry!
It is you!
Come on!
Oh, Bodger!
It is you, you silly dog.
Cut it out, Bodger.
Bodger, stop it.
And so it was,
3 devoted friends came marching home,
Together as always,
They came to the end of
their incredible journey.