[man] Toby!
Toby Tyler!
Toby.
Where are you?
Toby Tyler.
[brass band playing]
[crowd cheering]
[roaring]
[monkeys screeching]
Stand back, please.
Make way for the elephants.
Look out there.
This is dangerous.
- Stand back.
Stand back, please.
- [laughing]
Make way for the elephants.
[roaring]
[calliope playing]
[man] Here you are, ladies and
gents. Get a cane, get a whip.
One cent, and here's
a balloon for you.
Just a penny, a copper penny.
Balloons here.
One penny. One copper penny.
- Balloons here...
- [man] Get your tickets
for the show.
My balloon.
I want to get another balloon.
[man] Balloons here,
all kinds, all colors...
Step right in
and enjoy the show.
Hurry, now. Step in
Hurry, hurry, hurry.
Are you going in?
No, sir.
Step in and enjoy
the show, gentlemen.
[man] There you are,
little lady, and thank you,
madam, very much.
Ladies and gentlemen, step right
up. Fresh-roasted peanuts.
Peanuts, popcorn,
candied apples and taffy,
all fresh and delicious.
All right, folks,
step right up here.
The peanuts are grown
on the plantation and roasted
here on the premises.
Are you a looker
or a buyer?
About how many peanuts would you
say I could get for a penny?
In the normal course
of business, I don't
sell them by the penny.
- [sighing] Oh.
- However,
seeing as you're a handsome
young rooster with cash in hand,
I devise I might
part with, say,
oh, six genuine plantation-grown
Georgie goobers.
Six?
It's more than
if you bought them by the bag.
That's a solemn fact.
Here.
Folks, step up.
It's all fresh and
it's all refreshing.
Nice and cold and refreshing.
Plantation peanuts.
Do you swap the ones
that are bad?
Bad? I don't vend bad peanuts
in my establishment, boy.
Maybe a little underbred,
perhaps timeworn,
but not really bad.
Tastes bad.
Here's two more. Run along,
or you'll miss the best part.
- Oh, I'm not going.
- Not going?
Ah, you lack
the price of a ticket.
Yes, sir.
I suppose your parents
are bringing you tonight.
No, sir, I don't
have any parents.
Orphan boy, eh?
Well, have you ever thought
of joining the circus, lad?
Me?
Imagine, being a part of
the glorious confraternity
of the big top.
That company of artistes
who travel
the length and breadth
of this great land of ours.
- How would you like that?
- But what could I do?
You could become...
...a concessionaire.
I could?
- A con...
- ...cessionaire.
Rolls out on the tongue
mighty important, don't it, boy?
- Yes, sir.
- Free transportation,
snug place to sleep,
all you can eat,
see the performance anytime,
rub shoulders with the great
and near great.
And if that weren't enough,
each and every Saturday night
yours truly, Harry Tupper,
will present you...
...with one of these.
What do you say, lad?
Is it a bargain?
I'd like that better
than anything else
in the whole world.
You would, eh?
The only trouble is Uncle Daniel
and Aunt Olive need me.
Aunt and uncle?
They're awful poor,
and there's lots of work
for me around the farm.
I understand.
It does you credit.
I'm a loyal man myself,
and I love to see it in others.
- I could ask them.
- Don't give it another thought.
I'll just pick up a boy
in the next town.
Plenty would be glad
for such an opportunity.
Yes, sir.
Anyway, thank you.
Wait a minute.
Come here.
Just so's you and I part
the best of friends,
here's a free pass
for tonight's performance.
- But Mr. Tupper...
- Bring a friend
and enjoy yourself.
Courtesy of yours truly,
Harry Tupper.
- Mr. Tupper...
- Farewell. Ice-cold lemonade.
It's pink, it's cold,
it's refreshing.
[Tupper] Ice-cold lemonade.
Pink and refreshing.
Ice-cold lemonade.
Hey, Red.
Red, look at what I've got here.
Look, Red.
Guess what this is.
A genuine free pass
to the circus. Look.
- [whinnies]
- Yahoo!
Where have you been?
I said where have you been?
Answer me.
I'm sorry, Uncle Daniel.
I meant to come right back,
but there was a parade.
And then I happened to go
by the circus grounds,
and a man gave me a free pass.
- Look.
- Circus?
Did you know the hogs
broke the fence down
because you didn't feed them
and rooted up the turnip field?
Toby, we'd counted on
selling that crop.
You know how we need money
in the house.
- You're a shiftless,
ungrateful boy.
- Don't be hard on him.
Boys get skittish
when a circus comes to town.
He don't have a right
to behave like other boys.
He's got no rights at all.
- And he knows why.
- Don't say that to him.
I'm a poor man, yet I took you
in out of decency's sake
- when no one else
would have you.
- Daniel.
I don't see why we didn't
send you to the county home
in the first place.
You're no kin to us.
You're nothing to us.
Nothin' but a millstone
around our necks.
You don't mean that, Daniel.
You just go up to bed
and stay there.
There'll be no place
at supper for you.
Those were cruel things to say.
Get on with the supper, Olive.
[man] Hurry it up, Tupper.
- This wagon's already loaded.
- [man #2] Gangway.
Horses coming through.
- [man] Giddyup.
- [man #2] Move those
stringers out.
Guy out over here.
Men, guy out!
Over here!
[Toby] Mr. Tupper?
Mr. Tupper?
- Here I am, Mr. Tupper.
- Well, what of it?
Don't you remember me,
Mr. Tupper?
- You said I could work for you.
- So?
- I'm ready.
- [man] Move it, move it!
What about
that aunt and uncle?
Well, it's all right.
They don't want me.
They said I was a millstone
around their necks.
All right,
you got the job.
- Fifty cents a week.
- Today you said a dollar.
If Harry Tupper said a dollar,
he meant a dollar.
But don't let me catch you
running away once I teach you
the business.
- It takes a lot out of me, boy.
- No, sir.
Gentlemen's agreement.
It's one of the most solemn
things there is. Understand?
- Yes, sir.
- You stay here and
stay out of trouble.
I'll be right back.
- Mr. Tupper?
- Yes?
- I'm hungry.
- So?
I didn't have anything
to eat for supper.
[sighing]
All right.
[man]
Throw a blanket over the him!
He's coming down with a cold!
There you are, my boy.
Nutritional gold
from the Indies.
- See that it lasts you
till morning.
- Yes, sir.
- [man] Give us
a hand, will you?
- [man #2] Up.
[man] Olie!
- [man #2] Chuck wagon ready.
- [man #3] Pull that back.
[man #3] Get some of this stuff
back in there.
- [man] We're leavin', boys.
- [man #2] Lift it up.
- [man shouting]
- Steady up, boys. Steady.
Steady!
[horse whinnying]
[man]
Clear that... [indistinct]
Hey!
What are you doing?
- Give that back, you thief!
- [screeching]
[monkey screeching]
What's going on?
What did you do to that chimp?
Me? I didn't do a thing.
He stole my banana.
[screeching]
All right, troublemaker.
Settle down.
Now, as for you,
you'd better get home.
I told you
to stay out of trouble.
He stole my banana.
- What's wrong here?
- I-I-I... Nothing, Colonel,
nothing at all.
The chimp just got
a little excited.
- Who's this?
- This is my new helper, sir.
- Picking them small,
aren't you?
- Well, sir...
He has no folks,
the poor lad,
and I thought I'd take him
under my wing and give him
a helping hand.
Spare me your
kind intentions, Tupper.
Get these wagons moving.
The boy can ride
up top with Ben.
Thunderation, Colonel.
Why pick me to wet-nurse
Tupper's sniveling brats?
Trim your wagon, Ben.
We're moving.
Olie, get these sideboards up.
- Mr. Tupper?
- Hmm?
I kind of changed my mind.
Oh, now, lad.
Listen. Don't you worry none
about our rough ways. No, sir.
We don't mean a thing by it.
Not a blessed thing. No, no.
Here, look. Look what
Mr. Tupper has here for you.
There's a bag for you
of peppermint jaws.
That should last you
till morning.
All right, now, lad.
Right up this ladder here.
I'll take that for you.
You'll be snug
as a mouse up there.
Mr. Cotter will
take good care of you.
[man] All right, keep them cats
covered when you move 'em!
Colonel Castle says you ride
with me, you ride.
Get a tight tailhold
on yourself, sonny.
Bess, Will, ha!
Get. Giddap.
Let's get
one thing straight.
Me, I don't like kids.
Especially runaways.
They're a weak-livered lot.
Kid has a good home.
First time something
goes wrong, he runs away.
Then he finds things
don't suit him just right.
He wants to run
back home again.
Go ahead. Jump.
Nobody'll miss you.
I doubt you're worth missing.
Jump. Don't be scared.
I'm not scared.
And I'm not scared
of you either.
Fair enough, sonny.
My name isn't Sonny.
It's Toby Tyler.
All right, sonny.
We'll call you Toby.
Now, it's none
of my business, Toby,
but maybe you better
catch some sleep.
Morning comes early
with this outfit.
- I'm not sleepy.
- Suit yourself.
Do do dee
A deedle dah dee dum
bah dee dum dum
A biddle-dee-dee
and a biddle-dee-do
[humming]
And away I go
Never know when and then
[humming]
It's better not knowin'
I don't care
A biddle-dee-dee
and a biddle-dee-di
[humming]
And away go I
Ho there.
Get up, get up.
Not too sad
My way of thinkin'
not too bad
Never know when and then
[humming]
It's better not knowin'
I don't care
You better be up and doin',
before Harry Tupper
comes for you.
Thanks for taking care of me
last night, Ben.
- I guess I fell asleep.
- Don't mean nothin' to me.
I didn't want you fallin' off
the wagon and me getting blamed.
Anyway, thanks.
I won't bother you anymore.
I'm sure glad to hear that.
[spitting]
[screeching]
[man] Get Mrs. Connor
and a couple of girls
to look at this canvas.
For a big fella he sure throws
a puny shadow, don't he?
- He sure does.
- Reckon I ought to tell him
his apron strings
is draggin'?
I didn't say nothin'.
[man] Hey, Dots,
you seen our stake wagon?
- Should I wash up here?
- That's water, ain't it?
- Yes, sir.
- All right.
Now you do me a favor
and keep out of my way.
- What's the matter?
- You sure got
a bad temper, mister.
Don't let that bother you.
You're working for Harry Tupper.
- A real fine fellow.
- At least he's friendly.
Oh, sure.
And just by happenstance,
here's Mr. Friendly himself,
come looking for you.
What's the idea of making me
chase all over for you?
Morning, Mr. Tupper.
I was just washing up.
Not on my time, you aren't.
Come on.
Move along, move along.
Step it along.
[sighing]
Look. We don't want to be
wool-gathering all over camp
when there's work
to be done, do we?
Now, let's move along, boy.
Let's...
- Put me down!
- No, Ben, it was my fault.
You keep out of this, boy.
It's got nothin' to do with you.
Take your dirty hands
off of me.
Oh, I aim to, Mr. Tupper.
I aim to.
Now, I don't believe
in coddling, Mr. Tupper,
but I got my fill of you
mistreating your helpers.
It just don't
sit well with me.
That boy works for me, and
I'll do what I want with him.
Sure, Mr. Tupper.
You just tell him
what you want him to do.
If he don't do it,
you can fire him.
But if I ever catch you
mistreating him again,
well, I'm just liable
to do something like this.
No, Ben, no!
As for you,
you listen to Mr. Tupper.
Work hard and do your job right.
He's your employer.
You be respectful.
Yes, sir.
You can work soon as
you've had breakfast.
Cookhouse is down there.
Well?
Why, Mr. Tupper,
you're all wet.
Here.
A biddle-dee-dee
and a biddle-dee-do
[humming]
Away I go
- There you are.
- Thanks.
[Jeanette]
Why don't you sit here?
Oh, thank you.
- You're new around here,
aren't you?
- Yes, ma'am.
- Who's that?
- I was just trying to find out.
You're not supposed to be here.
This is a performer's table.
Stop it, Ajax.
I asked him to sit down.
Did you hear what I said?
And look at me
when I talk to you!
[Jeanette] Oh, Ajax,
let him alone.
[Ajax] He's not supposed
to be at our table.
Go on. Get away.
Well, well,
there you are, my boy.
Colonel Castle 'specially
asked me to look out for you.
- Me?
- Are you taking a professional
nom de plume this season,
or do you plan
to use your own name?
- I guess I'll use my own name.
- Which is?
- Toby Tyler.
- Of course. Wonderful name.
I've always liked it.
May I present Mademoiselle
Jeanette and Monsieur Ajax?
You're heard
of Toby Tyler, of course.
Well, gosh,
I didn't know who he was.
It's a little late
for apologies.
Will you have breakfast
with my family and me?
- Yes, sir.
- Fine. Right this way.
Allow me to introduce myself.
I'm Sam Treat, circus clown.
- A clown!
- At your service.
Ow.
[with accent]
What is it that you do
with the circus, Mr. Tyler?
Oh, I'm a con...
con-stash-in-aire.
A con-stash-in-aire?
[laughing]
Papa Schultz used to say,
"What would a circus be
without a con-stash-inaire?"
[chuckling]
Come on. The kids are sure
gonna be glad to meet you.
- How big of a family
do you have?
- It depends.
Most of the time I'd say
somewhere between four and five.
- Sit down.
- Thanks.
All right, kids.
Breakfast.
Gosh, when you said you had
a family, I thought that you...
It's all right.
They're family to me.
Not what you're used to,
I suppose.
To tell you the truth, I don't
have a regular family either.
That's why I joined the circus.
- That so?
- I ran away, you know.
- I never would have guessed.
- It wasn't because
they didn't want me,
but they're awful poor,
and I was a millstone
around their necks.
Millstone, huh?
That's pretty bad.
Sure is.
You, uh, you figure
you'll ever go back?
I guess not.
Not till I can earn
enough money to bring home,
to show them I'm not
what they said I was.
You know,
Papa Schultz used to say,
[with accent] "Happiness
you should spend around,
und it will come back
even more so.
Money you should
save in something."
- Who was Papa Schultz?
- An old clown I used to know.
I always wanted to make
people happy, the way he did.
- That's why I ran away
with the circus.
- You ran away too?
Papa gave me this pouch
to save money in.
He said, "The circus is
for elephants und Papa Schultz.
Everybody else should
take their money and go home."
But you didn't.
There you are, Toby.
Save your money.
Don't wait till it's too late.
Thank you, Mr. Treat.
I'll save all my money
and work hard
and do everything
Mr. Tupper tells me, and...
- Oh, my gosh!
- What's the matter?
I forgot.
Mr. Tupper's waiting for me.
Bye. Bye.
Bye. Come back again.
[whistle blows]
- Peanuts, popcorn,
candied apples.
- [crowd gasping]
[Tupper] Peanuts!
Peanuts, popcorn,
candied apples.
All right, folks.
Right here, ice-cold lemonade.
It's refreshing.
Candied apples,
peanuts, popcorn.
[crowd gasping]
- [cymbals crash]
- [horn toots]
Peanuts, popcorn,
candied apples.
- [drumroll]
- And now, ladies and gentlemen,
you are about to witness
those youthful
equestrians extraordinaire,
with their famous
educated steeds.
Mademoiselle Jeanette
and Monsieur Ajax.
Peanuts, popcorn,
candied apples.
Peanuts...
Hey, sit down, boy,
will you?
Oh, thank you, sir.
[whistle blowing]
Ice-cold lemonade.
It's pink, cold and refreshing.
- Great show, isn't it?
- Yes, sir.
Peanuts, popcorn,
candied apples.
Ice-cold lemonade here.
It's pink, it's cold.
A dollar, thirty,
thirty-five, forty,
sixty, sixty-five...
What's that?
Why, you blithering
greenhorn.
Don't you know any better
than to take a lead slug?
I'm sorry, Mr. Tupper.
I don't know that much
about money.
Oh, you don't?
Oh, then, I'll teach you.
Here is lesson number one.
I'm going to replace
this slug with a nickel
from your first week's pay.
Yes, sir.
What do I do with these?
- Where did you get them?
- They were left over.
When I tried to give them back,
they said, "Keep the change."
That, my lad, is what is known
in circus parlance as "a tip."
- Understand?
- No.
Good.
There's an old circus custom
that all tips belong
to the head concessionaire.
- That's me.
- Yes, sir.
However, if you report
all your tips,
I will split them
with you.
Thus, a dime for me
and a nickel for you.
Thank you, sir.
But you must promise to keep
our little arrangement a secret.
You see, in the circus world,
one must pretend to have
a hard nature.
I wouldn't want folks
to think that I was a softie.
Now, get busy
and clean up that mess.
[screeching]
[jabbering]
Why, you little...
Mr. Tupper'll
skin me alive.
I hope you get sick!
I hope you get so sick
that you turn green.
[screeching]
[yowling]
[whimpering]
- He's awful sick, isn't he?
- It don't look too good,
that's a fact.
It's all my fault.
I didn't want him
to get that sick.
This fellow'll eat anything.
Sometimes I think
he's part ostrich.
Let's see here.
A trunk key.
A button hook.
A hairbrush?
- A piece of clothesline.
- You sure scared me.
Don't worry about this fellow.
You couldn't hurt him...
He is almost indestruct...
Indestructible.
- You couldn't do it.
- Do you think
you can fix him up?
I always have.
Old reliable.
Castor oil.
Get a good grip on him,
and I'll give him some.
Gosh, I wanted to
make friends with him.
He'll never
forgive me for this.
Hang on tight.
Don't let him bite.
- There we are.
- [screeching]
- Hold still.
- Easy, easy.
Hold him tight.
I sure hate to put him back
in that old monkey cage.
It might be a good idea
to keep him warm tonight.
Here. Wrap him in this.
Maybe he can sleep
with me tonight.
You better ask Ben. The monks
are his responsibility.
Thanks, Mr. Treat.
Good night.
We're gonna be
real good friends now,
aren't we, Mr. Stubbs?
Stubbs?
Why Mr. Stubbs?
He reminds me
of old Mr. Stubbs.
He runs the general store
back home.
Yes, sir, real good friends.
That's gonna be us, Mr. Stubbs.
How I ever let you sweet-talk me
into this, I don't know.
Colonel Castle's
number one rule is:
"Animals ride in the cages
where they belong."
Don't you think
he's looking better?
- He'll be his old self
in the morning.
- That'll be real nice.
Giddap! Ha!
Wake up, Toby.
Wake up.
- What time is it?
- Late. Canvas wagon
had a breakdown.
Maybe I ought
to find Mr. Tupper.
- He'll be lookin' for me.
- Hold on.
We're gonna parade
into Woodvale.
We'll set canvas after.
- You mean I get
to ride in a parade?
- Yeah.
Here.
You want to be circus?
Look circus.
- How about a hat
for Mr. Stubbs?
- Never mind about that.
Whatever you do,
hang onto that chimp.
Don't you think
he's looking better, Ben?
Yeah.
- [popping]
- Hey, I almost forgot.
It's the Fourth of July.
That means firecrackers.
Uh-huh. The big cats
are sure gonna love them.
Ha. Giddyup.
[brass band playing]
[roaring]
[Ben]
Bess, Will, steady now!
Hold up!
Bess, Will, whoa!
Stop, you consarn...
Jump, Toby, jump!
[screaming]
[man] There's a kid
under that wagon.
Get that kid out of there.
Look out!
Look out! Look out!
Call an ambulance, someone!
- Toby, you all right?
- Yeah, sure.
Thanks, boys.
- How did this happen?
- Chimp was loose,
got scared
and riled the horses.
- How'd the chimp get loose?
- My fault. He was
up top with me.
You know the rules, Ben.
You're through.
See me after the show.
[Colonel] The monkeys!
Olie, Omaha, get after
those monks before they
tear this town apart.
Mr. Stubbs. He's loose.
Keep those wagons moving.
Close it up.
- [brass band playing]
- Mr. Stubbs!
[gunshots]
Take cover!
[gunshot]
[jabbering, screeching]
Hey, son, get down.
That chimp in there's
got my .45.
Mr. Stubbs!
Get back down there.
He's got
just one more shot.
[gunshot]
Rest easy, folks.
That's the last bullet.
[gunshot]
Sheriff.
- Wait!
- Get back!
Hate to do this, but I'll get
him before he shoots someone.
- No!
- Hey, come back here!
Oh, hi, Mr. Stubbs.
It's me, Toby.
Look out, boy.
Don't rile him.
- [gunshot]
- Oh, horrible!
We're friends,
Mr. Stubbs, remember?
Careful with that gun.
Good old boy.
Easy.
Easy, Mr. Stubbs.
Good old boy.
Good old Mr. Stubbs.
Easy.
Give it to me. Please?
No, Mr. Stubbs! No!
Mr. Stubbs!
Too late to be sorry now.
Come on.
He didn't know
it was loaded.
That chimp's pretty good
with a shooting iron.
- Yeah, maybe you ought
to deputize him.
- [laughing]
- Where are you going?
- Taking a walk.
Free country.
- Where are you going?
- Leaving.
Planning on buying
that livery stable
you've been thinking about?
Might.
Well, good luck.
[Colonel]
Come in, come in.
Why doesn't Ben just
tell him it was my fault?
You know why Ben's so big?
He's just plain stuffed
with mulehead pride.
Well, Ben,
it's been quite a day.
Those runaway monks fiascoed us
into the best business
we've done all season.
Telegraph from our man
in Kingsville
says they're sold out of "blues"
for the performance tomorrow.
And listen to this.
"Monkeys capture Woodvale.
Boy disarms
gun-toting chimpanzee.
Animals celebrate
Independence Day
by making break for freedom."
That busted wagon was the best
thing that ever happened to us.
Why the getup?
You trying to scare the animals?
I come by
to pick up my pay, Colonel.
- Your pay? What for?
- You fired me today.
Oh, now, Ben.
You know me.
I was just letting out
a little steam.
What's the sense
of running my show
if I can't get sore
at people?
If you'll pay me
the money that's due.
Stop whimpering
about your money.
Where's that boy, Tyler?
Toby? He's outside.
- What's he got to do with this?
- Toby?
Toby Tyler, come in here.
Now, Toby, I want you
and the chimpanzee
to ride up
on the monkey cage tomorrow.
Folks in Kingsville
want to look you over
after those stories.
A chimp up on the seat?
Are you out of your mind?
That's what started the fracas.
With you in charge,
I'm not worried about a thing.
Oh, no. No, sir. You don't
get around me that way.
Toby, I'd like
to thank you for saving
that chimp's life today.
He's kind of
a pet of mine.
I've got a weakness
for troublemakers.
- That's why I like
old Ben here.
- Colonel...
Seems like you handle
that chimp pretty well.
How'd you like
to take care of him?
Keep him out of mischief?
- You mean it, sir?
- He's your responsibility.
Now, run along.
Thank you, sir.
Look, Colonel, I don't
think this is gonna work.
What are you standing
around here for?
Climb out of that suit
and get those wagons moving.
It's a long haul
to Kingsville.
Welcome home, Ben.
- Where have you been?
- I was...
I don't care what Colonel Castle
says about that chimp.
You just be sure he doesn't
interfere with your work.
I have to go into town
on some business.
- You remember
everything I told you?
- Yes, sir.
See that all the stock
is locked in the green box,
fetch enough water
for all the jars,
and it's Saturday.
- Saturday?
- Yes, sir. The day you pay me.
And what, young Croesus,
are you doing with the money
I've been showering down on you
the past couple of weeks?
Oh, I save it, sir.
That's a slug,
Mr. Tupper.
So it is. Just wanted to see
if you were on your toes.
Here you are.
You make sure that chimp
stays out of my stock box.
I won't be gone long,
and I want you to carry on
with your work.
Yes, sir.
You ever see so much money
in your life, Mr. Stubbs?
Three dollars and 47 cents.
I'm pretty near rich.
Won't Uncle Daniel
be surprised when I bring
all this money home.
Come on.
I better tie you up.
Let's go.
I've got to go tie you up.
Stay there.
Now, don't move.
Here we go.
Come on.
Sit down.
I got a lot of chores to do.
I'd better get started.
Hello. Come in.
Come on in.
Well, if it isn't
the great peanut salesman.
The death-defying daredevil
of the lemonade stand.
Stop it, Ajax. We haven't
seen you around lately.
Well, Mr. Tupper
kind of keeps me going.
Oh, sure.
He's got an important job.
- Chasing flies away
from the lemonade.
- Don't mind him, Toby.
Oh, I don't. Next to Mr. Tupper,
he's kind of friendly.
- That sure is a pretty horse.
- You like horses?
What would a peanut seller
know about horses?
- Hey, Jeanette, watch this.
- Oh.
I do so know something
about horses.
It so happens
I have a horse of my own.
- Toby, really?
- His name's Old Red.
Of course, he isn't really old.
That's just his name.
- Is he a gaited horse?
- Gaited?
You know, what gait
does he favor most?
Oh, I guess he favors most
the gate that leads down
to the pasture.
- Lots of sweet clover
down there.
- Toby, you're joking.
Hey, Jeanette.
Look at me.
- That's pretty good.
- Don't look at him.
He thinks whenever he's
in that ring the whole world
has to stop and watch.
Tell me some more
about Old Red. Can he jump?
Hey, Jeanette!
Ajax, you know
what the colonel said about
practicing without the belt.
Who cares?
Just keep watching.
Ajax.
[screaming]
- Ajax.
- Get away from me.
- It's pretty bad.
- Get him to his tent. Move.
Careful of that leg.
Both hands under it.
Easy, easy.
Get the doctor, quick.
Who's responsible for this?
Who let him practice
without the belt?
- Where were you?
- I was out...
Never mind.
Don't bother me
with it now.
Now what?
Here we are, going into
our peak time, and a top act
goes up the chimney.
Well, what do we
do about it?
- Colonel?
- What?
- Toby Tyler can ride.
- Who?
- [Jeanette] It's true.
Toby's been riding
since he was little.
He has his own horse at home.
You. Toby.
Sorry, sir. I'll get right back
to the lemonade stand.
- Can you ride?
- Me?
Well, sir, it was just
around the farm, kind of.
Never mind. You have experience.
I'll take care of the rest.
- But I don't think...
- That's good. Don't think.
Jeanette, come stand
over here next to Toby.
Let's see
what we've got here.
Sure. Sure. They jive together
like ham and beans.
- What do you think?
- Hold on, Colonel.
Yes, sir, we may
have something here,
if we work it right.
- Right, Sam?
- I think it's
a great idea, Colonel.
Now, you listen to me, Toby.
Let's get this straight.
We're gonna make
a rosinback rider out of you.
It won't be easy, but by
the Eternal, that's exactly
what's gonna happen.
But, sir, I gotta work
for Mr. Tupper.
- We've got
a gentleman's agreement.
- I'll take care of Tupper.
All right,
start first thing tomorrow.
We'll be in Waterford
in two weeks.
I want this boy riding by then.
Now, take over.
- He's all yours.
- But, Colonel, two weeks.
Well, I gotta be going.
I'll zee you later.
- I'll see you now.
- You heard the colonel.
He's all ours.
Sure.
Well, it just
isn't fair, Colonel.
Toby Tyler is the best boy
I ever had. You can't
take him away from me.
Will you stop whimpering
and get out of here?
- Find yourself another boy.
- I don't want another boy.
Customers like him.
He brings in tips.
- I mean, money.
- Listen, Tupper, if you...
Now, Colonel,
don't you go boiling up.
I know you're a hard man.
People say a lot
of things about you.
But I never heard
no one say that you
weren't fair and honest.
Now, don't you try
to bear-grease me.
Well, it... It's just that I
feel responsible for that boy.
He's liable to get hurt
around them horses.
Ben'll take good care of him.
You know that.
Yeah. Well, it just don't
rest easy on my conscience.
Just how much do you think
it would take to soothe
that conscience of yours down?
Well, I don't like to put it
in terms of money.
But how about
40 dollars a week?
I think of the going rate on
your conscience lower than that.
- Let's make it ten.
- How does 30 sound to you?
- It sounds like 15.
- Uh, Colonel, uh...
I want to help you.
I'll tell you what.
No, Mr. Tupper.
I'll tell you what I'll do.
I'll give you 20 dollars
a week finder's fee.
If you say another word...
That's a fair proposition.
I'll just draw up
a piece of paper.
- What?
- A gentlemen's agreement.
If you and I can't trust
one another, what kind
of world would this be?
- Get out of here!
- Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
- Ben?
- Yeah?
- You ever tell a lie?
- Same as anyone else.
Finally gave it up, though.
Too much trouble.
Any lamebrain
can lie himself into something.
Then there's all that trouble
of working yourself
back out of it.
It's not worth it.
Ben, I told one of those lies.
- You don't say.
- I can't ride.
Not hardly at all.
I know it.
- When you figure on leavin'?
- How'd you know?
Ought to be a pretty good
pile of coins in that pouch now.
I surmise you can buy a ticket
home and have money left over
to give your Uncle Daniel.
Would you look after Mr. Stubbs?
He don't know I'm going.
He won't starve.
I'll come back someday
and buy him from Col. Castle.
Sure. Why don't you
get some sleep?
Ben?
Next to Mr. Stubbs, you and Sam
are the best friends I got.
I'll sure hate to say goodbye.
Don't get all wrought-up.
A few weeks, you'll forget
what I look like.
I'll never forget you, Ben.
Go to sleep.
A dee da da dum
Dum duh dee da da dum
Duh duh dee da
Da dee da dum
Da da da dee da
Da dee da dee
Da dee da da dee da
Da dee dum dum
Toby.
Better get up.
You've got a big day
ahead of you.
Yes, sir.
Mr. Stubbs.
My money. Where is it?
Where's my money?
What'd you do with it?
- Tell me!
- [screeching]
Tell me!
Tell me, Mr. Stubbs!
What'd you do with my money?
Tell me!
Tell me, Mr. Stubbs, tell me!
- What's the trouble?
- Ben, Mr. Stubbs
threw my money away.
And I looked
all over for it.
Why, the ornery,
thieving little chimp.
Why'd you do it, Mr. Stubbs?
- Take it easy, Toby.
- That's what I get
for making a friend out of him.
Colonel Castle said
he was your responsibility.
You took him on, didn't you?
Nobody made you do it.
- No.
- Then don't go
blaming the chimp.
But, Ben, all my money,
my savings, it's gone.
You think money
is your only problem?
Ha! That's easy.
Here. Take what I've got.
There's enough to get you home
and some left over.
Go on. Take it and
get out of here before
you get in any deeper.
You mean you don't
want to run away?
You want to go on taking care
of this ungrateful little chimp?
You want to go in the ring and
work off some of that trouble
you've lied yourself into?
All right.
See you're in that ring
at 11:00 sharp this morning.
And don't think
it's gonna be fun.
[Ben] That's a great trick,
but let's learn to stand first.
Get back. Back.
No, no. You go the same
direction as the horse.
Keep a leg on each side
and your mind in the middle.
Keep your body limber.
That's right.
Steady.
Hup, up, up.
Carry your weight low.
Now, feel his motion
through your feet.
Go with it.
Don't fight it.
Whoa!
On your knees now.
Stand up. Stand up!
Whoa.
- [screaming]
- [Ben] Wait for the horse.
Hang on.
No, you're supposed to ride him,
not kiss him.
No, no, no.
Let go of his ears.
Whoa.
Stand up.
- Hang on.
- It's no use. I can't do it.
- That's just what Ajax said.
- He did, did he?
He said you'd put your tail
between your legs and quit.
- Oh, yeah? I'll show him.
- Now let go of the rope.
Let go.
That's better.
It's not good, but it's better.
Get off that horse now.
Get off.
- Now get ready
for the fork jump.
- Now?
Yeah, now. And this time,
watch your timing.
Get ready. Set.
Go.
[grunting]
I missed.
It's not bad for a beginning.
We'll work on
the stand-ups after lunch.
Olie Madden.
Madame Tenzinne.
Two for you.
Greta Nielson.
Toby Tyler.
- Harris Tilford.
- Toby's busy now.
I'll take that for him.
Frank Vernon.
Harry Birch.
Rufus Rakin.
"Dear Toby,
We've had a very bad time.
I'm afraid your Uncle Daniel
is not well.
Without your help,
the work around the farm
is just too much for him.
- We need you, Toby..."
- [Toby] Mr. Tupper!
- You dropped something.
- Yes. Thank you. Thank you.
Well, uh, how's
our star performer getting on?
Awful, but Ben says
to come back after lunch.
My boy, I have
complete faith in you.
And just to prove
Harry Tupper is not just
sounding off his bazoo,
look what I have for you.
The best secondhand
riding shoes money can buy.
Now, I ask you, is Mr. Tupper
your friend, or is he?
- Well...
- There's no need
to thank me, boy.
You forget your chores here.
Run along and meet
your friend, Mr. Stubbs.
- Mr. Tupper?
- Mmm?
I don't know how to say this,
but I want to take back some of
the things I thought about you.
Yes. Well, there's no need
to mention it.
I'll admit I'm not the most
patient man in the world.
But it's how we behave
when the chips are down
that really counts.
Am I right?
[humming]
[Toby] Ben?
Think I could tell
my aunt and uncle I'm
gonna be a bareback rider?
I don't see why not.
Think I'll ever
ride real good?
Well, you ain't
no Pawnee Bill,
but by the time we open,
you will look professional,
or my name
ain't Benjamin Obadiah Cotter.
Ben? How do you spell "uncle"?
Uncle?
Well, now... that depends.
In some parts you spell it
one way, other parts
spell it the other.
What part are we in?
It's not the spellin'
of a letter that's important.
It's what you say in it.
Now, did you tell the folks
you missed them?
- Not exactly.
- Well, then, did you
say you love them?
Folks put an awful lot of store
in things like that.
I love you very much.
Cordially...
Ben, how do you spell
"cordially"?
Why don't you just sign it
"Your friend, Toby Tyler,"
and stop bothering me.
[audience applauding]
You'd be scared too,
if you had to go out
in front of all those people.
Well, how are we
getting along?
It doesn't seem
to fit too well.
[with accent] Let's see.
Let's see can we do something
about that there.
Stay right there
for a minute. Let's see.
If we take up the slack
in the back here,
I think maybe that the front...
The front would be, uh...
The front is...
Turn around this way once,
because across here...
Ooh, ooh,
If we did a sleeve,
und this doesn't look too...
- It's awful, isn't it?
- I think so.
I don't think
even magic could help it.
There's all kinds
of magic, you know.
The magic where you got the hat
and you take the rabbit...
But this is no good for...
Oh, ho, ho.
I got the magic.
I got the right kind of magic.
Close the eyes.
Und keep them closed tight.
Now, then,
how does it go again?
Oh, yes. "Needles and pins,
needles and pins.
When you presto the change-o,
the magic commences."
Open the eyes.
- Surprise.
- [all] Good luck, Toby.
Monsieur Toby, in a few moments
you will make your debut
as a featured performer
in Colonel Castle's
Great American Circus.
- But I...
- Shh. And we,
your fellow performers,
not wishing to see
the luster of this occasion
dimmed in any way,
- from a sartorial
point of view...
- What?
Or as Papa Schultz might say,
"When you go in front
of the people,
you should never wear
this ridiculous, awful...
the baggy pants...
- You shouldn't do it."
- [all chuckling]
- Good luck, Toby.
- Thanks.
Here's the rest of it, Toby.
You have just about
three minutes to get dressed,
Monsieur Toby.
[ band plays The Blue Danube]
Mr. Stubbs,
have you seen my shoes?
Good night. I left them over
at the lemonade stand.
- Where's Toby?
- Still dressing, I guess.
Mr. Stubbs,
how'd you get loose?
Toby?
No, Mr. Stubbs!
"Master Toby Tyler"?
They're all for me.
They're from Aunt Olive.
Mr. Stubbs,
they did write!
What the devil
are you doing here?
- Look, Ben, they did write.
- You haven't got time now.
Hurry.
I'll take care of the chimp.
[drumroll]
Now, ladies and gentlemen,
we present
for your kind approval
those daring young equestrians,
Mademoiselle Jeanette
and Monsieur Toby.
- Jeanette and Toby.
- [applause]
Candy, ice-cold lemonade.
It's pink, it's cold,
it's refreshing...
I...
Peanuts! Fresh-roasted!
Lemonade. Here we are.
It's pink, cold, refreshing.
It's ice-cold... lemonade...
It's made...
Peanuts! Fresh-roasted!
[crowd cheering]
- Toby, you rode like a champ.
- You were just great.
Excuse me.
I got to read my letters.
[laughing]
[Olive's voice]
We miss you so much, Toby,
and wonder why you don't
answer our letters.
Your Uncle Daniel is not well.
He has taken over the chores
you used to do,
and, with the rest of the work,
it's too much for him.
They want me to come home,
Mr. Stubbs. They need me.
I've got to go
before they try and stop me.
[fanfare]
I can't take you with me,
you know, Mr. Stubbs.
You don't belong to me.
They'd say I stole you.
- You understand, don't you?
- Mm-hmm.
I'll come back
and get you someday.
Honest I will.
Toby?
Toby!
"Dear Ben and Sam,
I'm sorry to tell you this,
but I am leaving the circus..."
That ungrateful little whelp.
After all I've done for him.
Good morning, gentlemen.
You got a phone?
Operator, get me the sheriff
over to Bartonsville.
Yeah, it's important.
Sheriff?
This is Harry Tupper,
representing Castle's
Great American Circus.
Yeah. I want you to keep
your eye open for a small boy,
about 11 years old.
Calls himself Toby Tyler.
I figure he's going
in your direction.
He ran away from the circus.
Took along a valuable animal
belonging to Colonel Castle,
a chimpanzee.
Thanks, Sheriff.
Say, Sheriff,
you find the boy, we'll be glad
to express our appreciation.
Know what I mean?
All right.
Say, I don't suppose either
of you have glimpsed the lad.
No.
- Oh, a hunter, eh?
- Mm-hmm.
I suppose you know these parts
around here pretty well.
- Some.
- Tell you what.
You find that boy,
and there's a reward of, say,
ten dollars in it for you.
Sorry, I'm not much
on tracking small boys.
Bobcat's about
fearsome enough for me.
Yeah. Suit yourself.
Mr. Stubbs!
What are you doing here?
They'll be after me
for sure now, Mr. Stubbs.
You know I'm glad
to see you, but, gosh.
Oh, vell,
as Papa Schultz vould say,
"Here ve is,
und vhere ve is,
is further away
than vhere ve vas,
next to vhere
ve're gonna be."
Zo, I take you home,
und we write Colonel Castle
where you is.
Don't get your feet wet,
Mr. Stubbs.
Oh, biddle-dee-dee
and a biddle-dee oh
[humming]
And I don't know where
[whistling]
- [humming]
- [squealing]
[humming]
[Mr. Stubbs jabbers]
- [footsteps]
- [whispering]
Quiet, Mr. Stubbs.
Shh.
We'll cut across this way.
You raising something, Jasper?
- [dog barking]
- [squealing]
Mr. Stubbs!
- [dog barking]
- [Mr. Stubbs chattering]
[dog barking]
[screeching]
- [dog barking]
- Mr. Stubbs!
Mr. Stubbs!
- [dog barking]
- [screeching]
[screeching]
[gunshot]
[crying] Mr. Stubbs.
Oh, Mr. Stubbs.
Mr. Stubbs,
please don't leave me.
Don't leave me.
[crying]
You did it.
You shot him. Why?
I thought it was
something else.
You killed him.
You're a murderer.
I'm sorry.
Believe me, I'm sorry.
Get away from us.
[crying]
What's this?
What? Huh?
Oh, Mr. Stubbs.
Don't leave me, Mr. Stubbs.
Well, now, Toby, that's too bad.
That's really too bad.
You see, Toby.
If you hadn't run away,
this wouldn't have happened.
It's your fault.
- My fault?
- Surely you see that.
Mr. Stubbs would be alive
and well if you hadn't run off.
- Come on. Let's go back.
- I want Mr. Stubbs.
Now, look!
Now, look, Toby.
Mr. Stubbs is dead.
And there's nothing you can do
to change that. So, come on.
Maybe the colonel
will give you another pet.
- No! I won't leave him.
- Come on.
It wasn't the boy's fault.
It was mine.
It's all right.
Accidents will happen.
The important thing is
we found the lad safe and sound.
Hey! Hey, wait a minute!
Wait!
Wait a minute.
I'll tell him! Stop!
Colonel Castle, I ran away,
and Mr. Stubbs followed me.
I didn't want it to happen.
Honest I didn't.
Toby... Toby, there is
someone here to see you.
[Olive] Toby.
Toby, will you
forgive me?
You lily-livered skunk.
I found out what you did
with Toby's letters.
Now, Ben, I...
I didn't want to upset the lad.
Tampering with the mails.
That calls for a jail sentence.
Just a little tamper.
I'm gonna make you one of
those gentlemen's agreements
you're fond of.
Fine, fine. I'd like that
just fine. Anything you say.
I want you to give up
that share of Toby's money
you've been getting.
Ben, let's talk this over.
You don't know
what you're saying.
I want you to stay away
from that boy.
Yes. Absolutely, yes.
And I want you to behave
real nice and pretty.
Depend on it. Oh, yes, sir.
Because if you don't,
I'm liable to do
something like this.
Yes, Ben, yes.
No, Ben, no!
- Happy to see you back, Toby.
- Thank you.
Hi. Looks like a full house
tonight. Do your best now.
- I'll sure try.
- Good.
You've made a lot
of good friends, Toby.
I just wish you
could've met Mr. Stubbs.
Colonel Castle
told us about him.
This was his wagon.
He was my best friend.
Well, I see you're showing
the folks around, eh, Toby?
- Uh-huh.
- Would you do me a big favor
and go and tell Sam Treat to
meet me behind the stock tent?
Sure.
Come on.
Sam!
What are you doing here?
Mr. Stubbs!
Oh, Mr. Stubbs.
Is he all right?
Bullet only ventilated
his hide a little.
Mr. Stubbs.
Mr. Stubbs. Mr. Stubbs.
[whistle blowing]
Popcorn,
candied... apples...
- Peanuts?
- Yes, sir.
Peanuts, popcorn,
candied apples.
And now, may I direct
your attention
to a feat of horsemanship
and balance
seldom witnessed
in the sawdust ring.
Ladies and gentlemen,
- Monsieur Toby.
- [applause]
[band plays fanfare]
[applause]
[Toby] Whoa!
[audience laughing]
[laughing continues]
[cheering, applause]
Ice-cold lemonade here.
It's pink, it's cold,
it's refreshing.
[audience laughing]
That little boy.
Isn't he wonderful?
[both] He's our boy.
[cheering, applause]
- Ben.
- Colonel, I'm sorry about this.
This is the greatest yet.
Why didn't you tell me?
- I didn't know.
- Congratulations, Ben.
Congratulations.
We'll bill him
as "Monsieur Stubbs."
[applause]
- [fanfare]
- [cheering]
Peanuts, popcorn, lemonade.
It's pink,
it's refreshing...
It's cold.
Obradio CamaroZ28