- Destination, monsieur?
- Monte Carlo.
Uh, rue, uh, de "boisie-arie."
Au rue Dubec,
a droite a place
"dee-l-eena."
Will you give it to me
in English?
Sure. We're lost.
Thanks.
Hey!
- Herbie!
- What's he doing?
I think he's getting us un-lost.
Hi, there. Say, uh,
we're looking for the
Trans France Race Exposition.
Oui, straight ahead
on your right.
You can't miss it.
- That's going to be some race.
- Yeah.
Well, you're looking
at the winner right here!
This car? The winner?
- He didn't.
- He did.
All of this
for the museum payroll?
The most magnificent
diamond in the world!
L'etoile de Joie!
Could we have just
a little peek?
On this very afternoon,
at 1:00, precisely,
you and all of Paris will be
able to take the peek!
Now, fresh from his triumphs
on the European
racing circuit,
Bruno Von Stickle...
Who'll be driving
his laser 917 GTE coupe.
Here we have
a magnificent Pantera...
Ah, I see the American entry is
just arriving, Mr. Jim Douglas.
Mr. Douglas will be driving a...
A-a...
Mr. Douglas will be driving
a most unusual entry.
Something funny
must've happened.
Uh-huh. Us.
How about giving Jim Douglas
and his partner,
Wheely Applegate...
A nice, warm welcome, huh?
Eh, this little car of yours
is the toast of America.
When was your last win?
Uh... 12 years ago.
That was only because,
uh, that was our last race.
Yeah.
Yes, this race... We're kind of
staging a comeback here,
and so it's very
important to us.
I-I mean, we won't
be coming back very far
unless we qualify, will we?
Qualify? Are you kiddin'?
Don't let his modesty
or this little car coming out
of retirement fool ya!
There isn't a finer-tuned,
cleaner engine anywhere!
I'm sure it
should be easy to keep clean.
All you have to do is
drop it in the washing machine
along with your socks.
Appreciate your humor,
but just don't
you worry about
this little washing
machine... Car!
It's a real jewel!
But Monsieur Ribeaux,
isn't it too much
responsibility...
- For one man?
- One man?
One man and the finest
security system
that can be devised.
All in the computer.
Now, this alone
will keep the diamonds safe
from the grasp of a thief.
But, monsieur, one would
only have to reach in and...
The pillow is sensitive
to the heat of the hand
when it gets close
to the diamond.
I'm sorry, monsieur.
What does that do?
I'm engaging a system
of electric eye beams
that surrounds the pedestal.
One last precaution,
gentlemen.
Would you please
step out of the room?
Now the entire floor
is a trap!
The mere ashes from a cigar
would activate the alarm.
Right on schedule.
Only ten steps
to six million dollars.
One step to Devil's Island if
anything touches that floor.
Pardon, Monsieur Ribeaux,
but you forgot to give me the
computer and the numbers.
I did not forget!
They were put in my trust
and will remain with me.
One does not part with
the only copy in existence!
Patience, Quincey.
Electronics is the answer.
This notebook is our passport
to the future.
I think I shall put my trust
in this bit of rope.
When the man has it
all worked out for us,
silly not to use it.
You had to bring
the whole kit, didn't you?
I was just checking
for the radar beam.
It's there.
Now it isn't.
Some chunk of rock, eh?
One could spend a lifetime
without setting eyes
on a rock like that.
You'll love getting your hands on it.
Ah!
Patience, Quincey.
Pillow's the trap.
One more set of numbers.
Why can't a man write
an "o" that looks like an "o"?
Or is it a "9"?
Can't take a chance.
I don't trust nobody.
I'm glad I come prepared.
The old ways are still
the best ways.
We've got six minutes
before the guard checks.
Get on with it!
Aren't you ever gonna
get that thing fixed?
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry. I...
- Excuse me! Oh, I just, eh...
- Oh.
Jim!
A word to the wise.
Paris may be the land of love,
but it can also be the land
of heartbreak.
I'll tell you what I'll do.
I'll make a deal with you.
I'm willing to resist
the girls, if you are.
- Well, that's some sacrifice.
- I know.
But I'm willing to make it.
You're made of
strong stuff, Wheely.
Patience, patience, Quincey.
You tell
that to the guard.
He'll be here in two minutes.
Give me that!
Well, we're comin' into this
big right hand sweeper, see.
Dropped him into third gear
and really jumped on it.
Took three cars.
Then back into fourth,
and we were flyin'!
Tach-in'
seven or eight thousand.
We blew off the lead car
100 yards from the finish line.
Won it going away.
How about that?
Hmm?
Je ne comprens pas,
parlez anglais.
I didn't understand
what he was saying.
That's okay.
He didn't understand
what you were saying either.
Come to think of it,
I don't think I understood
what you were saying.
There's no more time.
That guard's practically
in the door.
You want that stone,
don't ya?
Yeah, and there's
only one way to get it.
It's not possible.
Attention!
Attention, everyone,
attention!
Nobody is to leave the area.
I repeat.
- Nobody is to leave the area.
- We still have to qualify!
Come on!
- What's the trouble?
- I-I don't know!
Ladies and gentlemen,
there has been a theft
in the museum.
Everyone will be searched
before leaving the area.
I repeat.
Nobody is to leave the area
until they have been searched.
Here, mate,
there's no point in us both
getting caught, is there?
No point in either of us
getting caught.
I repeat.
Nobody is to leave the area.
Nobody is to leave the area
until he has been searched.
We'll never see it again!
That little car there?
Indeed you can.
It will be in a showroom
on the Champs-Elysées
at 4:30 this afternoon.
Yes, yes, yes.
But are you sure all
the security precautions
had been taken?
I've searched my memory.
Could I have forgotten
something?
Inspector, some residue
from a footprint.
I might have overlooked it,
but I seemed to hear
your voice calling out,
"Fontenoy, remember,
no clue is too small!"
Did you also hear me saying,
"Take it to lab and get it
analyzed, Fontenoy?"
Yes, sir, and I'm doing just that.
No!
No, I couldn't have
forgotten anything.
I am as sure
the security was on yesterday
as I am sure it's off today!
Fontenoy!
Attention, please.
The qualifying rounds
will begin in eight minutes.
- Douglas and Applegate.
- Douglas.
Ah, yes, Monsieur Douglas.
You're in the heat
after this one.
- Good luck.
- Thank you.
That's the same heat
I'm in, Douglas.
And you're going to need
more than luck.
You're going to need wings.
Oh, yeah? Well, you may be
in for a little surprise.
I can see your surprise.
It is very little.
Attention...
Look for an even
bigger surprise
when the race starts.
There
will be qualifying
today and tomorrow,
with the top 16 times running
in the Trans France race.
You are not in this heat!
Come back!
Say, Herbie,
where you going?
Herbie, you could
get us disqualified!
He could get us killed!
- What was that?
- I don't know!
Forget the music!
Whoa!
He's out of his mind.
He's out of his mind, all right.
Over that luscious
little Lancia.
What is...
I'm telling you, Paris
and women have got him.
I'm gonna have to warn him
the same way I did you.
Like father, like car.
What are you doing?
- Now, wait a minute, buddy...
- What do you mean, "buddy"?
- Uh, Miss Buddy.
- You... You...
Yeah, Jim Douglas.
And I'm very sorry.
You think...
That because
I'm a woman driver,
you can get away
with anything you please!
Well, I'm not a pigeon
for your fun and games.
I've had it with you clowns!
No, I'm not the clown.
Believe me, it was Herbie.
Oh, yes, you're blaming
your dizzy mechanic.
No, no, it's...
Herbie's the car,
and he's kinda like a person.
He's... now, I know
that sounds funny.
Crazy, is more like it!
Well, what were you doing
out there, Douglas?
Well, it's kinda hard
to explain, sir...
Not for me, it isn't.
He doesn't want a woman
in the race.
Look, Miss Darcy, you'll be given
another chance to qualify.
We're terribly sorry.
You're sorry, he's sorry,
everybody's sorry.
But I didn't qualify!
Attention,
Antonio Vittoro.
If you wish to qualify,
Mr. Douglas,
you have exactly 10 minutes.
Hear that, Herbie?
You forget that powder puff
and get your mind on racing!
You better believe it!
Gilbert.
We're going to cook that
chicken, European-style.
When he sticks out his neck,
- we will chop it off.
- Uh-huh. Oui, oui!
Jawohl, jawohl.
We'll see whose neck
gets chopped off.
Right, Herbie?
Attention,
attention, attention!
You better close
your mouth, turkey,
'cause you're gonna
get our tire marks
right across your teeth!
- Where'd they go?
- I really got snookered.
I'm even rustier than I thought.
Hey! Herbie,
what are you doing?
It's her again!
Oh, no!
Well, it took a crowd to do it.
But at least we lost
the Lancia.
And not to mention the
first qualifying round.
Did you get a hold
of Double X?
He wasn't very happy.
Who is? Where is
that stupid little car?
Patience, patience...
Oh, excuse me, sir.
There are impressive
racing cars here,
but I don't seem
to see the little Volkswagen.
Ah, you mean the Douglas car.
It will be here.
Patience, my friend, patience.
One more person says
"patience" to me, I'll...
We better have it now,
because if we don't turn up
with that diamond,
Double X is going to mark
the spot where we're buried.
Here, here. Don't dig
our graves just yet.
Come on, let's grab it.
- Don't tell me, "patience"!
- In front of 100 witnesses?
We need a plan.
Attention, everyone.
Attention.
We would like to show a film
of the route
the racing cars will take
when they leave Paris.
If someone
will catch the lights
while I draw the drapes...
I think the gentleman
just gave us a plan.
The fine machines you have seen here
will be among those
testing the grueling route,
stretching through
our fair city,
twisting through
the French Alps...
Back up slowly, as if
nothing was the matter.
In the city, the cars will
be able to pick up speed...
As they race along
the French countryside.
...only by the challenge
that becomes evident...
As we approach
the famous French Alps.
It's not here, max.
The car's just not here.
...will test the endurance...
Of even the sturdiest of cars.
Perhaps we're backing
in the wrong direction.
Just keep backing up.
There remains the final dash
for Monte Carlo.
And for someone,
victory is just a step away.
- Herbie! Excuse me.
- You mean, no Herbie.
Garcon! Garcon!
Garcon!
Excusez moi!
Oui.
- Etes-vous, cuckoo?
- Oui. Cuckoo.
My car. My car!
Has anybody seen my car?
- Oh, that was your car?
- Yes, yes. It's gone!
- Yes, it's gone.
- Did you see who took it?
Not exactly, mademoiselle.
Excuse me,
I hate to bother you...
You! I should have
known I'd see you.
You and trouble go together.
Yeah, okay.
Look, we've lost our car...
And I'd just like
to know if you'd seen it,
by any chance.
Who cares about
your silly Volkswagen?
My Lancia has been stolen!
- Stolen?
- Uh, uh, your car?
- And your car.
- Yeah.
- I saw them both.
- Then you saw who stole them!
You would not believe this.
I would not believe this.
- No one would believe this.
- What?
I think they steal each other.
Come on.
Taxi!
Cuckoo.
Cuckoo! Cuckoo! Coo!
Talk about
a needle in a haystack.
How are we gonna find 'em?
I don't know.
Just keep looking.
My life is riding on that car.
Lady, I got a few things
to prove myself.
Where would you
take a boyfriend
on first night to Paris?
"Boyfriend"?
Don't tell me this is your
cute way of making a pass.
If I had romance in mind,
would he be along?
Right.
- It's Herbie.
- Herbie. I don't believe this.
Well, it's true!
There's something
about that car.
He's got a... He...
Well, we've been through
a lot together.
Yeah, well, nothing like this.
Hey! Regardons! Regarde!
...Bateaux-Mouches.
Do you think this is
something to laugh about?
Forgive me, mademoiselle.
I laugh at the radio.
Two automobiles,
they take a ride
on the Bateaux-Mouches.
Would you
believe such a thing?
Bateaux-Mouches?
Take a left at that bridge!
Maybe I can explain this
over dinner tonight.
Maybe not.
I don't know, Herbie.
12 years is a long time.
Hope we can handle it.
Hope I can handle it.
- Well, all taken care of, Jim.
- Yeah?
Had a little talk with Herbie.
Had to straighten him out.
I don't mind havin'
a car that's got a heart,
but I will not tolerate
a car falling in love
with another car.
What did you expect him
to fall in love with,
the Goodyear blimp?
The Goodyear...
Yeah.
Anyway, I said, "Listen Herbie,
"we're here
for one thing only.
"And that's to make the
biggest comeback
"in racing history.
"So, no women in training camp.
"Just forget that little chick.
"And you can do it.
"Just a matter of mind
over metal."
- You expecting company?
- No.
Detective Fontenoy here.
And this is the famous
Inspector Bouchet.
I'm Jim Douglas
and this is my partner
Wheely Applegate.
Look, if there's a problem
about our car cruisin'
on the Bateaux-Mouches...
Bateaux-Mouches? Eh, no, no.
It's about the
six million dollar diamond
stolen this morning.
Perhaps the most beautiful
diamond in all the world.
Fontenoy.
No?
We are questioning everyone
who was in the area
at the time.
Perhaps you can help us.
Pushing the car won't help me
get the cap off.
- Must've rolled.
- Well, pull the hand brake on.
Door's locked.
The window!
Put your hand
through the window!
Ooh!
Aah.
Let me get at it!
I'm gonna hotwire this car.
We'll get the diamond
at the garage.
Right.
Well, I'm not waiting.
Car, it's either you... Or me!
Oof!
I suppose
you're going to tell me
that car started up
and drove away by itself.
No, and I'm not going
to tell Double X that either.
What's happening?
There's seven cars ahead of us
and we're in last place.
That's what's happening!
- Darcy.
- Oui. Qualifying today?
I hope so.
New Herbie?
He's not even an old Herbie.
He's not any Herbie at all!
My whole lecture must've
fallen on a deaf carburetor.
He doesn't need a lecture.
He needs an old-age pension.
You listen to me, Herbie,
and you listen good.
You and I didn't come
out of moth balls
to be the laughingstock
of the continent.
Either get the lead out
of your pants right now,
or I'm going to ship you
back to the states,
have you stuffed
and hung on a wall
in Retirement Village!
Ah!
Ooh! Now you're talking.
We got the old Herbie back!
The old Herbie and the
new Herbie, rolled into one!
I'm telling you,
it's the old Herbie,
and he's doing it for us!
He's not doing it for us.
He's doing it for her.
Okay, so he did it for her.
I never saw anything like that.
- Congratulations, you did it!
- Thank you, thank you!
- Somebody did it.
- Who cares, Wheely?
It's, "Hello, comeback!"
In record time for this track.
You shattered
Von Stickle's mark.
Congratulations, Douglas.
You have just won the right
to taste my dust tomorrow.
And mine, Douglas.
Today, you break my record.
Tomorrow, I will turn
your "Hello, comeback"
into "Goodbye forever."
Auf wiedersehen.
Couple of
charm school dropouts.
Yeah.
Well, one showboat
deserves another.
I'll go get him.
Félicitations!
Absolutely amazing!
I knew I had a good car
under me, but...
The exact same time
as the Douglas car.
- A track record!
- What?
- Congratulations!
- Thank you.
Oh, thank you for staying
off the track.
It's one way
I can prove what I can do.
Well, it wasn't exactly you.
You've got a real problem
about women in racing,
Mr. Douglas.
What is it? We drive too slow...
Or too fast?
Oh, I didn't mean that.
It's not you at all,
it's your car.
And my car.
Excuse me, I don't want
to hear about your car.
No, I have to tell you this.
I know it's gonna be hard
to believe, but...
You see,
Herbie's not just a car.
I didn't believe it myself
at first,
but the little guy
has actually got a...
He's...
When a car like Herbie
comes to Paris,
he meets a beautiful Lancia,
that is also a car like Herbie,
with a, with a...
You know, it's natural
that they're gonna fall in...
You're right.
I wouldn't believe it either.
When the men come by
from the booby hatch,
go quietly.
Just trying to warn you
about your car.
Let me warn you about me.
I'm in this race to win,
and frankly, I'd like to see...
You and your car
disappear entirely.
Oh.
Quincey.
Pull over! We want that car!
What are you going to do?
I'm gonna pull over.
Hang on!
Ohh.
Darkness is about
to fall upon you.
Amazing!
Whoa!
Hot, hot, hot!
You...
They're still comin'!
I think they are
trying to kill us!
Mon dieu! Mon dieu!
I never
thought she'd go that far
to make us disappear.
Who's that?
That cute little
time bomb, Diane.
She set us up to knock us
out of the race,
just like she said.
Now, wait a minute.
She didn't say that.
Oh, of course not.
They never say what they mean.
That's what makes
the female of the species
deadlier than the male.
You read that someplace.
Yes, and I've got a mother,
three sisters
and two ex-wives to prove it.
They never told me
they wanted me out,
but every time I came home,
the lock was changed.
I don't take that kind of
strong-arm stuff
from anybody, male or female!
Then somebody better teach
this female
the rules of the game...
Before the game is over.
If she doesn't know 'em now,
she will when
I get through with her!
You might as well
settle back, Herbie.
Once Jim gets started,
nothin' can stop him.
Who hired thugs?
I'm just as good as anybody
out there on that track!
And I don't need anybody
to win my races for me!
We...
That is the trouble
with you, all of you!
You don't think
a woman can do anything!
Yeah, I know he seems
like a quiet sort of guy,
but when a fight
is inevitable, he never ducks.
"Women are
supposed to be nurses
"and secretaries
and school teachers!"
I've taken that all my life.
I took it from my mother
and my father!
And my aunts and my uncles!
But I'm not going
to take it from you!
When old Jim gets started,
I hate to get in his way.
He's a regular steamroller.
- Whoa!
- Coward!
I'm a race driver
and I can win it on my own!
Oh!
You know, I think you can.
Double X?
Uh, yeah.
I'm afraid we-we-we've
had another complication.
I'm beginning to think
you are the complication.
That...
That item should have been
in my hands by now!
Oh, don't worry, sir.
It's still in the gas tank.
Then bring me the gas tank!
What are you waiting for?
We've lost them again, sir.
We don't know where they are.
Excuse me. I'm looking
for Inspector Bouchet.
Oui, monsieur.
Impossible!
Are you trying to tell me
a couple of
simpleminded Americans...
Ah...
- Disappeared?
- Hold on.
Hope we're not
disturbing you, Inspector.
No, gentlemen!
Your timing could not
be more perfect.
Good.
I want to thank you for
your continued cooperation...
In this matter
of the stolen diamond.
Tonight, we're asking
for your help.
Somebody's out
to get our car!
Ah, that's impossible.
I think they're trying
to knock us out of the race!
Ahh!
I was wondering if there's
some way, I don't know,
we can put the car
in protective custody
for the night.
That is, if you're not too busy
trying to find that diamond.
No, no!
One is just as important
as the other, I assure you.
I'll only be a moment. Uh...
Oh! I-I mean, uh...
- We'll wait in the car.
- Good idea.
We wouldn't want anything
to happen to it.
Not now.
Hello.
The car is here.
Never mind how...
Never mind how.
No, no!
It's too risky for me.
I will see to it that the car
will be at number 32,
Avenue Mozart
within the hour.
Don't get lost on the way!
Your worry is now my worry,
gentlemen. Rest easily.
I'll take personal charge
of this valuable possession.
- Inspector!
- What is it, Fontenoy?
Off duty or not, sir,
I couldn't sleep,
thinking about the diamond...
And how it would
be weighing on your mind.
At the moment, Fontenoy,
I have a car
weighing on my mind.
Somebody's trying to knock
us out of the race.
Well, with your excellent time
in the trials,
it would not take a master
of deduction
like Inspector Bouchet...
To see that you have
an excellent chance to win!
Which is why I personally
will ensure
the safety
of this automobile.
Now, put your minds at ease.
Get a good night's sleep.
Thank you! You too, Herbie.
A big day tomorrow, pal.
- Good night.
- No, no. Permit me, sir.
- What do you mean?
You have enough responsibility
trying to find the diamond.
- I'll look after the car.
- Don't be ridiculous!
Aah, aah!
What are you doing?
Anything for you
and the force.
Get out of the car!
Leave it to me, sir.
I'll keep this little car
hidden so no one will find it.
Fontenoy...
My best man.
Huh.
- Good night.
My very best.
We've checked that, sir.
It's nowhere.
We've covered the whole city.
Now what?
In the morning,
before the race,
that ridiculous little car
will get gasoline.
When it does,
you'll be there.
Welcome, everyone,
to the inaugural running
of the Trans France race.
They're all here:
qualifying drivers and cars
from the world over,
each looking forward,
expectantly,
for the chance
at the magnificent trophy...
And the $20,000
winner-take-all prize.
This promises to be one of
the most punishing races ever.
And these drivers know it.
They've no doubt gone
through these cars,
time after time after time.
And yet, we have them all here,
still refining
and tuning car after car,
each preparing
for the gruelling race...
That will test the endurance
of man and machine.
I just wish I had
a machine to test.
I hope, uh, what's-his-name
didn't hide Herbie so well,
he can't find him.
I wish you hadn't said that.
I mean, I'm a mechanic.
And a mechanic is nothing
without his car.
A million and one details
have to be taken care of
for a race.
You know me, how I pride
myself on being thorough.
My tools!
Where's my tools!
Right here.
- I knew that.
- Uh-huh.
Inspector, the race is about
to begin! Where's our car?
Believe me,
I am as concerned as you are!
But I'm sure Fontenoy
will be here.
He's unpredictable,
but he's dependable.
What?
Let me check
headquarters again.
He'll be here.
You be ready.
Who's that?
He's Double X, you dummy.
Uh-oh, better duck.
Here comes trouble.
Hello.
- Uh, look, about last night.
- I know. Me too.
Sorry.
Not about missing me
with that vase, I hope.
No, no.
I guess I was
a little uptight last night.
Nervous about the race.
Yeah, yeah. Well, I threw a few
brick bats myself.
In the wrong direction.
We didn't get off to
a flying start, did we?
Herbie and I take a little
getting used to.
When you keep
including Herbie like that,
you take a lot
of getting used to.
By the way, where is... it?
- Well, I...
- Douglas,
did you misplace
your little car?
Just temporarily.
You should look under a rock
or two. You might find it.
No, not under a rock, Gilbert.
Under a gravestone.
Attention, everyone.
All drivers, bring your
machines to the grid.
Five minutes 'til race time.
It's just as well, Douglas.
You know the saying,
"They never come back."
- Well, I better go.
- Diane!
Good luck.
I think you mean that.
Drivers will please take
your position...
As quickly as possible.
- Well, take the brake off!
- The brake is off!
You know somethin'?
That Lancia's waiting
on Herbie.
Well, so are we, and all we
need is her hanging around.
All right! Push it, push it!
- No, mademoiselle!
- Listen, I...
I hope you had nothing
to do with this.
I didn't, but I think
I can tell you who did.
I know, it's your Herbie.
That's right! Herbie's missing
and your Lancia's
missing Herbie.
You must think
I'm an absolute fool
with this
"Herbie, Herbie, Herbie."
Well, I don't believe in fairy
tales or Herbie or you!
Jim, pop the hood, will ya?
What are you doing?
You want your car
started, don't ya?
Listen, uh,
I know how you feel,
but you better
get over it right now.
Forget Herbie.
You know why he isn't
here, don't you?
He's found somebody
else, that's why.
He didn't have the guts to tell
you himself, so I'm telling you.
Oh, yeah, we're talkin'
about the same guy, all right.
Old Herbie. Old fun-lovin',
fickle, Herbie.
Now you see him,
now you don't.
He's right, you know.
So far, we've had to tell this
to a Fiat,
a Thunderbird
and an Austin-Healey.
I know how you feel. It's...
Fun while it lasted, but...
You know, the truth is,
you weren't the first
and you won't be the last.
You might as well take off.
Will somebody help me
start my car?
Oui, mademoiselle.
S'il vous plait.
Let me have a look.
Thank you!
No problem.
I was beginning to think
everybody around here
was crazy.
Well, so much for the Lancia.
Yeah. So much for
both of them, I guess.
Douglas, let's go.
Don't you realize you've
got pole position?
I also realize
we don't have a car.
But it'll be here.
It'd better be. In two
minutes, Douglas,
or you can try again next year.
Mesdames et monsieurs...
Ladies and gentlemen,
the first running
of the Trans France race...
Is about to begin.
What's that?
It's an armored truck.
That armored truck is us!
- Excuse me. Excuse me.
- Yes. Yes.
Where's Herbie?
Are you crazy?
We're supposed
to be in a race,
and here you are guarding
the Bank of England...
Or the crown jewels
or who knows what!
We didn't travel 6,000 miles
just to see
some French pastry
dressed up like a tin soldier.
I'll tell you something.
I've had it with the French...
The men, women and the...
Herbie?
Are we still in it?
From the looks of it, you'll be
starting and finishing in last place.
Quickly, you've no time to lose.
You have things to attend to.
- Gas! Let's move it, Wheely!
- Check! Top of my list!
Fill it up!
Monsieur Douglas, stop!
What do you mean,
stop?
The tank is full.
I filled it this morning.
Let's go, Wheely.
Come on, Herbie. What're you
doing? The race is back there.
I know what he's doing.
He can't fool me.
He's looking for that Lancia.
Inspector.
Well, what I was going
to say, sir...
Suppose there was
a connection
between the men who attacked
and the men who stole
the diamond.
Not now, Fontenoy!
But, sir, what if they've hidden
the stolen diamond in the car?
- What?
- If I may suggest, sir,
we should have our men
search that car immediately.
- Search?
- Yes!
- There is no time!
- The car is still here.
Yes?
Yes, but it is obviously...
Tuning up, or something.
Just say the word,
and the men and I...
Will search that car
from bumper to bumper.
The word is no, Fontenoy!
N-no?
What you don't seem
to understand is that, um,
a thorough search
would take over an hour.
And an hour's delay
would deprive Douglas
of winning a race...
He has traveled halfway
around the globe to enter.
Sir, I admire you
for your consideration.
And I understand now exactly
how you are thinking.
Sorry, sir.
Forget the Lancia, Herbie.
She's gone.
You heard him right.
Gone, split!
Yeah, that's right.
She took off in that race
like you never existed.
She wanted me to tell you,
it was fun while it lasted,
but when push came to shove,
she shoved off.
That's just the way
women are.
Might as well face it.
You've been deserted,
jilted. Abandoned!
Too late now.
We'll get it in Monte Carlo
after the race.
Inspector, I think
you will be proud of me.
What now, Fontenoy?
I have done exactly what I knew
you would have wanted me to...
notified Monte Carlo.
Their police will search
the car as soon as it arrives.
I'll take care at once, sir.
Whoa!
UH...
Catch anything?
I didn't think so.
- Which way?
- Right.
Left!
Hope they get that trophy
to Monte Carlo
on a fast jet.
We may beat 'em to it.
Unfortunately, somebody
put the Alps in our way.
The way Herbie's flyin',
nothing can stop him,
including the Himalayas.
Some road. It's not
even on the map.
Maybe you oughta
ask directions.
From who,
a French mountain goat?
There must be somebody.
Wheely, you...
Maybe I'll just call from in here.
Yeah.
Hey, there's somebody
out there.
No, that's just me! I never
heard a real echo before.
Will you sit down, Wheely?
Just one more, okay?
Come on, Wheely!
Uh, I got somebody.
Those are the guys
who were after Herbie.
Get out of the car.
- I'm taking over.
- I'll drive the car!
If it worked once,
maybe it'll work again.
Hey, buddy, I like
your "yodel-ay-hee-oo"!
Well, we're back
on the beam.
How many cars you figure
are ahead of us?
Would you believe all of 'em?
Is that a knocking I hear
in the gas tank?
Not in my gas tank.
Never!
Sounds like something
clunking around in there.
Well, we either listen
to the driver...
And stop to take
the gas tank apart,
or we listen to the mechanic
and try to win this race.
Well, I'm listening
to the mechanic.
Let's go, Herbie!
- What's wrong?
- I don't know.
The oil pressure's up,
there's plenty of gas.
But he's not getting it.
I hate to mention this again,
but I heard some clunking...
You mean that nonsense
about the gas tank again?
Yeah, that's...
All right, let's get it straight,
once and for all,
who the mechanic is
around here, okay?
You say it's the gas tank,
and I say it isn't the gas tank.
You see?
It isn't the gas tank.
It's this... Rock
that was in the gas tank.
Hold it!
There's only one kind of rock
that glistens like that.
Well, sure, quartz.
You can find millions of 'em
around any quarry in Philly.
But... Not one that's worth...
Six million bucks.
- Huh?
- L'etoile de Joie.
The tall, the what?
Etoile de Joie.
Oh, wow!
That's...
That's the biggest hunk
of diamond
I've ever seen in my life.
What I don't understand
is how it...
The black sedan!
- Huh? Where?
- No, no, no.
They're the ones
that robbed the museum.
Don't you see?
They weren't trying
to knock us out of the race.
They were trying to get this.
Thank you for helping us, gentlemen,
and up with your hands.
You gave us the slip
for the last time.
We'll take the rock.
I don't suppose you'd
believe that was just a
big hunk of quartz.
The rock.
Let me have it.
Aah!
Ha-ha-ha!
The rock.
Well, come on, hand it over.
Oh! Oh!
Ooh! Ooh!
Well, what do we
do with them now?
Thanks, Herbie. We tie 'em up!
Double X,
we lost them.
First time we've ever
been done in by a car.
The goods
will be in Monte Carlo
in a couple of hours.
No chance of stopping them.
See, we... We're rather
tied up at the moment.
Get me the airport.
We passed every car
on the road.
All except the Lancia.
Well, after the way
she jilted Herbie,
that's one car he won't
wanna come in second to.
Right, Herbie?
Hey, isn't that it?
It sure is.
Maybe we
should've stopped.
Stop? Are you kidding?
Throw away 100 grand
and the biggest comeback
of our lives?
We've got this thing.
We're a shoe-in.
- She's in trouble.
- Well, sure,
plenty of cars get in trouble.
Let the rescue boys
bail her out.
Yeah, but I mean,
she could be in real danger.
I'm sorry, Wheely.
Sometimes a comeback
comes second.
Herbie doesn't seem
to think so.
Well, yeah, sure. Why should
Herbie want to stop...
After the lies
you told him back there?
Shh!
Yeah, the jilted lover.
Why, if he knew that
that little Lancia...
Had been waiting on him
at the starting line,
wouldn't even budge...
Until you lied to her about
him throwing her over...
I mean, she...
Why, he'd...
I mean, he'd be back
at her side right now.
I hate to say this, Jim,
but you got a big mouth.
You know that?
Hang on, Diane!
Thank you.
- Thank you.
- You okay?
I think so. I missed a shift
and lost control.
That's not all
you could've lost.
Herbie,
what're you doin'?
Herbie, there's no time!
Forget it, Wheely.
He's gonna get his girlfriend
out of the mud.
And us out of the race.
I see it,
but I don't believe it.
Well, you can believe this,
we are now out of the money,
because "Sometimes
a comeback comes second."
Who's giving up, buddy?
Not me!
- Come on, you come with us.
- No, no, I...
I'm gonna stay with my car.
Looks like we're all
gonna stay with her car.
Let's go, Wheely!
You're not going
anyplace, are you?
Uh, Herbie?
Now listen to me.
Uh, Herbie, I know
just how you feel,
but I also know
you're not a quitter.
Now show 'em
you can do it, Herbie.
Win it for them!
And for her.
Oh, hey!
The rest is up to you.
- Good luck.
- Thanks.
Aw, come on, Herbie!
Open up, will ya?
Come on!
I know you're sore
about what I told you,
but I'm sorry, okay?
Look, I did it for you.
Okay, okay,
I did it for us.
What do you want me to do,
get down on my knees?
Okay.
All right, I lied to ya,
and I'm sorry.
And I promise I'll never,
never do it again, okay?
Boy, you sure don't
forgive easy, do ya?
Bouchet, did you miss a turn
on your way to the Eiffel Tower?
No. A little
unfinished business, Emile.
You've wounded me, my friend.
You think I cannot handle
a little diamond search?
Five of my best men
are waiting for the cars
to enter Monte Carlo.
- That is exactly why I'm here.
- A-ha!
Afraid I will steal
some of your glory?
There is no glory
to be stolen.
I wish to rectify
a terrible mistake...
And save everyone
from embarrassment.
- The search is off.
- Off?
The message was an error
by another zealous
young detective,
anxious to make an overnight
reputation for himself.
Ah, yes,
but for this kind of news
they invented the telephone.
Ooh-la-la!
This is a matter that needed
my personal attention.
Who knows what
complications could arise
from a situation like this?
This is a big race.
It could cause...
An international incident.
Hmm.
Ah!
Well, it, uh, seems
your young man in Paris...
Has caused you
a lot of trouble.
I assure you, Emile,
I intend to put an end to it.
Wiser heads
are always called upon
to clean up
the mistakes of the young.
- It's true.
- And our reward,
we get it
when we reach heaven.
Perhaps a bit sooner.
Three down and two to go.
Dirty road hog!
Why doesn't he learn
how to drive?
He knows how to drive.
That's the trouble.
Yeah, I see what you mean.
If we don't get him
by the tunnel...
There's no way
we can pass him!
Bruno was right.
They never come back.
H-h-Herbie!
Ha-ha! I don't b...
believe it!
We did it!
They don't come back, huh?
I guess Herbie wasn't listening.
- Whoo!
- Whoo-whoo-whoo-whoo!
Ha-ha!
Swine!
Herbie! Herbie!
How does it feel to be back
in the winner's circle?
Pretty good!
Well, for the 20th time,
it was a great race,
and we enjoyed
every minute of it...
Almost every minute of it.
Well, I'm enjoying
every minute of this,
I can tell you that.
And, uh, both of us
would like to thank you all
very, very much.
Au revoir! Arrivederci!
Ciao! Buenas noches!
Sayonara.
Right. See ya around, Douglas.
Hey, that's
some cute little memento
you got there, old buddy.
Well, this little memento's
as much yours as mine,
old buddy.
And it's more Herbie's
than anybody's.
You can say that again.
Well, look who's here.
May I add my congratulations.
You'll congratulate us even more
when you see what we've got for ya.
- It was right in Herbie's gas tank.
- Ah.
This whatcha been lookin' for?
Yes.
It's had a rough trip, hasn't it?
But it's winding up in the right hands.
Indeed, it is.
Don't know how we
missed connections, sir,
but here I am.
Fontenoy.
You see? I knew the diamond
would be found.
It's an honor to be at your side
in this moment
of triumph, Inspector.
And I have more good news, sir.
The two thieves have been captured.
Good!
Good! Then I'd say
the case is concluded.
Yeah.
But, you know, there seems
there'd be a mastermind
behind this kind of thing.
Yeah, or that museum
has some
pretty lousy security.
Sir, men have been
challenged to a duel
for such an accusation.
The museum's security
was virtually foolproof.
I made an interesting
discovery just today, sir.
- Fontenoy...
- From the sensitized floor...
...to the radar beam
surrounding the pedestal
to the very pillow
on which the diamond rested,
all the traps were conceived
and executed by one man.
- Fontenoy.
- No, sir.
Give credit
where credit is due.
The combinations to the entire
security system
were devised
and known only to you!
The only question is,
who besides the inspector
knew the details
of these precautions?
Who besides the Inspector?
The answer to
that question is...
Nobody!
My retirement has been
delayed too long.
Now I hope no one will be
foolish enough to make a move.
Move this ridiculous car,
or I'll be forced to kill you!
Ah!
Even a mastermind can be
outsmarted by this car.
Thanks, Herbie.
Inspector.
I always hoped
you'd be present when I
cracked my first big case, sir.
Fontenoy!
Uh, excuse me, sir.
Sorry, sir. Sorry.
I think you'll find
it's all here, monsieur.
I'm so happy!
I personally will see to it
that this magnificent
automobile
receives the greatest honor
France can bestow.
S'il vous plait,
the, uh, VW?
VW.
Yes, the VW. The white one with
the 53 on the side.
Yes, yes, I know the car.
It is the toast of all Monte Carlo.
Yes. It's also our transportation,
if you wouldn't mind.
Oh, I wouldn't mind, monsieur,
but it is no longer here.
What?
It was stolen.
Mademoiselle,
you would not believe this.
I would not believe this.
No one would believe this.
It was stolen...
By another car.
I know that you believe
about Herbie,
but you're probably
not ready to believe...
Giselle can do anything
she wants to.
- Giselle?
- Mm-hmm.
We're strong women, she and I.
Shall we make it a foursome?
Let's go.
Take us to ze most romantic
spot in Monte Carlo.
Well...
Yeah, bein' chief mechanic
is important,
but I didn't exactly
win the race all by myself.
No?
Well, almost.