[ Soft music plays ]
Bobby goldsboro:
¶ these are the best times ¶
¶ the moments
we can't let slip away ¶
¶ life's little game we play ¶
¶ living from day to day ¶
¶ oooooh-oooooh-ooh-ooh ¶
¶ but once in a lifetime ¶
¶ once in a lifetime ¶
¶ a minute like this
is ours to share ¶
¶ remember these moments well ¶
¶ for moments like these
are rare as dreams ¶
¶ and golden rainbows ¶
¶ soft as nights
when summer wind blows by ¶
¶ together we laugh and cry ¶
¶ together we'll learn to fly ¶
¶ LA LA LA LA LA LA LA ¶
¶ mmmm-mmmm-mmmm-mmmmmmm ¶
¶ ahhh-ahhh-ahhh ¶
¶ these are the best times ¶
¶ come take my hand ¶
¶ together we'll cross
the timeless sands ¶
¶ chasing the endless sun ¶
¶ living our lives as one ¶
¶ these are the best times ¶
girl: Daddy, it's me.
Daddy, it's me.
Man: Yes, it is you.
And you know what?
It's my birthday.
And, daddy,
I grew up last night,
and I married someone
exactly like you.
Why, you lucky girl, Wendy,
you lucky girl.
[ Children laughing ]
The little savages.
Don't they screen them
at that school they go to?
Mommy, daddy, this is Bart.
He's my best friend.
Hello,
Mr. and Mrs. mccready.
Woman:
Nice to meet you, Bart.
Can Bart and I go
in the backyard and play?
It's hot in here.
Be careful of that
pretty birthday dress.
I will.
Bye, Mr. mccready.
Man: If Wendy had to find
someone to run around with,
why didn't she find someone
who had his front teeth?
[ Cheering, laughing ]
What a bunch.
How Wendy ever got mixed up
with a group like this,
I'll never know.
Mommy, daddy, Bart's here!
Bart...
[ Engine revs ]
[ Tires screech ]
[ Clears throat ]
Oh, hi, dad.
Mr. mccready.
Wendy, Bart.
I don't care
what you have to say!
I'm looking for action!
If you'd been on your toes,
we could have had this union
agreement settled weeks ago!
Mr. hershberger, we are doing
everything that we can.
Maybe that is not enough!
Did you ever think
of that?!
Well, uh, uh, no.
Well, I have, and I'm giving
you fair warning.
Unless the two of you --
what is the matter with you,
mccready?
Nothing, nothing.
You're staring!
You're not listening
to a word I'm saying!
Who me?
No, I was just thinking
of something else for a minute.
I don't pay you people
to think of something else!
I pay you to think
about my problems!
He wasn't really thinking
of something else.
He was thinking of another
part of your problems.
Oh? What part, mccready?
Uh, well...
It's 2:00!
We have to tee off at 2:30!
Give us a few more days,
and I promise you
that your trouble
with the unions will be over,
because we must remember
that right
is on our side, right?
Right. Right.
[ Door slams ]
[ Distant laughter ]
Hey! Take it easy,
will ya, Eddie?!
Sorry, Bart.
Eddie, you idiot!
Oh, boy.
[ Sighs ]
Bart...
What are we going to do?
What do you mean?
If we both get scholarships.
I'd guess we'd have to go.
That would really be tough.
Do you realize how long
we've all known each other?
Ever since I can remember.
But I don't think we have
anything to worry about.
Hey, look, we'll all end up
over at city college.
It's not so easy to win
a scholarship to huntington.
Yeah, I know.
But you know what would
be worse than anything?
What if one of us won and --
and the other one didn't?
That's not gonna happen.
If we were gonna win
a scholarship,
we'd have heard by now.
Yeah.
Yeah, I guess you're right.
All right, everybody.
Come on,
we gotta get goin'.
What do you mean
we gotta get goin'?
Because it's time,
that's why.
You always mess up
everything.
I told you old man beezly's
comin' back
from his vacation tonight.
If he finds out I've been
goin' to the beach again
while he's away,
he'll kill me.
Together: Oh, Stanley!
It's all right for you guys
to complain, but remember --
I get the responsibility.
¶ Ridin' along
down a California highway ¶
¶ tryin' to get back to L.A. ¶
¶ me and my woman
drivin' in the hot sun ¶
¶ looking back at San Jose ¶
¶ might hop a freighter
or work as a waiter ¶
¶ could be anybody's guess ¶
¶ all we know now, though,
we're not sure how is ¶
¶ we gotta make Los Angeles ¶
get down, roly poly.
[ Siren wails ]
¶ Ramblin' along
and singin' a song ¶
¶ tryin' to do things our way ¶
¶ gotta keep movin',
gotta keep groovin' ¶
¶ livin' life from day to day ¶
¶ what we will go through
or where we will go to ¶
¶ could be anybody's guess ¶
¶ all we know now, though,
we're not sure how is ¶
¶ we gotta make Los Angeles ¶
fore!!
Those rotten kids!
How can they grow up
that way?!
Juvenile delinquents --
it's bad enough
all the things
you read about them!
Now they're ruining
a man's golf game!
It's barbaric!
You can certainly take
the shot over again, sir.
Well, I certainly will.
Oh...Weren't you
a little further
away from the hole, sir?
Is that what you think,
kershaw?
Who, me? Oh, no, sir.
Of course not me.
Uh...Come to think of it,
that's exactly where you were.
Maybe even a little closer.
That's the first sensible
thing you've said all day.
I'll tell you,
it's a problem, sue.
I don't know why you worry
so much about it, Charlie.
She's just a young girl.
She's having fun.
We should have sent her
to Europe this summer.
Anything to get her
away from Bart
and that crazy bunch
she runs around with.
She's been running around
with that bunch all her life.
Yeah, and where
are they goin'? Nowhere!
Not one of them has a job
except maybe
that nitwit Stanley,
and the only reason he does
is so he can cart the rest
of them around.
Not one of them has an idea
what to do with his life.
Charlie,
you have a short memory.
Neither did you
when you were their age.
They'll get along.
You'll see.
I will, huh?
Well, let me tell you --
one of these days,
Wendy's gonna start thinking
about getting married.
And when she does,
I hope she has more
to choose from
than that bunch
of birdbrains.
Charlie,
stop shaking that at me.
[ Tires screeching,
distant laughter ]
Hey! Hi, Mr. mccready!
Hi, Mr. mccready.
Hi, mom. Hi, dad.
Hey, did anyone call?
Who would call?
You're with all of them.
Did you kids have a good time
at the beach?
It was great,
really great.
We had a great
time at the beach.
Stanley,
what are you doing
with Mr. beezly's
ambulance?
Mr. and Mrs. beezly went
to the lake for a few days,
and while he's away,
he left me in charge.
That's your way
of taking care of it --
using the ambulance
to go to the beach.
What if there should be
a call for it?
I don't know.
We never had a call for it.
But if somebody did call,
they'd have to call
over to Collins.
They have all
the new equipment anyway.
It doesn't sound like you're
very loyal to Mr. beezly.
You have to think
of the public, too.
When that thing goes over 40,
it really shakes.
I'd hate to be
in the back of it
during a real emergency.
Man:
Car one, come in!
I see.
They're calling car one!
Is that this thing?
It has to be!
It's the only one we have!
Stanley!!
I said, come in car one!
Where are ya?!
Yes, sir.
This is Stanley.
Well, where are ya?
Well, I stopped to get
a bite to eat, sir.
Get in here quick!
Yes, sir.
I'm on my way, sir.
And make it quick!
Hey, gang,
I've got to go right now.
Is there an emergency?
You're darn right, there is.
Old man beezly's back.
This could be the end
of a beautiful relationship.
Look, Randy, please --
sweep the sand out of the back
of the ambulance.
The rest of you guys --
you get your things.
We've got to straighten up.
Come on, let's move.
Mr. mccready...
Thank you for your broom,
and I'll bring it back.
Some of you guys are gonna
have to go with Larry,
and I'm gonna drop Randy off.
You come with me.
Bye-bye.
See you later.
Bye-bye. See you later.
[ Engine turns over,
siren wails ]
See ya! Bye!
Bye!
That's the end of that job,
that's for sure.
I don't think Stanley
was too interested
in Mr. beezly's business
anyway.
But you do admit people should
be interested in something?
Oh, yeah. Sure.
Good. Tell me, Bart,
what are you interested in?
Well, a lot of things.
Like what?
You know -- music, movies,
the beach, football --
all kinds of stuff.
Is that all, Bart?
Oh, well, no, Mr. mccready.
Wendy, too.
[ Sighs ]
Why don't we all
go inside?
I think everyone should be
ready for something cold.
Yeah, sounds great.
Would you care
for some iced tea, Charlie?
No, I wouldn't care
for some iced tea.
Darling,
if you want some coffee,
there's plenty in the kitchen.
Mm-hmm, that's nice.
Look!
There's that Dr. Skinner!
He wrote that book
I gave you last Christmas!
The one you never read.
The ball game will be on
in a couple of minutes.
Great.
I'm going shopping,
but I'll be back early.
Mm-hmm.
You know, Charlie,
you're such an interesting
person to be around.
Mm-hmm.
Man: Dr. Skinner,
let's begin with you...
What did you say?
What is the difference
between the teenager
nothing. Nothing.
In our fast-moving,
loose generation
have fun.
And the one
that preceded it?
Right off, I'd like to say
that in my opinion,
there's no difference
between the teenager today
and the teenager
20 years ago.
In many ways,
they're better.
You don't know
the teenagers I know.
There is a generation gap.
Yes, of course.
But who creates all that?
I think the parent.
I find that hard to believe.
Not when you analyze it,
Mr. Michaels --
you take the typical parent
of a teenage daughter.
Does he try
to involve himself
with his daughter
and her friends,
or does he just sit around
and criticize them?
Does he really care?
Parents, why don't you ask
yourself this question.
When was the last time
you took your daughter
on a picnic?
Have you ever gone
bike riding with her?
Have you joined your daughter
and her friends on a barbecue?
These are questions
we may all ask ourselves.
Parents, have you
really tried to become
a part
of your teenager's life?
It's up to you to answer
that question honestly.
And we'll resume
our discussion
after this brief message
from our sponsor.
Friends, do you suffer
from arthritis, neuritis,
bursitis, or flea-bitis?
Do you have trouble sleeping
at night?
Are you listless
during the day?
If so, try "cure all,"
the all-purpose pill --
bye, dad.
Goodbye, Wendy.
Wendy?
Where are you going?
To the beach.
Oh.
I don't know
what he's doin' here.
I know he doesn't like me.
Something's gotten
into him.
That's the only way
I can explain it.
That sure is somethin'
to figure out.
Yuck!
Hi, gang!
Hey, kids, isn't that
Wendy's dad with them?
It couldn't be.
No, I think it really is.
What's he doing here?
Beats me.
How's everybody?
Uh, I-I think everybody
knows my dad, don't they?
Yeah, sure.
Oh, sure. Oh, sure.
Well?
Great. Great.
Fine.
Good, good.
How are you,
Mr. mccready?
I'm fine, fine.
Hey, look,
don't let me bother you.
You kids go right ahead
and do whatever it is you do --
swimmin'
and volley-ball playin'.
I'll just set up
my little camp here and relax.
Set up camp --
he sounds like an Indian.
Hey, Bart...
You guys ready, huh?
It's okay with us.
Outta sight.
We've been lookin'
for some pigeons.
Okay, guys,
let's get 'em today, huh?
Hey, gang!
Hey, wait for me!
Mine! Mine!
[ Cheering ]
I got it!
Oh!
Keep it movin'.
Okay, one more point,
and we got 'em!
Oh, wow!
Wendy: Come on, dad!
You can do it!
Come on, Mr. mccready!
Come on, dad, come on!
Hey!
Young woman:
All right, let's go!
Aaaahhhh!
Come on, guys!
Let's hit it!
All right! Yeah!
Whoo!
All right!
[ Indistinct yelling ]
Hey, wait! Wait!
I'm gonna get me
one of those!
Dad, no!
Oh, my gosh.
Aaaaahhhhh!
Get up here, guys.
Be careful.
Is he okay?
Oh! Oh! Ohh! Ohh!
Are you okay?
Dad, are you all right?
Fine, fine, hon.
[ Sighs ]
Okay, let's try another one.
Wait a minute!
Are you kidding?!
No.
There you go.
Maybe you'd better rest
for a while.
You probably took on
too much water.
You'll be all right.
Hey, kids, do I have a deal!
Hi, Stanley!
Roly poly,
get outta here! Come on!
Hi, Mr. mccready.
What are you doin' here?
It's none of your business
what I'm doin' here.
It just seems kind of weird,
that's all.
What's your big deal,
Stanley?
It's my dad --
he went away for the weekend,
and he gave me the keys
to his boat.
I can't believe it.
Hey, great!
I can't believe it, either.
Did you bring your skis?
They're in the back
of the ice truck.
Great!
Okay! All right!
What are you doing
with the ice truck?
I thought you worked
for that ambulance service.
They had to lay me off on
account of the summer slump.
Summer slump?
Dad, maybe you'd better sit
here and relax in the sun.
I'll relax on the boat,
Wendy.
Really,
it'd be much better if --
Wendy, I came out
to have a good time today.
I'm going to have a good time.
[ Indistinct yelling ]
Good goin'!
Isn't he terrific, dad?
Oh, he's all right.
He's a little bit more
than all right.
It's a question
of balance.
Once you get up,
it's easy.
All right!
He wants to stop.
Okay, I'll go next.
Stanley,
I believe I'll go next.
You were going
to rest.
I didn't come out here
I came out
to have a good time.
[ Barks ]
Aah! Aaaahhh! Aah!
Come on. Come on.
Hey! Hey! Wait!
Don't pull on the bar!
Let it pull you!
You can do it!
All right!
Come on!
[ Indistinct yelling ]
Yeah. Yeah!
Whoo!
More!
Give it some gas.
[ Engine revs ]
All right!
You're doin' fine, dad!
You're doin' fine!
He's gonna hit the ramp.
Get over!
Get over, dad!
Aaaahhhh!
Aaaaaaahhhhhhh!
Oh, hey, I got it!
Perfect!
Hey, the good part's comin' up
pretty soon!
[ Indistinct talking ]
Look at that.
Ha ha ha!
Great, just great!
The good part's comin' up
in a minute.
Aaaaahhhhh!
Aaaaaaahhhhh!
Did you see that?!
Yes, Mr. schlimmer.
I understand, Mr. schlimmer.
Yes, I know you're upset,
but I'm upset, too.
I'm the one that lost
three days' work.
[ Talking, laughter continues ]
Hold on a minute,
Mr. schlimmer.
What's all that laughter?
It's the kids.
They're watching
a funny movie.
I'm on the phone.
Stanley said you left him
the keys to the boat.
I left him the keys
to the house.
The keys to the boat happened
to be on the same ring.
That's not the impression
he gave me.
What I don't understand is
why you get yourself involved
with those ding-a-ling kids.
I'm not trying
to lecture you,
but don't you think that we,
as adults,
should set ourselves up
as an example?
Look, Mr. schlimmer,
if it's all the same with you,
I'd rather explain this
when I'm feeling better.
Fine, Mr. schlimmer.
Thank you. Goodbye.
[ Groans ]
Imagine me getting lectured
by Stanley's father.
He ought to be lecturing
Stanley.
That idiot
driving those kids around
in those trucks
is ridiculous.
Everyone
wants to contribute.
And that's just
Stanley's way.
He drives the kids around
where they want to go.
That makes him happy.
I don't think it makes
his employers very happy.
As soon as they find out,
they fire him.
He just gets another job
with another delivery truck.
It's kind of nutty,
but it works.
That's what
I've been telling you.
They're nuts.
So are those sociologists,
thinking I could get along
with them.
That wasn't too good a move.
What a bunch.
I hope you're not
going to blame Wendy.
Of course I don't blame Wendy.
You know that.
Because I wouldn't want it
to spoil her birthday.
Her birthday?
Yes, well, I mean, she is
planning on having a party.
She's always had
a birthday party.
What's the matter with that?
Well, nothing.
I mean,
absolutely nothing, dear.
I'm just glad to know
that you approve.
Is there anything else
I can get for you, darling?
Nothing. No, thanks.
I'm fine.
Oh, by the way,
speaking of Wendy's party,
barby Phelps
had a beach party,
and Wendy was wondering --
no! Positively no!
I heard all about
barby Phelps' beach party!
They had to call out
the coast guard!
No beach party!
Don't you think
Wendy's old enough
to have the kind of party
she likes?
Yes, and that's the kind of
party she's going to have...
Right here at home...
Where I can watch 'em!
[ Slow music plays ]
Woman: ¶ I love the way
you smile at me ¶
¶ the twinkle in your eyes ¶
¶ the way you want
the world to know ¶
¶ it just can't be disguised ¶
¶ of all the memories
close to me ¶
¶ funny, but it's true ¶
¶ the moments I love most of all
are ones when I'm near you ¶
[ music stops ]
Did you hear that?
What?
Nothing.
That's good.
Charlie,
what are you doing?
They think I'm asleep.
They're gonna get
into my liquor cabinet.
You're not going down there!
Yes, I am.
You promised Wendy.
Well, I'll just go down
and get a glass of water.
You can get a glass up here.
I like
the downstairs water better
than the upstairs water.
Charlie!
[ Door closes ]
Dancing
without music and lights?
Hmm, maybe your mother
will put up
with this sort of thing,
but I won't.
Ohh! Ohhh!
Dad!
Dad, it's Wendy!
Mr. mccready!
How many fingers
am I holding up?
It's Bart!
It's Bart! It's Wendy!
[ Barking ]
Get! Get!
Let go! Let go!
Napoleon!
[ Gasps ] Oh!
Oh! Oh, you naughty boy!
You stop that, Napoleon!
What is the matter
with you?!
Sorry, Mr. mccready.
It's quite all right,
Mrs. levin.
I guess you can't expect
a dog to like everyone.
Mr. mccready,
do you have a headache
from your party last night?
No, Mrs. levin,
it was just a little accident.
Matter of fact,
it wasn't even my party.
It was Wendy's.
Oh, it sounded
like so much fun.
Isn't it wonderful when young
people have such a nice time?
Yes, Mrs. levin.
Wonderful.
[ Napoleon growls ]
[ Barking ]
Just look at this!
You said that my name would
never appear in the newspapers!
Not only is my name
in the newspapers,
my picture is all over
the front page!
I wouldn't worry
about it, Mr. hershberger.
It's just
the local newspaper.
The local newspaper?
The local newspaper?!
There are three million people
in this city,
and they're all staring
at my picture this morning,
hating me!
They're not all
hating you, sir.
Three million of them?
That's impossible.
Kershaw, when are you going
to get that contract signed?
The contract
between the dockworkers
and hershberger
shipping alliance
will be signed tomorrow,
and you can count on that.
You're sure?!
The only things
that separate us
are just commas and periods,
right, mccready?
Mccready?
Mccready!
Hmm?
You aren't listening again!
No, sir. I mean, yes...
I, was, uh,
I was listening, sir.
Not only
were you not listening,
but you're being
downright unsociable!
Unsociable? I'm sorry.
I certainly hadn't meant
to be.
Say, how's your wife?
My wife?!
Mm-hmm.
Who cares?!
Mccready, you've got to get
ahold of yourself.
Hershberger represents
at least half of our business.
I've got a family problem
I can't get out of my mind.
There is no place in business
for a family problem!
A family problem? Oh.
Is there something
the matter with sue?
No, it's Wendy.
I've got to hand it
to you, ira.
Your daughters
chose fine husbands.
Oh, yes. Yes --
an engineer,
a doctor, a lawyer.
I'm proud of them all.
They're all huntington men.
That's where you find
the right kind of husband.
I wish Wendy
were going there.
You mean she's not?
She's going to city college.
What?!
It's this group
she's gone with
ever since she was a kid --
some sense of loyalty.
They're all going there.
The worst part is,
they're all going nowhere.
Not one of them
has an ounce of initiative.
I can't understand
what she sees in them.
You're letting her go
to city college?
She's getting toward
the marrying age, isn't she?
That's
what I'm worried about.
Why don't you send her
to huntington?
You just don't send Wendy
anywhere.
She did take the scholarship
test with her boyfriend,
but her heart wasn't in it.
Even at that,
she almost made it.
How do you know?
I talked
to the registrar there.
Are you talking
about the Claude archer
that was in the same class
with me?
I think so.
I'll tell him you're
letting the kid
think she won a scholarship,
but you'll pay
for everything.
But, ira --
I'm sure he'll go along.
But, ira,
I can't do that.
Gertrude, get me Claude archer
up at huntington.
Ira, I can't do that!
You don't have to do anything
but pay.
[ Sighs ]
I can't believe it.
Hi, hon, Wendy.
Charlie! Charlie,
Wendy's won a scholarship!
I really did.
Wonderful, wonderful.
Charlie,
you didn't hear her.
Wendy's actually won
a scholarship to huntington!
That's not wonderful,
that's super!
Super, super.
You're darn right, it is!
Can we have some champagne?
Huh?
We have some.
Of course
we have champagne.
We have lots of champagne.
Yep, that's one thing
we have plenty of -- champagne.
Oh, Wendy, it'll probably be
a little difficult at first,
being away from home,
but after a while,
you'll learn to love it.
I know I did.
Wendy: I don't know why they
waited so long to notify me.
Classes start
in a couple of days.
I've been wondering
about that myself.
[ Cork pops ]
Oh! Ha ha ha ha!
[ Laughing ] Dear!
It'll just take me a minute
to clean up.
[ Doorbell rings ]
Oh, that must be Bart.
You don't mind if I pass
on the champagne, do you?
Invite him in.
Maybe he'd like some.
We have plenty.
I know, but...Well,
I'd just as soon tell Bart
about this thing myself.
All right, dear.
You go ahead.
Good night.
Good night, darling.
[ Sighs ]
Wendy...
Yeah, dad?
Good night, Wendy.
Good night, dad.
[ Soft music plays ]
[ Waves crashing ]
You know, I-I really
didn't want this to happen.
Nothing's happened.
Yeah.
We sure would have had
a lot of fun with everyone
going to the same place,
though.
Yeah. Well, you'll have
a lot of fun up there, too.
I suppose.
Hey, look, if, uh --
if you need a ride up,
just let me know,
'cause I'll be around.
Yeah. Sure, Bart.
I know.
Great about Wendy winnin'
that scholarship, huh?
Yeah, terrific.
A week from now, this
could never have happened.
We would have all been goin'
over to city.
It's crazy the way things
work out, isn't it?
Yeah, crazy.
Huh?
Come on, Stanley,
let's go, huh?
Yeah, sure.
What do you mean
she went up with Bart?
She was goin' up with me
tomorrow.
There are only two more days
of registration left.
She'll be able to register
first thing in the morning.
What if she doesn't talk
to Claude archer?
They're are plenty of people
up there helping out.
I want her to talk
to Claude archer!
You don't have to bite
my head off.
It's just
that it's kind of important.
Where's she staying?
Mother Barlow's.
Just think --
the same place I stayed.
It was always a little strict,
but I think it's better
that way.
A little regimentation
in her life
wouldn't hurt anything.
Long distance, please.
Yes, I'd like to place
a phone call
to mother Barlow's
boardinghouse,
university Avenue,
huntington, California.
Yes, that's right.
B-a-r-l-o-w.
[ Telephone ringing ]
Hello.
Hello?
I must have the wrong number.
How do you know already?
Is this hollingsworth 2-8560?
Yeah.
Mother Barlow's
boardinghouse?
Yeah.
Is mother Barlow in?
No, she won't be back
till about 7:00.
She went to the races
this afternoon.
Went to the races?
What's the matter with that?
Nothing, nothing at all.
Is there a Wendy mccready
registered there?
Just a sec.
Oh, yeah, she's that chick
that came in today.
She's up in a corner room.
May I speak with her, please?
You could, only
there's no phone up there.
Could you go get her?
Who's this?
This is her father.
Well, pops, we don't run
any messenger service.
If she happens to come by
the desk,
I'll tell her you called,
okay?
Okay. [ Click ]
Wait right here, huh?
[ Indistinct talking, laughter ]
You missed!
Mother Barlow?
Don't bother me now, Sonny.
I'm concentrating.
Oh.
I've got ya now.
Will you kids keep quiet?!
I'm trying to line up
a shot!
I don't know what this place
is coming to.
Yeah...Yeah.
Say, mother Barlow --
outta my way, Sonny!
Well,
that oughta take care
of you two boys
for the night.
Shall we rack 'em up
again?
No, no,
I'm a little tired.
I think I'll turn in.
Uh, m-mother Barlow?
Uh, ma'am?
Old age
can sure creep up.
It does that
to all of us.
Well, what's your problem,
Sonny?
[ Screaming ]
I have no problem --
let me go!
Will you quit that?!
Sorry, mother Barlow.
Get up to your rooms
where you belong!
[ Giggling ]
Darn kids!
They never give you
a moment of peace or quiet.
Times sure change,
don't they, Sonny?
They sure do.
There's quite a bit going on.
Is it an initiation
or something?
No, nothin' that I know of.
Say...
Haven't I seen you
somewhere before?
Yes, but that was many,
many years ago.
I doubt very much
you'd remember me.
But I would.
I never forget a horse
or a face.
Oh, sure!
You're the fellow that
was always running around
after that skinny girl.
Hmm. What was her name?
Uh...Lou --
something like that.
Sue. Sue lyons.
Remarkable you'd remember.
Yeah, well,
she isn't here anymore.
I know that.
I married her.
You did? That's funny.
I'd have said
that she was one
who never
would have gotten married.
It just so happens we've
been married a long time.
Matter of fact, our daughter
stays up here now --
Wendy mccready.
She's the pretty little thing
in the corner room.
We don't have a phone
up there.
I've heard that.
Would you mind if I spent
a few minutes with her now?
Well, you could,
but you're too late.
Visiting hours are over.
Yeah, but I've traveled
a long distance,
and it's rather important.
Couldn't you see her
in the morning?
No, I have to see her
tonight.
Well, it is 10:15,
and visiting hours are over
at 10:00.
You tell me that I can't see
my own daughter
because it's too late,
and you let these clowns
wander around here?!
Who's a clown?
Mother Barlow:
Just a minute, Sonny.
They happen to live here.
Boys live here?!
Didn't you know that?
I certainly did not!
And 10:15 or no 10:15,
I'm going to see my daughter!
Don't you make any trouble!
There won't be any trouble.
Boys...
Wait a minute!
I'm a lawyer!
I have my rights!
Co-ed dorms.
Look, I think I'll be
a little bit longer.
You may as well
take off, huh?
Wendy!
Wen-- ugh!
Wendy? Wendy?!
Aah!
Wait a minute!
No!
Aaahhh! Aaahhh!
Aaaaaahhhhh!
Peeping tom!!
Peeping tom! Help!
Police!! Help!
Help! Peeping tom!
Peeping tom!
$100 bail
posted by Wendy mccready
for Charlie mccready.
You know,
I can't understand it.
What?
This being a college town,
parents are always coming down
to bail out their kids.
This is the first time
I've ever seen
a kid come down
to bail out her parent.
Don't let it bother you,
judge.
There are a lot of things
I can't understand, either.
Bailiff...
Thank you.
Oh, dad,
are you all right?
I'm all right, hon.
Are you sure?
You look kind of pale.
You'd look a little pale
if you'd been through
what I've been through.
You'll have to fill in this form
before you can go.
Mr. mccready,
don't get me wrong --
it's none of my business --
didn't you come a long way
to be a peepin' tom?
Peeping tom.
I wouldn't be in
all this trouble
if it weren't for that dingbat
housemother of yours.
She is a little odd,
isn't she?
"Odd" isn't the word
for her.
The last thing mom said
before I left home
was to be sure and stay
at mother Barlow's.
She said mother Barlow's
was the one place
that realized
how a lady should behave.
There's one thing your mother
didn't realize --
mother Barlow's nuts.
Dad, what are you doing
up here?
I just came up to see
how you're getting along,
that's all.
That's kind of hard to say.
She's only been up here
a day.
Bart,
when I want your opinion,
I'll ask for it.
Dad, I'm doing fine.
It's just that
I tried to phone you,
but I couldn't get through.
She hasn't got a phone
up there.
I know
she doesn't have a phone!
I'm sorry.
Look, Bart,
it's only about four blocks
back to the boardinghouse.
Would you mind
if Wendy and I walked back?
I'd like to have a few minutes
with her alone.
Actually, I-I wo--
I guess maybe I-I'd better
get goin'.
I got a long way to drive
tonight anyway.
Good night.
Bart...
Thanks a lot
for bringing me up.
And thanks
for the Chinese dinner.
It was great.
Yeah, we have to remember
that place.
Yeah.
Take it easy, okay?
I will.
Thanks again.
I'll see ya later.
Goodbye, Bart.
Goodbye, Mr. mccready.
[ Engine turns over ]
Great night, isn't it?
Yeah.
Yeah, it's beautiful.
[ Sighs ]
Well, what is it, dad?
Are you worried
about something?
No, no.
If it's about
mother Barlow's --
no, no.
Is mom okay?
Fine, fine.
You had me worried
about it.
Now, what is it, dad?
It's your registration,
Wendy.
My registration?
That's no small matter,
honey.
I'm sure you remember me
talking about Claude archer.
Who?
Head of registration.
Yeah.
He's a good friend of ira's.
Mine, too, for that matter.
When you register, be sure
and talk to Claude archer
and no one else.
Why?
Well, b-because he'll give
you what you need, honey --
your major, your minor,
how many units
you should carry.
It's special attention you
won't get from anyone else.
Boy, that sure is weird.
What's weird?
You came 400 Miles to tell me
to talk to someone
by the name of Claude archer?
[ Yelling ]
Yes, I came 400 --
[ normal voice ]
Yes, I came 400 Miles,
and I got mixed up
with that housemother.
And I fell 30 feet
into a swimming pool.
I got thrown into jail,
booked as a peeping tom,
and now I gotta fly back 400
Miles in this wrinkled suit.
And I did it all so you
would talk to Claude archer
when you register.
Now, weird or not, Wendy,
will you talk to him?
Well, sure, dad.
If it means that much to you,
I'll do anything.
Oh, Charlie...
Charlie, I almost forgot.
Would you add a dozen eggs,
a pound of bacon,
and a couple of cans
of tomato soup to that list?
Are you sure that's all?
That's all.
[ Dog barking ]
Stop that, Napoleon!
Sorry, Mr. mccready!
Quite all right,
Mrs. levin.
Do you happen to be going
to the store, Mr. mccready?
Yes, I am.
Oh, would you mind
picking up
some dog food for Napoleon?
Not at all, Mrs. levin.
Why do you act that way
to Mr. mccready, Napoleon,
when he does
such nice things for you?
Woman:
Check okay at stand one.
[ Clears throat ]
Just trying to get through,
that's all.
[ Child crying ]
How many times have I told
you not to touch things?!
Woman #2: Bill, please open up
check stand 6.
Woman #3:
Change on number 4, please.
Stanley?
Oh, hi, Mr. mccready.
How are ya?
Fine, Stanley, fine.
Where do they keep
the dog food?
We moved it over to row 13
towards the front.
Wendy told me you were
working for a bakery now.
I was, but they had some
internal problems over there.
It just got too much
for me.
I like it much better here.
Mm-hmm.
I suppose
they have a delivery truck,
and you take care
of the deliveries?
How did you know?
Just a guess, Stanley.
Let me help you find
that dog food.
That's all right.
It's pretty well hidden.
Oh, Mr. mcginnis, hi!
Stanley.
Good news about Wendy,
huh?
What?
How great she's gettin' along
up at school.
How come you know how great
she's doin', and I don't?
A whole bunch of us
went up there last Sunday.
It was Bart's idea.
We used the truck,
so don't let on
to old man mcginnis, okay?
What are you kids doin'
up there botherin' Wendy?
We never bother Wendy.
She's always glad to see us.
That was really
a smart idea you had
about having Wendy take
all those art courses.
She could never get stuff
like that at city.
Art? Wendy's taking art?
Well, yeah.
Send her to one
of the best schools,
she ends up
with a bunch of artists.
What's wrong with artists?
Plenty.
I don't know
how you can say that.
You don't, huh?
Just take a man
like Michelangelo.
I read his biography.
Boy, what he didn't have
to go through, Mr. mccready.
But look
at what he ended up doing.
He painted the ceiling
of the sistine chapel.
Most people get dizzy
just looking up at it.
But he painted the whole thing
lyin' on his back.
I know you have a hard job,
but let's face it --
you could never do
anything like that.
It's awful hard to put down
a guy like Mr. Michelangelo.
I'm not putting down
anyone.
And I certainly don't need
a lecture on Mr. Michelangelo.
If you ask
my honest opinion,
you expect me to give you
an honest answer.
If you'll remember
correctly,
I didn't ask for your opinion
on anything.
I just asked you
where the dog food was.
Always nice talkin' to you,
Mr. mccready.
Can you imagine?!
Taking art!
Why did Claude archer think
I sent her up there?
So she could marry
an artist?!
[ Intercom buzzes ]
Yes.
I have Mr. mccready's daughter
on line 4.
Would he like to take it
in there?
Yes,
I'll take it in here.
Wendy?
Are you all right, hon?
Sure, dad. I'm fine.
I tried to get mom,
but she's not home.
She's probably gone shopping.
Is there anything
I can do for you?
I'd like to come home
next Saturday.
You can come home
any time you want to.
How are you planning
on getting down?
A boy's driving me.
A boy's driving you?
What kind of a boy?
Two arms, two legs --
that sort of thing.
I mean, what does he do?
Don't worry about him.
He's just your type.
He is?
You'll love him.
I will, huh?
She said I'll love him.
He goes to law school.
Goes to law school.
And he's vice-president
of his class.
Vice-president of his class.
And he's a free ride home.
And he's a -- huh?
He's a graduate student,
and I'm just a freshman.
I don't know if I want to.
It's about time you met
some more mature people.
Yeah, fine, honey.
I'll tell mom you'll be home
late Saturday afternoon.
Goodbye, hon.
Charlie, it looks like
you're off to a good start.
Yes, indeed.
Fine. And a couple of bottles
of champagne please.
Yeah, that's good,
but you must have imported.
1962. Make sure
it's well-chilled. Bye-bye.
1962 was a good year,
wasn't it, hon?
For what?
[ Doorbell rings ]
It can't be them already.
Hi, Mr. mccready.
Is Wendy home?
No, should she be?
I just called up north,
and the guy at the desk
told me
that she was on her way
down here.
Haven't you heard from her?
She did call my office
about a week ago.
Oh, well, I guess
she just must have been goin'
someplace else then.
I'm sorry
to have bothered you.
That's quite all right,
Bart.
Charlie,
why did you lie to that boy?
I didn't lie to him.
I just didn't admit anything,
that's all.
People are entitled to have
mental reservations, you know.
That's just legal talk!
You lied to him!
Wendy's
finally getting acquainted
with the right kind
of people,
and I don't want Bart around
ruining everything.
But Bart's always been around.
Well, he's not going to be
anymore.
Mom, dad, I'm home!
Sue: Wendy!
Charlie: Wendy!
Come on in, Roger.
Hello, dear.
Hello, darling.
Hi.
This is
Roger rhinehurst.
Roger.
[ Southern accent ]
Very nice to meet you.
Very nice
to meet you, Roger.
Won't you come in?
I'll be just
one moment.
Say, Roger, do I detect
a Southern accent there?
Yes, sir.
Where you from?
Charleston, sir.
Oh, lovely town.
How come you came all the way
out to huntington?
Well, father's
a former state senator.
He was a man who knew where
he wanted to get in life,
and he always got there.
He taught me the same thing.
So when it was time for me
to go to law school,
I said to myself,
"Roger, you want to be a state
senator like your father,
then you ought to go to
the best possible law school."
So here I am
out at huntington.
Needless to say,
father approved.
and I quite agree.
Yes, a young person
should really think about
what he's doing these days...
...the future
being so uncertain.
Yes, well, in my case,
I think things are
pretty well taken care of.
Good. Good.
Say, I forgot to offer you
a drink.
No, thank you.
I never touch hard liquor.
Oh!
That's nothing
to be ashamed of, Roger.
That's what father
always says.
I will take a little
ginger ale, though, please.
Ginger ale.
Of course. Wendy?
Nothing for me, dad.
I'm fine.
Be right back.
Sue...He's a law student...
And what a gentleman.
He's the one, hon.
Charlie,
you just met him.
It doesn't make
any difference, I tell you.
His father's
a state senator.
He'll probably be better
than that.
Charlie, I think
you're getting carried away.
Maybe I am, hon.
Maybe I am.
But he's the one
for our Wendy.
There we go.
Cheers.
I'd like to meet that father
of yours sometime.
Sounds like
an interesting man.
Yes, he is.
I admit some people
might think
he's a bit old-fashioned.
I mean,
he doesn't go in too much
for the modern way
of dress --
you know,
those various fads
that young people
have today.
Can't say that I do, either.
Being modern is one thing,
but there's certainly
no excuse for being sloppy.
We've never encouraged
that sort of thing
around this household.
Hey, Wendy,
how you doin'?!
[ Dog barking,
indistinct talking, laughter ]
I hope you don't mind us
poppin' in like this.
Roly poly,
what are you doin'?!
Cut that out, now.
Come on.
Cut that out.
How are you, Mr. mccready?
I was fine.
Stanley, kids,
this is Roger rhinehurst.
Very nice to meet you,
Mr. rhinehurst.
Are you a friend
of Mr. mccready's?
He's a friend of Wendy's.
Oh, I'm sorry.
That's quite all right.
Is this your dog?
Stanley: Yeah.
Did he get ya?
Are you all right?
I think so.
Get that dog out of here!
Come on, roly poly,
outside.
You'll be okay.
He didn't even break
the skin.
You won't even need a shot.
It's the dog
that should be shot.
You must own a cat.
I do have one
at the fraternity.
Roly poly hates cats.
Yes, well, I'm not a cat.
But roly poly hates cats
so bad,
he even hates the owners
of cats.
Stanley!
I'm sorry. This whole thing
is quite unusual.
What's quite unusual?
Wendy: I put him
in the truck, okay?
Where's Bart?
How come he's not around?
He'll be here
in a few minutes.
Bart?
Bart knows Wendy's home?
We were comin' back
from the beach,
and Pete said he saw Wendy,
so I gave Bart a ring.
[ Tires screech ]
Hey, it's Bart!
He looks upset.
If you'll excuse me,
I just remembered there's
something I forgot to do.
Hi, Bart.
Where's your dad?
He's in the den.
Aren't you gonna say
hello?
Hello.
Oh, Bart, there you are.
Wendy did come home
after all.
Yeah, I can see that.
I suppose
you're going to tell me
you didn't know
she was coming home?
Let me make something clear.
I don't have to tell you
everything
that goes on in this family.
But you don't have to lie
to me either.
You can call it a lie.
I call it
a mental reservation.
A mental reservation?
Do you call
that phony scholarship
a mental reservation?!
Phony?
What do you mean "phony"?
Come on,
don't act innocent!
Somehow you bought it
or you stole it!
But it was a phony,
and you know it!
You have no right
to come --
oh, dad...
Was it a phony scholarship?
Well, phony's
not the right word, hon.
Was it?
I did it
for your own good.
That's why
you came flying up.
I had to see Claude archer
and Claude archer only.
How dumb could I be?
Wendy...
I thought
I had done something --
something special.
You know,
I was even a little bit proud.
And all the time, you were
just making a fool out of me.
I never meant to make a fool
out of you, hon.
And you --
good old loyal Bart!
You knew all the time,
but you weren't man enough
to tell me!
Well, you've probably paid
for the first semester,
so I'll go back
and laugh it up
and make sure
you get your money's worth!
Goodbye, team.
Any mail from Wendy?
Uh, no, not today,
Mrs. levin.
Just bills, huh?
You know, it's a sad thing,
Mr. mccready.
Bills,
we always have with us.
Children, not always.
[ Engine turns over ]
The last thing
that you should do
is go running after her.
I had a daughter
who went a little flaky,
but I held my ground,
and she came around.
In this case, I'm the one
who went a little flaky.
[ Intercom buzzes ]
Yes?
Bart is here to see you.
Bart?
Send him in, please.
Hello, Mr. kershaw,
Mr. mccready.
Bart.
Uh, I, uh,I went up there
a couple of days ago
and waited
around her place.
She didn't come home
till real late.
Then she wouldn't even
talk to me.
Today I looked
all over school for her,
but I couldn't even
find her.
Thanks, Bart,
for your effort.
Yeah.
Mr. mccready...
I'm really worried
about her.
I know you are, Bart.
So am I.
This is more serious
than I thought, mccready.
[ Intercom buzzes ]
Gertrude: Mr. hershberger's on
his way in, and he looks wild!
Hershberger!
Oh, good morning,
Mr. hershberger.
Don't you
"good morning" me!
Don't you watch
television?!
Why should we?
I'm on every station,
that's why!
The strike's on?
Down with hershberger!
Down with hershberger...
I thought we had the
dockworkers all locked up.
Don't overworry.
That's just the half of it.
The meatpackers and truckers
went out in sympathy.
Even if I could get the goods
off the boats,
I couldn't get it
to the market.
Oh, when I think of all the
money I'm paying you people...
Hershberger's hamburger!
[ Indistinct yelling ]
Strike!
We've been infiltrated
by a bunch of nuts!
Strike!  Strik!
Hershberger's hamburger!
I think we've found
a youth.
What do you think
about this?
Why does everybody
hate me?
I don't know, but I'll
certainly look into it.
What is your name, sir?
Klutch!
[ Chuckles ]
Is that your first
or last name?
That's the whole name.
That's it -- the name.
Can you tell us
what group you represent?
This is the league
to keep ships
out of San Francisco bay.
The ships
are polluting this bay,
and we're gonna see
that they're outta here!
Isn't that right?!
Right!
You can say that again!
Man: We're not interested
in your lunatic ideas
about keeping ships out!
We're trying to run
a legitimate strike here,
and we don't want your people
in our line!
[ Indistinct yelling ]
We're not interested
in your strike!
We just want to keep
hershberger's crummy ships
out of the harbor, right?!
Well, if that isn't
the end!
The dockworkers won't unload
the goods off of my ships,
the truck drivers
wouldn't move them if they did,
and now this bunch of nuts
wants to keep my crummy ships
out of the harbor altogether!
Why do I pay you people
all this money
to keep me out of trouble?!
I have to agree with you.
You have every right
to complain.
What are you gonna do
about it?!
I'm thinking.
Why don't you go back
where you come from?!
[ Indistinct yelling ]
Come on, come on!
What do you do when
you're not picketing ships?
I paint.
Do you go to school?
I used to,
but...What do they know?
Nothin'!
With all the ships
in San Francisco bay,
how come you picked
Mr. hershberger's?
Because he has
the most ships.
He is the biggest offender
of all!
Isn't he?!
Yeah, he's a real creep!
That voice, that face...
They -- they ring a bell.
I've seen her before
somewhere.
Uh, what face?
The one that called me
a creep.
All these faces --
they all get to look alike
in a crowd.
With everybody
calling you a creep,
it's easy
to get confused.
Yeah, I guess.
It was probably
your imagination.
It is not my imagination!
Down with hershberger!
Ira, that girl looks
an awful lot like your daughter.
She is not
one of my daughters!
All of my daughters
are home, here, married!
Well, I've seen that girl
somewhere before.
Stopping all shipping --
it seems like that would
ruin our commerce.
Who cares?
Yeah, who cares?!
I'm sure she's your daughter.
She is not my daughter!
It seems like all these people
agree with you.
Why don't we ask
the people?
People,
do you agree with me?!
Yeah!
Yeah,
that goes double for me!
Hey!
Did you see
what he just did?!
He pushed her!
Wait till I get my hands
on you!
He'll rue the day
he did that!
This is all your fault!
It was your stupid idea
to call Claude archer!
And you, hershberger --
if it weren't for you
and those crummy ships,
none of this
would have happened!
Just think about that!
I don't know
how I got mixed up
with you people at all!
Where are you going?
I'm going up there.
I'm going to talk to her.
I'm going to get her.
This is ridiculous.
I'll get my bag,
go with you.
You're not going anywhere.
She's my daughter.
I know
she's your daughter.
She knows
Everybody knows
she's your daughter.
She is my daughter, too.
I want to talk to her
alone.
Alone!
Can you understand that?!
You've got to understand
my position.
I do understand
your position,
and you have done enough!
[ Sighs ]
Maybe you're right.
Oh, look, Charlie,
give me 24 hours.
Plan to meet me on the wharf
tomorrow for lunch.
I'll try
to have Wendy there,
and maybe we can
work things out after all.
I hope so.
Thanks.
Goodbye, Charlie.
[ Engine turns over ]
Mr. mccready...
Did you see Wendy on TV?
Of course
I saw Wendy on TV.
Everybody in the world
saw Wendy on TV.
That guy -- who was he?
How do I know?
What are we gonna do?
I don't know
what we're gonna do about it,
but Mrs. mccready and I
are going to meet with Wendy
tomorrow
at Fisherman's wharf.
Don't you think it'd help
if I went along?
Thanks, Bart,
but this is a family problem.
There's nothing
for you to do.
[ Sighs ]
Ú[ Engine turns over ]
What am I gonna do?
What is he gonna say?
He's going to be
all right.
We'll explain everything
to him.
Just a minute.
Is Wendy here?
Yes, she's sitting
right over there.
We've been up all night
thrashing this thing out,
and she's terribly sorry
about what happened.
But please be kind to her,
because...
[ Sighs ]
She has
a little problem.
A little problem?
Hi, Wendy.
Hi, dad.
How are you, darling?
Fine.
Well...
[ Chuckles ]
Hey,
isn't this the place
that has that wonderful
clam chowder?
Yeah. Yes.
Remember the last time
we were here?
Charlie waters
had too much to drink,
and he insisted
on wearing that funny hat.
Ha ha ha ha!
The management
threatened to throw him out!
Wendy,
what's your little problem?
I'm engaged.
Engaged? To whom?
Well...I'm afraid it's
to the fellow you saw on TV.
Klutch?! You're engaged
to klutch?!
Charlie, calm down.
Everybody's looking at you.
My daughter's getting married
to someone like that,
and you want me to be calm?!
You'd better explain it all
to your father.
Yes.
Well, dad...
I couldn't help it.
I just got involved.
He needed help,
and I felt sorry for him.
I guess
I felt sorry for myself, too.
It was right after
I left home.
He's the kind of guy
that gets an idea in his head
and can't get it out.
He thinks we're engaged,
and that's all there is to it.
Can't you tell him
that you're not?
It's not that easy.
Easy or not,
I'll take care of this.
Where is this character?
He has a houseboat
over in sausalito.
Tell your father
about the painting.
He gave me this painting --
his best abstract --
and then he said
we were engaged.
He said it was in place
of a ring,
and he won't take it back.
He says the painting's mine,
and I'm his,
and if anything
ever comes between us,
he'll do something awful,
like kill himself.
That's not all bad.
Charlie!
I'll handle this.
I don't want you
to get hurt.
I can handle myself.
Where is this joker?
Gate 7, bayside.
It's kind of tricky
getting there.
And, dad, watch out for him.
He's a little funny
when he's working.
Where's the painting?
In the check room.
It's big. I hope
you can get it in the cab.
That's the least
of my problems.
Do you have any idea
how we're going to get it
in there?
Well, I, uh,
I figured we'd --
we'd fit it in.
We don't own the highway.
I know that.
Maybe we could just tie it
on the roof.
It's against the law
to tie anything to the roof
of a cab without a luggage rack.
There happens to be laws
in this state.
Yes, I know
there happen to be laws.
I happen to be a lawyer.
I thought
you were a painter.
No, I'm not a painter.
Let's not worry
about what I am.
Just get me and this thing
over to sausalito, huh?
[ Whistle blows ]
[ Trolley bell clangs ]
Ohh!
[ Tires screech ]
[ Tires screeching ]
[ Horns honking ]
Oh, boy.
Is that yours, mister?
Yeah.
I tried to stop
as quick as I could.
It's not your fault.
Rolled clean on it,
didn't I?
It sure looks that way.
Move back!
What is this?!
What's goin' on here?!
Art exhibit.
[ Crowd laughing ]
We're busy!
Hold the horns!
Anybody hurt?
Nope.
Any damage?
All in the way
you look at it.
Who belongs to that thing?
I guess I do...In a way.
What are you gonna do
about it?!
Could you back up
a little?
On a cable?
Not without backing up
the whole city.
[ Crowd laughing ]
We're just gonna
have to plow through.
Well, if you have to,
you have to.
Everybody
out of the street.
It hurts me to do this.
Okay.
[ Bell clangs ]
Sure hope
it wasn't a masterpiece.
If it was,
he's got two of them now.
[ Bell clangs ]
[ Boat horn honks ]
Wait right here.
Mr. mccready...
What are you doing here?
You told me
you were comin' up here.
I wanted to see Wendy.
She's back at Fisherman's
wharf with her mother.
But that guy's back there
someplace, isn't he?
I'll take care of this.
You know...He, uh...
He looked kind of rough on TV.
Bart, this is my affair.
Please. I'll handle it.
You don't need any help?
Bart, please.
Stay out of it.
Stay out!!
[ Clears throat ]
Can't you read?
It says, "stay out."
Uh-huh.
None of this -- none of it --
is for sale.
That's a shame, but I'm
not here to buy anything.
If you think I would part
with works of art like this
for mere money,
you must be insane.
I can see your point,
but as I said before,
I don't want
to buy anything.
What did you say?
You don't want to buy
anything?
That's right.
What are you doing here?
Who are you?
I'm Wendy's father.
So...You're Wendy's father.
Daddy's come
to save his little girl.
Well, you're too late.
We're engaged.
Uh, no, you're not.
I've brought back the ring.
Aah!
My beautiful...Painting.
Uh, heh heh.
It was an accident.
But who knows?
Could be worth
twice as much this way.
You...Barbarian!
Aah!
My precious cat!
Now you've done it.
Done what?
You'll pay.
Oh, no, no.
No, no, wait a minute.
I haven't done anything!
Can't we talk this over?
You madman!
You ruined everything!
I haven't ruined anything!
I just came to tell you
you're not engaged!
You fiend!
Aah! Aah!
Why don't you just try
to relax a little.
For this...
You will die!
No, no, no!
Now, wait a minute!
Mr. klutch, I feel it
only fair to warn you,
as an attorney of the law,
according to section 190
in the penal code,
murder is a felony!
Aah!
You wouldn't want to spend
the rest of your life
on probation, would you?!
Yeah, I guess you would.
What did my daughter
see in you?!
Heh heh!
[ Groans ]
Goodbye...Mr. Klutch.
[ Growling ]
[ Cheers and applause ]
Man: He sure looks good
in red.
Man #2: What a glass jaw
he's got.
Thanks for stepping in,
Bart,
although
it really wasn't necessary.
I had him anyway.
Uh...
However...
On the other hand,
I guess
I would have deserved it
if he had belted me
all over the place, huh?
Bart...
[ Sighs ]
How'd you know?
About what?
About Wendy
and the scholarship.
How'd you know?
Because when you win
a scholarship,
they notify you two weeks
after you've taken the test,
not two days
before the term starts!
That's how I know!
Bart...
You won the scholarship,
didn't you?
Why didn't you say
something?
I guess I...Decided
to go to city.
Because you thought Wendy
was going there, right?
Well, yeah!
[ Sighs ]
Let's go home...
All of us.
Dad?
I wanted you
to be the first to see.
Wendy...
Ah, you look
like a dream, honey.
You don't look so bad
yourself.
For an old man,
I'll hold up.
We'd better get going.
Mom's left already.
I'm waiting just for you.
Dad,
we're going to be late!
Don't worry, honey.
It's fashionable
for the bride
to be a few minutes late
on her wedding day.
It's 10 minutes after already!
Bart will be going crazy!
Get us to the church
as fast as you can.
Yes, sir.
[ Tires screech ]
Stanley!
Not today!
What are you doing parked
in the middle of the street?!
What are you doin'
drivin' so fast?!
All right, we can
straighten this out later,
but now we have to get
to the church.
We can't go any further
right now.
Oh!
Don't worry, Wendy.
I'll get you to the wedding.
Thanks, Stanley.
You don't think
we're goin' to the church
in that thing, do you?!
We don't have any choice!
We're late already!
I guess we have to.
Mr. mccready,
you can't ride in the front.
Why not?
We can't all fit.
Roly poly's in the front.
We can't put him in the back.
He'll eat the stuff.
The dog sits in front,
and I sit in back?
You wouldn't want Wendy to,
would ya?
No, I wouldn't want
Wendy to!
Let's just go!
Don't slam...
The door.
What's the matter?
Nothin', I hope.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
What could be
keeping them?
Oh, reverend,
I don't know what happened.
They left the house
more than 30 minutes ago!
All I know is I've got
another wedding scheduled
in five minutes.
They'll be here,
reverend.
They'd better be.
I don't know what it is
with you people!
You never seem able
to get yourselves organized!
I'm sure that something
terrible has happened,
or mccready
would have been here on time.
What's that?
Haven't I seen your picture
somewhere, Sonny?
Dad, are you all right?
Splendid, honey.
Everything's just fine.
That's good.
It sure is an honor
driving you to your wedding.
Thank you, Stanley.
Excuse me.
Don't get me wrong.
I'm sure
this is no fault of yours.
It's just that
my Saturdays are hard enough
without this sort of thing
happening.
Ah, thank heavens.
Here they are now.
Ohh! Ohh!
That's not my daughter!
It's the bride
from the next service!
Nothing like this
has ever happened before!
I don't know how
to explain this!
Here she is now!
She came
in a delicatessen truck?
At least she got here.
Let's everybody get moving
into the church!
Places! Places! Places!
Oh, here.
Everybody, move!
Hey, get me out of here!
The door's stuck,
and the father of the bride's
in there.
Out of my way, Sonny!
I'll get him out!
Out of my way!
Mrs. mccready,
what's happening now?!
My husband's stuck
in the truck!
Stuck in the truck?!
I got him sprung now, honey!
Can we get things goin' then,
please?!
Right away!
Here we go!
¶ LA LA LA LA
LA LA LA LA LA LA LA ¶
oh, darling!
You made it!
Yeah.
[ Sniffs ]
What's the matter?
Nothing. Nothing.
All right, everybody,
hurry up into the church!
[ Organ music plays ]
¶ These are the best times ¶
¶ the moments
we can't let slip away ¶
¶ life's little game we play ¶
¶ living from day to day ¶
¶ oooooh, oooooh ¶
¶ but once in a lifetime ¶
¶ a minute like this
is ours to share ¶
¶ remember these moments well ¶
¶ for moments like these
are rare as dreams ¶
¶ and golden rainbows ¶
¶ soft as nights
when summer wind blows by ¶
¶ together we laugh and cry ¶
¶ together we'll learn to fly ¶
¶ ooh ooh ooh ooh ooh... ¶
mccready, somebody
ought to tell you that --
oh, never mind.
Come on, dad.
It's time.
Honey...I smell.
Maybe just a little bit
of liverwurst,
but it's nothing
to worry about.
Now, come on.
¶ Oooooh, oooooh... ¶
I wanted it to be so nice
for you, Wendy.
It is nice, dad.
I wanted it
to be beautiful.
But it is beautiful.
It's so beautiful.
Everyone's laughing at us,
Wendy.
It doesn't matter.
You see,
Bart's up there now...
...and I know he loves me.
And I know you and mom
love me.
And all my old friends
are here.
And I know
maybe they're kind of nuts,
but they love me, too.
And they're hoping
and praying
that Bart and I
have a great life.
And that's not bad, dad.
You're right, Wendy.
That's not half bad.
¶ Come take my hand ¶
¶ come take my hand ¶
¶ together we'll cross
the timeless sands ¶
¶ the timeless sands ¶
¶ chasing the endless sun ¶
¶ the endless sun ¶
¶ living our lives as one ¶
¶ these are the best times ¶