I don't know, George.
Is it too windy for flying a kite?
Thinking that's a yes.
George?
George!
Hi.
You're right, George. It's awesome.
You want to fly it yourself?
And regretting this in three, two, one.
George!
Hey.
Hi.
You feel safe with your feet
on the ground
- Where everything's predictable
- George, come down from there!
So many possibilities passing you by
Well, drop your things
And look up to the sky
Sorry about that.
My monkey got carried away.
- 'Cause when you're up for anything
- George!
- That's not safe!
- You reach higher
You take your worries and say goodbye
When you're up for anything
- You live open and free
- Sorry about that.
So come on, come on with me
- I guess you never heard it before
- Hi.
- George!
- But nothing is impossible
Sometimes you got to give it another try
But dig deep and put your fears aside
'Cause when you're up for anything
you reach higher
- Begging your pardon. Have a nice day!
- You take your worries and say goodbye
When you're up for anything
You live open and free
So come on, come on with me, yeah
You can wait for life to bring you
- All your hopes and dreams
- Bye.
- Wrapped in a bow
- Yikes!
I won't tell you what to do
No
- But happiness is out there
- My bad.
And how much you can grab is up to you
It's up to you
George, the park is no place
to fly a kite.
'Cause when you're up for anything
you reach higher
You take your worries and say goodbye
When you're up for anything
You live open and free
So come on, come on
When you're up for anything
you reach higher
You take your worries and say goodbye
When you're up for anything
you live open and free...
Okay, now you gotta go
a little to the left.
Now to the right. No!
George, that was very, very, very...
not good.
When will you learn caution, George?
Forget about "no"
and "yes" and "banana."
You need to learn the word "caution."
How about the word "lawsuit?"
I'm so sorry.
Here's my contact information.
My insurance company
and dry cleaner are on the back. I...
There you go. Yes, one for you, too.
It'll come out. I promise.
Come along, George.
Bye!
Okay, George. I need you
to wait here while I get cleaned up.
And please...
no more surprises.
The time for adventure is over.
George?
I'll be right there.
Hi.
George?
Come down from there.
But he's havin' so much fun.
Yes, but he shouldn't be...
Who are you?
I've come to see a man about a monkey.
Let me guess. Yellow hat,
yellow suit, look of deep distress.
You must be Ted,
which means that must be...
Hello.
Hello, George.
It's an honor to meet you.
Hal Houston from GSA,
the Global Space Agency.
And this is my tactical assistant,
Andrew.
- Hello.
- Hi.
We've had our eye on George
for some time.
- Look, if we owe you for any damage...
- Oh, no, no. Nothing like that.
We want George
for a very important mission.
A space mission.
Yes, you! Hop aboard.
Did you know the first astronauts
were monkeys?
They went boldly
where no man has gone before.
They were heroes.
How would you like to be one of them?
So, what is this mission?
I'm glad you asked. Andrew?
Welcome to majestic Central Africa.
Oops.
As I was saying,
majestic Central Africa!
This is where you came from, George.
Lately it's been getting a lot of rain,
causing rivers to overflow.
And do you know what that means? Andrew.
That's right, flooding.
To help control the flooding, we created
a device about as big as your hand,
which we call the Regional
Dam Synchronizer. RDS.
We put it in our satellite,
and with the satellite...
we can control
the distribution of water.
We call it Project Stop Flooding.
The problem is...
and this is the embarrassing part.
Our satellite containing the RDS
has failed and can't be fixed.
And without it... Andrew.
Oh, boy.
More flooding.
Yes, George. The flooding is very bad
for the animals and the land.
That's why we need a brave monkey
to go up in space
and get that RDS,
so we can install it...
Here in our new Ground
Communications Tower in Africa.
Right on the Louis Leakey Dam.
We're not taking a chance on putting it
directly in a space satellite again.
Why can't you just put another RDS
in that tower and not go to space?
It's custom-built! It would take
forever to create a new one.
So what do you say, George?
Can we count on ya?
No! No! I mean...
No kidding, that's a valuable mission,
but why not send a human?
The human-size rockets
have all been moved to museums.
But I tracked down a monkey capsule
in mint condition.
Thanks for the offer, Mr. Houston,
but I don't think it's a good idea.
I'm sorry, George.
Not everyone loves adventure like we do.
Let's go, Andrew.
Hey. Wait.
I didn't say no, exactly.
Are you sure this is safe?
Why, it's as safe as flying a kite!
Okay, George.
But only if you complete
the training without a hitch.
Let's get you in training!
Let's go
Oh, yeah
Well, let's say
you're caught up in a bind
Well, I've got the perfect guy in mind
He sees things a different way
A stumble here and there,
but things are okay
At first glance
you just might have your doubts
But this guy he always works it out
Stays tough and saves the day
'Cause giving up ain't in his DNA
Yeah, he might be a little strange
But he'll help you, yes, he can
Yeah, he's only just
your ordinary superman
- He can help you, yes he can
- Yes, he can
He's your ordinary superman
He's so cool you wanna be like him
Nonstop and never givin' in
Head first and steely-eyed
When things are down
he's always lookin' upside
He might take a different route than you
But he's got a different point of view
Leaves most folks scratchin' their heads
If only they would listen to what I said
That he might be a little strange
But he'll help you, yes, he can
Yeah, he's only just
your ordinary superman
He can help you, yes, he can
Yes, he can, he's your ordinary superman
- He can help you, yes, he can
- Baby, yes, he can
He's your ordinary superman
- Yeah! Yeah!
- He's just a superman...
George!
George, I now certify you space-ready.
What do you say, Ted?
I say...
Congratulations, George.
You've got the right stuff.
I'm gonna miss you, George.
Be careful up there.
I can't go with you, George,
but I brought you something
to keep you company.
I love you, too.
And I'll be right here waiting for you.
Good luck on your mission,
Space Monkey George.
Relax, Ted. Everything's gonna be fine.
Are you sure?
Yes!
I personally reviewed and accounted for
all aspects of this mission.
Trust me, nothing will go wrong.
Andrew, let's get the party started.
Space Monkey George,
are you ready for launch?
T minus five...
four, three, two, one.
Liftoff!
The capsule will auto dock
with the satellite in five...
four... three...
two... one.
Capsule has successfully
docked with the satellite.
Yeah!
Space Monkey George, proceed.
Good luck, George.
Okay, George.
Now just the way you practiced.
- Yeah!
- He has the RDS in his possession!
Hug it up, Teddy boy!
People...
Andrew, do something!
George, the RDS!
You've lost the RDS!
Go get it, George!
He did it!
That's my George.
Nice work, Space Monkey George.
We're bringing you home.
Activating capsule return.
And that's lunch.
We're celebrating. Come on, George.
You can join us.
We call it celestial slime.
Astronauts love it.
Or you can check the bag
I hid behind your seat.
Peanut butter and banana, his favorite.
I hope you don't mind.
No problem. It's my favorite, too.
Take five, George. You deserve it.
Should George be doing that?
Ted, stop worrying and relax.
The mission's accomplished.
What could happen now?
I've lost control.
- Houston, we have a problem!
- What?
Capsule is in freefall.
Freefall? That's not good! Right?
Technically, that's not good.
Yahoo!
Save my monkey!
Eject, George! Hit the red button!
George? The red button!
Eject! Hit the red button!
Emergency ejection enabled.
Ejection.
- He ejected!
- That's great! Now what?
Now we go get him.
Where are we going?
Central Africa.
Of course! Don't worry, Ted.
I'll find our monkey.
I'm not worried. I'm coming with you.
Hello?
So what's the plan?
Let's take a look
at the surrounding area. Andrew.
- Welcome to majestic Central...
- Let's not. Where's George?
Last report had George
over the Lotta Watta Falls.
We're pretty sure
he's within a 500-mile radius.
- 500-mile radius?
- You mean circumference.
I'm pretty sure it's radius.
Circumference goes around the circle.
- Definitely circumference.
- Hold on.
Five hundred miles of anything
is really big.
Have you ever found an astronaut before?
We've never lost one before.
But we have five teams out looking.
Now you've got six.
Ted?
- Where are you going?
- To find my monkey.
Circumference?
Radius.
Yeah.
Excuse me. I need a pilot and a plane.
No tours today. Pilot out sick.
There must be someone who can fly.
Listen, friend. I told you.
We don't have any pilots available. Hey.
Global Space Agency?
Are you an astronaut?
Oh, that. It's a long story.
You guys know more
about piloting than anyone.
You can take the plane yourself.
- No, you don't understand.
- And if you want to get into the air today,
you'll need to fly it.
Flying an airplane...
how hard can it be?
It's like a car, except you drive
in the air where you can fall and...
What am I thinking? I can't do this!
That wasn't so hard.
I'm in the air.
And I'm heading for a tree!
Trees all look alike.
Except for that one
with the parachute on it.
Parachute? Yes!
"Reduce throttle.
Gently touch the water."
Simple.
Oh, no.
Look out!
Come in, Mr. Plane Rental Man.
I have the funniest story to tell ya.
Or not.
Okay.
Got map.
And subway tokens.
All right.
Everything's under control. Here I go.
I've got to find George.
The jungle is no place for a monkey.
Everything's so different
How'd you end up here
Reach out and grab it
Let your worries disappear
'Cause it's a once in a lifetime
opportunity
Is waitin' straight ahead
That's what I said
And if you fall down and skin your knee
Well, you get back up again
Roll with the changes
Take a few chances now and then
Make every moment count
And you just might have
the time of your life
Welcome to paradise
Hey, you, you're missing out
on all the fun
Just take it easy
seems you're always on the run
Slow it down
Take in the scenery
and give into the magic of the day
That's what I say
Woke up to sunshine
Now it's pouring rain
No guarantees, enjoy it all the same
I'm telling you,
it's all how you take it
Grab those lemons
and you make some lemonade
You got it made
And if you fall down and skin your knee
Well, you get back up again
Roll with the changes
Take a few chances now and then
Make every moment count
And you just might have
the time of your life
Welcome to paradise
Everything's so different
It's all so strange
Reach out and grab it
Roll with the change
And if you fall down and skin your knee
Well, you get back up again
Roll with the changes
Take a few chances now and then
Make every moment count
And you just might have
the time of your life
Welcome to paradise
To paradise
Goodnight, George, wherever you are.
Team 5. Come in, Team 5.
- Sir.
- Not now, Andrew.
I'm trying to contact Team 5.
You're speaking into your hot dog.
They're very good, by the way.
Team 5, anything yet?
No sign of the monkey or the capsule.
I'm tired of waiting around, Andrew.
There's an old saying...
"If you want something done right,
do it yourself."
This is Search Command One.
We're heading out.
Hot dog.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
I can't take this!
I just want my monkey so I can go home!
George?
Thank goodness I've found you!
I was so worried about you.
That is the last time you go into
outer space and crash-land on Earth,
you hear me?
I missed you so much, George.
Now, let's go home.
You know the problem with maps?
They only work if you know
where you are.
They should invent a map to help you know
where you are on the map.
Okay, I'm thinking the river is here.
What do you think, George?
George?
We're lost in Central Africa.
We need to work on getting home.
Ta-da!
Things around here
could be dangerous, George.
You need to exercise a little caution.
What I mean is that you need
to be more careful.
You're a curious little monkey,
and I know you like to play,
but from now on
I want you to stick by me, okay?
George?
George!
George? What did I say about caution?
Those are wild elephants.
I'm sure they are nice,
but so's a city bus
until it runs over you.
This is my serious voice now...
I want you to come down this minute.
I am not getting
on that big smelly thing!
Bye.
Now I want you to promise me, George,
no more adventures.
You got it?
You can't just go around wherever you like
in a jungle. You need to watch yourself.
Now I'm pretty sure if we go
this way, we'll reach the river.
And when we get to a village,
they'll call Mr. Houston for us.
We'll be home before you can say
"banana." Right, George?
George?
Oh, no. Remember? Caution?
George! Where are you?
What did I just say?
No! No, no! Bad George!
Now, let's go.
You need to learn that I'm the grown-up
and you're the monkey.
Monkeys do what grown-ups say.
That's how it's gonna be from now on.
No more Mr. Nice Man
With The Yellow Hat.
I'm putting my foot down!
Oh, boy.
What's all that growling?
Help! Please! Get me down.
That gorilla wants to eat me for dinner!
Don't be a worrywart. He's a vegetarian.
Well, except for a bug or two.
Right, Seymour?
- You... You know him?
- I rescued him.
I run this animal preserve.
Kulinda, Naja P. Doctor.
He helps me catch poachers like you.
Animal preserve? Poachers?
No, this is a terrible mistake.
I'm not a poacher.
I'm a museum director.
Right. And that's your city monkey?
It's true! Tell her, George.
This... this is just
a big misunderstanding.
It's really quite funny.
Come on, little fellow.
Let's get you home.
You like the hat?
Seymour, bring him.
Tree branch ahead. I wonder
if you could watch the head.
Okay, we'll work on that.
Have some fruit, little monkey.
I'll be down in a minute.
George.
George, I shouldn't have blown my top.
I guess even big people
can be wrong sometimes.
You know what I was really wrong about?
You're not bad, George.
You're the best George
in the whole world.
I'm so sorry.
Forgive me?
Buddy.
What's gotten into you two?
Come here, little monkey.
Look, Dr. Kulinda...
Don't try to form a bond with me
by using my name.
Call me...
Dr. African Scientist Worker Lady.
Okay, Dr. Worker...
African Scientist.
African Scientist Doctor Lady.
This can all be cleared up.
I just need one phone call.
Gonna lawyer up? Well, forget it, pal.
The phones are out.
I see you've met Strich.
She likes bananas.
Is there any way of communicating
with the outside world?
'Fraid not. Unless you poached
some pigeons, too.
All the phones went out the day they shot up
that rocket for the Project Stop Flooding.
Hey. You know about that?
That was George's mission.
Wait a minute.
You're the monkey astronaut
we've been hearing about?
That's right. And I'm with George.
I did hear that astronaut was friends
with some big city bozo
with a yellow hat.
That's me!
I should have figured it out.
How many ridiculous hats like yours
are there in the world?
I know, exactly! What?
Why didn't you say so earlier?
Seymour, untie him.
No! Okay, Seymour, remember that...
Watch the head thing!
Okay. Gettin' a little better.
Anything, Andrew?
Not yet, sir.
The map shows Kulinda
Animal Preserve is within range.
Maybe it's worth a flyover.
I think it's highly unlikely that George
would have gotten that far.
Well, it's just...
Well, you never know and...
Well, I've heard Doctor Kulinda's
tree house is so cool and awesome.
Well, if George made it to this area,
I'd bet he'd go there.
All right, fan-boy.
We'll give it a flyby.
Yes!
Sorry about the mix-up, Ted.
We appreciate what you are trying to do.
The river flooding
seems worse each year.
Hey, buddy. You did your best.
Dr. Lady Scientist?
Now that I know you're not
completely despicable,
you can call me Naja.
Okay.
Naja. So, there's nothing we can do
to fix the communications?
Nothing.
What? What is it, George?
I do hear something.
Like a helicopter?
Mr. Houston, come in.
Come in, Mister Houston.
We've had a sighting
of a monkey in a spacesuit.
Where is he?
A small village 30 miles east
of the Big River.
I'm on my way!
What did I tell ya, Andrew?
I knew I'd find our monkey.
Good job, sir.
It's turned around.
Wait! Wait!
It's gone.
We're stranded.
I want to go home to my city,
where it's nice and safe,
and my dry cleaner
expects me every Monday.
Get your hat on.
Before you get all misty-eye
about your dry cleaned life,
you should see something first.
Looks like you made
a new friend, George.
There's a place where the air is clean
The trees are towering,
the grass is green
And the sun smiles down
Feel the power and embrace the call
Take it in before it's all gone
- Here's your chance
- Hi.
Grab it now
And the dreams you long for
Can all be found right here
It's the beautiful wild
So full of strength and majesty
Lift up your heart
Open your eyes and see
Every inch out here is so alive
Where the hidden and the strong survive
It's the way it's always been
Yeah
New experiences everywhere
Just look closer, can you see it there?
The surprises never end
And the more you see
The more you're left in awe
Yeah!
It's the beautiful wild
Lift up your heart
Open your eyes and see
This does kind of grow on you.
- Ya think?
- Yeah.
That was fun. Kind of...
Exciting, yeah. Yes, I guess so.
Well, that explains why
our communications are out.
The antenna on the dam
has been knocked down.
But they'll fix it soon.
Can't live without our cell phones.
I wonder how that could have happened.
Hey, is there any chance that's the tower
where the RDS is supposed to go?
It sure is.
What is it, George?
- The space capsule!
- Let me see.
Oh, not good.
It's across the Forsaken Ravine.
You think the RDS
is still on board the capsule?
You want us to go get it?
I don't know, George.
You heard what Dr. Kulinda said earlier.
She used words like "ravine"
and "forsaken."
He's right. I don't think
you can get across.
George, you heard the doctor.
They'll fix the cell tower,
we'll call Houston,
and then you'll finish the mission.
Good day.
Andrew, tell 'em we're looking
for a monkey in a spacesuit.
We are looking for a monkey
in a spacesuit.
Not in English.
We speak English.
Well done, Andrew.
Have you seen the monkey?
You're not my monkey!
And I don't suppose you're going to be able
to tell me where you found that suit?
Well, Andrew, back to our search.
Sir, you better take a look at this.
There's a category 5 storm approaching.
One, two, three, four, five.
That's a lot of categories.
Better have the search team
return to base. Us, too.
What about Ted and George?
Oh, this is not good.
I did not need a storm now, Andrew.
I did not need this storm.
George, what's going on?
- That's some storm.
- Rain's coming. Better get prepared.
- I see. Is it gonna flood?
- I hope not.
Gee, I wish we could let Mr. Houston
know about the capsule right now.
I do, too. There's a good chance
the rain will wash it away.
But then the RDS could get destroyed.
That could be the end
of Project Stop Flooding.
I'm afraid so, Ted.
No.
Now, I'm sorry, George.
I know you want to get the RDS,
but you know it's impossible.
Well, it's very dangerous.
But maybe not impossible.
No, it's not a good idea.
No, we're not going.
You agree with me, right?
Don't ask my opinion.
You don't want to hear it.
Okay. Let's give it a shot.
Good luck. I wish I could go with you,
but I have to stay here
and take care of the animals.
Hopefully, the old bridge is still there.
And hopefully, it's still passable.
Almost got it.
Here we go. Bye!
Careful with that map, George.
That's what's keeping this adventure
from becoming a bad-venture.
I just thought of that.
Strich? What are you doing here?
Well...
guess this is where we get out.
Oh, no.
Come on. Come on, everyone.
I don't believe it.
We made it to the capsule.
We almost made it to the capsule.
Sorry, George. I know
you really wanted to get there.
George...
I don't think that bridge is safe.
I don't think it's on the same
continent as safe.
Oh, boy.
George, this is nuts!
Don't look down, Ted.
In fact, don't look anywhere.
Sweet.
I got the hang of this adventure thing.
Follow me, George.
Crocodile!
Perhaps you haven't noticed!
I'm not a monkey!
Oh, boy.
Monkey see, monkey do!
Yes!
Looks good as new.
The radio still works?
This is our ticket home, George!
Let's see. There must be a switch.
Hello. Can anyone hear me?
Other than those lion cubs?
George, don't you know if there's cubs,
that probably means there's a mama?
Or papa?
Let's get out of here.
What are you doing, George?
We don't want him to follow us.
Oh, you're saving the lion.
Hang on, lion!
Nice job, George.
Now I think it's our turn
to get rescued.
All this waiting, Andrew.
I want an ETA and I want it now!
Sir, the hot chocolate
will be ready in five minutes.
I can live with that.
This is Ted calling for Mr. Houston.
Please, come in.
Ted, Hal Houston here!
He's there! Mr. Houston. I found George.
We got him! That's astonishing, Ted!
And we retrieved the RDS
from the capsule.
Holy Canaveral! You're heroes.
Can you come get us?
You'll have to sit tight. We can't
get to you until after the storm.
There may be flooding.
Oh, no.
- Sir?
- Not now, Andrew.
But, sir, if Ted and George
could get to the satellite tower
and install the RDS,
that could stop the flooding.
Andrew, that's the most
ridiculous thing I...
Actually, it would.
Well, that's a tall order.
What do you say, boys?
Quite an ambitious plan.
But I've already crossed half a jungle,
swung on a vine
and faced down a lion, so...
What's another many-mile jaunt
through wild animals and hostile terrain?
We picked the right crew for this job.
Bring 'em home, Andrew.
I've locked on your signal
and I know where you are.
Go down the ravine to the Big River.
Go up the river to Louis Leakey Dam.
The satellite tower is on top.
You can't miss it.
Ravine, Big River, tower. Got it!
I'll tell the dam you're on your way.
Good luck. And take care of that RDS.
Team 6 is on it.
The RDS!
Oh, George, wait!
I'm a vine-swinging rookie, remember?
You mean me? Up there?
Oh, boy.
We've got him now.
I read somewhere that animals
are as afraid of us as we are of them.
Which means he's very, very afraid.
No, George.
You just sent him packing.
Oh, hi!
You make the best friends, George.
Well, the good news is
we have the RDS back.
The bad news is I have
no idea where we are.
Looks like an old log flume.
What? The log flume?
Good idea, George.
It should lead us to the river.
We'll be okay, Strich.
You can go on home.
- Thanks for your help!
- Bye!
- We have to be getting close.
- Hey!
Thanks.
I think... Yes! Look!
The Big River!
Oh, no!
Does this thing come with brakes?
Oh, no! We're going the wrong way!
Oh, boy. What are we gonna do?
Hey, George, that's my plane.
We got this.
Oh, yeah!
Bye!
Oh, no. The pontoon is loose!
George, you're gonna have
to take the control.
Sure, if I can fly a plane, you can.
Just go straight, and when I say to,
pull back on that steering wheel thing.
Better pull up, George.
Pull up, pull up, pull up, pull up!
Oh, no.
Well, nothing we can do now.
Nice work, pilot.
I'll take it from here.
There's Leakey Dam and the tower.
Right, George. The dock.
We just have to set down...
with only one pontoon.
Okay, lean left.
All right, George!
Hey! We were expecting you!
- We need to get to your satellite tower.
- There's no way up in this rain.
Not a problem. We've got George.
Oh, this doesn't look good.
It was a good try.
After all this.
Let's go inside.
You know something, George?
I think this may be one of those times
we throw caution to the wind.
What is he doing?
George?
You ready to go fly a kite?
Good luck, Space Monkey George.
Yeah!
George!
That's some monkey.
Is that what I think it is?
Project Stop Flooding activated.
The water's receding!
That was amazing, George.
I'll go on an adventure
with you any time.
Space Monkey George,
I present you with this hero's medal.
- Don't think we forgot you, Ted.
- For me?
- Yup.
- Really?
Congratulations!
Ted, George, a gift.
Next time you won't need a kite.
Oh, my.
Yeah!