[EXHALES]
# When the early morning hours
have come and gone #
# Through the misty morning
showers I greet the dawn #
# For when its light has hit the ground #
# There's lots of treasures to be found #
# Underneath the lovely London sky #
[MAN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
[HORSE WHINNIES]
# Though the lamps I'm turning
down please don't feel blue #
# For in this part of London town
the light shines through #
# Don't believe the things you've read #
# You never know what's up ahead #
# Underneath the lovely London sky #
# Have a pot of tea #
# Mend your broken cup #
# There's a different point of view awaiting
you if you would just look up #
- MAN: Oy! Get out of here!
- # I know #
# Yesterday you had to borrow
from your chums #
# Seems the promise of tomorrow
never comes #
# But since you dreamed the night away #
# Tomorrow's here, it's called today #
# So count your blessings you're a lucky guy #
# For you're underneath the lovely London sky #
[WHISTLING]
Morning, Jack.
[CONTINUES WHISTLING]
- Admiral above decks!
- # Listen #
# Soon the slump will disappear, it won't be long #
# Sooner than you think you'll
hear some bright new song #
You're all right, children?
# So hold on tight to those you love
and maybe soon from up above #
# You'll be blessed, so keep on looking high #
# While you're underneath
the lovely London sky #
# Lovely London sky #
[BIG BEN CHIMING]
Great steaming clams! They've done it again!
Those blundering blowfish have
rung Big Ben too soon!
Storm clouds. On the horizon, sir.
Heading straight for Cherry Tree Lane.
Batten down the hatches, Mr. Binnacle!
Rough seas ahead, I fear!
[ELLEN SCREAMING]
[WATER SPLASHING]
Michael!
- Jane!
- What is it, Ellen?
The bloody sink's exploded!
- Oh, dear.
- Oh, not again!
- JANE: Annabel! John!
- We heard, Aunt Jane! I'll ring the plumbers!
- I'll turn off the water at the mains.
- JANE: Yes, thank you, darlings.
Um, Ellen, fetch us a mop and towels, will you?
ELLEN: I told him to get them pipes fixed.
Been here since the Romans ruled.
- What's happening?
- ANNABEL: Don't go in the kitchen, Georgie.
Not without your wellies. Oh, uh, yes.
Hello. We've had a burst pipe.
WOMAN: [OVER PHONE] Just one moment, please.
- [KNOCKING ON DOOR]
- Excuse me. Ellen!
Can you please get the door?
I've got the plumbers here.
That was quick work, wasn't it?
- Here, Georgie. Take them.
- 17 Cherry Tree Lane.
- MAN: [OVER PHONE] By the park?
- Yes, I'm coming! Blimey.
- Ah! Good morning, mum.
- They don't look much like plumbers to me.
- I meant on the phone.
- We are not plumbers, we are lawyers.
Lawyers?
And here's me hoping you might prove useful.
[GOODING STAMMERS]
- Water's off!
- And the plumbers are on their way.
Well done, everybody.
- Phew! Such excitement.
- What are you doing here, Aunt Jane?
JANE: We're handing out breakfast
at the union hall.
I snuck away for a morning hug.
- Come here, Georgie.
- [BANGING ON DOOR]
Will you stop that banging? Barely eight
o'clock on a Sunday morning!
What you doing with my mop?
Forgive the intrusion, mum.
Our current workload prevents
us from taking weekends off.
GOODING: We would like to have a word
with Mr. Banks, if he is available.
"Notice of Repossession"?
Wait there.
Goodness. I'll be cleaning
up that mess all morning.
- Here, let me take that for you.
- Oh, thank you, sweetheart.
- Excuse me, sir. The wolves are at the door.
- What do they want?
Well, a good thrashing, if you ask me.
- Oh, it's like the River Thames in there!
- Don't worry, Ellen. I'll clean up.
- Why don't you see to... to the breakfast?
- Well, yes, somebody's got to, haven't they?
Unless we all wanna starve.
Why don't you let Ellen clean up?
I'm afraid, lately, that means
more work for me.
The other day, I found a butcher's
sack hanging on the coat rack...
- and my hat was in the larder.
- Oh, dear.
GEORGIE: Can we go to the park?
- Ah! I need a brush! I look a fright.
- ANNABEL: No, Georgie.
Michael, don't forget you've
got guests at the door.
MICHAEL: Oh, right.
- GEORGIE: Whoa.
- I'm sorry. We're...
struggling through a bit of chaos this morning.
- Please.
- GOODING: So it seems.
Unfortunately, Mr. Banks,
our business cannot wait.
- ELLEN: Excuse me, sir.
- Today, we were...
ELLEN: How exactly am I supposed
to make breakfast
when there's nothing in the larder but
pickled herrings and marmalade?
The groceries. I meant to go yesterday, huy!
Very well. Pickled herrings for breakfast
and marmalade for lunch.
There's a shop across the park, will
be open. The three of us can go.
- Thank you, John.
- But you said we would go to the park today!
We can cut through the park on the way.
- GEORGIE: But...
- ANNABEL: Enough, Georgie, come along.
- I'll take that, Father.
- Oh, thank you. Uh, please come through.
GOODING: Uh...
MICHAEL: Now, what is it that I can do for you?
I am Hamilton Gooding. This
is Mr. Templeton Frye.
We are solicitors with the
law firm of Gordy, Cordry,
- Gooding and Frye.
- [JANE GIGGLES]
What?
- No. Sorry, nothing.
- "Spruce"? Is that your garden club?
No, no, it's the, uh... Society for
the Protection of the Rights
- of the Underpaid Citizens of England.
- A labor organizer.
- She's a labor organizer.
- Yes.
Yes, but we also run soup kitchens. It's a
never-ending job these days, I'm afraid.
- I'm sure it is, Mrs. Banks.
- Miss Banks, actually. I'm Michael's sister.
- My wife passed away this last year.
- That's awful. Those poor children.
- Yes, our deepest condolences.
- Thank you. Forgive me, what brings the two
- of you here this morning?
- I'm going to say my goodbyes.
I'm late for work.
Mr. Banks, you took out a loan with
the Fidelity Fiduciary Bank...
- last year against the value of your home.
- You did what? Michael.
I had to, Jane.
With Kate and the bills piling
up, I really had no choice.
- It's hard enough these days, isn't it?
- Yes. Well... shh! It seems you have fallen
- three months behind in your payments.
- Oh. [SIGHS]
I'm so sorry.
Uh, Kate, my wife, used to
look after our finances.
And I've been a bit off stride. Forgive me.
- How much is it that I owe you, exactly?
- Unfortunately, the bank is now demanding
that you pay back the entire loan in full.
- The entire loan?
- Yes. It's all in the contract.
That's more than I make in a year.
- I couldn't possibly.
- Oh, dear.
You have five days.
If you are unable to pay in full
by Friday at midnight...
I'm afraid we will have to
repossess your home...
and you will have to vacate the premises.
- But I work for Fidelity Fiduciary.
- Not as an accountant, I presume.
No, as... as a teller. I took a part-time
position there this past year.
You see, I'm really an artist.
- Yes, be that as it may.
- But my... my father, George Banks,
- was a senior partner there.
- Father left us shares in the bank.
You could use those to pay off the loan.
- I was saving those for the children.
- Shares? In the bank?
Well, that does change things, doesn't it?
- Primed and ready, Mr. Binnacle?
- Ready and charged, sir.
Do you have the share certificate?
- I'm sorry, the what?
- FRYE: The document...
The document proving you
own shares in the bank.
I suppose it must be somewhere
among Father's old papers.
- Yes, I suppose it must.
- ADMIRAL BOOM: Three...
two...
one!
Fire!
[EXPLODES]
Good heavens!
[GRUNTS]
- [WHIMPERS] Are you housing anarchists?
- JANE: No, that's the Admiral, next door.
He fires off a cannon to mark the hour.
[GOODING COUGHS]
He's over five minutes late.
Yes. I'm afraid he's been running a
little behind these last few years.
As are we, this morning. You've
been given notice.
We'll see ourselves out. Come along, Mr. Frye.
I do hope you find that share certificate.
- I really do.
- Good day to you both!
You really have chosen the wrong
profession, you know.
[DOOR CLOSES]
Why didn't you tell me you'd taken out a loan?
[SIGHS] I didn't want to worry you.
Or the children.
I kept thinking I would catch
up. Kate always managed.
[SIGHS] Of all the thick-headed mistakes.
I can't lose our home, Jane.
She's everywhere, here.
Well, then, we're not going to let
that happen, but, Michael...
You know we neither of us have any money,
so we just have to find that share certificate.
Do you have any idea where
Father might have kept it?
I don't know. In the attic, perhaps?
- Yes.
- I'm sorry.
- I didn't mean to bring you into all of this.
- Michael!
- [SIGHS]
This is our family home, and
you're about to lose it.
So please, stop pretending everything's fine.
- You need...
- Are we going to lose our home?
- No. No, no, no.
- No, no. I...
- MICHAEL: Aunt Jane was only...
- I know...
I... I... I was just saying you
won't have to worry,
because your father owns shares in the bank.
But you said we don't have enough money.
Well, I can make more money. I am a banker
now, aren't I? That's what bankers do.
- Make money.
- But you're not a banker.
- You're a painter.
- Yes, well, painters don't make money.
Not these days. Here, you see.
The day has hardly begun, and I have
already made you 10 pounds!
- [CHILDREN GIGGLING]
- We'd best be going.
Yes, yes, let's get your hats on, shall we?
One moment, John.
Georgie shouldn't have to spend his 10
pounds on the shopping, should he?
Here you are.
Thank you, Father.
- Ah! Off to the park, I see.
- Yes, that's right, Ellen.
- That's nice.
- Shall we search the attic, then?
- Don't you have to go to work?
- No.
- Work can wait.
- Oh, thank you, Jane.
Well, why don't I check the attic and
you check Father's old wardrobe?
- Yes.
- We'll make lunch when we get home, Ellen.
- Gillie stays here.
- GEORGIE: Aw!
[CHUCKLES] Blimey, what little
grown-ups you've become.
ANNABEL: Father didn't give us enough, did he?
JOHN: Not nearly.
ANNABEL: Well, we can ask for
day-old bread at half off.
- That's what Mother used to do.
- Hello, Willoughby! Hello, Miss Lark!
- Hello, Georgie. Twins.
- GEORGIE: Oh!
Good boy, Willoughby.
Come on, Georgie, we haven't
got enough time for this.
- Aw.
- Come along. Come on, Wil.
[GASPS] The balloon lady! Can we get balloons?
No, Georgie! We haven't enough
for groceries as it is.
Oy! Georgie Banks! Keep off the grass.
I don't spend all day caring for it just
to see my work get trampled on.
- Go on, off it!
- Sorry.
What if Father does lose the house?
We'll just have to figure out a
way to get it back, I suppose.
You're right. That's what Mother would do.
No.
[MUSIC BOX CHIMING]
# We haven't spoken in so long, dear #
# This year has gone by in a blur #
# Today, seems everything's gone wrong here #
# I'm looking for the way things were #
# I know you'd laugh and call me tragic #
# For everything's in disarray #
# These rooms were always full of magic #
# That's vanished... #
# since you went away #
# This house is crowded now with questions #
# Your John's a walking questionnaire #
# And I could surely use a few suggestions #
# On how to brush our daughter's hair #
# When Georgie needed explanations #
# You always knew just what to say #
# And I miss our family conversations #
# It's silent... #
# since you went away #
# Winter has gone #
# But not from this room #
# Snow's left the lane #
# But the cherry trees forgot to bloom #
The certificate.
The certificate. [CLEARS THROAT]
# I'll carry on the way you told me #
# I say that like I have a choice #
# And though you are not here to hold me #
# In the echoes, I can hear your voice #
# But still one question fills my day, dear #
# The answer we most longed to know #
# Each moment since you went away, dear #
# My question, Kate, is... #
# Where'd you go? #
JANE: Nothing in the wardrobe!
- Oh, my goodness.
- Yes, it's quite a mess.
JANE: Yes, it is.
What are all your art things doing up here?
Oh. I wasn't using them anymore.
I should probably just get rid of it all.
Have you looked in Father's old desk?
MICHAEL: I honestly can't remember why
we kept most of this stuff to begin with.
I mean, why on earth did we
save this old broken thing?
Don't you remember that kite?
We used to love flying that
with Mother and Father.
Well, it won't fly anymore.
Out it goes. No looking back.
# Hold on tight to those you love
and maybe soon from up above #
- [BARKING]
- Willoughby!
- Naughty boy.
- [CONTINUES BARKING]
Hush.
ANNABEL: How long do you
think it will take us today?
Well, let's see. It's a 9-minute
walk to the shop.
- [GEORGIE GIGGLES]
- So if it takes 10 minutes...
- to purchase each item...
- Excuse me, children, coming through!
Georgie! Come back!
- JOHN: Georgie!
- PARK KEEPER: You two!
I've told you before, off the grass!
- But our brother!
- You heard me!
Now! What?
[ANNABEL PANTING]
[PANTING]
[CHUCKLES]
[GRUNTING]
Whoa! Oh!
- GEORGIE: [SCREAMING] Help!
- We're coming, Georgie!
GEORGIE: Help!
- Hold on!
- Help me!
- [SCREAMS]
- [JACK GRUNTS]
As I live and breathe.
You need to be more careful when the wind
rises, Georgie. You nearly lost your kite.
And you two nearly lost your Georgie.
He might have got away completely
had I not been holding on to
the other end of that string.
My goodness, Annabel, what have
you done to your clothes?
You could grow a garden in that much
soil, and, John... yes, just as filthy.
- How do you know our names?
- Because she's Mary Poppins, of course.
- May I say, you look lovely, as always.
- Do you really think so?
- Nice to see you, Jack.
- Good to see you too, Mary Poppins.
I was just your age when we first met,
- working for a chimney sweep.
- How is dear old Bert?
Traveling the world, he is.
Off to points unknown.
Well, now I am off to speak with
the father of these children.
This family is clearly in desperate
need of a nanny.
Now, quick march and best foot forward,
and I'll thank you not to dawdle.
Go on!
[ANNABEL SIGHS]
Father! Aunt Jane! Come quick!
- Quickly!
- What is it, Georgie?
Has something happened?
I was flying a kite and it
got caught on a nanny!
- Whatever are you talking about?
- Come! Come, look!
Wait, where did you get that kite?
I found it in the park.
She kept it from blowing away.
- Mary...
- Poppins.
Oh, close your mouth please, Michael.
We are still not a codfish.
[GIGGLES]
Jane Banks, still rather
inclined to giggle, I see.
Good heavens, it really is you.
- You seem hardly to have aged at all.
- Really! How incredibly rude.
One never discusses a woman's age, Michael.
I would have hoped I taught you better.
- I'm sorry, I didn't mean...
- You came back.
- I thought we'd never see you again.
- It is wonderful to see you.
Yes, it is, isn't it?
- ANNABEL: So, you know her, then?
- Mary Poppins used to be our nanny.
What brings you here after all this time?
MARY: Same thing that brought
me the first time.
- I've come to look after the Banks children.
- Us?
Oh, yes, you too.
ANNABEL: But we don't need a nanny.
Mother taught us to look after ourselves.
You did just misplace Georgie,
- I might point out.
- Only slightly. We got him back.
- We can do anything a nanny can.
- GEORGIE: Mary Poppins flew here on a kite.
- You can't do that, can you?
- What are you talking about, Georgie?
- Don't be silly.
- JANE: Oh, let him believe what he likes.
When your father and I were
young, we used to imagine...
that Mary Poppins could do all
sorts of impossible things.
- PARROT UMBRELLA: Actually...
- "Actually," what?
Actually, I'd like to get back to
the matter of my employment.
- Your umbrella talks!
- Georgie, please,
we're in the midst of a grown-up conversation.
ANNABEL: Why don't we go upstairs, Georgie?
But it did talk! I promise!
I'm afraid Georgie sometimes suffers
from an excess of imagination.
As I recall, you had the same affliction
yourself when you were young.
Did I, really? Well...
- those days are long behind me.
- Are they, indeed? Hmm.
- Now, about my employment...
- Yes, about your employment...
- the truth is, I simply can't afford...
- We can settle on terms later,
although I will want my old room back.
That's if it's not a complete disaster...
and I will insist on having
- every second Tuesday off.
- No, I'm afraid,
- I...
- Of course, Mary Poppins.
Good, good. That's all settled.
Then I'll stay. Now, if you'll excuse me...
the children have turned
themselves into dustbins.
So the first order of business is to see
them properly bathed and dressed.
Jane, have you gone completely mad?
- I can't afford to take on anyone else.
- Mary Poppins isn't just anyone.
Don't you see, Michael? No one's
hiring nannies anymore.
- The poor woman has nowhere to go.
- Well, neither will we...
- by the end of the week!
- Oh, don't be so grumpy.
You sound just like Father.
- I do not!
- Give Mary Poppins a chance.
You need help just as much as she does!
Very well. She can stay for
the time being, I suppose.
After all, she did fly all this way on a kite.
[BOTH LAUGH]
Those things, when we were
young, they didn't really...
- Happen?
- No.
- Of course not. Ridiculous.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
- Oh, hello, Mary Poppins.
- Hello, Ellen.
- How'd you do that?
- Do what?
And why didn't Father believe
you flew here on a kite?
- Because it's complete nonsense, of course.
- Grown-ups forget. They always do.
MARY: That will be quite enough of that.
I should have left you in the umbrella stand.
- [GASPS] Not with the canes!
- Oh.
- [GEORGIE GIGGLES]
- [SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
- What are you two whispering about?
- BOTH: Nothing.
"Nothing." Such a useful word, isn't it?
- It can mean anything and everything.
- ANNABEL: It's just that...
- You don't require the services of a nanny.
- Well, we have grown up a good deal
in the past year, after all.
Yes.
Well, we'll have to see what
can be done about that.
ANNABEL: That was our mother's, be careful.
I am always careful.
So, you're staying?
- Yes, I'll stay. Until the door opens.
- What does that mean?
- That door's always opening.
- Oh, not that door, another one.
- The bathroom door?
- [CHUCKLES] That's just silly, Georgie.
- Not the bathroom door?
- MARY: No. But a bath would prove useful.
Come along. Time for a good, clean start.
Mother always had us take
our baths in the evening.
Well, in my experience, Annabel...
the perfect time of day to have a
bath is when one needs a wash.
Georgie, you will go first.
We are perfectly capable of
drawing our own baths.
MARY: How very helpful, John.
In that case, you may turn off the tap.
But not quite yet, still need
to put in the bubbles.
- But I don't like soap bubbles.
- Well, then you shall have to try
to avoid them at all costs.
She's a tough nut, isn't she?
[SIGHS] All right then... but we'll
have to get this done quickly!
Right, we still have to get down to the grocers
and it looks as though it might rain.
- I know who you should ask.
- [JOHN SIGHS]
- Her umbrella can't talk, Georgie.
- The very idea.
- How do you know it can't?
- Because it can't.
The very notion is ridiculous.
Exactly right, Annabel. It's
nonsense. Foolishness.
It makes no sense. And if it makes
no sense, it can't be true.
# John, you're right #
# It's good to know you're bright #
# For intellect can wash away confusion #
# Georgie sees, and Annabel agrees #
# Most folderol's an optical illusion #
# You three know it's true
that one plus one is two #
# Yes, logic is the rock of our foundation #
# I suspect, and I'm never incorrect #
# That you're far too old to
give in to imagination #
[DOLPHIN CLICKING]
No, not yet.
[GEORGIE GASPS]
# Some people like to splash and
play, can you imagine that? #
# And take a seaside holiday
can you imagine that? #
# Too much glee leaves rings around the brain #
# Take that joy and send it down the drain #
# Some people like to laugh at life
and giggle through the day #
# They think the world's a brand-new, shiny toy #
# And if while dreaming in the
clouds, fall and go kersplat #
# Although they're down and bent in half #
# They brush right off and start to
laugh! Can you imagine that? #
On second thoughts, perhaps you're right.
- It makes no sense to take a bath this early.
- Wait! I want to take a bath!
Oh, really?
- Very well, then.
- [GEORGIE CHUCKLES]
- Up you go.
- [GASPS]
- And in you go.
- [ECHOING] Whoa!
[GASPS] Georgie!
- [ECHOING] Georgie!
- John!
- What happened? Will they be all right?
- Well, it is just a bath, after all.
- But then again, it's not my tub.
- ANNABEL: Shouldn't you go in after them?
Oh, no, I had my bath this morning, thank you.
Well, if you won't, I will!
[ECHOING] Whoa!
Off we go.
[GIGGLING]
[JOHN PANTING]
[WATER BUBBLING]
# Some people like to dive right
in, can you imagine that? #
# And flap about in bathtub gin,
can you imagine that? #
# Doggies paddling 20 leagues below #
- [BARKS]
- # Might seem real, but we know it's not so #
# To cook without a recipe,
can you imagine that? #
# And heaven knows what lives within that pot! #
# Some pirates follow treasure
maps and wear a silly hat #
# They search the world for buried gold #
# They won't grow up and don't grow
old! can you imagine that? #
Be sure to scrub behind your ears!
[DOLPHINS CLICKING]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[GIGGLES]
[CHILDREN EXCLAIMING]
- # Some answer when adventure calls! #
- ALL: # Can you imagine that? #
- # And sail straight over waterfalls! #
- # They see living as its own reward #
- Ahoy!
# They rock the boat, then... #
- Whoa!
- Man overboard!
# Some people look out on the
sea and see a brand-new day #
# Their spirit lifts them high above the blue #
# Yet, some others wear an anchor
and they sink in seconds flat #
# So... #
# Perhaps we've learnt when day is done
some stuff and nonsense could be fun! #
ALL: # Can you imagine that? #
[CHILDREN EXCLAIMING]
[GEORGIE LAUGHING]
MICHAEL: No.
No.
- No. Anything?
- No, nothing.
Just your old drawings, and
bills, and nothing else.
- Well, then that's it, it's not here.
- JOHN: Father, Aunt Jane!
ANNABEL: It was amazing! And
then there were these boats!
GEORGIE: Everything you could ever dream of!
ANNABEL: And then, he fell in the water!
Not now, please.
But it really happened! Tell him, Mary Poppins!
I have no idea what you're all talking about.
- We swam through a pirate ship!
- Enough, please!
You're right, Father. We're sorry.
No, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I don't mean to be cross with all of you. I...
I've just lost something very important.
Yes. And we're going to find it.
I'm sure your grandfather just tucked
it away somewhere for safekeeping.
The bank! Didn't Father have a safety
deposit box in the bank?
Yes. Yes, he did.
- Well, let's go.
- It's closed.
- We'll go first thing in the morning.
- But won't we need a key?
There's a whole drawer full of keys
in Father's old desk upstairs.
- MICHAEL: Is there?
- Yes!
My goodness, gracious, glory me.
You'd think by now they'd have learned
to pick up after themselves.
Cleaning is not a spectator
sport, I'll remind you.
John, Annabel, put all the books
back on the bookshelves.
Georgie Banks, come back here.
- Take out this rubbish, would you?
- Yes, Mary Poppins.
There's a good boy.
[GRUNTING]
Off you go, spit spot.
[GRUNTS]
[HORN HONKS]
MICHAEL: Oh, well.
That's that.
What about Mr. Dawes, Jr.?
- Couldn't he give you more time?
- Yes, I'm sure he could...
if he were still here but Dawes' nephew
has been running things lately.
I don't think he even knows who I am.
- Thank you.
- CLERK: Very good, sir.
Well, it's high time he found
out, don't you think?
Jan... Jane?
Jane!
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
- MAN: Banks.
- MICHAEL: Good morning.
Sorry.
- Jane. We can't just charge into his office.
- Hello, Miss Penny Farthing, is it?
Heavens, did the old secretary finally retire?
She always had that big jar of sweets
on the desk we'd raid as children.
WILKINS: I remember that jar.
Those little toffees that stuck
your teeth together.
Must get you one of those jars, Miss Farthing.
PENNY: Of course, sir.
This wouldn't happen to be your
sister, would it, Mr. Banks?
- Yes.
- Yes, Jane Banks. How do you do?
Great pleasure to meet you.
William Weatherall Wilkins.
Do step this way.
[DOOR CLOSES]
If I had known that George Banks'
son had taken a loan with us...
I would have handled the paperwork myself.
Unfortunately...
regarding an extension, there's
very little I can do at this point.
MICHAEL: I see.
Our father did leave us shares in the bank.
- Oh, well, that is good news!
- JANE: Yes. Yes, it is, but the
trouble is, we can't seem to
find the share certificate.
You wouldn't happen to have any record
of Father's shares, would you?
- I would think so.
- [BUZZER BUZZES]
Bring in the shareholder's ledger,
- would you, Miss Farthing?
- PENNY: Right away, Mr. Wilkins.
And what about your uncle, Mr. Dawes, Jr.?
He'd know if Father received
shares, wouldn't he?
I'm afraid dear old Uncle Dawes
is getting on in years.
- Non compos mentis...
- [DOOR OPENS]
Which, sadly, is why I had to take over for him.
Ah, thank you, Miss Farthing.
Let's see.
"Babcock... Baker..."
Hmm.
Doesn't seem to be a listing
for George Banks here.
Don't despair.
You still have until that big fellow out there
chimes his last on Friday night...
to find that certificate.
And I'll keep looking here as well.
- It's really been a great pleasure. Thank you.
- Very kind of you.
- Thank you, Mr. Wilkins.
- WILKINS: Not at all.
[SIGHS]
[DOOR CLOSES]
[BUZZER BUZZES]
Bring in all of George Banks'
old files, would you?
PENNY: Of course, Mr. Wilkins.
[BEDSPRINGS CREAKING]
Georgie, this is a nursery, let me
remind you, and not a music hall.
- Can we have another bath?
- Oh, pish posh.
Now, John, you'd best go downstairs
- and help Ellen...
- [CLATTERING]
- ELLEN: Whoa!
- ...put away the dishes.
Yes, Mary Poppins.
- Here, I can put those away myself.
- Very well, then.
Now, Georgie Banks...
if you were hoping that I will let you take this
sadly neglected kite to the park tomorrow,
- you'd better start patching it up this instant.
- Yes, Mary Poppins.
Hmm.
- Oh, let me help you with those.
- Oh, you're a good lad.
You're such a help, you are.
I only wish I could help your father
save this poor old house.
I could sell my broach and necklace, I suppose.
- Matching set, my old mum gave them to me.
- You'd do that for us?
- What? Sell my prized possessions?
- Oh, no...
- I didn't mean it like that.
- Oh, it's all right.
I think they're fakes, anyway.
No. Plenty in this house worth
more than them old trinkets.
If you'll excuse me, Ellen.
What's got into him?
[PANTING] Annabel!
- I know how to save the house!
- What do you mean?
If you two are going to keep
up all of this whispering...
I'd like you to practice doing
so as loudly as possible.
It will still be bad manners, but at least
then we'll all be in on the secret.
- Oh, hello, Jack!
- Mary Poppins, how are you this fine evening?
MARY: I'm settling in quite nicely, thank you.
- [SOFTLY] I was downstairs with Ellen...
- JACK: Do you know, when I was a lad...
I used to wave up to the boy
and girl who lived here.
- Oh. You mean Michael and Jane.
- Oh, Miss Jane Banks!
I see Mr. Banks about now and again.
It's been ages since I've seen her.
Well, she lives in a flat on the
other side of town now.
I'm sure you'll bump into her one of these days.
What are you doing? You know we're
not supposed to touch that.
This is authentic Royal Doulton china, Annabel.
Mother always said it was priceless...
and I bet it'll be enough
to pay off Father's debt.
That's a terrible idea, John.
- You know Mother loved that bowl.
- But she'd sell it herself to save the house!
- That was Mother's! Put that back!
- ANNABEL: No, Georgie, give it to me!
- GEORGIE: No! Put it back!
- ANNABEL: Let go, let go!
It's a good thing you come along
- when you did, Mary Poppins.
- [CHILDREN SHOUTING]
[BOWL BREAKS]
That didn't sound good, now did it?
What are the three of you up to?
- Give me the missing piece!
- I don't have it!
Well, look for it then!
Which of you broke the bowl?
- Georgie did.
- I did not! It was Annabel!
No, I didn't! If John hadn't taken it...
[ALL ARGUING]
- CLYDE: Actually, it was all three of them.
- MARY: Mmm.
Who said that?
- Oh, dear.
- ANNABEL: Look! The picture's changed.
MARY: It looks as though they've
broken your carriage wheel.
- SHAMUS: That they have. It's useless now.
- CLYDE: Useless as a chocolate teapot.
The bowl is speaking!
SHAMUS: And who do we think is gonna fix that?
Aye, there's the riddle. Them what
broke it fixes it. That's what I say.
- What do you think, Mary Poppins?
- Well, I suppose we have no choice.
- But how are we going to do that?
- I know a bit about fixing carriages.
But we can't fix the carriage
wheel. It isn't possible.
Everything is possible. Even the impossible.
Now, gather 'round, everyone. Spit, spot!
Georgie, don't forget Gillie.
- Are we ready?
- Ready.
[CHUCKLES]
Wow!
What just happened?
Where are we?
[CLINKS]
Looks like we're in china, so to speak.
Over here, everyone. This
wheel won't fix itself.
Now, tread lightly, this is fine porcelain,
and we don't want to chip the glaze.
[CHILDREN EXCLAIMING]
- GEORGIE: Whee!
- [CHILDREN GIGGLING]
Oh, Georgie, head up and feet
beneath you. You too, John.
[CHILDREN LAUGHING]
- Excuse me, driver, would you help us?
- Well, Mary Poppins, is it yourself?
- But he's...
- But you're...
That's right, I'm Irish. I'm
also part poodle. [BARKS]
[CHILDREN LAUGH]
How wonderful to see you, Shamus.
I'm so sorry about all this.
Now, would you help Jack lift the carriage
while the children put the wheel back on?
- With pleasure!
- She's talking to a dog!
- Well, of course she can talk. [CHUFFS]
- [JOHN GASPS SOFTLY]
MARY: Take your places, everyone.
[CLAPS HANDS]
Ready?
- And lift.
- [CHILDREN GRUNTING]
Yes. Let's see now, this should do it.
- There we are, shipshape.
- Not a bad job at all.
Suppose it'll have to do.
And back to the nursery we go.
- Back already?
- Can't we stay in this bowl for a while?
- I want a carriage ride.
- I wouldn't mind one m'self.
Well, I suppose it wouldn't do any harm.
- Shamus, would you mind?
- Not in the least.
- Climb aboard, everybody!
- CHILDREN: Hooray!
SHAMUS: Mind the step, plant yourselves comfy.
Now, where would we all like
to go on this fine, fine day?
The Royal Doulton Music Hall, please.
- Where?
- What's that?
We're on the brink of an adventure, children,
dont spoil it with too many questions.
- Let's go, Clyde!
- Easy.
# In the nursery, you were never by yourself #
# There was quite another world... #
- # upon your shelf #
- Hold on!
# Where each day crowds make their
way upon the sun's descent #
# To a mythical, mystical,
never-quite-logistical tent #
# Yes, in this dearly dynamical simply
ceramical Royal Doulton bowl #
# There's a cuddly and curious furly
and furious animal watering hole #
# Where the monkeys and humming birds
know the tunes and the words #
# Every beast large and small, loves
the very top drawer-able #
# Always encore-able Royal Doulton Music Hall #
Ooh, that one tickled my tail.
Nearly there, Mary Poppins!
BOTH: # Yes, in this marvelous, mystical
rather sophistical Royal Doulton bowl #
# There's a lot of birds queuing up #
# A lot of hams chewing up scenely
they swallow whole #
- # There are lots of cats tuning strings #
- MARY: # Nightingales in the wings #
BOTH: # Waiting for their big drum roll #
- # At the simply sensational #
- # Standing ovation-al #
- # Royal Doulton Music Hall #
- # Music Hall #
- SHAMUS: Here we are!
- [CLYDE CHUFFS]
But where's the music hall?
Oh, yes, that. Silly me.
- WOLF: Step right up! Step right up!
- [CHILDREN EXCLAIM]
- Sensational Royal Doulton Music Hall
- How on earth did she do that?
One thing you should know
about Mary Poppins...
- she never explains anything. Come on.
- WOLF: Hurry, hurry! Only a few seats left!
Get tickets while you can for the one-night
only... one and only... Mary Poppins!
What an honor it is to have
you join us this evening.
- Thank you.
- And who is this I see?
- Why, it's John, Annabel and Georgie Banks!
- You know us?
Of course. Everyone knows the Banks children.
We've all been watching you
in the nursery for years.
It's so good to finally meet you.
Hurry along, now. Get yourselves some
peanuts and candy floss and go right on in.
May we, Mary Poppins?
- Yes.
- [CHILDREN LAUGHING]
- GEORGIE: Come on! Let's get candy floss!
- Just keep away from the edge of the bowl.
[SNARLS]
# At the highly-acclaimable
nearly untamable #
[CROWD CHEERING]
# La vishly praisable, always roof-raise-able #
# Royal Doulton #
# Music Hall! #
Oh! Excuse me.
- Oh!
- [GIGGLING]
[ALL CHEERING]
Bucks and mares, cubs and does,
welcome to our show of shows!
It is my great honor to introduce
this evening's renowned guest...
the one...
the only...
- Mary Poppins!
- Oh.
- [MARY LAUGHS]
- [ALL CHEERING]
Thank you, thank you very
much. Yes, thank you.
- JACK: Come on!
- Oh, no, no.
- Come on up!
- Go on!
Silly Jack.
[JACK CHUCKLES]
- Thank you.
- Sing for us, Mary Poppins!
- No. No, no, no.
- Come on, have a go.
- No, I haven't sung in years.
- PENGUINS: Sing for us, Mary Poppins.
- Please. Please, Mary Poppins.
- Do sing for us.
Uh, no, I couldn't possibly.
D-flat major.
[ORCHESTRAL MUSIC PLAYING]
# Uncle Gutenberg was a bookworm
and he lived on Charing Cross #
# The memory of his volumes brings a smile #
# He would read me lots of stories
when he wasn't on the sauce #
# Now I'd like to share the wisdom
of my favorite bibliophile #
# He said #
[IN COCKNsEY ACCENT] # A cover is not the
book, so open it up and take a look #
# 'Cause under the covers one discovers
that the king may be a crook #
# Chapter titles are like signs and
if you read between the lines #
# You'll find your first impression was mistook #
# For a cover is nice but a
cover is not the book #
[ANIMALS SCATTING]
Mary Poppins, could you give us an example?
- Certainly!
- [GASPS AND SIGHS]
# Nellie Rubina was made of wood
but what could not be seen #
# Was though her trunk up top was barren
well, her roots were lush and green #
# Saw her blossoms bloomin' there #
# He took root, despite her bark and now
there's seedlings everywhere! #
BOTH: # Which proves a
cover is not the book #
# So open it up and take a look #
# 'Cause under the covers one discovers
that the king may be a crook #
- # Chapter titles are like signs #
- # And  if you read between the lines #
# You'll find your first impression was mistook #
# For a cover is nice but a
cover is not the book! #
Shall we do the one about
the "Wealthy Widow"?
- Oh, by all means!
- Always loved that one!
Well, go on then.
# Lady Hyacinth Macaw brought
all her treasures to a reef #
- # Where she only wore a smile #
- # Plus two feathers and a leaf #
MARY: # So no one tried to rob her
'cause she barely wore a stitch #
# For when you're in your birthday suit there
ain't much there to show you're rich! #
# Oh, a cover is not the book so
open it up and take a look #
# 'Cause under the covers one discovers
that the king may be a crook #
[SCATTING]
# You'll find your first impression was mistook #
# For a cover is nice, but a
cover is not the book #
Oh, give us the one about the
"Dirty Rascal," why don't ya?
- Isn't that one a bit long?
- Well, the quicker you're into it,
the quicker you're out of it.
# Once upon a time in a nursery rhyme #
# There was a castle with a
king hiding in a wing #
# 'Cause he never went to school
to learn a single thing #
# He had scepters and swords
And a parliament of Lords #
# But on the inside he was sad Egad! #
# Because he never had a wisdom for
numbers, a wisdom for words #
# Though his crown was quite immense
his brain was smaller than a bird's #
# So the queen of the nation made
a royal proclamation #
# "To the missus and the messers
the more or lessers #
# "Bring me all the land's professors" then
she went to the hair dressers #
# And they came from the East
And they came from the South #
# From each college, they poured knowledge
from their brains into his mouth #
# But the king couldn't learn so each
professor met their fate #
# For the queen had their heads removed
and placed upon the gate #
# And on that date #
# I state their wives all got a note, their
mate was now the late great #
# But then suddenly one day a
stranger started in to sing #
# He said, "I'm the dirty rascal and
I'm here to teach the king!" #
# And the queen clutched her jewels
for she hated royal fools #
# But this fool had some rules, they really
ought to teach in schools #
# Like you'll be a happy king if you
enjoy the things you've got #
# You should never try to be the kind
of person that you're not #
# So they sang and they laughed
for the king had found a friend #
# And they ran onto a rainbow
for the story's perfect end #
# So the moral is you mustn't let
the outside be the guide #
# For it's not so cut and dried #
# Well, unless it's Doctor Jekyll
then you better hide #
# Petrified! #
# No, the truth can't be denied, as
I have now have testified #
# All that really counts and matters
is the special stuff inside! #
- Hoorayl
- He did it!
[ALL CHEERING]
ALL: # Oh, a cover is not the book
so open it up and take a look #
# 'Cause under the covers one discovers
that the king may be a crook #
- # So please listen to what we've said #
- # And open a book tonight in bed #
# So one more time before we get the hook #
# Sing it out strong! #
- # A cover is nice #
- # Please take our advice #
- # Or you'll pay the price! #
# A cover is nice but a cover is not the book #
[ANIMALS SCATTING]
- [ALL CHEERING]
- Bravo!
- Gillie!
- [ANNABEL WHOOPING]
[SIGHS]
[ANNABEL WHOOPS]
Where's Georgie?
I don't know.
BADGER: Take this.
[GRUNTING]
What are you doing?
[BOTH GASP]
Well, well, if it isn't the boy
who cracked the bowl.
We've waited a long time for you Banks
children to come and visit us,
- so we could pay a visit to your nursery.
- But... but those are our things!
- WOLF: Oh, not anymore, they aren't.
- Give Gillie back!
He's mine! My mother made him for me!
- Hey! Leave our brother alone!
- Time to go, boys!
- [BADGER GRUNTING]
- Whoa!
[GRUNTING]
[GASPS]
[BINNACLE BLOWING WHISTLE]
[COUGHING]
- Annabel! Help!
- BOTH: Georgie!
JOHN: We're coming, Georgie!
GEORGIE: John!
[LAUGHS]
- Let me go! I want to go home!
- What home? You've lost your home!
[BOTH PANTING]
[BOTH EXCLAIM]
Shamus!
Clyde!
- That's right, it's us!
- Let's go get your brother back.
[LAUGHS]
[GASPS AND GRUNTS ANGRILY]
We're gaining on 'em!
- Give it more speed!
- Right away, sir.
[GRUNTING]
[LAUGHS]
Whoa!
Giddy-up, big fella!
[CLYDE PANTING]
[BOTH SCREAMING]
We're closing in. Get ready to jump!
- Ready. And now!
- [SCREAMS]
- SHAMUS: Well done, children!
- CLYDE: Give 'em what-for!
- Yeah, get rid of them!
- But, sir!
You heard me!
ANNABEL: Georgie, are you all right?
Annabel, look!
[ANNABEL STRAINING]
[GRUNTS]
[GASPS]
[BOTH SCREAMING]
- Stay with Georgie.
- Right.
[GRUNTS]
Be careful!
GEORGIE: What are you doing?
[GRUNTS ANGRILY]
[WINCES]
[GRUNTS]
- [CONTINUES PANTING]
- [GRUNTS]
[GROWLING]
[CHILDREN SCREAM]
[LAUGHS]
Oh, no!
ALL: The edge of the bowl!
[CHILDREN SCREAMING]
MARY: Georgie, it's all right, it's all right.
My goodness me.
- [BREATHING HEAVILY]
- Shh. It's all right.
You were having a nice sort
of nightmare, I must say.
You were right, Mary Poppins!
A cover is not the book.
We thought they were nice,
but they were mean!
- Whatever are you talking about?
- They tried to take Gillie!
No, Gillie is right here, sleeping,
as you should be.
But it was real!
They stole all our things and the wolf said we
were never going to see our home again!
That is absurd.
- But I had a nightmare like that, too.
- So did I, it seemed awfully real.
I don't want to lose our home.
You see, Georgie? That's why
we wanted Mother's bowl.
We were going to sell it to save the house.
I miss Mother.
Oh, listen to the three of you. You're
all worrying far too much.
After all, you can't lose what you've never lost.
- I don't understand.
- Well...
# Do you ever lie awake at night? #
# Just between the dark and the morning light #
# Searching for the things you used to know #
# Looking for the place where
the lost things go? #
# Do you ever dream or reminisce? #
# Wondering where to find what you truly miss? #
# Well, maybe all those things that you love so #
# Are waiting in the place where
the lost things go #
# Memories you've shared, gone
for good you feared #
# They're all around you still, though
they've disappeared #
# Nothing's really left or lost without a trace #
# Nothing's gone forever, only out of place #
# So maybe now the dish and my best spoon #
# Are playing hide and seek
just behind the Moon #
# Waiting there until it's time to show #
# Spring is like that now far
beneath the snow #
# Hiding in the place where the lost things #
# Go #
Now, time to get some sleep.
And in the morning, bright and early
we'll take that bowl to my cousin.
We'll have it mended.
# Time to close your eyes #
# So sleep can come around
for when you dream #
# You'll find all that's lost is found #
# Maybe on the Moon or maybe
somewhere new #
# Maybe all you're missing lives inside of you #
# So, when you need her
touch and loving gaze #
# "Gone but not forgotten"
is the perfect phrase #
# Smiling from a star that she makes
glow, trust she's always there #
# Watching as you grow #
# Find her in the place where the lost things #
# Go #
John, look!
Mary Poppins' scarf.
It wasn't a dream after all.
Shall we tell her?
Better not.
I expect she already knows.
[BIG BEN CHIMING]
ADMIRAL BOOM: Blast the devil, too soon!
Why can't those pea-brained
Big Ben buffoons get it right?
- Ahoy there, fair lady!
- Hello!
Good morning. Oh!
- JACK: Oh! I'm sorry, miss.
- Oh, no, no. It's quite all right. Don't worry.
- Let me help you with that.
- Thank you.
MARY: Good morning, Jane. I see
you've bumped into Jack.
The children and I are heading into
town to get something fixed.
Would you like to come with us?
Work calls, I'm afraid. We've got a rally today.
Oh, that's right. You ought to
give Jack one of those flyers.
- You're Miss Banks, aren't you?
- Yes.
I don't know if you remember me. I... I used
to wave to you when I'd see you up there
- in that very window.
- Yes.
Jack. Yes, of course, I remember.
- Ca... call me Jane, please.
- Of course, I was much younger then.
[CHUCKLES] True...
but your smile hasn't changed a bit.
Well, it's... it's this afternoon,
if you can make it.
"Spruce", eh? Good for you, Jane Banks.
All us lamplighters know what a fine
job you're doing for the workers.
- Well, we try our best.
- If you ever need a ladder raised
- or a lamp lit, consider it done.
- Thank you, Jack. Thank you. [CHUCKLES]
[CONVERSATION CONTINUES INDISTINCTLY]
- Polishing the keyhole, are we?
- Look at this.
Miss Jane's chatting with that
handsome lamplighter.
- It looks like he's lit her up as well, don't it?
- Oh, Ellen!
Oh, no, nothing will come of it. No,
she says that ship's sailed.
- And I say, there are always other ships.
- MICHAEL: My alarm didn't ring.
- Oh, dear. Let me help you.
- [SIGHS] I'm gonna be late.
- That's all that I need!
- Well, you're not late yet, are you?
Here you are.
Off you go.
[JANE GIGGLING]
- Good morning, Michael.
- Hello, forgive me, I have to run.
- Watch where you're... Michael!
- I am so sorry!
- It's fine. Um, I'm looking for number 19.
- BOTH: Oh, it's two doors down.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
Many thanks. Sincerely.
Michael, your briefcase!
Blimey, he'd leave his head on the breakfast
table if it weren't screwed on.
Here, Ellen. I'll take the briefcase.
The children and I are heading
that way on an errand.
- We'll stop by the bank afterwards.
- I'll give you a lift. My rounds are done.
- Wonderful.
- All aboard, everyone. Come on.
GEORGIE: On the bicycle?
- But there are five of us. We can't all fit.
- The weight on those wheels alone.
- Mary Poppins, how much do you weigh?
- Never you mind about that.
It's all a question of balance.
- Annabel here.
- Whoa!
- And then John.
- JOHN: Whoa!
Oh, sit up straight! You're not flour bags.
- Georgie at the front.
- Yay!
- Mary Poppins, you here.
- [ALL EXCLAIM]
- I've got it!
- Blimey!
All right, everybody.
- Primed and ready, Mr. Binnacle?
- Ready and charged, sir.
- Ready, everyone?
- CHILDREN: Ready!
- Are you sure this is quite safe?
- Not in the slightest. Ready.
ADMIRAL BOOM: Three!
Two!
- Steady!
- One!
- Fire!
- Go!
[CHILDREN EXCLAIMING]
[CHILDREN LAUGHING]
Now, pull over, right ahead. Thank you, Jack.
Right, off we go, jiggity-jog.
Thank you, Georgie.
This way, please.
Never noticed this alley before.
Well, clearly you've never had a Royal
Doulton bowl that wanted mending.
Straight ahead.
Here we are.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
"Topotrepolovsky's all repairs,
large and small fix-it shop."
Looks as though it's just
a small fix-it shop today.
That's just what we want. The bowl
only needs a small fix, after all.
- [GROANS] So now my head is a door knocker.
- [SIGHS]
I suppose my beak might be
useful for opening cans.
You fuss, fuss, fuss. Don't be so dramatic.
Cousin Topsy!
TOPSY: Mary Poppins!
Oh, for the love of all that is holy...
- do not come in!
- Don't be so rude!
TOPSY: Please stay away.
- It is Second Wednesday!
- [GASPS]
Second Wednesday. Oh, dear. I'd forgotten.
Still, today or never, that's my motto.
- Ouch!
- There we are!
Follow me.
TOPSY: So, in you come. You
do not listen to Topsy.
- [MARY STAMMERS]
- [RUMBLING]
TOPSY: Oh, no, it has begun!
[TOPSY EXCLAIMING]
[SIGHS]
[CHILDREN GASP]
- Now, what do you want?
- You have guests, cousin.
- You might at least greet them at the door.
- And how am I to do that, please,
when I am down here, up on the ceiling?
[SIGHS] Very well, we'll come to you.
Excuse me, please, Georgie. Now, this way.
- Be careful on the way up.
- TOPSY: Why be careful?
Leave it all for Topsy to fix.
Climb on my shelves. Step on the toys.
[CLATTERING]
- Kick the little china dolls in their faces.
- John, Annabel, Georgie and Jack...
- this is my cousin.
- Second cousin, many times removed.
- Tatiana Antanasia Cositori Topotrepolovsky.
- Oh, but you may call me Topsy. [CHUCKLES]
That's an unusual accent you've got there.
- Where are you from?
- Oh, that's...
- very interesting story...
- We have no idea.
- We need you to fix this bowl, dear.
- No, no, no, no. It is as I have told to you...
second Wednesday of the month...
when everything is turning turtle.
- [SIGHS]
- ANNABEL: "Turning turtle"?
What exactly does that mean?
It means my whole world goes flippity-flop
like a turtle on his back.
And I don't know my up from my
down, my east from my west.
- My topsy from my bottomsy.
- [CHILDREN GIGGLE]
- Yes, I think we've all grasped the concept.
- Good. That's quick for you.
You see, my littles, anything I try to fix...
on Second Wednesday goes kerflooey.
Kerflooey.
- Kerflooey!
- [CLATTERS]
- [CHILDREN GIGGLE]
- Please, cousin, you have always said
that you can fix anything.
[SIGHS] Sweet girl, you tell Mary
Poppins, who doesn't listen...
that any other day, Tatiana Antanasia
Cositori Topotrepolovsky can fix anything.
# If you ring with something
broken on a Thursday #
# I'll make new with my glue, pins and thread #
# What you bring, when I've
awoken on a Friday #
# I will mend, and then spend the day in bed #
# Children, Satur, Sun, and Mondays
are just everything-is-fun days #
# But in the second week, I wear a frown #
# For I know that after Tuesday comes
the Topsy-gets-bad-news day #
# It's the dreaded Second Wednesday #
# When from nine to noon my
life turns upside down #
[CHILDREN LAUGHING]
[GEORGIE SCREAMS]
# Fast is slow, low is high, stop
is go and that is why #
# Every Second Wednesday is a hurdle #
# From eight to nine all is well
then I roll over on my shell #
# And all because the world is turning turtle #
# Now day is night, dog is cat
black is white, thin is fat #
# That is why I'm loosening up my girdle #
# I cannot help this charming troupe #
# Don't mock me 'cause I'm in the soup #
# And why? Because the world is turning turtle #
# Oh, woe is me I'm as opposite as I can be #
# I long for Thursdays when the world is drab #
# When will it cease? Now my life
resembles War and Peace #
# That Tolstoy certainly had the gift
of gab I couldn't get through it #
# Bottom's top, yin is yang peace
and quiet's sturm und drang #
# Tuesday nights, my blood begins to curdle #
# East is west, in is out, and that
is why I need to shout #
# "Oh, no! The world is turning turtle!" #
# Oh, if you had come some other morn #
# You wouldn't have found me so forlorn #
# But since the day that I was born #
# Second Wednesdays is on the fritz #
# I couldn't mend this to save my soul
if this keeps up, I'll dig a hole #
# You say life's a cherry bowl, but
Wednesday's full of pits #
- # Tell us, can you fix this drum? #
- # Well, today is looking glum #
- # Can you mend this crack?
- # And broken string? #
# Well, perhaps if you all lend a hand #
CHILDREN AND JACK: # Our fingers
are at your command #
- # A broken songbird still can sing #
- # Let's do the turtle swing #
[GEORGIE GIGGLES]
[CHILDREN LAUGHING]
[SQUEALS]
# Oh, woe is me, now I'm on my head #
# How can that be? #
# Well, you say ”woe" but I say "lucky you" #
- # Lucky me?
- # Yes #
# Here, on your head #
# "A " is far behind and led by "Z” #
# It's good to get a different point of view #
I love your shoes.
You see, when the world turns upside down
the best thing is to turn right along with it.
I do see!
From down here, things look right side up!
[ALL LAUGH]
I wouldn't mind seeing things from that angle.
- Sounds like fun!
- Can we?
Very well. Flippity-flop.
[CHILDREN EXCLAIMING]
- # Near is
- # Far is #
- # Here is
- # There #
# Turtles turning everywhere #
# Things are getting clear #
# Well, knock on wood, my dear #
[GRUNTS]
# When you change the view
from where you stood #
# The things you view will change for good #
# I never thought of things that way #
# She never thought of things that way #
# Now Wednesdays are my favorite day #
ALL: # Now Wednesdays are her favorite day #
# 'Cause that's the day I'm quite contrary
and now, thanks to Cousin Mary #
# I have changed, to be exact I love the fact #
# The world is turning turtle #
# Turtle, turtle #
[ALL LAUGHING]
Come, give your bowl to me. [CHUCKLES]
No more am I afraid with
this new point of view.
Good.
Excuse me, but do you have any idea
how much our bowl might be worth?
In money?
Not very much, I'm afraid. But that
doesn't make it any less beautiful.
- Our mother always said it was priceless.
- Well, I'm sure it was to her.
Mary Poppins is right, for once. It is all
in the way that you look at things.
Thank you, cousin. Now, come
along, children. Get your hats.
And don't you worry about Mother's bowl.
I will fix and make perfect for you.
So you come back, maybe,
- next Second Wednesday?
- MARY: Yes. Spit spot.
- Nice meeting you, Topsy Turvy.
- [CHUCKLES] "Topsy Turvy".
[CHUCKLES] I like. It's catchy.
- Now, what do we do?
- I have no idea.
Well, like Topsy said, maybe we should
start looking at things differently.
[RUMBLING AND CREAKING]
Oh, marvelous, it looks like things are
starting to turn around for my cousin.
JOHN: Mary Poppins, this is not
the quickest way to the bank.
MARY: It is today.
- GEORGIE: Look, there's Aunt Jane!
- CHILDREN: Aunt Jane! Aunt Jane!
- GEORGIE: Hello!
- MARY: Off to the rally, are you, Jane?
Yes, all still here, thank goodness.
- Nobody fell off.
- [CHILDREN CHUCKLE]
Say, I could come back and give
you a hand with all that
once I drop the others at the bank.
Oh, no, please don't worry.
I'm perfectly fine. Really.
Oh, nonsense. The bank's
just around the corner...
and the children and I have plenty
of legs to get us there.
- Now, climb off, everyone. Ready, and jump.
- Steady the bicycle for me,
- would you, children?
- You're sure you don't mind, Jack?
'Course not. I was hoping to drop
by that rally of yours, anyway.
- You were? Oh, good.
- You can ride in the front basket.
- Really?
- [CHUCKLES] I think she'll be better here.
Here, is it?
- Yeah. Up you go.
- Now, where should I hold on?
Handlebars are fine.
- Ready?
- Yes, ready as I'll ever...
[SQUEALING]
[LAUGHING] My goodness!
Now, be careful here,
- 'cause there are cars crossing!
- JACK: That's all right. They'll see us.
[JANE SCREAMS AND LAUGHS]
Right, that's enough.
Step along, children.
[HORNS HONKING]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
JOHN: There must be someone at this bank
who could help us save our house.
- I'm sure Father's already asked.
- Well, we haven't.
Maybe we could get them to see
things from a new point of view.
Sit over there, please, Children.
- Good afternoon. I'd like to see Mr. Michael...
- I'll need a signature for those, sir.
Of course. Excuse me a moment.
Well!
FRYE: We mustn't be late for Mr. Wilkins.
[GOODING SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
What did you do that for?
You hurt his feelings.
You do know who those men
are, don't you, Georgie?
Yes. They're the lawyers.
- He's the nice one.
- Maybe we could convince him to help us.
JOHN: Worth a try.
Today or never, that's my motto.
[WHISPERS] Come on!
Now, how can I help you?
Finally. I'd like to see Mr.
Michael Banks, please.
WOMAN: [OVER PHONE] Hello. Operator.
- FRYE: May we go in?
- PENNY: He's expecting you.
Is there something I can do for you, children?
May I have a sweet, please?
Yes, of course you can, dear.
- [CHUCKLES]
- You all can.
FRYE: Is in foreclosure.
GOODING: Mr. Michael Banks, 17 Cherry Tree Lane.
FRYE: In foreclosure.
How many repossessions, so far, this month?
19, sir, and we have nearly that amount
scheduled for next week alone.
Who'd have thought this slump would
be so good for business, eh?
I wonder, Mr. Wilkins, if, perhaps as
Michael Banks is an employee,
you might consider giving him...
- a few more weeks.
- And lose our chance to get that house?
- I mean... [STAMMERS]
- I don't like to lose, Mr. Frye.
[BUZZER BUZZING]
WILKINS: Didn't I ask for
more tea, Miss Farthing?
Yes, sir. Right away, Mr. Wilkins.
Why don't you all help yourselves?
Come on.
"Office of the Bank Chairman".
We can't go in there.
WILKINS: I'm running a business, not a Charity.
FRYE: It's just that, well...
his family has suffered tremendous
hardship this past year...
WILKINS: You are not giving
Banks one more second...
to pay off that loan.
Do I make myself clear?
- Look.
- Shh!
- GEORGIE: It's the wolf.
- WILKINS: In two days, Banks will be out
on that street and the house...
- will be ours.
- JOHN: Georgie, no!
You can't steal our house.
I'm telling my father!
- Steal your...? Who are you?
- These are the Banks children.
WILKINS: Are they?
- Come here, boy, I think you might have...
- Let's go,
- Georgie!
- ANNABEL: Run!
Close that door, Miss Farthing!
[WHEEZING]
Fool!
Stop them.
MARY: Oh, there you are, Michael. The children
and I brought you your briefcase.
Oh, thank you.
- You're welcome.
- CHILDREN: Father!
- Where are the children?
- Father! Father! Father!
- Help!
- FRYE: Wait!
- MICHAEL: What is it? What's happened?
- He's the wolf, trying to steal our house!
What on earth are you talking about?
WILKINS: I'm afraid your children burst
into my office just now, Banks.
What?
I was just seeing if anything could be
done about extending your loan...
when they came in claiming I was
trying to steal your house.
- He is! We heard him!
- Mr. Wilkins is trying to help us!
But then, why was he chasing us?
I just thought they might stop running around
and making a scene if I offered
them some sweets.
- I'm so sorry, Mr. Wilkins.
- See it doesn't happen again.
After all, you don't want your father losing his
position on account of you, do you? Hmm?
I know time is running short, Banks...
but I want you to have every chance
of paying off that loan.
So, I will make sure that I'm in
my office on Friday evening...
until the last stroke of midnight.
- You have my word.
- Oh, thank you, sir. Thank you.
WILKINS: Gentlemen?
- But, Father, he really did do it.
- Not another word!
- Take them home this instant!
- MARY: Yes, sir.
- We'll discuss this when I get back!
- Come along, children.
JOHN: Now we've done it, haven't we?
I don't think I've ever seen Father
that Upset with us before.
- GEORGIE: But we were telling the truth!
- ANNABEL: That doesn't matter, Georgie.
We got him into trouble, and he doesn't even
know that we broke Mother's bowl.
Everything we've tried to fix,
we've only made it worse.
- Which way do we go, Mary Poppins?
- MARY: Now, why would you ask me?
The three of you are leading the way, after all.
- ANNABEL: Us?
- JOHN: But we were...
- Walking around in a fog.
- No, we weren't.
- I mean, we are in a fog, but...
- We were only talking.
Yes, too focused on where you've been
to pay attention to where you're going.
- But Father told us to go straight home!
- He'll be furious if we're late.
Not much to be done about that now, is there?
Are we lost, then?
JACK: That would depend on where you want to go.
- CHILDREN: Jack!
- At your service.
Say, what's with all the glum faces?
Lost Sixpence and found a penny?
- We've made a mess of everything.
- Father's...
- furious with us.
- And we can't find our way home.
- Lost? Are you, Mary Poppins?
- Hopelessly.
Well, now, I'm no expert...
but if ever I lose my way, I just look
for a little light to guide me.
# Let's say you're lost in a park, sure #
# You can give in to the dark, or #
# You can trip a little light fantastic with me #
# When you're alone in your room #
# Your choice is just embrace the gloom #
# Or you can trip a little light fantastic with me #
# For if you hide under the covers
you might never see the day #
# But if a spark can start inside your heart #
# Then you can always find the way #
# So when life is gettin' dreary, just
pretend that you're a leerie #
# As you trip a little light fantastic with me #
What's a leerie?
Why, it's what we lamplighters
call ourselves, of course.
Time to send up the call to arms.
Leeries, trip the light to lead the way!
# Now, when you're stuck in the mist, sure #
# You can struggle and resist, or #
# You can trip a little light fantastic with me #
# Now, say you're lost in the crowd, well #
# You can stamp and scream out loud, or #
# You can trip a little light fantastic with me #
# And when the fog comes rollin' in, just
keep your feet upon the path #
# Mustn't mope and frown or worse, lie
down don't let it be your epitaph #
# So, when life is gettin' scary
be your own illuminary #
# Who can shine their light
for all the world to see #
# As you trip a little light fantastic with me #
- ANNABEL: Hello.
- JOHN: Hello.
ANNABEL: Thank you!
# A leerie loves the edge of night #
# Though dim, to him, the world looks bright #
# He's got the gift of second sight #
- LEERIES: # To trip a little light fantastic! #
- JACK: # A leerie's job's to light the way #
LEERIES: # To take the night and make it day! #
# We mimic the Moon yes, that's our aim #
LEERIES: # For we're the keepers of the flame! #
# And if you're deep inside a tunnel
and there is no end in sight #
# Well, just carry on until the dawn
it's darkest right before the light #
- JOHN: Now what do we do?
- Well, just as Jack said, we follow the light.
[TAPPING]
[CHILDREN GASP]
Whoa! [LAUGHS]
[ANNABEL YELLS]
# As you trip a little light fantastic #
# Won 't you trip a little light fantastic? #
# Come on #
# Trip a little light fantastic with me #
[SLOW INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING]
[UPBEAT INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING]
LEERIES: Oy!
Oy!
ANGUS: Come along!
- Join us in a bit of kick and prance.
- What did he say?
"Kick and prance," it means
"dance." It's leerie speak.
You don't say the word you mean, you
say something that rhymes, only...
Here, I'll Show you how it works. Angus,
give us your weep and wail.
- To the rest of ya, that means "tale".
- # I was short of a sheet #
- # He was in the street #
- # just to tumble down the sink #
- # Just to get himself a drink #
- # Then I pinched what's fatter #
# He grabbed his ladder #
- # To smile and smirk #
- BOTH: # To work! #
There's nothing to it.
- Can you speak leerie, Mary Poppins?
- Can I speak leerie?
Of course she can. She's Mary Poppins!
- Can we do it with you?
- ALL CHILDREN: Please?
Oh, very well then.
JACK: # Children, tell us your sorry tale #
LEERIES: # Give us your weep and wail! #
- # Well, we had this bowl #
- # Rabbit in the hole #
- # That fell and broke #
- # Bicycle spoke #
- # So we took it to a shop #
- # Like a lollipop #
- # And went upside down! #
- MARY: # That's a circus clown #
- # Then went to the bank #
- # Rattle and clank #
- # Got lost in the fog #
- # Lump on a log #
- JOHN: # Till we found our friend #
- # To stand and defend #
- # Who took us on a trip #
- # Snap a horse's whip #
# And we tripped a little light fantastic! #
- # Now, that sounds a little bit bombastic #
- # But they tripped the light #
- # We tripped the light #
- # Let's trip a little light fantastic! #
[MUSIC CONTINUES]
JACK: # Join us, Mary Poppins! #
[LEERIES EXCLAIM]
You've got it! Now let's get you all back home!
ALL: # Now, if your life is gettin' foggy
that's no reason to complain #
# There's so much in store inside the
door of 17 Cherry Tree Lane! #
# So when troubles are incessant
simply be more incandescent #
# For your light comes with
a lifetime guarantee #
- # As you #
- # Trip a little light fantastic #
- # Won't you #
- # Come on! #
- # Trip a little light fantastic #
- # With me! #
- # Went to the bank, rattle and clank #
# Met with the boss pitch and toss,
got lost in the fog lump on a log #
# Trip a little light fantastic! #
CHILDREN: # Trip a little light fantastic! #
- # Trip a little light fantastic! #
- Where on earth have you all been?
I told you to bring them straight
home. I've been worried sick!
We're sorry we're late, Father.
It wasn't Mary Poppins' fault.
- We got lost in the fog.
- Jack and the leeries...
- led us down the frog and toad.
- He means road.
So you've been off filling the children's
heads with stuff and nonsense.
I've heard quite enough. Come in at once!
- Best to take my leave.
- Good night, Mary Poppins.
- Good night, Jack.
- Into the parlor, go on.
Go on.
Don't be too hard on 'em, sir, they're
only children, after all.
I know they're children, my children,
and I will deal with them as I see fit.
- Now leave us to it.
- Yes, sir.
- Not you, Mary Poppins. In here.
- Very well, sir.
You could have lost me my job.
Do you understand that?
Have you any idea how difficult it is to find
a good position like mine these days?
But there you all were, tearing about like a...
And you, Mary Poppins, I thought you were
here to look after these children.
- It wasn't her doing, it was me.
- No, it was us.
We thought maybe if we talked to Mr. Frye, he
could give you more time to save the house.
- We were only trying to help.
- Well, you didn't help!
Now...
I know it's been a hard year for our family...
and I've done all I can...
to keep you all from worrying, but I can't
do this on my own. It's too hard. I just...
I'm barely holding it together as it is.
I can't even seem to remember
my briefcase in the morning...
and there's no more time, we're
about to lose our home...
and I can't lose this house. I just can't.
I don't know what to do. [VOICE BREAKS]
I'm sorry, I don't know what to do.
Everything's fallen to pieces since
your mother... [CRYING]
Haven't we lost enough already?
We haven't lost Mother. Not really.
# Nothing's gone forever, only out of place #
# So when we need her touch and loving gaze #
# "Gone but not forgotten" is the perfect phrase #
# Smiling from a star that she makes glow #
# Trust she's always there #
# Watching as we grow #
- # Find her in the place #
- # Where the lost things go #
When did you all get so clever?
Last night, Mary Poppins told us...
I hope I'm as clever as you when I grow up.
[CHUCKLES] You're right.
Of course, you're right, Georgie.
Your mother's not gone. She's in your smile.
[CHUCKUNG]
And in your walk, John...
and Annabel's eyes.
And she'll always be with us wherever we go.
Love you.
Now, run along, wash your
hands, get ready for dinner.
Did you have something to do with
them trying to save the house?
I never said a word.
It was all the children's idea.
The whole time I've been looking after
them, they've been looking after me.
- I had it all backward.
- A Banks family trait.
What was I thinking?
Some people think a great deal too much.
Of that I'm certain.
[SIGHS]
[LEAVES RUSTLING]
- Here, Jane. Let me help you with that.
- Oh, thank you.
No luck?
We can look through everything
again if you like.
No. No, there's no point. It's nearly midnight.
We tried our best, but thank
you, Jack, so much...
and thanks to all your friends
for helping us. Thank you.
JACK: Of course.
Anything for you.
[CHUCKLES]
We'll be out in a moment.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
MARY: The children have packed up
the last of their things themselves.
MICHAEL: Well done, everyone.
All right, have you got Gillie?
Yes, Father.
Good, good.
ELLEN: Good riddance to that old kitchen.
Never could figure out that stove.
[MICHAEL CHUCKLES]
All right, well...
we've spent every last moment
that we can here.
It's time to say goodbye.
Goodbye, old friend!
ALL: Goodbye, old friend!
- ANNABEL: Oh, thank you.
- ELLEN: Thank you.
- ANNABEL: Hello, Willoughby.
- JOHN: Miss Lark. Admiral.
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
- What are you all doing here so late?
- We've been waitin' to see you off, sir.
We'd be here no matter what the hour.
MISS LARK: If you or your family
should ever need a place to stay...
Willoughby and I would be
happy for the company.
That's very kind of you, Miss Lark. Jane's
offered to put us up in her flat...
- at least for the time being.
- No, forever, for as long as you'd like.
- I wish you'd come with us, Ellen.
- Oh, don't you worry about me.
I got a nice room fixed up at my sister's.
- You won't leave us, will you, Mary Poppins?
- Oh, don't be silly.
She says she's not leaving until the door opens.
In any case, your home is with us.
I'm pleased she got caught
on your string, Georgie.
My kite!
- I forgot my kite!
- Very well, but be quick about it.
The Admiral's got something he would
like to give you, Mr. Banks, sir.
The H. M. S. Glad Tidings,
I commanded her myself.
- May she guide you safely into port.
- Thank you very much, Admiral.
I will take very good care of her.
Eight bells, Mr. Binnacle,
time to man our posts!
Yes, sir. Goodbye, Mr. Banks, sir.
- JANE: Bye. Bye.
- MICHAEL: Goodbye, Binnacle.
- GEORGIE: I found it!
- ANNABEL: Bye, Miss Lark.
JOHN: Bye, Willoughby.
Oh, I'm not sure that's gonna
get off the ground anymore.
It looks more glue than kite. Georgie, did...?
did you patch this up with
one of my old drawings?
It looks like you've done a fine job, there.
Look.
Can you see?
That's all of us together...
in front of the, Uh...
- What is it, Father?
- Wait.
"Certificate of shares"! This is it.
- This is what we've been looking for!
- ANNABEL AND JANE: Yes! Yes!
MICHAEL: We need to get to the bank!
- What's the time? Anyone?
- Um, seven minutes to midnight.
Seven minutes? It's not enough time, we
need to be at the bank by midnight.
- Take the van.
- No, it's no good.
You still wouldn't make it in time.
- Well, what can we do?
- Oh...
- Nothing. We can't turn back time.
- ANNABEL: Why not?
Everything is possible.
Even the impossible.
JOHN: Can we do that, Mary Poppins?
Can we turn back time?
Well, I don't see why that couldn't be arranged.
- [CHILDREN GASP AND LAUGH]
- But that's ridiculous.
- Indeed it is, Michael. It's nonsense.
- Foolishness!
It makes no sense!
- And if it makes no sense...
- CHILDREN: It can't be true!
- What are you all talking about?
- Never you mind about that.
You just get that kite to the bank as fast
as possible, and leave the rest to us.
- MICHAEL: How will you...
- ALL: Go!
- Now, we'll need a lot of help, Jack.
- JACK: Good as done!
- Go and gather the leeries!
- ANGUS: Right.
Children, help me ready the bicycle.
I'll take the reins this time.
Speed is of the essence.
JOHN: Have you ever ridden
a bicycle like this before?
Oh, please. How different can
it be from riding an elephant?
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
- Ready, and up!
- [ALL GRUNT]
Now, all we have to do is turn back time.
[CHILDREN EXCLAIMING]
GEORGIE: This is fun!
- A very good week's work, gentlemen.
- Thank you, sir.
It look as if Banks won't be joining us tonight.
He does have a few more minutes, sir.
You said you'd wait until the
last stroke of midnight.
Yes, I know that!
So we wait.
I'm a man of my word.
- How much time do we have?
- Um, there's only five minutes left, I think.
Good, now over to the tower, boys!
Sorry, this is as far as you go.
Back in a flash.
[JACK PANTS]
- Come on!
- LEERIE: Come on, lads!
[JACK GRUNTING]
Ladder!
Jack!
[GRUNTING]
- JACK: Ladder!
- LEERIE1: Ladder!
- LEERIE2: Ladder!
- LEERIE3: Ladder!
[GRUNTING]
[GRUNTS AND GASPS]
No, I can't watch!
[GRUNTING]
I mean, you would think they'd
never done this before.
What are we gonna do?
I've got an idea! Come on!
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
Now!
[GRUNTS]
CHILDREN: Yeah!
[GRUNTING]
Jack! You can turn the time back now!
- How? I can't reach the hands!
- Oh, honestly.
They better hurry.
We have less than a minute to go.
- ANGUS: We're too late, Jack!
- JACK: There's got to be a way!
Look!
- [LEERIES CHEERING]
- [LAUGHS]
WILKINS: And three, two, one...
Why hasn't Big Ben chimed?
Perhaps your watch is running fast.
Don't be a simpleton, my watch never runs fast.
Big Ben's gone dark.
Relight the Clock, Jack, quickly.
Look. They've relit Big Ben.
WILKINS: But that time is wrong.
The clock must have stopped.
[TIRES SCREECH]
WILKINS: That's Banks.
He's made it in time!
Not yet he hasn't. Get down
there and make sure...
he doesn't get inside until that
blasted clock strikes 12.
- But, sir...
- Now, Mr. Frye!
[BOTH PANTING]
[GRUNTS] Lock it, Mr. Frye!
MICHAEL: Hello!
- JANE: Hello! Let us in, please!
- MICHAEL: Please, let us in!
JANE: Hello?
Hello?
- Jane.
- What?
Let's...
Let's go fly a kite.
- There it is! It's the one with the light.
- The first one? Okay.
- You run. I'll unspool.
- JANE: Yes, quickly!
- Come on!
- MICHAEL: Come on!
JANE: [SHOUTING] Hello!
No, it won't work. He's never gonna see it.
[WIND HOWLING]
- [JANE GASPS]
- [BOTH LAUGH]
- MICHAEL: Let's get in.
- JANE: Yes, let's go!
- [KNOCKING ON DOOR]
- JANE: Let us in.
- Please!
- Please let us in!
MICHAEL: We need to get inside!
- [FRYE GRUNTS]
- Oh!
- Oh, thank you!
- Thank you!
Hurry, Mr. Banks!
What?
[DOOR OPENS]
What is all this?
It's what we've been looking for.
ADMIRAL BOOM: Three, two, one...
fire!
[BIG BEN CHIMING]
Mr. Binnacle...
Big Ben has finally got it right.
[BIG BEN TOLLING]
MICHAEL: And this goes... at the top.
- Uh... what's that? Where did this go? Uh...
- Is there?
- GEORGIE: Right there?
- MICHAEL: No.
- GEORGIE: No, there.
- This piece goes there.
And does it matter that it's all cut up in bits?
It's still worth something, is it?
It's still valid, so long as all
the pieces are there.
Is that so?
Now, Georgie, there was one more piece, a
corner piece with a lot of signatures on it.
- Do you remember that?
- I must have thrown it out. I'm sorry, Father.
MICHAEL: Oh, that's all right, Georgie.
No, it isn't.
I'm afraid you have a problem, Banks.
You see, without those signatures,
you have no bank shares...
no house...
you have nothing.
What?
- But he knows you have the bank shares!
- He's been planning this all along!
Take your children out of here, Banks.
I've had enough of their lies.
Don't you dare insult my children.
- Don't you dare.
- [PAPER RUSTLING]
They are not lying, and you know it!
I only wish I'd believed them sooner!
You all had him pegged right
from the start, didn't you?
Come on.
Take the house! Go ahead.
I have everything I need right here.
[DOOR OPENS]
He has you there, Willie.
Uncle Dawes?
What on earth are you doing here?
A little bird told me...
that you've been trying to cheat the Banks
family out of their shares in this bank.
That he has. We heard him.
MR. DAWES, JR.: I also hear...
you've been telling the whole of
London that I've gone loony.
The only loony thing I ever did was
trust you to look after this bank!
You can't be serious, I've nearly
doubled the profits of this bank.
Yes, by wringing it out of
the customers' pockets.
Their trust in us built this bank.
You've squandered every
last bit of their goodwill.
Well, Willie... I'm back, and you're out.
Gentlemen, would you show my
nephew to the door, please?
FRYE: Yes, sir, Mr. Dawes.
Get off!
You're not fit to run this bank!
Oh, we'll see about that!
I may be circling the drain but
I got a few steps left in me.
# So, when they tell you that you're finished #
# And your chance to dance is done #
# That's the time to stand
to strike up the band #
# And tell 'em that you've just begun #
# So when life's a real pea-souper
you must choose to be a trouper #
# For your light comes with
a lifetime guarantee #
# As you #
[UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING]
- # With me! #
- # Went to the bank, rattle and clank #
# Met with the boss, pitch and toss
got lost in the fog, lump on a log #
- # Trip a little #
- # Trip a little light fantastic! #
- # Light fantastic! #
[ALL LAUGHING]
MR. DAWES, JR.: Oh.
John, would you... would
you get the feet off the...
- Oh, yeah.
- Thank you. Oh!
- So glad to have you back, Mr. Dawes.
- Oh. Thank you, Michael.
By the way, those shares of yours...
- perfectly fine... save 'em for your family.
- I'm sorry, I don't understand.
I'd like to tell you a little story.
Once Upon a time...
there was a man with a wooden leg, named...
[MUMBLING]
- That's not it.
- [ALL CHUCKLE]
It's about a little boy named Michael.
Michael wanted to give his
tuppence to a bird lady...
but after a little persuasion, hmm?
He decided he'd give 'em to his father.
Michael's father, your grandfather...
gave those tuppence to this bank...
and told us to guard it well.
We did just that.
And after several quite clever investments...
if I do say so myself...
that tuppence has grown into quite a tidy sum.
- Really?
- Really, Michael.
In fact, enough to pay off that loan you took.
- The house is yours.
- [CHILDREN GASP]
Oh!
[ALL LAUGHING]
MICHAEL: What a beautiful
day to be going back home.
- Look at them lovely cherry blossoms.
- They're lovely.
- I shall have to paint them.
- [JANE CHUCKLES]
- What about you, Jane?
- What about me?
He means what about you and that
handsome lamplighter, Jack?
- [ALL CHUCKLING]
- No! No, we're just friends.
- Oh, go on.
- Really.
Stop it, Ellen!
- [ALL LAUGH]
- What's this?
- The Spring Fair, it's today! Can we go?
- Please?
- I don't see why not.
- CHILDREN: Hooray!
ANNABEL: Come on, Father, let's go!
JOHN: Will you go on the Ferris wheel with us?
- MICHAEL: Yes, and you too, Jane!
- JANE: Only if you come with me, Ellen.
ELLEN: What? Wouldn't be
caught dead on that thing.
[ELLEN EXCLAIMS]
[CHILDREN CHATTERING]
[INAUDIBLE CONVERSATION]
[BOTH LAUGHING]
MAN1: Follow me! Follow me! Follow me!
All right, all right. My turn, my turn.
- Let's see it.
- I've got it.
[ALL LAUGH]
MAN2: Come ride the Ferris wheel!
Come ride the Ferris wheel!
- MICHAEL: Georgie! [LAUGHS]
- ANNABEL: Georgie!
- Slow down!
- GEORGIE: Race you!
VENDOR: Lollipops!
ANNABEL: Look at the Ferris wheel!
The ponies!
# Life's a balloon that tumbles or rises #
# Depending on what is inside #
# Fill it with hope and playful surprises #
# And, oh, dearie ducks, then you're in for a ride #
# Look inside the balloon
and if you hear a tune #
# There's nowhere to go but up #
- [GASPS] May we have balloons?
- Yes, of course, we can. Let's go.
# Choose the secret we know
before life makes us grow #
# There's nowhere to go but up # [CHUCKLES]
Hello, we would like some of your
very finest balloons, please.
That you shall have.
But choose carefully, my dearie ducks.
Many have chosen the wrong balloon.
Be sure to choose the one that's right for you.
- Which balloon would you like, Georgie?
- Um...
- Why don't you go first, sir?
- MICHAEL: Me? [CHUCKLES]
Those days are long behind me.
I don't think I've held a balloon
since I was a child.
- Then you've forgotten what it's like.
- To hold a balloon?
To be a child!
# If your selection feels right, well,
then, dearie, hold tight #
# If you see your reflection your
heart will take flight #
# If you pick the right string, then
your heart will take wing #
# And there's nowhere to go but up #
- [MICHAEL GASPS] Oh! [LAUGHING]
- Father.
# Now I feel like that boy with a shiny new toy #
- # And there's nowhere to go but up #
- [LAUGHING] Michael!
# Just one day at the fair has me waltzing on air
and there's nowhere to go but up #
Jane, I remember! It's all true!
Every impossible thing we imagined
with Mary Poppins, it all happened!
# Now my heart is so light
that I think I just might #
# Start feeding the birds and then go fly a kite! #
# With your head in a cloud
only laughter's allowed #
# And there's nowhere to go but up! #
- [ALL LAUGH]
- Father!
You've got to choose your own balloons.
What balloon are you going to have?
This one.
- [CHILDREN CLAMORING]
- I'm going in the air!
[ALL EXCLAIMING AND CHEERING]
CHILDREN: # We're zigging and zagging
our feet never dragging #
# We might take a ride to the Moon #
# All this bobbing and weaving
all comes from believing #
# The magic inside the balloon #
JACK: # The past is the past
it lives on as history #
# And that's an important thing #
# The future comes fast, each second a mystery #
# For nobody knows what tomorrow may bring #
JANE: Oh.
- This one looks like you.
- How do you know?
Oh!
- Don't you lose her, son!
- I won't, sir!
# Up here in the blue, it's a marvelous view! #
BOTH: # Side by side is the best way to fly #
# Once I just looked above but now I am part of #
# The lovely London sky! #
Would you like to try one yourself, sir?
- Well, I'll give it a go.
- All right, love.
Choose carefully.
Well, nowhere to go but up.
ELLEN: # When the clouds make a muss
well, I won't make a fuss #
- # But I'll polish the stars #
- ALL: # Ellen, better let us! #
BOTH: # Give a lift to a foe, for
you reap what you sow #
ALL: # And there's nowhere to go but up! #
[GASPS]
I've set sail!
- Chart a course, Mr. Binnacle!
- That I will, sir!
[LAUGHING]
[ALL CHEERING]
ALL: # If your day's up the spout
well, there isn't a doubt #
# There's nowhere to go but up #
# And if you don't believe, just
hang onto my sleeve #
# For there's nowhere to go but up #
# As you fly over town, it gets harder to frown #
# And we'll all hit the heights
if we never look down #
# Let the past take a bow, the forever is now #
ALL: # And there's nowhere to go but up, up! #
# There's nowhere to go but up #
[CHUCKLES]
Of course, the grown-ups will
all forget by tomorrow.
- They always do.
- Only one balloon left, Mary Poppins.
- I think it must be yours.
- Yes, I suppose it must.
Practically perfect in every way.
- Welcome home, everyone.
- JANE: It's nice to be back, isn't it?
MICHAEL: [CHUCKLES] It is, it's so nice.
I never thought I'd feel this much
joy and wonder ever again, I...
thought that door was closed to me forever.
[CHILDREN CHATTERING EXCITEDLY]
[CHILDREN LAUGHING]
- JOHN: Come on, let's go!
- ANNABEL: Race you up the stairs!
- JOHN: No fair, you got a head start.
- GEORGIE: Oh, wait for me.
It's time.
She's gone, hasn't she, Michael?
Thank you, Mary Poppins.
Good bye.
[CHUCKLES]
I won't forget, Mary Poppins. Promise.
# So hold on tight to those you love #
# And maybe soon from up above #
# You'll be blessed, so keep on looking high #
# While you're underneath the lovely London #
# Sky #
[INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING]
# If your day's up the spout
well, there isn't a doubt #
# There's nowhere to go but up #
# And if you don't believe, just
hang onto my sleeve #
# For there's nowhere to go but up #
# As you fly over town, it gets harder to frown #
# And we'll all hit the heights
if we never look down #
# Let the past take a bow, the forever is now #
# And there's nowhere to go but up, up! #
# There's nowhere to go but up #