[Hr]
ZACH:
"Madison, Delaware," wow.
Mom, are you positive
there weren't any other places...
...looking for vice principals?
-Like where?
- Guantanamo Bay?
-Ooh, too hot.
- North Korea?
-No. They didn't call me back.
Detroit?
This is it.
Come on, come on.
Look. A yard.
You'd never get this in New York.
You don't have to sell me
on this place.
- I'm staying because I love you.
-Aw, I love you too.
And I looked into it.
Legally, I can't live on my own
until I'm 18.
[Hr]
Look at this kitchen.
It's bigger than our apartment.
We don't cook.
Well, look at all of this counter space
to put the takeout on. Whooh.
Do you hear that?
- No, I don't hear anything.
-Exactly.
WOMAN: Live from New York,
it's my sister Gale.
With special guest, my nephew Zach.
- Get in here with a hug.
-Heh, hey. Oh.
-It's an SNL reference.
-Yeah.
- You lived in New York.
- Oh, my goodness. Look at you.
-Ha-ha-ha.
You're not in any color.
- Hey.
-We should change that.
- Oh, my God. It's good to see you.
-Wow, you too.
Okay. Let me take him in.
Oh, my gosh. He gets more handsome
every time I see him.
- So good-looking.
-Thank you, Aunt Lorraine.
He's just a beautiful boy.
Thank God,
because you were such an ugly baby.
- There it is.
-What? It's fine. He's handsome now.
It's not like he's gonna go ugly,
handsome and then back to ugly.
No. The danger's passed. Heh, heh.
Oh, I almost forgot.
I got a present for you
because I'm a cool aunt.
This is from my new
signature men's line.
GALE: Ooh...
-Check it out.
- Awesome.
-it's limited edition...
...so you're not gonna see
a lot of men wearing that hat.
Yeah, I can't imagine
anyone would be wearing it.
-It's so limited edition.
-Try it on. Make sure it fits.
- Try it on right now? Okay.
LORRAINE: Take her for a spin.
Vroom, vroom, vroom, vroom, vroom.
BOTH:.
- Oh, yes. Look at that.
-I mean, come on. That is it.
0K8)'-
Um, I'm gonna go unload some boxes
now and see you around.
Oh, honey. Leave the hat on.
- I don't want you to burn.
LORRAINE: Mm.
- And you look good with it on.
-Thank you. Cool.
[Hr]
[SIGHS]
GIRL:
Smooth.
So you're the new neighbor?
Yeah. Nice to meet you.
How long was the drive
from New York?
No, I can just tell
by the pretty hat that you have.
Oh, no. This-- No.
This is--
This is actually a gift from my aunt.
It's also a gift for me and everyone
who gets to see you wearing it.
I'm Zach, by the way.
- I'm Hannah.
MAN: Hannah.
HANNAH:
I gotta go.
Good talk.
Hi. Hey, we're just moving in.
[Hr]
Just-- Just me and my mom.
- This hat was a gift.
-You see that fence?
Do you see the fence?
- Uh, yes.
-Stay on your side of it.
You stay away from my daughter,
you stay away from me...
...and we won't have a problem.
Well, just met our neighbor.
He's a big teddy bear.
LORRAINE:
Oh, Mr. Shivers?
Yeah, he moved to town
a few years ago.
Very mysterious.
Very sexy. I love his scent.
It's like mint and BO.
- It works.
-Yeah. Not my type.
[GASPS]
GALE:
I remember that day.
Oh.
[Hr]
You okay, sweetheart?
Yeah. Yeah. Sorry. Um...
I'm gonna go get a head start decorating
my room. Knock it off my bucket list.
How's he doing?
Oh, it's been hard.
He's putting up a wall.
Hopefully, a change of scenery
will help.
How are you doing?
Hopefully, a change of scenery
will help.
MAN [ON SCREEN]:
All right, Zach. Let's see what you got.
Fastball.
Two's a curve.
Gotta get up.
You gotta give me the sign.
There you go. Oh!
That's--
- Oh, see? Dad's not perfect.
ZACH: No. Heh, heh.
DAD".
Dad can get one drop.
All right. Read the signs.
It's all just to block.
Don't wanna jump up.
That's how the fastballs get by.
All right. Get ready.
Go fast now. Okay?
Honey? You okay?
Um, yeah. Just found
some old baby pictures.
I really did look like baby Gollum.
GIRL: Yeah, yeah.
That's always the case, right?
BOY: Hey, Becca.
BECCA: Oh, hey.
Yay! New friends, new friends,
new friends.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What do you think you're doing?
I'm going to work.
Gonna do some educating.
Some administrating.
Cool. Mom, I'm the new kid,
which presents its own set of obstacles.
Not sure walking in
with the vice principal is the play.
Just give me a 60-second head start
so I at least have a chance.
Deal. You promise you'll give it a shot?
You know I can't promise you that.
[LOCKS CLICK]
[THE BLUE VAN'S "RACKETEER"
PLAYING]
[ZACH CLICKS TONGUE]
I promise. All right?
And this door-locking thing...
Come on, you're better than that.
Sixty seconds start now,
60, 59, 58, 57, 56, 55, 54...
[SCHOOL BELL RINGS]
PRINCIPAL: All right. Let's find
our seats, ladies and gentlemen.
Find our seats quickly.
Let's find our seats.
Mm-hm.
- Okay. Let's settle down.
-Um...
Okay. Uh, sorry.
- Excuse me. Can we just--? Eeeh.
PRINCIPAL: Your friends will find you.
Okay, cool. Okay. Unh.
So you're the new kid.
- Oh, yeah.
-Cool, cool. Oh.
- Hi, Taylor.
-Hi, Chump.
- She just call you "Chump"?
-Yes, indeed, she did.
My real name is Champ, you know.
But she's never talked to me before
so we're making progress.
PRINCIPAL:
Three...
...two...
...one.
Settle down.
Good morning.
I am so happy to introduce you
to our new vice principal, Ms. Cooper.
And I hope that you show her
the same respect that you show me.
[KID IMITATES BREAKING WIND]
KIDS: Ha-ha-ha.
PRINCIPAL: Who did that?
Who did that?
Ms. Cooper.
I'm watching you.
Hi, everyone.
I know I speak
for the entire administration...
...when I say that we are
so excited for Friday's fall dance.
We can't stop twerking about it.
Oh, no, she didn't.
- Aw, she's worse than the last one.
-That's my mom.
Oh, well, the last one was fantastic.
L-- I'm kidding.
I don't even know what twerking is.
- But I hear it's very popular.
-So...
...you taking anyone to the dance?
- No.
-Yeah.
I was thinking about flying solo too.
Hey, we should go together.
-"Together"?
-Oh, not like "together" together.
Dance together or anything.
Although that could work.
You know, we get the crowd into it?
And then go split off with different girls.
And as a final reminder,
just be safe and have fun.
[CHATTERING]
Take this. Shoot me a text or tweet me.
Has my contact info.
My home address and locker number.
- You know where to find me.
PRINCIPAL: Anyone.
- Thanks.
PRINCIPAL: Anyone is caught dancing...
...with their butt facing their partner,
you will be sent home immediately.
[KIDS JEERING]
Immediately.
[Hr]
Hello?
Is someone there?
[TWIG SNAPS]
Did I scare you?
- Pfft, no.
-Really?
Because you jumped
like 10 feet high, so...
You know...
...I jump a lot.
It's how I stay in such great shape.
- That's good.
-I, um...
- Yeah, I didn't see you at school today.
-Aw, what, you were looking for me?
- No, no. I just-- I just observed--
-No, I'm homeschooled.
Oh, by your dad?
He seems...
...nice.
And intense.
- And a little tense.
-Don't take it personally.
- He doesn't really like anyone.
-Yeah.
So, um...
So is there anything fun to do around
here aside from scaring your neighbors?
- Okay. There is one thing that I like to do.
-Yeah?
Come with me.
Uh...
[Hr]
- Hey, where are we going?
-Don't worry. It'll be fun.
- You sure you know where you're going?
-Yes, come on.
This way.
You taking me somewhere to kill me?
Just curious.
Rm Playing it by ear.
Hannah?
Yes, Zach,
follow the stranger into the woods.
[SQUAWKING]
Come on, scaredy-cat.
We're almost there.
Okay. Just a little further.
Okay. Just wait here.
ZACH:
Okay.
Where exactly is here?
Watch this.
[Hr]
ZACH:
Whoa.
What do you think?
Uh...
It's not what I was expecting.
So, what is this place?
Well, they built it years ago,
but then they ran out of money.
Now it just sits here.
Come on. This is my favorite part.
[Hr]
Wait. What are you doing?
What are you afraid of?
I do this all the time.
I'm-- I'm not afraid.
I'm just not current with my tetanus shots.
[SIGHS]
I hate the suburbs.
HANNAH:
Come on.
You can do it. Just don't look down.
ZACH:
I know.
- You're not gonna fall.
-I wasn't planning on it.
- There you go.
-Hi.
Hi.
All right.
So I'm high off of the ground.
HANNAH:
It's cool, right?
Yeah. It's cool.
You can see everything from up here.
So...
...why'd you move to Madison?
Well, my mom said to me:
"Zach, if you could live anywhere
in the world, where would it be?"
And I said, "Can we please move
to Madison, Delaware?
- That'd be my dream."
-Are you always this sarcastic?
Always? No, that's a strong word.
Not always. Usually.
I'm sorry. It's just, um--
It's just been me and my mom
since my dad died last year, so yeah.
I'm sorry.
I don't really think about it
much anymore.
What about you?
I never knew my mom,
and we're always moving...
...from one town to the next.
That really sucks.
It's fine.
Hey-
Can I ask you something
really serious, Hannah?
Yeah. What?
- How do we get down?
-Heh. Heh.
- I'm serious. ls there a plan?
-No.
- How do you normally get down?
-You can't. You're stuck.
[ZACH CHUCKLES]
HANNAH: Wow, I can't believe you ate
that cotton candy.
ZACH: And you know what's scary
is it actually tasted kind of fine.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
So, uh...
...thanks for tonight. That was...
...the least terrible time I've had here.
-Oh, Zach. That's so sweet.
That's-- I-- Really.
0K8)'-
Hey, Hannah. I'm...
I'm probably gonna take out the trash
on Tuesdays and Thursdays.
So, you know,
you feel like creeping up on someone...
...that works for me.
All right.
I'll keep that in mind, scaredy-cat.
SHIVERS:
Hannah.
- What are you doing out here?
-I'm so sorry.
This is your last warning.
You stay away from us,
or something very bad will happen.
I believe you.
[ROCK MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
ZACH:
"What is X?"
[YAWNS]
What is X?
HANNAH:
Dad, it's not a big deal.
SHIVERS:
You have to understand--
HANNAH:
I don't have to understand anything.
We were just talking.
Why can't I have friends?
SHIVERS: You know why!
HANNAH: That's not fair.
You can't lock me up.
SHIVERS: You're never allowed to see
that boy. You understand me? Ever!
HANNAH:
Dad, please calm down.
[OBJECT SHATTERS]
- Hannah.
HANNAH: No!
[GIRL SCREAMS]
[Hr]
What?
- What?
-I heard a scream. ls Hannah okay?
- There was no scream.
-What?
Get out of here, or the last scream
you ever hear will be your own.
No. Wait, wait--
Mom.
- Hey, Mom. Mom. Morn.
-Oh, hey, sweetie.
- Hey, how about quinoa for dinner?
-Hannah's in trouble.
Oh, who's Hannah?
[LINE RINGS]
MAN:
Madison County 911.
Hi, yes. Uh, I live on Monroe. Um--
- Uh, it's an emergency, I think.
-Zach, what's going on?
ZACH: Yeah. Maybe possibly
a domestic disturbance. I don't know.
[INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER]
- You're under arrest.
-Oh... Wup. Wup, Wup, wup.
I love that enthusiasm. I love that.
Keep it, but we're just not there yet.
Hello, sir. My name's Officer Stevens.
This is Training Officer Brooks.
- Sorry about that.
-You don't need to be sorry.
- You're doing a great job.
BROOKS: Really?
STEVENS:
You're doing fantastic.
We got a call about a possible
10-16 at your residence.
Which is?
Um... Don't tell me.
It's a domestic disturbance.
Absolutely right.
- Really?
STEVENS: Absolutely right.
Strange because I've been here alone
and I haven't heard a thing.
No, no, he's lying.
Where's Hannah?
I know it was her screaming.
Heh. Okay, yes. Hannah's my daughter,
and she's been staying with me...
...for a while while her mother
sorted a few things out...
...with her new husband.
-Huh.
She flew back to London
yesterday morning.
STEVENS:
All right. Well, that checks out.
Apologies, sir.
Thank you for your time.
We're sorry for the disturbance.
[GIRL SCREAMS]
[Hr]
[SCREAMS]
Surround sound.
I didn't know being an audiophile
was a crime.
- Being a what? A what-a-phile?
-Whoa, whoa.
Whoa. That just means that he is
a connoisseur...
...of high-end audio equipment.
BROOKS: Oh.
Hi. I'm so sorry.
We haven't properly met.
I'm Gale Cooper, your new neighbor.
It's a beautiful home you have.
Pleasure's mine.
Thank you so much for stopping by
and bringing your...
...delightful son and the police.
Again, I'm so sorry.
STEVENS:
Apologies for this, sir.
We hate coming into the home
of an upstanding citizen.
BROOKS: Really sorry. I mean,
obviously, you're not doing anything...
STEVENS: If you would like to
press charges against the boy...
...we would love to help you.
- Hannah! Hannah!
-Whoa!
- Hannah!
-No. Hold on, big guy.
- No, just look upstairs. Trust me.
BROOKS: Should I tase him?
- I'll tase him.
- I like that moxie, but we'll hold off.
Have any idea what the penalty is
for filing a false police report?
- Three years.
-Close. It's actually a written warning.
Hold on.
Mom, tell me you don't believe him.
- Surround sound? Seriously?
-Zach,enough.
Go home.
- Oh, officers. I'm so sorry.
STEVENS: It's all right, ma'am.
We should recommend
a good treatment center for your son.
- Yeah. That kid's on drugs.
-That kid is on drugs.
Good night.
Gale.
-It's Lorraine.
-I can see you.
It's your sister.
- Hi. Thanks for coming.
-Hi.
I have to chaperone the dance
at the high school.
- I don't wanna leave Zach alone tonight.
-Gale.
He's a teenage boy
having a hard time adjusting.
You know what he needs? A night
in with his aunt, BeDazzling. Duh.
- Thanks. I hate fighting with him.
-I know.
- It'll get better. Just give it some time.
-Okay.
All right. Kit coming through,
and don't worry.
It's gonna be all about Zach tonight.
Zach!
So we went out
to sushi on Wednesday.
And we both ordered the chicken teriyaki,
which is like, "it's fate."
And then I haven't heard from him since,
which is a bummer because I liked him.
He didn't laugh at any of my jokes,
but I felt like there was something there.
I don't know. Not like I even care.
It's like, whatever.
I should listen to my psychic.
She says, "Stop dating losers,
and never go on a plane."
I knew it.
Oh, so you think he's playing hard to get?
Or the more likely scenario:
He lost his phone in, like, a fire.
- Yeah, I think he lost his phone.
-Yeah. I do too.
You know, I-- I totally forgot.
I have a huge test on Monday
that I gotta study for.
So I'm just gonna do that all night,
and definitely don't come in my room.
Oh, okay.
- Yeah. See you.
-Night, sweetie.
But you know what, I'm just gonna
call him. Now I'm worried he's dead.
[Hr]
[SIGHS]
ZACH:
Hey, hey, hey.
Over here.
Wait. So how is this gonna work?
Are you my wingman, or am I yours?
- You're wearing that?
-Gotta tell you something. Get down.
Dude, no.
This is a new suit, all right? Get off.
- Where are the girls?
-Uh, yeah. I just said that to get you here.
I need your help.
So there are no girls?
Well, there is one girl.
'Oh! My man!
~Shh! '
What? What?
But she's locked in this house,
and her dad's a psychopath.
Does she have a friend?
No. I'm serious.
[SIGHS]
You said there was gonna be girls,
and not only are there no girls...
...there's a psychopath, and I'm in a suit.
How do you know he's gonna leave?
I called and pretended to be the cops.
I asked him to come to the station.
- You can get in big trouble.
-Just a written warning.
Dude. It's wet dirt, dude.
My pants are gonna get muddied.
ZACH:
He's right there.
[Hr]
[ENGINE STARTS]
Whoa.
All right. Let's go.
- Come on. Dude.
-Okay, okay. Ooph!
- My dry-cleaning bill will be ridiculous.
-Come on.
Whoa.
Where'd you learn that, New York?
- No, YouTube.
-Oh.
[CREAKING]
- Okay, stay here and watch the driveway.
-Wait here by myself?
- Out in the dark?
-Yes, Champ. You're the lookout.
If Shivers comes back, just give
me a sign like:
[IMITATES OWL HOOTING]
Okay, just so we're clear...
...if I sense any danger,
I will run the other way.
[Hr]
[GRUNTS]
[CLOCK CLANGS AND CUCKOOS]
Where am I?
[Hr]
[ZACH YELLS]
You're supposed to be the lookout.
And that's not gonna change.
I'll just be the lookout in here.
No, no, by definition
you have to be somewhere out, looking.
Let me explain something. You know how
they say teenagers have no fear of death?
That they're never gonna get hurt?
Not me, okay?
I was born with the gift of fear.
I remember being 4...
...on a swing thinking,
"This is how it ends."
You're not gonna die.
At least not today.
- Okay? It's gonna be okay.
-Yeah, you're right.
- Okay.
-I'm being ridiculous.
Oh, bear traps.
Who puts bear traps in their basement?
I mean, seriously.
[CREAKING]
Let's go.
What? Let's go outside where it's safe.
Where there's no bear traps.
[CHAMP PANTING]
[GRUNTS AND THEN COUGHS]
I think I swallowed some web.
[RUMBLING]
Dude, this way.
Come on. Come on.
[RUMBLING]
- Up there.
-Oh...
[RUMBLING]
It's coming from that room.
[WHISPERS]
Hannah?
[Hr]
[RUMBLING]
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
That's weird.
It's like the noise
is coming from this bookcase.
Well, it's an old house.
[c:l_lc:I
Whoa. Check this out.
The Scarecrow Walks at Midnight.
The Ghost Next Door,
Night of the Living Dummy.
These are all Goosebumps manuscripts.
What's he doing with
a bunch of kids' books?
These aren't kids' books. Okay?
Kids' books help you fall asleep.
These books keep you up all night.
"R.L. Stine."
What ever happened to that guy?
Uh, who knows? He disappeared.
Does it matter? Let's go.
The Abominable Snowman
of Pasadena.
My grandma lives in Pasadena.
I stopped visiting after reading this.
0K8)'-
- We're not here for book club.
-I know, but why are these books locked?
I mean, who would lock a book?
Maybe there's like, a key or
something we can unlock it with.
Okay, if it really matters that much,
look at this. All right?
Mystery solved.
Now let's get back to why-- Look out!
Zach?
Hey, Hannah.
What are you doing in my house?
- I thought you were chained up, possibly.
-Why would you think that?
Because I heard you scream,
and then I called the police.
- Okay, both of you need to go right now.
-Yes. Okay.
One second.
Hi. Hi, I'm Champ. Nice to meet you.
Hey, we're going to the semiformal
later tonight...
...and, uh, I don't know,
you should come and invite a friend.
- I really don't care what she looks like.
-Did you unlock a book?
Yeah, I did. I'm sorry.
It's around here somewhere.
I just dropped it. I'll put it back
and we'll be out of your hair.
- Look. Here it is--
-No. Don't open it.
[ZACH & CHAMP GASP]
No!
[Hr]
[GROWLING]
[ROARS]
[SNOWMAN ROARS
AND CHAMP WHIMPERS]
[GRUNTING AND SNIFFING]
-[WHISPERS] What's going on?
-[WHISPERS] Nobody make a sound.
[ROARING]
[SCREAMING]
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
My dad's gonna kill me.
Wait. Zach.
Zach.
[Hr]
[DOGS BARKING]
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Wait, Hannah.
- Hannah. Hannah, wait.
-Go home. You're in over your head.
- You wanna tell me what's going on?
-No, I can't explain. I have to go.
Zach, wait. Wait. Come on. Listen.
- Stop. Stop. Stop.
-Dude, what are you doing?
- Dude. Dude, get off me.
-Listen very carefully.
That's the Abominable Snowman.
You don't get that nickname by accident.
And it crawled out of a book.
- That doesn't just happen, Zach.
-I'm going after Hannah.
Look, I read what it did to Pasadena.
It's no joke, man.
[Hr]
She went in there.
Yeah. She's not the only one
who went in there.
Dude, we should call the cops.
Have you met the cops in this town?
Fair enough.
Do you see the scratches on that wall?
Yes.
Just making sure.
[CHAMP SCREAMS
IN HIGH-PITCHED TONE]
- Oh!
-Is that your scream?
Don't judge me.
Over here. This way.
[Hr]
CHAMP:
What is she gonna do, read it a story?
Hannah? What is happening?
- How did that pop out of a book?
-[WHISPERING] Shh. It's here.
- Hey, we should get a gun.
-Are you kidding? We need a tank.
Wait. He's made out of snow.
- Flamethrower.
-Bag of salt.
-Quiet.
He can't be killed.
It's candy.
[Hr]
Look out!
[YELLING]
[ROARS]
[GRUNTING]
Come on. It's distracted.
- Hannah, come on. Let's go.
-What are you doing? Get off. No. Stop it.
The only way to stop them
is to suck them back into the book.
CHAMP: Drop the book.
Let it suck itself back in.
No, I'm not close enough.
[GROWLING]
- What are you doing? Open the book.
-Just wait.
ZACH: Hannah, open the book.
HANNAH: Not yet.
ZACH & CHAMP: Hannah!
-Now!
- The book.
-Hannah, what are you doing?
Hannah.
[SNARLING]
[SHRIEKS]
- No.
-No.
Don't let it get the book.
- Are you okay?
-Yeah.
- Come on, let's go!
-Come on. Come on.
Over here. Come on.
- Come on.
ZACH: Good idea. Punch it.
- Bad idea. Bad idea. Get off that thing.
-Aah!
[ROARING]
[Hr]
ZACH:
Run.
Hurry, this way.
Guys, come on. In here.
Guys, come on. Hurry!
[Hr]
Yes.
[SNARLS]
[SNARLING]
[ALL GRUNTING]
[HANNAH SHRIEKING]
[GRUNTING AND WHIMPERING]
All of you in the car, now!
CHAMP: What are you gonna do to us?
SHIVERS: Silence.
- We can't even ask questions--?
-Shut up.
They were trying to help.
I told you to stay away,
or something bad would happen.
That's the problem with kids today.
They don't listen.
You had to pick
Abominable Snowman of Pasadena.
You couldn't have picked
Little Shop of Hamsters.
- You're him, aren't you?
SHIVERS: Hm?
You're R.L. Stine.
SHIVERS:
R.L. who? I don't know who that is.
ZACH:
Oh, really?
Well, just as well,
because his books suck.
- What are you doing?
-I can't decide...
...which one I hate more,
Monster Blood or Go Eat Worms!
CHAMP:
I'm so confused.
You see the endings coming
from a mile away. It's like...
...stop trying to be Stephen King, man.
[TIRES SCREECHING]
Let me tell you about Steve King.
Steve King wishes he could write like me,
and I've sold way more books than him.
- But nobody ever talks about that!
-Okay.
Way more books!
HANNAH: Dad...
-Aah!
...your face is doing the red thing again.
No way.
Wait, you're R.L. Stine? That's you?
Really? Really?
Hey, can I get a picture real quick?
- No.No.
-Come on. Come on.
- The answer's "yes."
-I said no.
What? I-- No!
Get that thing out of here.
I'm sorry. I just wanted a photo
real quick for my lnstagram.
Oh, is that all? Let me see.
- Oh, yeah. Here you go.
-Thank you.
[Hr]
Hey, what happens now?
Go home, put on your p.j.'s,
get your blankie, you go nap-nap.
In the morning, this will
feel like a bad dream.
- Dad, wait.
-There's no time. Start packing.
We're moving again.
So, what do you wanna do now?
Zach,dude.
HANNAH:
But I don't wanna leave. I like it here.
STINE:
Hannah, you have to understand.
HANNAH:
I don't have to understand anything.
Why can't we be normal for once?
Because we're not a normal family.
Now go get your things.
I'm so over this.
Oh! Teenagers!
[YELLS]
I could've killed you.
- That was a terrible throw.
-How?
What are you doing here? Go home.
No, no. Not until you explain
what's going on.
No, no, no. I can't explain it.
We were almost just eaten
by Frosty the Snowman...
...which should be impossible, so try.
Okay, look.
[SIGHS]
Where do I begin?
When I was younger, I suffered from
terrible allergies that kept me indoors.
And all the kids threw rocks
at my window and called me names.
So I created my own friends.
Monsters, demons, ghouls...
...to terrorize my neighborhood
and all the kids that made fun of me.
And they became real to me.
And then one day...
...they actually...
...became...
...real.
My monsters
literally leapt off the page.
As long as the books remain locked,
we're safe...
...but when they open...
...well, you've just seen what happens.
I'm allergic to dust mites.
What's your point?
I'm just saying, I have allergies too
so I understand.
Why am I talking to you?
Hannah, let's go.
- Hannah.
-Sorry.
Let's go.
Hannah, you grab A to M,
I'll get M to zed.
And keep the man-eating plant
away from the bug-eyed aliens.
Oh, no. Not him.
MALE VOICE:
Hello, Papa.
[Hr]
How long's it been?
Feels like forever.
Who are your new friends?
- We're not.
-Barely know him.
Slappy, it's so nice to see you again.
- Did you miss me?
-Of course I missed you.
[THUNDER CRASHES]
[ZACH & HANNAH GASP]
So, what's the plan, friend?
You must've brought me out
for something fun.
Terrorize the locals?
Destroy the town?
Let's get silly.
You guessed it, Slappy.
I'm going to destroy Madison, and I--
And I couldn't do it without you.
Aw, shucks. You're giving me--
Oh, what's the word?
Goosebumps.
[LAUGHS]
- Oh, my God. He's so creepy.
-Oh, he is such a crack-up.
Such a clever dummy.
Who are you calling "dummy,"
dummy?
You're trying to put me back in?
No, no, no. Don't be silly.
I know when you're lying to me, Papa.
[THUNDER CRASHES]
You've made Slappy very unhappy.
He's not going back on the shelf
ever again.
Slappy, no, wait!
I think it's time I started
pulling the strings in this relationship.
Tonight is gonna be the best story
you've ever written.
All of your children
are coming out to play.
[LAUGHING]
Oh, thank God he's gone.
Oh, God.
He's gone.
And he's taken all the books.
[Hr]
[ENGINE REVS]
That one's a real page-turner.
[SLAPPY LAUGHING]
STINE: Congratulations.
You've just released a demon.
A ventriloquist dummy
with a serious Napoleonic complex.
For the record, I opened one book.
That was a mistake.
HANNAH: Snowman must've knocked
Slappy's book down.
I still blame him. I don't like you, boy.
[DOORKNOB CLICKING]
It's locked from the outside.
[CLATTERING]
Out the kitchen door. Go now.
[GASPS]
[Hr]
- Why is that here?
-I don't know.
[BOTH YELL]
- Hi.
-Wee-hee!
[GNOMES LAUGHING
AND CHATTERING]
Maybe they're friendly.
Not friendly. Definitely not friendly.
GNOME 1:
Whooh...
[GNOMES LAUGHING
AND CHATTERING]
[STINE YELLING]
STINE: He's stuck to my face.
Definitely not friendly.
HANNAH:
Dad! Aah!
Hold on. I'll save you.
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry. Are you okay?
CHAMP: Unh!
GNOME 2: Ready, set, go.
GNOME 3:
No!
I'm sorry.
Help me. Oh, no, no, no.
Help, someone.
Get back. Get back.
[CHAMP SCREAMS]
[BLOWING]
Get back.
GNOMES [IN UNISON]:
Heave-ho. Heave-ho.
- Help me. Help me. Get them off.
HANNAH: Okay.
GNOMES:
Heave-ho. Heave-ho.
STINE:
Quickly.
HANNAH:
Shut it. Shut it.
STINE: Did you get them all?
GNOMES: Heave-ho. Heave-ho...
- Untie me.
CHAMP: I imagined something different.
"Come over to my house.
There will be girls. I'm your wingman."
[GNOMES GRUNTING
AND LAUGHING]
Oh, no, no, no.
We need to get to the basement.
Jfslocked.
-I picked it.
STINE:
That's breaking and entering.
[Hr]
Watch out for the bear traps.
CHAMP: Why'd it have to be bear traps?
ZACH: All right, come on. Hurry.
[GNOMES GRUNTING]
STINE: Lock it. Lock it.
ZACH: Okay.
Why couldn't you have written stories
about rainbows and unicorns?
Because that doesn't sell
400 million copies.
Whoa, domestic?
No, worldwide.
It's still very impressive. Shut up.
[Hr]
HANNAH:
What is that?
- He's burning the books.
-Why's he doing that?
So there's no way to get
the monsters back inside.
It's Slappy's revenge.
Slappy's Revenge. That's a good title.
[CAR HORN HONKING]
[SLAPPY WHOOPING
AND LAUGHING]
Sorry, folks. I'd slow down,
but I can't reach the brake.
Hey, check out my new best seller.
It'll grow on you.
Dropped calls are gonna be
the least of this town's problems.
[WOMAN SHRIEKS]
I'm driving myself crazy.
[ALL SHOUTING AND SCREAMING]
STEVENS: The town has been invaded.
Communications are down.
We're talking mass chaos,
and no one knows how to stop it.
What do you think?
I'm not sure. I--
- I don't know.
-It's The Blob.
The Blob.
The original one with Steve McQueen.
I can't believe
you don't know that movie.
Come over to my house.
I got it on LaserDisc. We'll wa--
Power went out again.
God. All night with this.
Well, these emergency lights
should kick on soon.
[SQUEAKING]
[Hr]
Somebody left
their ventriloquist dummy.
Who you calling "dummy"?
It's talking. What is that thing?
I come in peace. Unarmed.
- I just wanna read you a bedtime story.
-Sir, shut your mouth.
SLAPPY: That's not gonna stop me.
-Hands where I can see them.
Officers, you've been relieved
of your duties. Ha, ha!
Now, freeze.
[SCRAPING]
LORRAINE:
Hello?
Oh, hello, cutie. You must be lost.
[DOG WHIMPERING]
Aw... And no tags.
Well, let's get you some water.
We'll take you around the neighborhood
and find your owner.
Is he handsome?
Is he single?
Is he thinking about leaving his wife
and needs a push?
[Hr]
All right. Trying not to spill.
Don't be clumsy, Lorraine.
Okay, you must be so thirsty.
[ROARS]
[SCREAMS]
[Hr]
HANNAH:
Everyone in town's been frozen.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God, Dad.
Dad, what happened to--?
Wait.
Oh. Oh, thank God.
Guys, false alarm. It's not my dad.
- What are we going to do?
-Without those manuscripts...
...there's nothing I can do.
If you wrote the monsters off the page,
maybe you could write them back on.
Wait-- Yeah. Why don't you do that?
STINE: You have any idea
how many stories I'd have to write...
...to capture every monster
I've created?
- I have carpal tunnel in both hands.
-Dad, listen to him. It's a great idea.
Just one.
One story to capture them all.
Hmm, simple. Just one, one story,
with every monster I've ever created.
Brilliant. Really good idea.
He's a keeper.
You have a better idea?
Mm-hm, mm-hm.
A much better idea.
No, not now, I don't, but--
We gotta get you to a computer
so you can start writing. All right, there's--
There's a computer store.
Just break in.
No, no, no. I need my typewriter.
- What?
STINE: Every story I've written...
...was on that Smith Corona.
It's not just me.
That typewriter is special.
It has a soul of its own.
[SIGHS]
If I write on anything else, it won't work.
Where's the typewriter?
Oh, don't worry.
It's somewhere safe.
[JASON DERULO'S "GET UGLY"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
♪ Get ugly a'
[ALL CHEERING]
♪ And everybody say a'
♪ Get ugly a'
♪ Get ugly N
Come on.
Come on, come OH, come on.
[PHONE BEEPING]
[SIGHS]
Just give me one bar.
This was working earlier.
- Brains.
-Aah!
Heh, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to scare you.
I did mean to scare you,
but in a playful way.
So, uh, is everything okay?
Uh-- Uh--
I'm sorry, I have to get hold of my son,
and I can't get any service.
Yeah. No one can tonight. It's weird.
[Hr]
ZACH: I don't know what's going on
with my phone.
I can't get reception.
Slappy's taken out the cell-phone towers.
That's what I'd do.
He's cutting us off. Isolating us.
[THUMPING]
What was that?
[INVISIBLE BOY CHUCKLING]
Ugh, it's the Invisible Boy.
He's a menace.
[CHUCKLING CONTINUES]
[SLAPS]
STINE: Shove him out the window.
Roll up the window.
ZACH: He's got his tie.
-Help, help.
STINE:
Hold on.
[INVISIBLE BOY YELLS]
INVISIBLE BOY:
Not cool!
Are you okay?
- Yeah.
-For sure.
Yeah. Wait. Wait, look out!
[ALL YELLING]
[STINE YELLS]
[ALL GRUNTING]
- Are you okay?
-Yeah.
Everyone okay?
It came out of nowhere.
[CREATU RE GROWLING]
[Hr]
[CHITTERING]
[ALL SCREAMING]
I don't remember writing
about a giant praying mantis.
- Right. Now I remember.
-Get us out of here!
What are you doing?
- Well, I can't drive if I can't see.
-Just go!
[Hr]
CHAMP:
Oh, my God.
- Watch out!
-Turn left!
- Stop driving straight. Step on it.
HANNAH: He's catching up.
- Turn right.
-Someone else wanna drive?
Because I'll pull over right now.
[ALL SCREAM]
[CHITTERING]
Why'd you come up
with something so freaky?
I just have a knack for it, I guess.
Oh, no. My Wagoneer.
I had such low mileage on it.
- How far are we from the high school?
-Not too far.
- We can out through the cemetery.
-I'm sorry, a cemetery?
Relax. The high school's
just past the woods.
STINE:
How do you know that?
Uh, sometimes I get a little stir-crazy
and go exploring.
- When?
-At night, after you go to bed.
You're grounded.
- That is so unfair.
STINE: It's fair.
Guys, you're both bringing up
good points, but let's keep moving.
Sneaking off at night
with strange boys.
- Unbelievable.
-Shut it.
[Hr]
[SIGHS]
- Do you have a dollar I could borrow?
-What? No.
- Why?
-I'm parched.
- Take one. I'm sure they'll understand.
-Really? Ha.
Lemonade, grape...
...or strawberry?
-Good God, man.
Here. Orange.
[CHUCKLES]
Don't know what I was thinking. There's
way more going on here than New York.
- What?
-Uh, you cut yourself.
- Is it bad?
-Uh, yeah. It's really bad.
- Is my face messed up?
-Yeah.
Big time.
You look exactly the same.
[BOTTLE CLINKS]
Did you hear that?
[Hr]
[GRUNTING AND SNIFFING]
[SODA FIZZES]
[SNARLING AND SNIFFING]
What are you doing?
That's the Werewolf of Fever Swamp.
He can smell my scent.
No, it's not working. I have to hide.
[Hr]
Come on.
[SNARLING AND SNIFFING]
Shh,no,no,no.
Do something.
[TOY SQUEAKS]
Come on, come on. Come on.
Come on. Go, go, go.
[BARKING]
STINE:
He's on our tail. Go.
ZACH:
Go. He's right behind us.
[WEREWOLF WHIMPERS]
Come on. Go, go.
Ha-ha-ha. Oh!
I'm stuck. Help me get out.
- What are you doing?
-There's no time.
- I said get me out of here.
-Gotta go. There's no time.
I said get me out--
Oh, no. Keep going. He's chasing us.
I'm going as fast as I can.
[WHISTLES]
- Just go. We're right behind you.
-Okay.
Come on. We gotta go.
Get up. Get up.
- Come on, come on!
-Let's go, guys.
HANNAH:
Come on, come on, come on.
Ha! Let's see him get through that.
[THUMPING]
Go, go. Run, run.
[BARKING AND SNARLING]
Jfslocked.
STINE: This way.
[WEREWOLF SNARLS]
[CLAWS SCRAPING]
[ROARS]
Whoa!
[WHIMPERING]
I'm okay.
I'm still okay.
- Who is that?
-it's my Aunt Lorraine.
- Oh, my gosh. I think I killed that bear.
-It was actually a werewolf.
- What?
-What are you doing here?
This is the back of my store.
Didn't know where else to go.
I can't get ahold of your mother
or the cops or anyone.
- Hello.
-Uh, hi. Hello.
Hi.
I don't think
we've been properly introduced. Um--
I'm-- I'm Lorraine.
Hello. R.L. Stine.
We owe you a great debt of gratitude.
- Your reckless driving saved our lives.
-Oh, that old thing? Ha, ha.
- Lorraine. Lorraine.
-So...
Lorraine, we don't have time.
I need you to go to the police.
Tell them to meet us at the high school.
- All right? Can you do that? Okay.
-I can do that.
Did you wanna exchange numbers?
STINE:
It's not a good time, but yes!
[Hr]
CHAMP:
Oh, God, this is a bad idea.
What was that?
[CREATURE SCREECHING
IN DISTANCE]
STINE: You okay?
-Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. Just a root. Nothing scary here.
So how did you get
the nickname "Champ"?
It's not a nickname.
Wait. That's your real name?
Is it short for something?
- My full name is Champion.
-Your actual name is Champion. Heh.
Sorry.
CHAMP:
Dad won a bronze in the '92 Olympics.
STINE:
Really?
[Hr]
CHAMP: My mom, she was
an all-American sprinter...
...and a two-time
world debate champion.
So they named me "Champ."
- If you're scared, I can hold your hand.
-Please, you're the soaredy-cat.
[SHRIEKING]
Wait. Hold on. It's okay.
It's just a statue.
All right? You're fine.
It's all right. All right?
Just give me a sec. it's--
It's caught on your jacket.
My hero.
There. You're free to go.
[Hr]
What is it?
Nothing.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Yeah, totally. I'm fi-- Unh!
- Zach!
-Unh! Unh!
[ZACH YELLS]
[GHOULS GRUNTING
AND GROWLING]
Run!
- Ghouls. Go, go.
-Oh! Oh!
[Hr]
Oh, they're getting closer.
- Go. Here. Go. Go.
STINE: Come on. Come on.
ZACH:
Go, go, go.
STINE:
Hurry, quick, quick, quick.
Unh, I'm stuck.
- Go on without me. Save yourself.
-Okay. Good luck.
No, I didn't mean it. Champion!
What kind of monster
would take me up on that?
ZACH: Pull.
-Everybody pull.
I'll kill him.
Where is that little imbecile?
Wait for us, you coward!
All right. Okay, Lorraine. You got this.
Just tell the cops to head to the high
school and that everyone's in trouble.
You can do this. Okay. Unh!
Nope. Wrong door.
Hello?
Is anyone in here?
[Hr]
Calling all cops, calling all the cops.
Head to the high school.
My nephew's in trouble.
He's with R.L. Stine.
They think they know how to stop all this.
Hello? Can anyone hear me?
SLAPPY:
I can hear you.
Sergeant Slappy,
ready to protect and serve.
Oh, my goodness.
- You're...
-Don't do it.
-...a talking...
-Don't say it.
-...dummy.
-You said it.
[SCREAMS]
You have the right to remain silent.
Where did they put my typewriter?
I know it was this way.
It might've been the other way.
- We should split up.
CHAMP: What? No.
Ever read your books?
We're never supposed to split up.
Come on.
How many display cases could there be?
- You're touching me.
-Yeah. Hang on a second.
- Hannah doesn't know, does she?
-She doesn't know what?
That she's not real.
[Hr]
She thinks she's a person. Okay?
Not some figment of your imagination.
How could you lie to her?
I was trying to protect her.
Oh, yeah? Well, good job with that.
This gift of mine is a curse.
You have no idea
how lonely it's been until Hannah.
She's different.
I wrote her in such a way that she thinks
she's real, and she is real to me, Zach.
I don't expect you to understand.
ZACH:
Actually, I do.
STINE:
I'm afraid of losing her.
And the truth is,
I'm afraid of being alone.
I suppose I stopped connecting
with real people when I was your age.
After my dad died,
I shut everyone out too.
Maybe we can both start over...
...if we're alive tomorrow.
There you are.
Are you okay?
You look like you just saw a ghost.
Okay. Well, come on.
We found the typewriter.
Oh, my sweet darling,
I've missed you so much.
- All right, so start writing.
-Yes, but what's the story?
What? Monsters lose,
good guys win, the end.
No, no, no. It doesn't work unless
it's a real Goosebumps story with...
...twists and turns and frights.
Not to mention
some personal growth for our hero.
- What?
STINE: Go to the gym.
Warn everyone.
Tell them to barricade the school.
- Where are you going?
-To find someplace to write.
Slappy's going to come for me.
I have a deadline, literally. Now go.
[Hr]
Unbelievable.
[OVER SPEAKERS]
♪ Off, off, off, off, off with your head ♪
♪ Dance, dance till you're dead 4'
♪ Heads will roll, heads will roll A'
[ALL CHEERING]
♪ Heads will roll on the floor a'
ZACH:
Excuse me.
Sorry. Coming through.
Come on. We gotta get to the stage.
♪ Heads will roll, heads will roll A'
♪ Heads will roll on the floor h'
So this is what
a high-school dance is like.
Uh,yeah.
Usually the dancing's better...
...but you get the idea.
MAN 1: That what they call dancing now?
MAN 2: I'm not sure.
Zach.
ZACH: Morn. Morn.
GALE: Zach.
- I couldn't get hold of you or Lorraine.
-I know. I know.
Mom, everyone here is in danger,
we have to barricade the school.
- Oh, no. Not this again.
HANNAH: He's telling you the truth.
Hi, I'm Hannah. I live next door.
[RECORD SCRATCHES
AND MUSIC STOPS]
All right.
Okay, everyone, listen up. Okay?
- Okay. Everybody, you gotta listen up--
COACH: Champ.
CHAMP: I have something to say.
-Get down.
[CROWD JEERING]
CHAMP: Uh... Wow.
BOY 1: Get off the stage.
Okay, um...
Uh, okay, uh...
Listen to my best friend Zach.
- Just-- Just tell them.
-Thanks, Champ.
- Yeah.
-Yeah. All right. Um...
This is going to sound insane...
...but monsters have invaded Madison.
[ALL CHATTERING AND LAUGHING]
Guys, it's the truth. Okay?
He's telling the truth. it's--
He's not making this up.
They've blocked every road out of town,
they've torn down the cell towers...
...and we've been cut off
from the rest of the world.
And they could be coming for us
any second so we need to work to--
[BOY 2 SCREAMS]
He's right. It's the Boogeyman...
...and he's picking his nose.
[ALL LAUGHING]
- I'm not making--
BOY 2: Aah!
There's a giant bug,
and it's eating everybody's cars!
- Uh, it's getting old, dude.
-No, seriously!
[BOY 2 SCREAMS]
[ALL GASPING]
[CHITTERING]
[ALL SCREAMING]
They're here.
Whoa.
[THUMPING]
Ha, ha!
Now, this is a real homecoming.
[LAUGHING]
[Hr]
[GNOMES LAUGHING]
All right. Everyone, calm down. Okay?
I know what to do...
...but I can't do it by myself.
Take this.
Invite the rest of our friends
to the party.
ZACH".
Look. Those things out there...
...they're R.L. Stine's monsters.
He's here, and he can fix this,
but we need to buy him time to write.
And don't worry,
he's a very quick writer.
The night was cold.
Cold was the night.
[WOLVES HOWLING]
SLAPPY:
Come close. Don't be shy.
You don't wanna miss the show.
[TYPEWRITER CLACKING]
All right, everyone.
These are all the exits.
Find anything to barricade the doors
because we cannot let the monsters in.
Come on, guys. We don't have
a lot of time. Stack them up there.
Come on, quickly. Quickly. Yes.
[Hr]
All my friends in one place.
I've never been so happy.
I don't want this day to end...
...and it doesn't have to...
...as long as we get rid of Stine.
- Charge!
GNOMES: Woo-hoo!
[SNOWMAN ROARING]
[GRUNTING AND GROWLING]
[INSECTS BUZZING]
[GRUNTING]
Go, go, go. It's not gonna hold. Go.
GO, go!
ROBOTS:
We come in peace.
[ROARS]
- We should be helping.
-We should be leaving.
[TAYLOR SHRIEKS]
[SNARLS]
Uh... Wow.
What? What?
Where are you going?
We are so through.
[GROWLING]
Please, no. Please. Please.
No, please.
[CHAMP YELLS
THEN WEREWOLF SNARLS]
[CHAMP GRUNTING
AND WEREWOLF BARKING]
[GASPS]
[TAYLOR SHRIEKS]
[WEREWOLF WHIMPERING]
- Oh, my God. How'd you do that?
-Oh, um...
Silver fillings. I have a ton of cavities.
When I was 10,
I didn't brush my teeth for a year.
Ugh, werewolf hair. Oh.
[Hr]
You saved my life, Chump.
It's actually "Champ."
I was just gonna say "hug me again,"
but yeah, yeah, that works too.
[Hr]
[LAUGHING]
[WHISPERING]
We can't keep this up. There's too many.
We have to get to Stine.
- Let's go.
-Okay.
All the monsters had converged.
The vicious vampire bats...
...the praying mantis...
...the haunted mask...
SLAPPY: Forgetting somebody?
-Slappy.
- How did you find me?
-Ha-ha-ha.
I know you. I created you.
Or is it the other way around?
I always forget. We're so similar.
SIaPPV?
- Slappy?
-Hi.
[SHRIEKS]
"Everyone in the high school
joined forces...
...to defeat Slappy and his monsters."
Hmm. But Sappy had other 'fleas.
No.
[SCREAMING AND GROANING]
Dad!
- Are you okay?
-That dumb dummy broke my fingers.
I was almost finished.
- One or two pages left.
ZACH: Forget two pages.
- Just write two words, "the end."
-It doesn't work like that.
PRINCIPAL [OVER PA]:
School-wide announcement:
Monsters have overwhelmed
Madison High.
Retreat in an orderly fashion
to the storage room.
I repeat, retreat in an orderly fashion
[ALL SCREAMING]
- We'll figure this out later. Let's go.
-Follow me.
Come on, go!
- Aah!
-Hannah. No.
[GRUNTING]
Close it. Close it.
[Hr]
- Are you okay?
-Yeah. Yeah. Thanks.
- Come with me.
HANNAH: Okay.
Wait. Wait, she's a--
Yes, and I don't care.
[MONSTERS GRUNTING
AND GROWLING]
[Hr]
All right. Come on, come on, come on.
Go, go, go. Shut it! Go!
PRINCIPAL:
Get that door. Get it. Get it. Get it.
Oh, God.
PRINCIPAL:
Wait. Mom, Mom, Mom. You okay?
Are you okay? Yeah.
- What do we do? They'll get through.
ZACH: I don't know.
STINE:
Slappy wants me.
That's who he's after.
Listen, if I can lure them away in a bus,
they'll follow me. You'll all be safe.
- I'm coming with you.
-No. I need to do this alone.
I've been running from people
my whole life.
I was so angry at the real world
that I created these terrible monsters.
PRINCIPAL:
Hold that door down.
But I'm not mad anymore.
It's my fault, not this town's.
- Not yours.
-There's gotta be another way.
Hannah, sweetheart...
...it's time for me to face my demons.
- I believe in you.
-Shut up! I'm sorry.
I mean, shut up.
[Hr]
I have an idea.
[ENGINE STARTS]
[CHITTERING]
Oh, Papa.
There's no escaping from us.
[ALL GRUNTING AND GROWLING]
Bring him to me.
[LAUGHS]
[PRAYING MANTIS CHITTERING]
[MONSTERS GRUNTING
AND GROWLING]
[Hr]
STINE:
Did it work?
Not yet.
Come on. Come on, work.
Come on, come on.
Uh-oh.
[LAUGHS]
Yes! High five.
- Oh, boy. Bad idea.
-Sorry.
Yes. It worked.
Oh, be careful, Zach.
[ALL CHEERING]
We're gonna get through this.
Not a good time.
0K8)'-
STINE:
Okay. Go.
It was clear there was
only one place left to hide.
- I can't type while walking.
-Commit it to memory.
There was one place to hide.
It was the, uh, arcade gallery.
- There is no arcade gallery.
-Okay. That was, in fact, the funhouse.
CHAMP: Wait, guys. Why don't we just
sit at one of these tables?
Come on. Guys!
[MONSTERS GRUNTING
AND GROWLING]
Follow the scent.
Lead me to Stine.
[HOWLS]
[TYPEWRITER CLACKING]
[Hr]
STINE: Stine's ingenious plan
worked to perfection.
The funhouse was terrifying. Not so
much for Stine as it was for the others.
But it offered refuge from
the real terrors that lurked outside.
You wish.
He found us. Quickly, follow me.
Papa, you left without saying goodbye.
Trying to hide from me?
That's like hiding from yourself.
I was your best friend,
and you turned your back on me.
Locked me up, imprisoned me
in the pages of a book.
SLAPPYS [IN UNISON]: You stuck me
on a shelf for years and years.
The key was right there.
SLAPPY:
And you never used it.
You're not real, Slappy. I created you.
I can write you out.
I've been saving this monster
just for you.
- Say hello to my gelatinous friend.
-Run!
[SLAPPY LAUGHING]
It's The Blob That Ate Everyone.
Don't let it touch you.
[BLOB GROWLING]
We need to get to higher ground.
The Ferris wheel.
Zach, you go on ahead.
I'll hold it off. You finish the book.
What? What do I write?
- What's the end?
-it's the story I've been writing.
It's what's happening right now.
You can do this. End it.
Wait.
[Hr]
[GROWLS]
HANNAH:
Dad!
[GASPING]
Hannah, he's gonna be okay.
All right? We have to finish the book.
0K8)'-
Not so fun, is it?
ZACH:
Here we go.
0K8)'-
[STINE GRUNTING]
How do you like it, Papa?
The world is just outside your grasp,
but you can't move.
You're trapped.
That's what it felt like
to be locked inside your books.
Wait. The book.
Where is it?
ZACH:
As the monsters converged...
...Zach closed his eyes
and the monsters...
...were swallowed back
into the world of paper and ink.
Can you type any faster?
- This is my first time using a typewriter.
-Keep going.
[MONSTERS GRUNTING
AND GROWLING]
Eureka, eureka, 23-69...
- They're coming. What are we gonna do?
-Finish it, Zach.
One by one, the monsters
disappeared back into the book...
...never to be seen...
...again.
The end.
- Here.
-What happens now?
ZACH:
We're about to find out.
[ALL GRUNTING]
[ALL SCREAMING]
CHAMP:
We're all gonna die!
ZACH:
Just hold on.
Hold on tight.
CHAMP:
Where's the seat belt in this thing?
[ALL GRUNTING AND GROANING]
ZACH:
Let's go.
CHAMP:
Right.
[ALL COUGHING]
I'm okay. I'm okay.
Okay. Hurry up.
All the monsters will be here any second.
All the monsters.
Wait. What are you waiting for?
Come on. Open the book.
[Hr]
Hannah, there's something
that you need to know.
- You're not gonna--
-Open the book.
No. You don't understand.
If we open the book, that means--
It means I'll be stuck
on a shelf someplace forever.
You knew?
How many sweet sixteens
can one girl have?
Zach, it's time to move on.
Now open the book, scaredy-cat.
[MONSTERS GRUNTING
AND GROWLING]
No.
- Okay. Then I'll open it.
-Wait, no. Hannah!
[Hr]
[YELLING]
Wait, Hannah. I've got you.
[GRUNTING]
[GNOMES LAUGHING
AND SHATTERING]
[YELLS]
Oh, oh, oh'. Ha-ha-ha.
[BLOB GROWLING]
Maybe if I hold onto you tight enough--
You have to let go, Zach.
BOTH:
Whoa!
[SLAPPY LAUGHING]
[STINE GRUNTING]
Slappy's not happy.
Neither is Stine!
Stupid dummy!
See you in your dreams.
[SLAPPY LAUGHING]
You'll be okay.
I'll always be in your imagination...
...which is really where I belong.
I'm just sad we never
got to share a dance.
[Hr]
Wait.
Wait, wait.
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[Hr]
Hey-
PAINTER: Yeah.
One more coat, we should be good.
PRINCIPAL:
Let's go, ladies and gentlemen.
Welcome back to class, guys.
- All right. Welcome back.
-Hey. Watch it.
PRINCPAL:
We're back to business. Let's go.
[BOTH CHUCKLING]
Okay. I'll give you
a 60-second head start.
It's okay, Mom.
Let's go in together.
[LOCKS CLICK]
So mature.
GALE:
You love it.
GIRL 1: After fourth period.
GIRL 2: Oh, okay. That would be great.
You okay? You breathing?
You're gonna be great.
Okay? You look great. You smell great.
My God, what is that?
I rub myself in cilantro every morning.
- Of course you do, my sexy little salsa.
-Ha-ha-ha.
- Go on.
-Okay. I'm off to work.
Oh, what did I have for you?
- There it is.
-Ah!
Oh. Oh. Went too far. Got it.
[CHATTERING]
[Hr]
Hello. Ahem.
My name is Mr. R. L. Stine,
and I will be your new English teacher...
...because Mr. Boyd
is still recuperating from injuries...
...sustained in a mutant-insect attack.
Now...
...every story ever told...
...can be broken down
into three distinct parts.
The beginning...
...the middle...
...and the twist.
[SCHOOL BELL RINGS]
- Hello, Mr. Stine.
-Hello, Mr. Black.
- Uh, who was that?
-He's the new drama teacher.
- Can I ask you something?
-Of course.
Do you miss her?
Not a day goes by
that I don't think of her.
But she'll always be in here...
...and in there.
And right here...
...and in here.
And also right over there.
[Hr]
Ha, ha. I may have written
one more book.
Hannah.
You're-- You're real.
- You came back.
-I had to. You owe me a dance.
[STINE GRUNTS AND SHOUTS]
Come on, let's go.
[TYPEWRITER KEY CLACKS]
[Hr]
INVISIBLE BOY:
You forgot about me. Ha-ha-ha.
[SCREAMS]
[Hr]
[CHITTERING]
[HOWLS]
[LAUGHING]
[SQUAWKING]
[Hr]
[GNOME LAUGHING]
[GNOME LAUGHS]