♪ Your altitude
♪ Is only viewed
♪ As an indication
of your attitude
♪ For you're only as small
♪ As your dreams
♪ You may be small
Not big and tall
♪ But a giant's what you
'twill be called
♪ For you're only
as small as your dreams
♪ I know that I... ♪
Sorry!
Yeah, sorry about that.
That's not the story
we're telling.
No. We're here
for Peter Rabbit.
The hero of our tale.
A young rabbit in a blue coat
and no pants.
Hey! Pick on someone
your own size.
My pleasure.
I didn't mean me.
Going into his
garden again, I see.
There are safer ways
to get a meal, you know!
Yeah, but they're not as fun.
Oi.
What did I tell you about
sneakin' into McGregor's?
Make sure to
get you some cauliflower?
That's a good boy.
Now, off you get.
All right,
talk to me, Benjamin.
He's mowed half the lawn,
which maybe gives us
just enough time.
Look at him.
Pure evil.
Even cuts grass angry.
Hey, here's a crazy thought.
What if we don't go in,
because last time,
you almost got caught.
You're so adorable.
I could just eat you up.
That's exactly what
he wants to do to you.
Higher. Higher.
Why are you always on top?
Because I'm the oldest.
We're triplets!
I'm still the oldest.
By 16 seconds.
When's the last time
you brushed your tail?
Whoa!
All right, rest time's over.
Come on.
- Yeah.
- Race you.
Not if I race you first.
No fair.
Take it all in
because we're about
to take it all in.
Sorry. I don't know
why I'm so out of shape.
I only eat salad.
It's the dressing.
Get it on the side.
Or just have
a drizzle of lemon.
It'll change your life,
trust me.
Right. You all know the drill.
I'm not gonna pretend
that what we're about to do
isn't reckless, foolhardy,
even dangerous.
But we will succeed,
because each of us
plays a vital role
specifically tailored
to our individual talents.
Lookout. Lookout.
Hero.
Now let's do this.
Right behind ya.
- Not a chance.
- Why?
Are you afraid I'm gonna get
my foot caught in a trap
and I'll have to gnaw it off, and
then you'll call me "Stumpy"
for the rest of my life, and
I'll have a horrifying scar,
but all the real scars
will be on the inside?
Sorry you had to hear that.
It's okay. We're family.
This is a safe space.
All right, bring it in.
- We all ready?
- Yep.
- Absolutely.
- Always.
- I guess.
- Love you guys.
Now, let's do this.
It's gonna be a fun one.
Lettuce, radishes, radicchio.
I'll tell you
what's "radicchio."
How easy it is to steal
this man's vegetables.
Because "radicchio"
sounds like "ridiculous."
Don't explain the joke.
- Flopsy!
- Yeah!
Mopsy!
Cotton-Tail!
I'm good!
Tomayto, tomahto.
Potayto, potahto.
No one actually says "potahto,"
have you noticed that?
Stop messing around.
I can mess around all I want.
He can't hear us
over the lawn...
Mower.
Rabbits.
No, no, stop.
- Leave.
- Scram.
Get out of there.
Peter, no.
- I'm gonna put this in there.
- Don't do that.
- You think this is a bad idea?
- Yes, it's a bad idea.
I'm getting mixed signals.
Yes or no?
It's a definite no.
I can't see your
mouth through the gate.
No. No. No. No.
- I think you said yes.
- No.
- I'm going with "yes."
- No, no, Peter.
- What?
- God.
No.
Peter. No!
- Get out of there.
- Ooh.
Rabbit, I'm gonna
put you in a pie.
Leave the jacket.
Like I did your dad.
Morning, Mr. McGregor.
It's you.
Beautiful day, isn't it?
Give me that rabbit.
You got a little
something in your...
You're okay.
Are you okay?
Did he just wink?
I didn't even know
we could do that.
You look very well.
That vein that's usually bulging out
of your head's really calmed down.
Have you been meditating?
This is my garden.
Let me pass that along.
This is his garden.
There we are.
I think we're
all on the same page.
So these rabbits
will now surrender
their natural instinct
to feed themselves.
Next time will be their last.
I'll be sure to
pass that along, too.
Come on, sweeties.
Come on.
This is Bea.
She's next-door neighbor to Mr.
McGregor and the rabbits.
Guess which one
she likes better?
Inside. Come on. I'll get
you something to drink.
You must stop going in there.
You almost
got caught this time.
Come here, little one.
Dry you off.
She's an artist.
She moved out to the country
to work on her paintings.
Don't feel bad if you don't
understand them, like them,
even know which way to
look at them.
They are terrible
and she knows it.
So for fun, she's been painting
portraits of the locals.
Beautiful.
But a constant reminder
of what Peter and his family
had gone through.
I promise I'll always
be here for you.
And she has,
ever since their mother died.
The rain stopped.
Sorry about Dad's jacket.
I'm sorry you
lost Dad's jacket.
I just said that.
Yeah, but coming
from the oldest,
it just kind of means more.
Just a jacket.
Dad and Mum are still in here.
And here. And here.
But less so with you,
since you're just a cousin,
you know. You're a nephew,
and by marriage.
I'm not taking
anything away, I'm just...
You know,
I want to be accurate.
Okay, just promise me
you'll stay out of the garden.
Got it back, Dad.
Got you, rabbit.
I knew you'd come.
The lady's not here
to protect you now.
I've got a hankering
for pie tonight.
Rabbit pie.
What?
Whoa.
Is he...
That's pretty conclusive.
Very conclusive.
That means that... That I...
That I...
That I did it. I did it.
- What?
- I did it.
Got rid of him. Who's hungry?
Bite into those guys.
You went into his garden?
No. I went into our garden.
Without lookouts?
That's the sort of thing
that will get someone killed.
And it did.
McGregor's gone?
He's in a better place now.
- Really?
- Yeah.
That ice cream truck
with the flashing lights.
In actuality,
Peter couldn't even claim
that he gave the old man's
heart a fright.
Credit for that
goes to 78 years
of terrible lifestyle choices.
- Wow.
- No way.
All right, this is our land now, so
let's not go crazy straightaway.
It's our job to nurture it,
to sustain it,
prepare for the future.
With privilege, comes
responsibility...
I'm sorry. I almost got through
that with a straight face.
Knock yourself out.
♪ I was lying on the grass
♪ Of Sunday morning of
last week
♪ Indulging in my self defeat
♪ I know it's up for me
♪ If you steal my sunshine
♪ Making sure
I'm not in too deep
♪ If you steal my sunshine
♪ Keeping versed
and on my feet
♪ If you steal my sunshine
Wait for me!
I wasn't designed for running!
♪ If you steal my sunshine
♪ Let's all bow down to Peter
♪ 'Cause he gave us sunshine
♪ Made the garden one
big bird feeder
♪ 'Cause he gave us sunshine
♪ Now our life
is so much sweeter
♪ Thanks to Mr... ♪
Sorry about that.
Help yourself to anything.
Try the tomatoes.
Whoa. Look at you,
big fella.
Wait, didn't you...
Did you try to eat me?
It was you! I knew it.
How are you? So good to see you.
Hey, little rabbit.
Got your land back, I see.
All hail the prodigal son.
- It's no big deal.
- No, no, a very big deal.
You vanquished McGregor.
Well, if vanquished
means I said to him,
"I've had enough
of your tyranny."
And he said,
"I will put you in a pie."
And I said, "No, sir.
I will put you in a pie, sir."
It doesn't, but thank you for
the party.
Was Pigling eating celery?
It's a shame when you
don't know who you are
or where you belong, you know?
Want some?
I'll just take one.
Thanks, Tommy.
You're one of the good ones.
Hey! This garden comes
with a free house!
♪ Can I get a witness
in the darkness?
♪ 'Cause there ain't no love
at all to be found
♪ Sugar, just step into
your sneakers
♪ And step behind the speakers
♪ Your heart will keep
me beating
♪ I said, roll up, roll up,
roll up
♪ Yeah, come get your love
♪ I don't care, I don't care
♪ Why you're dancing tonight
♪ Just as long as you're there
in the break of the light
♪ So, roll up ♪
Yeah, that's right!
- Mr. McGregor will torment us no more!
- Whoa!
- No more!
Meet Thomas McGregor.
Or, as he is known
in the store where he works,
Mr. McGregor.
You're seeing him
at his happiest.
Preparing his troops
for battle.
People who say
you can't control everything
haven't met this Mr. McGregor.
72.043 degrees.
The angle at which Apollo 13
was launched.
I know, Carlos,
you think I'm crazy.
But the little girl
who wants to be an astronaut
is going to know, and you've
just blown up her dreams.
This is a nightmare.
You've got to toss and fluff,
toss and fluff.
It's the small things.
You mustn't be afraid
to really get in there, gang.
Our toilets should be clean
as a drinking fountain.
Mr. McGregor.
The general manager
has asked to see you.
This is it. My promotion.
They said
it could be this week.
How do I look?
Like a man about to drink
toilet water from a straw?
Perfect.
I have some bad news, Thomas.
- No.
- Your great-uncle passed away.
I just received word.
I'm very sorry.
I didn't even know
I had a great-uncle.
What about the promotion?
- Excuse me?
- The associate general manager.
The post I've been working
towards for the last 10 years.
You're in shock, I understand.
In times of grief...
No, there's no grief.
I just want to know.
Did I get
the promotion or not?
- No. It went to Bannerman.
- Bannerman?
But he is an imbecile.
I mean, he's not even that.
To be rightfully
called an imbecile,
would be aspirational
for Nigel Bannerman.
But he also happens to be the
managing director's nephew.
So you're promoting a
flagrantly unqualified half-wit
to a position of immense importance
based purely on nepotism.
This is Great Britain.
It's practically
written in our charter.
You think I want
our best man passed over?
Well, then,
don't pass me over.
This is not the time to be
thinking about work, Thomas.
Take some time.
Take as much time as you like.
No, I don't want time!
I'm sorry.
I don't want... I'm sorry.
I want the promotion,
is the thing,
and I deserve the promotion.
Give me the promotion, June,
I won't tell anyone.
Please.
Give me the promotion.
Sorry.
- I'm sorry, sir.
- It's all right.
- Sorry, sir.
- Maybe next time.
What up, McG...
Bannerman.
Congratulations.
I didn't even want it.
I was in Ibiza last night.
Heavy lies the crown, yeah?
Pow.
I'm taking a break.
I'll be in my big office.
♪ I'm a rebel just for
kicks, now
♪ I been feeling it
since 1966, now
♪ Might be over now,
but I feel it still ♪
Come here!
I gave my life to you!
I gave you everything!
Why did you treat me...
I'm sorry.
This might actually be
a blessing in disguise.
Get some perspective.
Get a hobby.
Get some dirt underneath
your fingernails.
You sound like every employer,
teacher, family member,
friend, and vague acquaintance
I've ever had.
I'm going to take
your name tag now, Thomas.
No, not...
Welcome to Harrods.
I hope you enjoy drinking
dirty toilet water.
Might I suggest some time
in the country?
It's calming.
Serene!
Hee-haw!
Yeah!
One hundred and eighty!
Joust! Joust!
Ooh.
Yeah!
Streaker!
Yeah, now it's a party.
- Hors d'oeuvres?
- I'll just take one.
No, it's hitch kick,
then boogaloo.
When am I going to
get to choreograph?
When you're the oldest.
Aw, I can't wait that long.
Hey, let's go
get Mum and Dad.
Where do you want it, Peter?
Anywhere's fine.
I mean, maybe a...
Maybe a little higher?
A lit... No, too much.
A little lower.
To the left.
No, to the right.
More. Too far. Lower.
To the right. Up.
Lower. Down.
Right. Right.
Lower. Lower. Lower.
Up. Middle. Left.
Right. Lower. Up.
Your right. My left.
Your down. My up.
Left. Right.
Perfect.
He's gone now, guys.
I just wish
you were here to enjoy it.
I'm never letting anyone
take it from us again.
Thomas McGregor?
Sign here, please.
From Windermere?
Fancy place, that.
I don't know anyone from
Windermere.
Well, it's from
Unclaimed Property.
Usually means
you've inherited something.
Inherited
something, he did.
From that great-uncle
he knew nothing about.
Turns out intimacy issues
run in the family.
Windermere?
That's in the country.
Well, fancy country.
The houses there
go for a king's ransom.
Ransom enough to
buy my own toy shop?
I'd imagine so.
And fill it with the finest
merchandise?
Should do, yeah.
Ransom enough to have
tempered glass shelving
and seasonal
window decorations?
That I might have to do
some research on, sir.
Can I get back to you
mail-time tomorrow?
Round trip to Windermere,
please.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
♪ I don't give a damn
what the people say
♪ I'm gonna do it my way,
gonna do it my way
♪ Boom, boom, boom, boom,
and bang, bang, bang
♪ I'm gonna let it all out,
do my thing
♪ Boom, boom, boom,
and a bang, bang, bang ♪
Good evening. Are you
aware of this location?
- The McGregor manor?
- Yes.
- Is that where you're staying?
- It's just temporary.
I am merely appraising
the manor's condition
before putting it
on the market to sell.
But you do want me
to take you there?
Yes.
- Well, hop in.
- Thank you.
I think you're really going
to love living there.
Please don't talk to me
on the drive.
- Give it to me.
- Here.
I can fly!!
I think I cracked a rib.
How many ribs do we have?
- Thirteen.
- No way.
Sweet.
No, but don't...
I can fly...
It's nothing against the country.
I just find it disgusting.
Yes, you've made that
quite clear on the journey, sir.
I would just like
the record to reflect that.
Well, I shall create a record
and make sure that it reflects it.
A human.
Dear. Everybody out! Out!
Get out! Humans are coming!
Human! Human!
You know, it's like, who am I?
Who are you? Yeah?
You know, like,
we're all connected,
but with what rope?
A human! Humans are coming!
- What should we do?
- What?
Everybody hide!
Your quills
are stabbing me.
I wasn't designed for hiding.
Who lives like this?
Hit the lights!
No. Tommy!
Tommy, hide!
No, just because
you can't see him,
doesn't mean he can't
see you. Understand?
Now hide!
What? No, Tommy.
Now you're just
posing as a candelabra.
Now you're just a tablecloth.
Now you're just a...
What are you?
I'm a lazy Susan.
What?
Tommy! Tommy!
Get... Get out!
Get...
Get out!
Every single one of you!
Out, you vermin!
Stay out of my house!
He had the key.
He must be a McGregor.
Headlights.
Felix, blink.
Blink, blink, blink, blink.
Come on, big guy.
Blink, blink, blink.
Headlights.
Come on, deer.
The sun came up again?
I can't believe it!
I thought when I closed
my eyes last night,
that that was it!
But we have another day of this!
Whoo-hoo!
It wasn't a nightmare.
It's a nightmare.
What is that music?
I don't know.
But it sounds very dramatic
and life-changing.
Hello, sweeties.
You checking
on the new neighbor?
Don't worry.
He can't be any worse
than the old crab bucket,
rest his soul.
Never know, maybe he'll be
a nice, normal man.
He looks nice.
Looks very normal.
That's not very normal, is it?
That's normal.
Anyway,
it's gonna be exciting.
We'll have somebody
new around here.
They're not all bad,
I promise.
I'll explain it to him.
We all share
our land around here.
I'm gonna give him the benefit
of the doubt.
No.
It's not over. We can
always go in the back...
Or through the...
Or use the...
Or behind the...
I didn't even know
that was a way in.
I see the gates
are back up?
I guess you weren't
the prodigal son after all.
That'll do, pig. That'll do.
It was a fun night, though.
I haven't eaten that much
in a long time.
The diet starts now.
Now.
- Now.
- Hey, look.
Now.
Hello. Sorry.
I didn't mean to startle you. I'm Bea.
I just live over here.
Hello. I'm Thomas.
I live way over there
in London.
That way.
Yes. I'm just
here temporarily.
I'm fixing up
this place to sell,
using the proceeds
to open my own toy store,
preferably near Harrods
so they can witness
their own downfall.
My. That's a lot
of information right there.
- Sorry.
- Good for you
for not being
afraid to open up.
- What are they saying?
- Shh, I can read lips.
I'm just a little
out of my element.
I think you'll find the elements
here are pretty fabulous.
"I think you'll find
the elephants around here
"are really flatulent."
What?
In my opinion, it's just the
most beautiful place on Earth.
Well, it just got
a lot more beautiful.
Gee.
You didn't just say that.
And clean, sturdy, functional.
The gate.
- Yes.
- I thought you were saying
- I was beautiful.
- Did you...
No, no, no. No,
I wouldn't say that.
- I would say that. I'm not...
- No, hey, I'm not fishing.
- It's fine.
- You are beautiful.
And you're different
to the gate.
I can't read lips,
but I know her,
and she's telling him
to take down those gates,
and let us into the garden.
Well, enjoy your brief stay.
Just, please, don't be
like the nasty old man
who used to live here.
He was a real twit.
- He was my uncle.
- You didn't let me finish.
He was a real...
Sorry, I can't...
No. There's no saving that one.
He was a real twit.
- No offense.
- None taken.
- I never knew him.
- You seem much more reasonable.
Do I?
Although, I must say, these
gates are incredibly sturdy.
Are you expecting
an alien invasion?
I just need to keep the
wildlife out where they belong.
Well, they actually belong
everywhere.
It was kind of their place
first. We're the latecomers.
How long does it take to say,
"Leave the gate open,
and let in the rabbits"?
Leave the gate
open, and let in the rabbits.
I certainly will, madam.
And might I say, those rabbits
are incredibly cute.
Especially the one
with the blue coat. He's my favorite.
And, here's a present.
Wait. Why is she
bringing him a present?
How nice of you.
It's for bird-watching.
Thank you.
There's one. It has wings.
Yes, that's a pretty
defining feature
of the bird,
I think you'll find.
You spotted your first bird.
Make sure to mark it down later.
Mark it down?
So there's a way of organizing and
documenting the chaos of the sky?
Yes.
Well, it was nice
to meet you, Thomas.
Yes, you, too.
And let's keep this
gate open, shall we,
so the wildlife can run free?
- Absolutely.
- She did it.
We're in. Come on.
Maybe it's not so bad here,
after all.
- No.
- I don't care.
- I'm going in.
- Right behind you.
No. Not a chance.
You remember what happened
to Dad, right?
But you go in all the time.
That's my character flaw.
You get your
own character flaw.
- Come on, Benjamin.
- Why does he get to go?
Yeah, why do I have to go in?
Because that's
his character flaw.
He goes along with everything I say, no
matter how stupid and reckless it is.
No, I don't!
You're not the boss of me!
- Benjamin.
- Coming!
I can't let him go in by himself.
He's being stupid and reckless.
I hope they're
going to be okay.
They'll be fine, and if not,
I guess I'll just be
the new head of the family.
Peter, please be okay!
I'm still
so out of shape.
How's it working with the
putting the dressing on the side?
Good. But I don't understand why it's
healthier to drink it all at once.
Disgusting.
Come on.
What'd I tell ya?
Easy peasy lemon squeezy.
- Rats.
- Run!
Hello.
This guy is so much faster
than the old one.
I think
we have a problem.
- What is it?
- Everything's upside down.
Where are you?
We never should
have come in the garden.
No guts, no glory.
Are you ever
scared of anything?
Yeah. Dying alone.
That's why I brought you here.
Do you know what we do
with rats in the city?
We find them,
and we exterminate them.
Ha!
Benjamin.
- Follow me.
- I can't see anything.
- Follow my voice.
- I can't hear anything!
Follow your heart?
What?
That way, that way, that way.
Play dead.
This is what happens
when you make
a McGregor look foolish
playing carnival games
in the shed.
You see this, everyone?
This is what happens!
Why am I talking to wildlife?
I am losing my mind.
I do... They're not
going to respond.
Come on, come on!
Jump!
Okay, okay.
Flopsy, take the bag,
go to the window
and you put it over his head.
Okay.
Mopsy, you take the bag,
go over to the window,
put it over his head.
Got it.
Cotton-Tail, take the bag...
- Just give him a wet willy.
- Got it.
No!
You okay, big guy?
Close one?
I could've been killed.
And not just me.
What if he got the girls?
This isn't a joke, Peter.
I know.
I'm sorry.
You're all right though,
right?
I got your jacket back.
It's not as symbolic as mine.
You know, not being
your dad's and all.
And it's brown, too, which is a
mistake because you're brown.
I mean, brown on brown,
who wears that?
It's a bit matchy-matchy.
Yeah, it's actually
a bit confusing.
Half the time
we think you're naked.
I just look for the buttons.
But then one time,
it was your nipples.
Anyway, you got it back,
and you're okay.
No thanks to him. Look at him.
Skinny bag of wet.
Now, turn around
and drive us home, Eugene.
Here's good.
New to the area.
Probably take the next turn.
Just using more fuel.
Not a surprise
that he's not
environmentally friendly.
Hey, we don't
inherit the Earth,
we borrow it
from our children.
I read that on a plastic cup.
If you do a U-turn...
It's actually a safe place
for a U-turn here.
I think that's the...
- Where...
- Where is he taking us?
He's taking us into town.
- So this is London.
- Wow.
Big Ben! Wow!
It's gigantic.
I hope you appreciate this,
Flopsy.
I never got to travel
when I was your age.
What? You were my age,
like, three streets ago.
It goes so fast.
Whoa.
This must be Harrods.
Wow. Classy.
What can I do for you?
I have a vermin problem.
Rabbits, I'm guessing.
- How do you know that?
- You're the new McGregor.
- Bea's neighbor.
- How do you know that?
- She mentioned you.
- She did?
What did she say?
That you want to sell
your house in a hurry
and use the profits
to open your own toy store,
preferably near Harrods,
so they can witness
their own downfall.
That's incredibly specifically
accurate, and a little disappointing.
Who do you think
these guys are?
They're wearing aprons,
so that could mean
only one thing.
- They're hedgehogs.
Just make sure she doesn't find out
you're launching them rabbits.
She loves 'em. Like family.
Read their lips, Mopsy.
If I was a learned fellow,
I'd say she
anthropomorphizes 'em
in lieu of any genuine
human interaction.
But he's not a learned fellow.
Which is why I think she's just
got a thing for those rabbits.
"Which is why I think she's just
got a thing for most man butts."
What would you suggest?
An electric fence
will keep 'em out.
To launch 'em,
you'll need some firepower.
Firepower seems like...
I don't want to...
Get down.
That's them! I knew it.
Where are you?
I know you're in there.
Come out! I saw you!
Launch them.
I want to launch them.
Right. Follow me.
It's okay. I've got
11 more ribs.
You actually have
13 on each side.
What?
Which is technically 26
because they go...
Now you're down to 19.
Again, you push this button.
The signal will travel
through the air to this.
This'll start the spark,
and anything
near it will explode.
I do understand the fundamental
concepts of basic things.
It's tricky. A little bit.
Thank you.
Thank you!
Drive safe!
Just match its speed.
Our natural rabbits' pace
should be able to keep up.
Do you know what?
That would never have worked.
Watch it, boxhead!
Leave him alone, babe.
He's just a country bumpkin.
Morons.
"Country bumpkin"?
I'm not a country bumpkin.
I'm from London,
which is where I'd like to...
- Thomas?
- Bea.
- Hello.
- How are you?
- I'm very well. You...
What are you doing here?
Just...
Just picking up some, um,
hardware.
- It's lovely to see you.
- What?
- Can I offer you a lift?
- Why is she here?
No.
He's stealing her bike.
That's all right. It's more
difficult than I thought it was.
No. He's stealing her.
No.
She's going willingly and seems
to be enjoying his company.
Come on, come on.
Come on.
That's a lot of smiling.
More than before, even.
She is showing more teeth.
Must mean she likes him.
Aw.
Not "aw."
She doesn't like him.
She's just really nice.
She smiles at us all the time.
Not like that.
Come in.
Would you like
something to drink?
Yes, please.
Are these your paintings?
That's just
a work in progress.
No, no, this is,
this is beautiful.
Thank you.
What a majestic
mountain range.
It's an old woman in a hat.
Right. Yeah. There's...
There's the hat.
- That's her eyes.
- Yes.
- And that's her chin.
- It's her foot.
That's her foot.
I'm allergic to
blackberries.
I'm sorry. My throat closes up.
Allergic to blackberries?
Is that even a thing?
Is that where we've got to?
I mean, everyone's suddenly
allergic to everything.
Stop using it as a crutch!
You know, some people do have
legitimate medical conditions.
Of course, of course.
It's a real struggle
and my heart goes out to them.
It's very tough, very sad. I
don't want to get any letters.
But this guy, come on!
What about these?
That's just something
I do for fun,
when I'm not focusing
on my real work.
These are beautiful.
You don't have to say that.
I mean, they must be good
if I like them,
given how much I hate rabbits.
I mean, somehow, you managed to make
them look not like the vermin they are.
Vermin? Vermin?
- What does "vermin" mean?
- Like a rodent.
Rodent? Rodent?
What does "rodent" mean?
Like a rat or a mouse.
You think rabbits are vermin?
You're joking, right?
Yes. I'm joking.
'Cause I'm hilarious and
whimsical.
Rabbits are actually
perfect creatures.
They're generous,
honest, pure.
You should see the way
they talk to each other.
They do this incredible thing
when they're apologizing.
Rabbits apologize?
They put their heads
together, like this.
No. No, no, no,
don't apologize to him.
Why is she apologizing to him?
Wow,
that's taking a long time.
She's apologizing
the heck out of that guy.
And this was
only the beginning.
It didn't get any easier for
Peter and the others to stomach.
Or understand.
Anyway.
You'll see.
You'll grow to love them.
But romance
is a powerful thing.
It can sneak up
on any two people.
Even if one is amazing,
and the other is a McGregor.
♪ Girl, I say
♪ If only life would
lean our way
♪ Well, you and me
we'd run away
♪ To be wherever
our adventure awaits
♪ I heard your heart say
love, love, love
And after my parents
died, I was put in a group home.
Peel.
That must have been awfully
traumatic for you.
Did you deal
with it okay? Peel.
Didn't affect me in the
slightest. Peel.
Yes, I can see that.
Maybe I have some tendencies.
Yeah, to commit rabbit-cide.
- Is that a word?
- No.
Well, I think we all have
our tendencies. Peel.
What are yours?
I guess I don't like people
who aren't who
they say they are.
It's more about me.
I keep saying
I'm a real painter,
yet I can't seem
to finish anything real.
But she paints us.
We're real.
Aren't we real?
Yep, definitely real.
What do you miss
most about the store?
And don't say, "Having
everything in its proper place."
I get it.
You have control issues.
I miss being helpful.
A parent or grandparent
comes into the shop
looking for a gift
for the child they love.
I ask a few simple questions, and
know exactly what they need.
I love helping people
get what they want.
You know?
Especially when they don't
even know that they want it.
Those are the best.
Also, neatly arranged displays.
I'm sorry, I can't help it.
Yes! Bananas! I win!
Wait, "taradiddle"
isn't a word.
Yes, it is. It means "fib,"
"pretentious nonsense."
That is exactly the sort of definition
you'd make up for a made-up word.
Mr. McGregor, are you accusing
me of taradiddling?
♪ I heard your heart say
love, love, love
No. Damn it.
Come here, come here.
I'll protect you.
♪ Love, love, love
♪ Love, love, love ♪
Come in. Come in, quick.
- Closed.
- Pull up a chair.
We're wearing fur.
- Thank you.
- You're drenched. Sit down.
Let me help you dry off.
Thank you very much.
I could stay here forever.
Hiya.
Hello.
Haven't seen you
in the longest time.
Meet my new friend, Thomas.
- Would you like to have a hold?
- Among other things.
Look.
My two boys
getting along perfectly.
Nothing could make me happier.
Do you mind if I paint this?
Nothing would make me happier.
You're mine now, rabbit.
Thomas, are your eyes emerald
or sea-foam green?
Sea-foam green with a hint
of battleship gray.
I thought so.
Thomas?
And that's what separates us
from the French.
Yup. Kiwi green.
You're the professional.
Yay.
Ooh.
Yay. Ooh.
Yay.
No, no, no, it's an old woman
in a hat, you see?
I just assumed she would've
reentered at that exact moment.
You need to stop.
It's not going to end well.
I think I found it.
The perfect ma...
My painting!
It's ruined.
You know how uncontrollable
wildlife can be. I just...
- Bad rabbit. Bad rabbit!
- Yes, bad rabbit.
- Naughty.
- Bad rabbit!
- Out, get out.
- Out.
I said, shoo. Shoo!
Get out of here!
I'm so sorry.
He just went mad.
Are you all right?
He's gotta go.
No way!
The sun came up again!
If I knew this was
gonna keep happening,
certainly wouldn't have
fertilized all those eggs!
Now I have to stick around
till they hatch!
And be present and involved!
And so,
Peter prepared his troops
for full-on battle.
Why you kids walking so slow?
And that is how you
sneak up on someone.
♪ Come on, they're ten percent
pluck twenty percent blur
♪ Fifteen percent concentrated
power of fur
♪ Five percent muscle
fifty percent brains
♪ A hundred percent reason
To remember the names
♪ No, they don't need
their name known forever
♪ They just want to be rid
of young Mr. McGregor
♪ They're feelin' the pressure
♪ Tired of runnin' around
feelin' frightened
♪ Despite the fact
that Bea somehow thinks
♪ That she likes him
but they know the code
♪ It's not about the salary
♪ It's all about the celery
and maybe some radishes
♪ Maybe some cabbages,
gotta let the animals know
♪ That means when they get
ready, gotta go, go, go ♪
You can do this, Flops.
Take a deep breath,
pull it back,
and picture the one face you'd
most like to see get hit.
Ooh. Got someone.
Sorry!
Stop it.
♪ Me and my cousins,
and you and your cousins
♪ It's a line that's
always running
♪ Me and my cousins,
and you and your cousins
♪ I can feel it coming ♪
He's got to go.
His face was so
classic. He was like...
All of the rakes. I mean,
I didn't even think
it would work that well.
It was right on the edge
of believability.
You guys.
How did you even get that
wheelbarrow up there?
It was a perfectly crafted
sequence.
Now listen.
We've got him
just where we want him.
It's on to the next phase.
That might not be possible.
That's a serious
electric fence.
Why is he feeding it
peanut butter?
Yummy.
He's trying to bait us
into touching it.
What happens if we touch it?
We're about to find out.
No, Mrs. Tiggy-Winkle!
Stop! No.
I'm four and a half years old.
I need some excitement
before I check out.
- Don't do it!
- No, Tiggy-Winkle, stop!
Mrs. Tiggy-Winkle,
it's not worth it!
Look away.
Guys, I have an idea.
You remember what
Dad used to say to us?
"Never go into
McGregor's garden."
Yeah, but what else
did he say to us?
Don't electrify
a lady hedgehog.
Maybe we should rethink some of
the other stuff Dad said to us.
Yeah, like, "You can't
put lipstick on a pig."
- No, no, no, no.
- This is lip balm.
It's cherry flavor, so it
might appear to be lipstick,
but this is lip balm.
Yes, yes, yes.
Okay, he also used to say,
"You can't out-clever a fox,
"so use his cleverness against him."
Come on, Mrs. Tiggy-Winkle!
That's enough!
Two-winged
flying
bird.
And here we go.
And zap.
And zap?
Zap. Zap.
♪ I've been up, I've been
down, I've always got
Zap, zap, zap, zap,
zap, zap, zap!
♪ Hoping that I could find
♪ One of them
that's silver-lined
What is happening?
♪ All it wants on my parade
♪ Because
♪ Because when life
gives me lemons I make
♪ Lemonade, lemons
I make lemonade
♪ I wake up every morning
feeling sad
♪ And I sleep
with the light on ♪
Wow, another McGregor down.
Looks like
you did it again, Peter.
Let me just check.
Yeah, I felt brain.
Now, if history is any
indication,
that ice cream truck with the
lights'll take him away.
Sorry.
Explosives.
Hide. Quick.
Follow me.
You push this, signal goes
through the air, towards this,
and everything in there goes...
Good-bye, rabbits.
Rabbits?
Hello? Rabbits?
- Rabbits?
- Thomas?
Yeah?
What are you doing
out in the garden so late?
I'm picking wildflowers.
It's for you.
He's come back to life.
With a light on his head.
He's evolving.
What were you doing
out in the garden?
Doing?
Yeah. By the tree.
"Doing" can mean
so many things, can't it?
- I mean, I was, I was...
- Would you mind?
- It's just awfully bright.
- I was do... Is it?
Is it distracting you from what
you were asking me just then?
Is it better down?
Up. Up. It's quite bright.
And so we advance to endgame.
You sure you know
what you're doing?
What? We're tryin' to get
our garden back.
Is that really
what this is all about?
Of course,
that's what it's about.
You think I've got some
kind of ulterior motive,
that I'm harboring some kind of
emotional connection to her,
because of losing
my own mother and father
and I think if she goes,
what have I got?
It's only about the garden,
and I don't know what's
happened to my voice. It...
It shouldn't be this high.
It should be lower.
I love her like a mother.
Yes, that was very convincing.
It's only about the garden.
Yes, it is.
I'm stuck. My voice is stuck.
- Cotton-Tail, can you just...
- Yeah.
Thank you. Let's do this.
- Nice to see you.
- Thank you.
I'm not sure I want to be
part of this anymore.
Of course, you do.
Just do what I say.
It will all work out.
"Like always?"
Said the rabbit who almost
got thrown into a river.
Trust me.
I got this.
Cotton-Tail, go.
Hello?
Ready. Aim. Hold it.
Hold it.
- Thomas.
- Fire!
- Morning.
- You fancy a spot of lunch later?
Yes. That...
Lunch would be lovely.
I was thinking of
making a salad.
Yeah.
Or maybe a soup.
What would you prefer?
Let me think. Soup. Soup.
Would you like water,
or sparkling water, or...
Would you just
pick one, please?
Look at you, you're doing
your relaxation pose.
- Arms up.
- Yeah. What?
- Really? Up?
- Yep, up they go.
- You know where to aim.
All right.
- You look really relaxed.
- So relaxed.
Just going to
do some painting.
Blackberries. Blackberries!
No, but he's allergic to...
Clever.
Shoot for the mouth.
I might put some music on.
I hope it's not too loud.
Get in there and create!
I'm out.
- Flopsy.
- Visualize the face.
Look at my face.
Turn his face into my face.
Now stop looking at my face
and look at his face,
but see my face, and fire!
- Yes!
- Flopsy!
Blackberries.
Ooh.
That should do it.
What?
This guy's like
some kind of sorcerer.
That's it.
This is starting to
get out of control.
No, no, this is perfect.
Remember your training.
Wait, did we train for this?
Whoa!
How is this perfect?
She should've heard us by now.
♪ This is my fight song
♪ Take back my life song
♪ Prove I'm all right song
I'm hit.
- I'm hit.
- Mopsy!
No!
Flopsy, I need you
to know something.
I'm not the oldest.
- What?
- You were always so cute and lovable.
And Cotton-Tail,
well, she's...
Cotton-Tail,
so Mum and Dad told us
I was the oldest,
so I had something.
But, really,
you're the oldest,
and I'm nothing.
No! Mopsy, don't go.
Mopsy?
It was just a tomato.
I'm fine.
Guys, I'm fine!
It's just a tomato!
Hey, you never heard
any of that stuff, got me?
Dink.
♪ Fight left in me ♪
Gotcha! You listen to me.
I am not a bad guy.
You turned me into this.
I am a nice person.
I've chilled out, man.
I'm cool now.
I've evolved, but you,
you're still the same.
Still full of mischief.
And that's why things are not
going to end well for you.
Because you poked at me
and you poked at me,
until all that's left
for me to do is wring your...
What's going on here?
You've got to chew your food!
I saved him.
What happened? Is he okay?
Yeah, I... He...
The poor little guy,
he was choking on some radish.
So I just...
I've checked his pulse,
and everything's
gonna be okay.
You're going to be okay!
So off you go. Off you go.
There we are.
It's a miracle.
Yeah.
I thought I heard
some loud noises.
It was a bit of a ruckus.
I was painting, so I can't
be sure, but did you...
No, I don't think so...
I was weeding.
I do make grunting noises when
I weed sometimes.
It's just people have used explosives
before to keep the rabbits out.
Explosives?
But you wouldn't do that.
I wouldn't do
something like that.
- No, of course not.
- They're angels.
This is their place
as much as ours.
- Yeah, exactly.
- Learned that from you.
I just thought I heard
something.
Is that a two-winged
flying bird up there?
- I must mark it down.
- Where?
- Up there.
- She believes him.
We'll never
get rid of him now.
I don't think so.
Up there. Just in
that... In the faraway tree.
You are using explosives.
You lied to me.
Well, yes, but...
My house.
My paintings.
Their burrow.
This is going to be difficult
for you to hear,
but he did it.
He detonated it.
He's a rabbit.
I know.
But somehow,
he found the detonator,
and he took his paw...
And he did all that
to come between us.
He's a rabbit!
All right. Okay.
Let's be reasonable.
For a start, you know
they rob from the garden.
Did you know
they set traps in my bed?
So when I woke up,
I hurt my little fingers!
And then they used
electricity against me,
which we invented,
but they modified for
their own nefarious purposes!
And they saw the Bananagrams,
they saw the bicycle ride,
they saw the walk in the park.
And where did they get
the jackets? We don't know!
But they've
been there all along.
You're a crazy person.
I can't believe
I thought I liked you.
You do like me.
And I like you. That's...
Are you okay, sweeties?
I'm sorry.
Come on.
Let's get away
from this evil man.
I'm sorry.
Yes, so am I.
Another day?
I can't believe it!
This is so exciting!
I know, right?
Can you believe it?
Although, things aren't going
so great now,
so maybe last night
should've been it!
♪ We're a thousand miles
from comfort
♪ We have traveled
land and sea
This wasn't part
of the plan?
♪ But as long as
you are with me
♪ There's no place
I'd rather be
Hello, sweetie.
Come in.
I'm so sorry about your home.
It's all my fault. I should never
have invited him into our lives.
He's such an idiot,
and going after you like that
when you've done absolutely
nothing to goad him.
You're just going
about your business,
a complete innocent.
Sad truth is, though, I
actually kind of fell for him.
I could have loved him, even.
I should see
about a train ticket.
♪ With every step we take
♪ Kyoto to the Bay
♪ Strolling so casually
I messed up, guys.
Really bad.
If this were based on
a different kind of storybook,
Peter's parents would say
something like...
You haven't really been
trying to protect Bea.
You're just scared
of losing her.
But sharing love
is not losing love.
Love is infinite.
You think we loved you any
less after we had the girls?
Be honest with yourself,
Peter, and go with your heart.
You've got a good one.
But it's not based
on that kind of storybook,
so this is what they said.
♪ We staked out on a mission
♪ To find our inner peace
♪ Make it everlasting
♪ So nothing is incomplete ♪
Thomas!
I thought it was you.
I've been trying to call you.
I'm sorry, there's
no reception in Windermere.
How barbaric.
On the contrary,
it's one of its many beauties.
I have some good news.
Bannerman's no longer with us.
- He died.
- Earring infection in both ears.
Said it was the stress
of working here for one day.
Quit, moved to France,
of course.
- I'm sorry, is he dead?
- No.
I thought maybe "moving
to France" was a euphemism.
The job's yours
if you want it,
pending a psychological
evaluation,
but you seem much better.
Interested?
Where would I find
men's scarves?
- Lower ground.
Just take the escalator down.
Right, right, left.
With your hip-to-waist ratio,
I'd suggest a green check.
You work here?
Do you?
I'm thinking.
- Do you?
- I...
I'm gonna go make this right.
I've wrecked our home.
I've wrecked Bea's home.
I'm a real home-wrecker.
Think I'm using
that expression properly.
I got us into this,
and I let you all down.
I'm really sorry.
I prepared a speech.
"I got us into this,
"and I let you all down.
"I'm really sorry."
I guess that was
the whole thing.
Kind of crushed it
the first time.
I should've listened
to you, Benjamin.
Not just about this,
about everything.
You're so much wiser than me.
It wasn't about the garden.
I don't know where
I'd be without you.
In a pie, probably.
Probably.
And I should've been
a better big brother.
Truth is,
I'm a little lost
without Mum and Dad.
I miss them so much.
- So do we.
- Yeah.
Me, too.
So, are we good?
This was pretty bad,
even for you.
I'm scared, Peter.
Don't be. I'm gonna fix this.
- What should we do?
- Just make sure
she doesn't leave
until I get back.
Should we break
both ankles or just one?
I'm sorry, that was weird.
- Both.
- What?
Just stall her.
I won't let you down.
- I promise.
- You can count on us.
Also, I didn't kill
old McGregor.
He died of a heart attack.
- We know.
- The whole time.
- We thought you needed a victory.
- Okay, then.
Laser-focused
with a half thought-out plan,
this is what
a hero looks like.
Or a lunatic.
The line between the two
is very blurry.
Okay, listen up.
Here's what we're going to do.
Wait, why do you
get to be in charge?
Because I'm the oldest.
By 16 seconds.
Mopsy. Sweet, sweet Mopsy.
Wait, you both know
that I'm the oldest, right?
♪ When I wake up
♪ Well, I know I'm gonna be
Here we go, just gotta...
Oops, sorry.
Sorry. Sorry. Sorry. Sorry.
♪ I'm gonna be the man
who goes along with you ♪
Sorry. Sorry.
No, it's leaving.
Wait for me!
Benjamin!
You're coming with me?
Yes, it's my character flaw.
But there's no other character
I'd rather have
a flaw for than you...
I'm so glad you came.
I feel terrible
that I hurt you.
I prepared a speech.
"I feel terrible that..."
Benjamin!
No! Benjamin, I'm sorry!
Run! Run, jump! You can do it!
You can... Yes!
Peter, you're a terrible
apologizer.
Excuse me, town mouse, do you
know how to get to Harrods?
Absolutely.
Are you boys from the country?
How can you tell?
Brown on brown.
It's a bit matchy-matchy.
Come with me, I'll give you
the grand tour.
Thanks.
We're kind of in a hurry.
Plenty to see
along the way.
Tower Bridge.
Buckingham Palace.
Guards wearing beavers.
Big Ben.
Much larger than I thought.
View of the skyline.
It's just stunning,
but, Johnny,
we're on a time-sensitive
mission,
and it seems like
you're drawing it out a bit
because of pride
for your hometown.
London's one of the most culturally
significant cities in the world.
What kind of host would I be
if I didn't share it with you?
You're right, if we're actually
here, we should see everything.
Thanks, Johnny,
we owe you one.
My pleasure. Always happy
to help out a fellow rodent.
Rodent?
It's a shame.
But don't worry, I'll get you
to the train on time.
Yes!
Who would
do such a thing?
I have many enemies.
Okay, he's got to be here.
Where is he? Where is he?
Where is he?
A talking bunny doll?
I am a rabbit.
I like carrots.
Beep-boop, beep...
This isn't happening.
He's just an illusion.
Deep breaths. Deep breaths.
Mr. McGregor. Psst.
Remember me from before?
No, no, no, no!
I just want to talk.
Rabbits don't talk!
I knew you could talk!
Wait, are you talking
or am I just hallucinating?
Call Security. He's gone
crackers again.
You ruined my life!
McGregor!
You got to come back with us.
Back to Bea.
She's about to leave.
She's gonna give up painting
and go home.
She wants nothing
to do with me.
That's because she thinks
this is all your fault.
But we both know that I had a little
tiny something to do with it.
"Little"?
- "Tiny"?
- Okay, a lot.
I'm not good at owning up
to my mistakes.
I'm working on it.
- McGregor!
- I just hope it's not too late.
I let her down.
It's over.
It's not.
I just wanted you gone.
I didn't think of
anyone but myself.
I'm sorry I electrocuted you.
I'm sorry I put
traps on your head.
I'm sorry I rubbed my butt
on your hairbrush.
Wait. Wait. What?
Nothing. Stay focused.
Please come back. Not for me.
- For Bea.
- How do I know this isn't a trick?
You don't.
You just have to trust me.
Trust us.
So you really are
talking?
No. Like you said,
you chilled out, man.
You're cool now.
And you're listening
to your heart.
That's what you're hearing.
McGregor!
Unlock this door!
Now listen to your heart.
It's telling you to turn left,
run six paces to that window,
break it open,
and let's get the
heck out of here!
McGregor! Open up!
McGregor!
And so the two
former enemies
and one of their cousins
set out across the country,
a ticking clock
their common adversary.
It was dangerous, gutsy,
convoluted,
and, in a story like this,
pretty much a journey
guaranteed to succeed.
So let's just
hit the highlights.
Everybody, hang on!
Now!
Headlights.
What?
They're not even on.
Come on! This is ridiculous.
Shoo.
Okay. Come on.
Get out of here. Go.
I'm fine! I'm fine!
Thomas?
What are you doing?
You once said
that everyone has
a place in this world.
Well, this is your place,
and you shouldn't have to leave
because of something I did.
Were they with you?
Yes. They came to London.
- "They came to London"?
- Yes.
Yes. To talk me
into coming back.
Well, they probably didn't talk.
It was probably all in my head.
Well... No.
But that's not the point.
You shouldn't have to leave.
I'm sorry for
everything that I did.
And I love you, Bea.
Aw.
You tried to kill them.
You blew up their home.
You blew up my home.
'Cause I got caught up
in everything, you know?
I got caught up in our fight.
"Our" fight?
You're still going on
about this. Pathetic.
Come on, Betty, let's go.
It was my fault.
I take full responsibility.
My hero.
Finally admitting
that he blew up the burrow.
Not, as you
previously claimed,
the button on the detonator
being pushed by a rabbit!
Hello, sweetie.
Are you okay?
You were a part of this?
I told you!
I did tell you.
I can't believe this.
It's a lot to process.
- It really is.
- Yes.
Please forgive us.
You mind moving
all this out the way?
I mean, this is
our house and all.
Perfect country gem.
My stupid sister's
going to be so jealous.
I'm sorry. The manor's
no longer for sale.
Yeah, 'cause it's already
been sold. We bought it.
- Sorry, who are you?
- I'm the man who sold it.
And also the man
who is canceling the sale.
No. Sale's final.
You sold it already?
- Yes, but I...
- You and your husband
- need to move off now.
- I'm not her husband.
I just... We're...
Although...
- Get up.
- Bea...
Come on. There's only one way
out of this.
- You with me?
- Yep.
- Absolutely.
- Always.
- Of course.
- Love you guys.
Shall we? It's so cute.
It's like a 3D version of a
storybook, really.
- Allow me.
- Thank you.
What is that?
A gross little goblin or
something.
Clear off!
We'll get pest control.
- Darling.
♪ I've been up
I've been down
♪ I don't care, it can rain
♪ All it wants on my parade
♪ Because when life gives me
lemons, I make... ♪
No. No, no.
Absolutely not.
- Nah, you can have it.
- We'll keep the deposit.
- Bye!
- Bye! Lovely couple.
So down-to-earth.
What a mess you made.
Well done.
Did you just wink at him?
I didn't know
you could do that.
There's a lot of things they can
do that you don't know about.
A lot of things.
♪ Life's tough when
you're scared and small
♪ Still tough
when you're big and tall
♪ Or wrong side
of McGregor's wall
♪ And suddenly your heart
is like a tennis ball
♪ Up and down, side to side
♪ Served so hard
you'd think you'd died
♪ No love for you
Help yourselves, sweeties.
Within reason.
♪ No wall
could ever split us up
♪ Our love's forever
♪ No hate
Streaker!
I'm so sorry
this keeps happening.
Mind if I give it a go?
♪ Life's rough
when you feel confused
♪ Still rough
when you hear the news
♪ That each day
got to pick and choose
♪ The same old sides
the mes and yous
♪ But don't be sad,
you're welcome here
♪ Even certain carnivores
are in the clear
♪ I promise you
♪ Wind blows and heaven knows
♪ That sun can turn to rain
♪ There's nothing much
to fear though
♪ Doors close and we all know
♪ That love can turn to pain
♪ So let's be
each other's heroes
♪ No gate
♪ No wall could
ever split us up
♪ Our love's forever
♪ No hate
♪ No fear could
ever keep us down
♪ We'll stick together
♪ Life's nice on a sunny day
♪ French press
and a plate of hay
♪ But some days
can't escape the fray
♪ Crazily careening
like a bird of prey
♪ This old house
is never locked
♪ Even Tiggy-Winkles
needn't need to knock
♪ I promise you
♪ No gate
♪ No wall
could ever split us up
♪ Our love's forever
♪ No hate
♪ No fear
could ever keep us down
♪ We'll stick together
Did everyone
live happily ever after?
Well, of course. It's the
law in these storybooks.
All you have to do
is toss and fluff.
Toss and fluff. Very simple.
You give it a go.
How's it going? Yes?
It's good. Going really well.
How do I know all this?
I lived through it.
Grew up a little,
lost my lisp,
and found my voice.
Wake up, Rooster!
I'm telling a story here!
Sorry, I've been up since the
crack of dawn with these kids!
And they're the best
thing that's ever happened to me.
That was a great story, Flopsy.
What are you gonna call it?
I'm calling it,
"The Tale of Peter Rabbit."
I love it. But how about
"The Tale of Peter,
Flopsy, Mopsy,
Cotton-Tail, and Benjamin:
A Loving Family"?
Aw.
Or maybe you had it
right the first time.
"Peter Rabbit."
♪ No gate
♪ No wall could
ever split us up
♪ Our love's forever
♪ No hate
♪ No fear could
ever keep us down
♪ We'll stick together ♪