Okay, Wood. In position.
Get ready.
Right.
Who can save Princess Juliet, held captive by the evil Count Lorka?
Who can save the city? Who?
Who...?
This is a job for Condorman!
Aah!
Harry!
Flap, Woody!
- Flap!
- Aaah!
It should've worked.
- Here. Drink this.
- I can't understand it.
- Drink this and calm down.
- I am calm!
I am calm.
Those wings were foolproof, Harry.
They were foolproof.
Woody, you're a great cartoonist,
and you're a great comic book writer...
...but you're a lousy bird.
I mean, you could've got yourself killled.
That's the way I create. You know that.
If Condorman can't do something in real life,
then I won't have him do it in one of my comic books.
Kids all over the world read my stuff.
They trust me. They know if I fake it.
Condorman's American. His word is his bond.
Well, hooray for the Red, White and Blue.
Woody, we've been buddies for a long time.
Now, I respect you, I admire you. You're sincere,
you're conscientious, but sometimes you go too far.
- How so?
- Well, take now.
Okay, so Condorman's first assignment
is to help the French government.
And you come here to Paris and stay with me
to get the feel of things.
Well, fine. But did you have to try to fly off the Eiffel Tower
and nearly drown?
Come on, Woody. You're so wrapped up in your characaters
that you're losing sight of reality.
Go home. New England's nice this time of year.
Relax, take it easy.
Condorman would find enough excitement
in New York City to last a lifetime.
No, no, no, no, no.
Besides, Superman's got the Big Apple sewn up.
No, Condorman's gotta be international.
And as for reality and fantasy,
look what you do for a living.
Huh? What a fantastic life, huh? To be a spy.
I am not a spy, Woody.
CIA, huh? Cloak and dagger, secret missions.
Parachuting behind enemy lines, memorizing code words.
Oh, that has to be the greatest, Harry!
Woody, not everybody at the Agency is Robert Redford.
- Oh, come on! When you went to Bangkok--
- Read my lips...
I am a file clerk. Nothing more, nothing less.
You have my notes. Prepare the Benson file for an audit,
and then contact our people in Geneva.
Oh, there's Harry now.
Morning, Richard.
- How's it going, Harry?
- Late again. Bus strike.
- Harry?
- Sir?
What's up, Russ?
The Geneva meeting. I'm going to be gone for two days.
I want you to keep an eye on things for me.
Right. Uh, what about the Istanbul papers?
The exchange takes place the day after tomorrow.
You can handle that, Harry. They're not important anyway.
But Harrington won't be back from Rio 'til the weekend.
We're not sending Harrington. Our Russian friends insist
the exchange be handled by civilians.
Huh, civilians? What are the Ruskies worried about?
That the Chinese'll find out they got spies in Turkey?
Exactly.
- Have you recruited the civilian?
- That's where you come in. Just pick someone suitable.
Wh-- uh, me? But Russ... but Russ... Russ?
- Russ, I don't think I can handle this.
- You're always asking for more authority. This is your big chance.
What do I do? Stop the first American tourist I see and say,
"Hey, mister, how would you like to do your country a favor...
"... and drop of some secret papers
to a Russian in Istanbul?"
Something like that, yes. Now you're learning!
But, Ru---
Russ, what if I need to get ahold of you on the--?
Hey, Woody? Harry.
Remember how I saved your life this morning?
Well, I got a big favor to ask.
You like trains?
What's with the outfit?
[Imitating Humphrey Bogart:]
"Of all the stations... in all the world..."
- You like?
- I hate.
Give me the hat and trenchcoat.
- What? No!
- Woody, you were hired because you're a civilian.
I mean, take it easy with the Bogart schtick.
All right, but leave me the coat, please.
It gives me confidence.
Okay, okay. But remember you're supposed to blend in.
I got it. I got it.
Yeah, that's you. Give me your wrist.
Oh!
Oh, I like that. I like it!
I knew you would. Here's the key.
Don't lose it!
Thanks, Harry. And don't worry...
I won't let the organization down.
Do me a favor, buddy.
When you get on board the train, just have a couple of stiff drinks,
go to sleep and stay out of trouble.
Hey... you're talking to Woody, right? Right?
Sure. Now get on board.
Harry. when do I get off again?
At the end of the line, Woody.
Istanbul.
Whoa!
Oh, I'm so sorry.
I'm a bit unsteady. It was jet lag.
No, train lag. Whatever.
Now you be carful!
Excuse me.
No... it was my faul... fault, I...
I tripped you with a purpose.
I thought it was you.
I believe we have something we can give each other?
Oh, absolutely.
I mean, I'm a man...
- ...you're a woman.
- I speak of documents.
Papers.
Papers?
Ah, papers! Yes, papers.
Istanbul, right?
Exchange must be discreet.
Of course.
Your order, sir?
- I'll have one of those.
- One Istanbul Express?
Yes, a double.
A double? Nobody orders it a double, sir.
Okay.
Make it a triple.
What's your name?
Natalia.
"Natalia."
I need your papers.
Is something wrong?
It's just that you're so beautiful.
- For a spy.
- Spy?!
But we are both civilians.
Everything may not be quite as it seems.
You are not a civilian?
In point of fact, no.
I'm working as a top-level operative in
international espionage.
Just passing through, doing a favor for a civilian.
Is that so?
Yes.
One triple Istanbul Express.
So, do you have a code name?
Does the name "Condorman" mean anything to you?
- Condorman, eh?
- Yes, Condorman.
"Vulture of the Western World."
I must go.
Please don--
[ Muffled: ]
Please don't go.
Those men over by the door, they're after me. I must go.
Oh, why don't we leave together?
If you're with me, maybe they won't try anything.
Nothing will stop them.
Aren't you forgetting Condorman, "Vulture of the" etc., etc.?
We are in great danger.
Danger? I laugh at danger.
Step aside.
You step aside or you will die.
I'm sorry I had to get so violent,
but it was the only language they understood.
- Are you all right?
- Oh, I'm fine apart from a large dry cleaning bill.
I'll tell you one thing: if I ever come back to Istanbul,
I'm gonna put this place on my "try to avoid" list.
Are you okay?
I was afraid for you.
You were?
That's very nice.
Well...
Oh! I believe these are for you.
The Istanbul papers?
Thank you... for everything.
It was nothing. I do this two or three times a week.
Natalia...
I--
Do svidaniya, Condorman!
Hello, Natalia.
Welcome home.
Oh, Sergei. I did not expect you.
I am sure you didn't, my dear, any more than I expected
you would go to Istanbul.
I had to go there.
We cannot trust the Americans, as I found out.
Really? And what did you find out, my little dove?
I must go and change. The journey, it was very long.
The exchange was supposed to be a civilian operation, eh?
I anticipated them and I was right.
They sent a top agent.
I had the office check him but there is no file on this man.
He was good.
Very smooth and very tough.
Perhaps even as good as you, Sergei.
And his name?
Surely when you were finding out how tough and how smooth
he was, you found out his name, no?
He called himself Condorman.
Condorman?
How quaint.
But he is good.
The way he handled those three Turks was impressive.
If they got hold of you who knows what would have happened.
But you were stupid to be seen by a Chinese agent.
And I am not one to let anybody jeopardize my position, am I?
Oh, my dear Natalia.
That is why I have changed my mind about bringing you with me...
to Monte Carlo to act as hostess
to the oil meetings with our Arabian friends.
You see, you need a little re-education
to remind you of the teachings of our masters.
Harry, my Laser Lady.
Isn't she beautiful?
Who is Condorman?
- "Condorman"?
- Condorman.
Well, uh... Condorman is what we call a comic hero,
in a comic book.
A comic book?
Yeah, you know, like Donald Duck, Popeye, Superman.
He's not a real person?
- Who, Condorman?
- Yes, Condorman.
No, Russ, comic book characters aren't real people.
Not as a rule, anyway. I mean, uh, Donald Duck for example...
...he's not a real duck.
Just a drawing.
Hmm.
Interesting.
Well, I don't know how interesting it is.
I mean, every kid knows that. I've known it all my life.
Haven't you ever read a comic book?
Harry, Condorman is a real person.
Well, if you say so, Russ. I always thought it's a cartoon.
Uh, is that all you wanted to talk to me about?
Listen, Harry, we have a Russian agent who wants to defect.
Now, this Russian insists that we use one particular agent
of ours to facilitate the defection.
Apparently they have some kind of rapport.
Now, we have been given the code name of the agent wanted,
but we've never heard of it.
Now it's vital that we find this man
and use him to handle this operation.
I want you to go through every file we've got
and find out who has been using the code name "Condorman".
What's the matter?
I think I know who's been using that name.
Are you serious?!
- Very.
- I could get killed!
It's not a dangerious operation, buddy.
It's just a simple defection.
Simple defection for you, maybe.
I delievered "simple" papers in Istanbul,
and nearly got shish-kabobbed by three Turkish behemoths.
Every precaution is going to be taken for your safety.
The Bear is very important to us--
Bear? What bear?
The Bear is the code name for the Russian spy
who wants to defect.
Oh, I'm sorry, fellas. I refuse to place my fragile life in jeopardy
over anybody who goes under the name of "The Bear".
Ah, come on, Woody. A little cloak, a little dagger.
Mr. Wilkins, I feel certain that patriotism
counts for something with a matter--
Patriotism? Forget patriotism.
I have a family to think of.
Family?
Yes, Gopher Boys, Spongeman, deadlines and things.
Condorman and Laser Lady make their debut next week.
Do you realize that we are talking about
the most important defection in this decade?
I'm not a spy!
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Come on, Woody. You know yourself that you won't even put
anything in the comics unless it's been tested and proven.
Well, now here's your chance.
Out of the ink well and into real life!
It's the chance of a lifetime.
Whatever you're dreaming up for Condorman or Spongeman,
all you have to do is draw us the plans and we'll do the rest.
We can build anything you need and deliver it
anywhere in the world at our expense.
Right, Russ?
Right... Russ?
You know, Mr. Wilkins, we wouldn't be asking you to do this...
if it weren't for the fact that the Bear
insisted upon you being the escort.
Well, how could the Bear know about me?
Because you've already met her in Istanbul.
Natalia Rambova of the KGB.
Natalia!
Impossible.
No. No, impossible.
Absolutely out of the question.
Now hang on a minute!
You said you'd do this in my way with my designs.
But this is going to cost us a fortune!
Look, it's a tricky transfer, I grant you,
but can't you... simplify a little bit?
Uh, Russ has a point, Wood.
See, he wants you to bring him the Bear, not a comic book.
Yeah, okay. Okay.
If I don't get the equipment, I don't get the Bear.
Over to you, Russ.
Well, I don't know. I...
Of course, if all else fails, we are prepared, Russ.
Uh, we could always go to Plan B.
Okay.
Get Fabrication on it immediately.
Right, Russ.
I want you there yesterday.
Plan B.
What's Plan B, Harry?
I don't know.
But I hope to have it ready
by the time you get to Yugoslavia.
Natalia?
Ah!
- Natalia!
- Yes? Yes?
Condorman?
Who else?
I knew you would come.
I hope you didn't mind the gypsy disguise.
I figured you'd look good in anything.
- We must hurry before we're discovered.
- You're right. Come on.
Come on.
Take your time. Everything's ready.
We should be able to leave the country.
Oh, problem!
An escape as gypsies. How very romantic, comrade.
And who is your American friend?
Put up your hands and move over there!
You don't understand. I'm really on your side.
I'm a double agent. I was delivering
some secret information to the Bear, here.
We're old comrades from Istanbul.
Is that your story, comrade?
- Yes.
- Really?
Krokov would be most interested.
He has suspected your defection for some time.
Boris.
Hand over your weapons.
I don't have one. Condorman does not carry a gun.
It is against my code.
What?!
Guns scare me. The noise.
All I carry is my trusty old cane.
- You are all right?
- That's a hair trigger!
- Fastest cane in the West!
- Watch out!
Multi-purpose!
Come on!
Right through here.
You are not nervous, eh?
Me, Condorman, nervous? No.
Watch out!
It's okay. It's nothing to worry about.
Just testing the steering mechanism.
So...
you decided to defect?
Oh, life has not been very easy for me at home.
It's been on my mind for some time now.
Well, why didn't you do it from Istanbul?
Something happened between Krokov and me
when I got back to Russia that made my decision.
I realized it was now or never.
- Krokov?
- The man those agents talked about back there.
This Krokov...
he isn't your husband by any chance, is he?
No. I am single woman.
Free, single woman.
Well, I'm very glad to hear that.
I was thinking... America is so far away, you know.
Oh, but you'll love it when you get there.
Fall in New England, the Grand Canyon, New York, those buildings!
Thanksgiving, toasted marshmallows, Sunday Funnies,
the Senior Prom, baseball, you'd be crazy not to...
But how did that happen?!
Look, I had two men following them.
What?
No, no, no, absolutely not.
I want her alive.
That is far too good for that little traitor.
What?
No, the man is expendable.
Well, send out the Brocknoviach.
And make sure that Morovich is personally in charge.
(In Russian:)
Morovich speaking.
I need the Brocknoviach.
Brocknoviach!
(Speaking commands in Russian)
съезжать!
(Move out!)
It's like a storybook town.
Just look at it. So quiet.
It's too quiet.
What do you mean?
The people. Where are the people?
Natalia, you gotta learn to lighten up. Relax!
Something is wrong.
съезжать!
(Move out!)
- Krokov will do anything to get me back.
- Forget Krokov. You're with me now.
- Natalia!
- What is it?
You tell me.
The Brocknoviach!
- We cannot outrun them in this old truck!
- You have a point there.
But...
Incredible!
Fantastic!
- What are we going to do now?
- Well...
we push another button.
I don't believe it!
- Who are those guys?
- The Brocknoviach is the KGB pursuit squadron.
Superb drivers and each one is a dedicated killer.
Look out!
Okay, okay.
Let's warm things up a bit.
- Do something!
- There's nothing left to do.
Stop!
- He's crazy! He will kill us!
- Stop, nothing. That's what he wants.
It's Morovich!
- You know that guy?
- He is homicidal maniac.
- You've got to stop him.
- Of course, I've got to stop him. The trick is how!
Whoa!
Escaped?!
- And in a gypsy truck?!
- The gyspy truck turned into a racecar.
- But you had the Brocknoviach!
- Before my eye, the racecar turned into a hydrofoil!
Have you seen this report on this Condorman?
On this man Wilkins?
He is an amateur, do you hear? He is NOT an agent of the CIA!
He is a writer of comic books!
We shall be a laughing stock back home.
Comrade, please.
All I ask is one more chance to get this Condorman.
All right, my dear Morovich.
You will get that chance.
According to my calculations...
he should land somehwere...
in north coast of Italy.
Roundabout there should be the place.
- Vito?
- Yes, Comrade Kommisar?
Contact Barotsini. We are collecting an old debt.
Tell him what we want.
Not far to go.
Where are we?
I don't know, but don't worry. We're safe and clear now.
How can you say that?
It's logic. If we don't know where we are,
it stands to reason Krokov doesn't know, either.
I doubt whether he'd have us followed into Italy.
- Hey.
- You don't know Krokov.
Hey, that will be perfect!
Come on.
Ah, this'll be fine.
We'll sleep here and get an early start in the morning.
Tomorrow I'll find a telephone, call Harry,
and we'll be home in no time.
Polizia!
On your feet! You are under arrest.
Uh, signore... uh, scusi... uh, there's been a mistake.
You have got the wrong couple.
- Comprende?
- Woody, you must do something!
How can I do something?
Obviously he's got us mixed up with another couple?
It said we killed a man in Monte Carlo.
"In Monte Carlo"? We've never even been to Monte Carlo!
Krokov is behind this.
Guard...
Guard, you really are making a big mistake.
The authorities from Monte Carlo are on their way.
Krokov's men.
- You know what I think?
- What?
I think we're in serious trouble.
Oh, Gopher Boy, what would you do now?
What?
Oh, nothing.
Nothing.
J'essuie Inspector Jamoe, Police, Monaco.
Wake up!
Bring your thing.
Hey, fella. You think this is it? Do you think you got us licked?
Huh? The world isn't a vacuum, you know.
You mark this: I'm an American citizen.
You don't speakity English, huh? No understando... mio?
What language do they speak in Monaco?
Hey, ugly American, remember Plan B? This is it.
Harry?!
This?
Get in.
Have you got the key?
Not now. We're being watched by you-know-who!
Besides, the Ruskies can't be far behind.
You're all over the front page.
- Does Russ know about this?
- He's working on the rest of the plan.
- "Bazooka Boy meets Hannibal Smith".
- Great! One of my favorites!
- Okay, Harry, give me the keys.
- Let's get out of here first.
Stop! It's Morovich.
Get out of here! Fast!
There!
Down there!
Harry! The keys!
- Okay.
- Come on!
- Okay?
- Uh-huh.
I wish to speak!
Yes?
This man is already married!
To who is this man married?
To me.
What is this? I never saw her before!
Come home, Pietro, please, for the sake of the children.
You are lying! She is nothing but a liar. She is crazy.
I wish I was, but Pietro Jr. cry for his father.
- You will leave her at once.
- I will not.
Uncle Luigi and I have come to take you home.
I will throw her out myself.
- Don't you lay a hand on me!
- Who will stop me?
Uncle Luigi!
I will squeeze the truth of this Uncle Luigi.
- We believe they are headed in the direction of--
- The Alps.
That's what we suspect.
In which case, they could cross at any one of a number of places:
Near Mont Blanc, through Simplon Pass, below--
I know exactly where they will cross.
You do?
The best-kept secrets of Woodrow Wilkins can be found by
any small child for the price of a tiny coin.
Here is a truck that turns into a racing car.
Here, a car that turns into a hovercraft.
Genius weapons,
exploding rockets,
it's all here, including, my friend...
"Bazooka Boy meets Hannibal Smith"?
Where they will cross the Alps.
Whoa.
Well, here it is. We made it.
- At last, a real inn with hot water.
- And food!
Well, we'll stay here tonight, but in one room.
We mustn't separate.
Right.
What is this? Why are all these children looking at us?
Uh, it's out of season. Maybe they're just glad to see tourists.
- Hi there.
- Buongiorno.
That's your room. I hope you are very happy.
- But, meant for two.
- Two people? Yes, sir.
- Two people.
- Arrivederci. Bye.
- Two peoples!
Oh, I can feel that hot water from that shower already.
Uh... unless, uh...
well, I can feel it later if, uh...
- Be my guest.
- Oh, thanks a lot.
You are her, aren't you?
Of course it's her.
- It is.
- It isn't.
It is.
What is this? Why are you children staring at me?
"The Empress of Space, Time, and Beauty."
Laser Lady.
How did you get to be Laser Lady?
You scared the dickens out of me.
I turned around and you're gone,
Woody's out like a light.
I figured, "Boom, that's it!"
They heard the shower running and they... grabbed you.
Natalia? You all right?
Yes, yes, I'm all right.
Harry, who are you?
What do you mean?
Woody is Condorman, I am Laser Lady, who are you?
How'd you find out?
The children here read comic books, too.
Let's take a little walk.
I knew you'd find out sooner or later,
but I held my peace because of Woody.
It's all my fault.
Wow!
No wonder they can eat so much pasta.
Harry!
Va en primo. Baillamo.
(Come now. Dance with me. Let's go.)
- Listen, I--
-  Adiamo subito.
When you got it, you got it.
A ruble for your thoughts.
When I parted from Krokov, I promised myself
I would never love again a man who lived a life of deception.
But now...
now I think there's deception and exception.
I don't understand.
But I do.
When I go to America, and start reading the Sunday funnies,
and eating my Big Mac, and planning for the senior prom--
You may have missed the prom.
I would like it very much if I could pick up my American telephone,
call my friend Woody and say,
"Come over and be democratic with me."
I'll bring the dip if you bring the Dostoyevski.
That's a yes.
What are we doing up here?
You see that? That's our first-class ticket to freedom.
This is it!
Oh, good old Russ. He got it exactly right.
- He did?
- What is it?
They're jet rods. And as with the other one,
you just hook it up there on the cable...
like so...
Then you open up the stirrups...
climb aboard...
and when youre ready to go,
pull that lever and zowie! Right up the mountain.
Whoa. Hold on.
Harry, there's nothing to be afraid of.
Uh, Woody... I can't handle heights.
Okay, you climb on with me. And hold on.
Whoa.
Ready?
Okay!
Morovich...
- you see them?
- Da.
Shoot.
Woody!
Don't you touch me!
Don't!
I think they're gone.
We can move now.
I... may... never... move... again!
Good morning, Natalia.
I trust you slept well.
Surely you don't think I'd let you get away
after all you've meant to me.
I hate you.
And I wish to kill you.
You don't know how tempted I was.
I wish you would have.
Anything would have been better than this.
Save your tears. I am going to save your life.
Our story will be that you pretended to defect
in order to kidnap this Condorman.
I shall lay the blame on Morovich for failing this mission.
Of course, he will have to be killed.
We can't have the Party hearing his side of the story, can we?
You pig.
Do you really think that things will be the same between us?
For the moment, I don't care.
But remember, Natalia, whatever happens in the future
is better than a slow death in a Siberian slave hut, no?
Don't touch me.
Very well.
But, for the moment, things will have
to appear as normal between ourselves.
You will have to play the role of perfect hostess,
a role you were born for.
And if you have any design on escape,
this comfortable villa is an impregnable fortress.
Your every move would be watched.
The oil ministers arrive tomorrow.
I want you up and about, looking your best.
Laughing and ensuring they are happy, hmm?
Get out of here!
That's better.
That's the spirit.
I will leave you now for a moment
to get your redemption into your head.
And, Natalia...
remember, any more trouble from you
and I shall personally kill you immediately.
Woody?
- I just talked to Russ.
- Natalia?
Krokov's got her at the Russian villa in Monte Carlo.
- We gotta get her out of there.
- Woody...
we've been ordered back to Paris.
Our mission's considered a bust.
I can't go back. Not without Natalia.
I love her, Harry.
I know.
Look, I still have Top Red clearance.
That gives me anything I need, including Fort Knox, right?
Now, wait a minute.
That was before we were ordered back to Paris, Woody.
Forget orders. Tell them you didn't see me in time,
that it was too late.
I can't do that, Woody--
Harry, two days. That's all I ask.
Two days.
Please.
Okay, buddy. You got it.
- Harry, you're beautiful!
- Will you stop? People will talk!
Now here's what I have in mind...
- Oh, hello, Sergei.
- Hello, Ori. What's happened?
Oh, amazing, Sergei. Amazing.
This Arab, he took the house to the limit.
- What is that?
- 5 million Francs.
Who is that man?
I called in to the Underground.
He was nothing more than another Bedouin.
Then, several months ago, he struck oil and now...
Now he's the seventh richest man in the world.
Make sure he is at tomorrow's party.
But the question remains: can we produce it in sufficient quantity?
Now, do you... do you see that as a problem in the long run?
That all depends.
What was your question again, huh?
Well, actually what I said was,
"Do you think our North Sea will produce enough oil?"
North Sea? Ha! A Caesar salad's worth!
Pardon me, please.
Business. I have to close a deal for Rhode Island.
Huh.
Amazing.
So?
Everything's "go".
You talk to her yet?
I can't get near her.
Every time I turn around, someone tries to sell me something.
Well, whatever you do, don't buy.
When are you gonna make your move?
Hey!
Right. I'm gonna try and get to her now.
You give me five minutes, then let it go.
- Okay?
- Okay. Five minutes.
Don't worry about me.
Hmmph.
Enchanting.
A beautiful place, Monaco.
Yes, it is. I do not believe we have met.
Natalia Rambova.
Don't scream out, the Cavalry's here.
- Woo--
- No!
Woody!
They told me you were dead.
I've come to get you. Come on!
No.
I cannot go with you.
What do you mean?
I'm sorry...
but I've changed my mind.
You've changed your mind?!
Are you crazy? This isn't like deciding what restaurant you're
going to eat in. This is a defection!
It's Krokov.
Krokov? Forget Krokov! Now come with me.
No, no, Krokov--
Krokov had a plan. It was a plan. Don't be stupid.
Krokov thought you were a top American agent.
My defection was a ruse to kidnap you.
But now we know you're nothing more than a foolish dreamer
who draws comic books, not worth the bullet to kill you.
So go now, please, and don't try to do anyth--
I see you've already met the Sheik.
Yes.
He thought we had met before.
Is that so?
But I was... mistaken.
A foolish dream, perhaps.
It was a pleasure meeting you.
I'm sorry we did not have more time.
Some other day, perhaps.
If you bring the dip, I'll bring the Dostoyevski.
"I'll bring the dip..."
"I'll bring the dip!"
Natalia!
Three... two... one...
Come on! This way!
Natalia!
After them.
Downstairs, quick!
Good, Harry. Good.
- Nein!
- Halt!
Coming through!
Oh, Russ, if you could see me now!
There's no key!
Quick! Give me a hand!
We're trapped!
Don't you believe it!
Woody, I'm frightened!
Don't worry.
Condorman has it all figured out.
But how can we escape? Fly?
You are not serious.
You want out?
I want you.
Then get behind me and hold on tight!
Morovich... prepare them.
Uh-oh.
Woody, I can't hold on much longer.
When are we going to land?
As soon as I see Harry at the rendezvous.
Oh, you beauty, you doll.
We made it.
Oh, no!
Somebody stop that car!
Ooh, I got... I got... I got... oh!
Aah!
Well, Russ...
easy come, easy go.
Okay.
Here we go.
Yeah...
eh...
yeah, yeah...
On the boat, Natalia.
Let's go!
Why did you come and get me? You could have left me at the villa.
Why did you pretend you didn't want to come?
I could not let you be discovered and killed. If I had tried to
ask you to help me you would have done something stupid.
Instead of the sane and sensible thing we're doing now.
Yeah, but how do you feel about my being
"a foolish dreamer who draws comic books", huh?
- Did I say that?
- Uh-huh.
Laser Lady would say anything to save the man she loves.
Will you two come on?!
Come on, down!
Now.
съезжать!
(Move out!)
- Harry, change places!
- Right!
I thought I'd never get to use you, baby.
- Hit the smoke!-
- Gotcha!
Let's head for home!
Nice shootin', Woody!
I hate to say this, but we're in serious trouble!
Head for skylift!
Return to base.
Return to base!
He's gonna ram us!
Take it up!
There's a long, high drive into deep left field.
Back goes Nelson to the track, to the wall, it's gone!
Natalia, you brought us luck. I could kiss you!
- Not bad, Condorman. We should go to more baseball games.
- Yeah, I'll get us season tickets!
Hey, you two lovebirds. Do you mind?
I'm trying to watch the ball game.
Um, Natalia, look up.
It's a little American present to you.
Oh, my own airship!
Harry...
thank you.
So that's them, huh?
Yes, sir. That's them.
But this is nothing but trouble. If you want my advice--
This assignment is very delicate.
It needs handling with the greatest of finesse.
But that's exactly what I mean, sir.
I don't think this man is qualified.
Nonsense. He got the girl out, didn't he?
Do it.
Right away.
Set it up.
I'll get right on it.
Hey, Woody, you're a good old boy
and I've got a wonderful proposition for you.
Have you ever thought of taking Condorman to...