WOMAN:
Good night, sweetheart.
BOY:
Good night, Mom.
MAN:
Sleep tight, kiddo.
(LIGHT SWITCH CLICKS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(OWL HOOTING)
(TICKING)
(WIND BLOWING GENTLY)
(DOOR CREAKING OPEN)
(GASPS SOFTLY)
(WIND BLOWING)
(GASPS)
(WIND WHISTLING)
(GURGLING SNARL)
(SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING LOUDER)
Whoa!
(SHRIEKING)
(SCREAMING)
Oh! Aye! Oh! Oh!
(SHRIEKING)
(ALARM BLARING)
(YELPS)
COMPUTER VOICE:
Simulation terminated.
All right,
Mr. Bile, is it?
Uh... my friends
call me Phlegm.
Uh-huh.
Mr. Bile, can you tell me
what you did wrong?
I fell down?
No, no, before that.
Can anyone tell me
Mr. Bile's big mistake?
Anyone?
(COUGHS)
(GROANS)
Let's take a look
at the tape.
Here we go.
Uh, right...
puh-puh-puh-puh...
Ah! There, see?
The door.
You left it wide open.
(WHIMPERS)
(ALL MURMURING)
And leaving the door open
is the worst mistake
any employee can make
because...?
Um... it could let in a draft?
It could let in
a child!
Oh! Mr. Waternoose!
There is nothing more toxic
or deadly than a human child.
A single touch could kill you!
Leave a door open
and a child could walk
right into this factory!
Right into the monster world!
I won't go
in a kid's room!
You can't make me!
You're going in there
because we need this.
(CHILDREN SCREAMING)
(WHIMPERING)
(STATIC AND FEEDBACK)
(SCREAMING STOPS)
Our city is counting on you
to collect those children's
screams.
Without scream,
we have no power.
Yes, it's dangerous work
and that's why I need
you to be at your best.
I need scarers who are
confident, tenacious
tough, intimidating.
I need scarers like... like...
James P. Sullivan.
(SNORING)
Hey! Good morning,
Monstropolis.
It's now five after
the hour of 6:00 A.M.
in the big monster city.
Temperature's a
balmy 65 degrees...
Which is good news
for you reptiles...
And it looks like it's
going to be a perfect day
to maybe, hey,
just lie in bed, sleep in
or simply... work out that flab
that's hanging over the bed!
Get up, Sulley!
...(SCREAMING)
...(HONKING)
I don't believe I ordered
a wake-up call, Mikey.
Hey! Less talk, more pain,
marshmallow boy!
...Feel the burn!
...(GROWLING)
You call yourself
a monster?
(GROWLING)
Scary feet, scary feet,
scary feet!
Oop! The kid's awake!
Okay, scary feet, scary feet,
scary feet, scary feet...
Kid's asleep!
(ROARING)
Twins! In a bunk bed!
(GROWLING)
Ooh! I thought I had you there.
Okay, Sulley, here we go.
You ready? Follow it.
Oh! It's over here!
Oh, look over there!
Don't let the kid
touch you!
Don't let it touch you!
♪ I don't know,
but it's been said ♪
♪ I love scaring kids in bed! ♪
Come on, fight that plaque!
Fight that plaque!
Scary monsters
don't have plaque!
118... do you have 119?
Do I see 120?
Oh, I don't believe it!
I'm not even
breaking a sweat.
Not you!
Look! The new
commercial's on!
(YELLS)
ANNOUNCER: The future is bright
at Monsters, Incorporated.
I'm in this one!
ANNOUNCER:
We're part of your life.
We power your car.
We warm your home.
We light your city.
I'm Monsters, Incorporated.
Hey, look! Betty!
ANNOUNCER: Carefully matching every
child to their ideal monster...
...(ROARS)
...(SCREAMS)
to produce superior scream
refined into clean,
dependable energy.
Every time you turn something on
Monsters, Incorporated,
is there.
I'm Monsters, Incorporated!
ANNOUNCER:
We know the challenge...
The window of innocence
is shrinking.
Human kids are harder to scare.
Of course, M.I. is prepared
for the future
with the top scarers...
(CHILD SCREAMING)
the best refineries
and research
into new energy techniques.
...(YELLING)
...(SHRIEKING)
Okay, here I come.
We're working for a better
tomorrow... today!
WORKERS:
We're Monsters, Incorporated!
WATERNOOSE: We're M.I....
Monsters, Incorporated.
We scare because we care.
I can't believe it.
Oh, Mike...
I was on TV!
Did you see me?
I'm a natural!
(PHONE RINGS)
Hello.
I know!
Hey, wasn't I great?
Did the whole
family see it?
It's your mom.
What can I say?
The camera loves me.
(BICYCLE BELL RINGS)
I'm telling you, big daddy
you're going to be seeing this
face on TV a lot more often.
Yeah? Like, on
Monstropolis@s Most Wanted?
(MOCKING LAUGHTER)
You've been jealous
of my good looks
since the
fourth grade, pal.
Have a good day, sweetie.
You, too, hon.
Whoo!
Okay, Sulley, hop on in.
Nope. Uh-uh. Uh-uh.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
Where you going?
What are you doing?
Mikey, there's a scream
shortage. We're walking.
...Walking?!
...Yep.
No, no, no, my baby.
Come on. Come on.
Look, she needs
to be driven.
Bye, baby.
I... I'll call you!
MIKE: Hey, genius,
you want to know why
I bought the car? Huh?
Not really.
To drive it!
You know, like,
on the street?
With the honk-honk
and the vroom-vroom
and no walking involved.
(MOCK WHINING)
Give it a rest,
will you, butterball?
Come on, you could
use the exercise.
I could use
the exercise?!
Look at you.
You have your own climate!
GIRL MONSTERS: How many
tentacles jump the rope?
BOY MONSTER: Morning, Mike!
Morning, Sulley!
Hey! Morning, kids.
Hey, kids.
How you doing?
Bye, Mike!
Bye, Sulley!
BIG EYE:
Ow! Hey!
(HUMMING)
(SNEEZING)
Ah, nuts.
(SINGING)
Hey, hey, hey! Fellas!
Hey, Tony!
Tony! Ba-da-bing!
...Tony!
...Hey, Tony!
Pow, pow,
pow, pow, pow!
I hear somebody's
close to breaking
the all-time
scare record.
Ah, just trying
to make sure
there's enough scream
to go around.
(LAUGHING)
Hey! On the house!
...Hey, thanks!
...Grazie!
MIKE:
Ba-da-bing!
(STARTLED GASP)
Oh, great.
Hey, Ted!
Good morning!
(CLUCKING)
See that, Mikey?
Ted's walking to work.
Big deal.
Guy takes five steps
and he's there.
(PHONES RINGING)
FEMALE MONSTER:
Monsters, Inc. Please hold.
Morning, Sulley.
Morning, Ricky.
Hey, it's
the Sullster!
See you on the scare floor,
buddy!
Hey, Marge.
Hey, how was jury duty?
Morning, Sulley!
Hey!
Hey, it's still
leaning to the left.
It is not!
Hey, fellas.
Hey, Jerry.
Hey, Mr. Sullivan!
Guys, I told you,
call me Sulley.
(NERVOUS GIGGLING)
I don't think so.
We just wanted to wish
you good luck today.
Hey. Hey, hey,
hey, hey!
Come on, get lost,
you two.
You're making him
lose his focus.
Oh. Sorry.
See you later,
fellas.
Go get 'em,
Mr. Sullivan!
Quiet! You'd make
him lose his focus.
Oh, no. Sorry!
Shut up!
- (PHONES RINGING)
- Monsters, Inc. Please hold.
Monsters, Inc.
I'll connect you.
Ms. Fearmonger is on vacation.
Would you like her voice mail?
Oh, Schmoopsie-poo.
- (SNAKES SQUEALING)
- Googley Bear!
Happy birthday.
Oh, Googley-woogley,
you remembered!
Hey, Sulley-wulley.
Oh, hey, Celia...
weelia.
(CLEARS THROAT):
Happy birthday.
Thanks.
So, uh... are we going
anywhere special tonight?
I just got us
into a little place
called, um...
Harryhausen's.
(GASPS)
Harryhausen's?!
But it's impossible to
get a reservation there!
Not for Googley Bear.
I will see you
at quitting time
and not a minute later.
Okay, sweetheart.
Think romantical
thoughts.
♪ You and me ♪
♪ Me and you ♪
♪ Both of us together! ♪
You know, pal, she's the one.
That's it.
She is the one!
I'm happy for you.
Oh, and, uh,
thanks for hooking me up
with those reservations.
Oh, no problem.
They're under the
name Googley Bear.
Oh, good ide...
You know,
that wasn't very funny.
(GASPS)
What the...?
Wazowski!
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTS)
(CHUCKLING)
What do you know?
It scares little kids
and little monsters.
I wasn't scared.
I have... allergies.
(COUGHING)
Uh-huh. Sure.
Hey, Randall, save it for
the scare floor, will you?
I'm in the zone today,
Sullivan.
Going to be doing
some serious scaring.
Putting up some big numbers.
Wow, Randall.
That's great.
That should make it
even more humiliating
when we break the record first.
Ha, ha!
Shh, shh, shh,
shh, shh.
Do you hear that?
It's the winds of change.
(MOCKING VOICE): "You hear it?
You hear the winds of ch...?"
Oh, what a creep.
One of these days,
I am really...
going to let you
teach that guy a lesson.
(DEEP CROAKING)
(LIQUID SQUISHING)
Chalooby! Baby!
MIKE:
Good morning, Roz
my succulent
little garden snail.
And who would
we be scaring today?
Wazowski, you didn't file
your paperwork last night.
Oh, that darn paperwork.
Wouldn't it be easier
if it all just blew away?
(CHAIR SQUEAKING)
Don't let it happen again.
Yes, well, I'll, uh...
I'll try to be less careless.
I'm watching you, Wazowskl.
Always watching.
Whoo! She's nuts.
Always!
CELIA (OVER PA):
All scare floors are now active.
Assistants, please report
to your stations.
(METALLIC CLUNK)
(MACHINE BEEPS, BELL DINGS)
(BELL DINGS)
(CLANKING AND WHIRRING)
(CHIME RINGS)
Okay, people, eastern seaboard
coming on-line.
We got scarers coming out!
(DRAMATIC BRASS FANFARE
PLAYING)
Ooh, they're
so awesome.
(KNUCKLES CRACKING)
(CLANGING AND GROWLING)
(SNARLS)
(BLOWING)
(GROWLING)
Hey... may
the best monster win.
I plan to.
(BELL RINGING)
We are on in seven... six...
five... four... three...
two...
(HORN BLARING)
(GROWLS)
You're the boss.
You're the big,
hairy boss.
(CHILD SCREAMING)
(BELL DINGS)
Oh, I'm feeling good today,
Mikey!
Yeah!
MIKE:
Whoa!
Attaboy.
Another door coming right up.
(WHIRRING AND CLANKING)
(CHILD SCREAMING)
(BELL DINGS)
(GROWLING)
You're still behind,
Randall.
You know, maybe I should realign
the scream intake valve.
Just get me
another door!
A door! Yes, door!
(CHILD SCREAMING)
(BELL DINGS)
(BELLS DINGING)
(BEEPING)
(METALLIC CLANKING)
(CLICK AND HISS)
(CHILDREN SCREAMING)
(BELLS DINGING)
Well, Jerry, what's
the damage so far?
We may actually
make our quota today, sir.
Hmm. First time
in a month.
(GURGLING AND BURPING)
Huh?!
(DOOR BUZZING)
(SCREAMING AND SOBBING)
What happened?
The kid almost
touched me!
She got this close
to me!
She wasn't
scared of you?
She was only six!
I could've been dead!
I could've died!
Keep it together, man.
(WHISTLING)
Hey! We got a dead
door over here!
...We're coming!
...Coming!
...Look out!
...Out of the way!
...Coming through!
...Excuse us.
(WHIMPERING)
We've lost 58 doors
this week, sir.
Oh, kids these days.
They just don't get
scared like they used to.
Let her rip!
(BUZZING)
(METALLIC CLANK)
(EERIE BLUBBERING)
(CHILD SCREAMING)
(BELL DINGS)
Uh, sir?
What?!
Look.
CELIA (OVER PA):
Attention.
WE HAVE A NEW SCARE LEADER:
Randall Boggs.
(SNICKERING)
(ASSISTANTS CHEERING)
(CHILDREN SCREAMING)
(KNUCKLES CRACKING)
Slumber party.
(LAUGHING)
Whoo!
(BEEPING)
CELIA (OVER PA):
Never mind.
Hey! Watch it!
(SULLEY LAUGHING)
Well, James, that was
an impressive display!
Oh, just doing my job,
Mr. Waternoose.
Of course, I did
learn from the best.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
If I don't see a new door at
my station in five seconds
I will personally put you
through the shredder!
(SCREAMS)
Hey, Wazowski, nice job!
Those numbers
are pretty sweet.
Are they?
You know,
I hadn't even noticed.
And, uh...
how is Georgie doing?
He's doing great!
I love working
with that big guy.
(CHILD SCREAMING)
Keep the doors coming,
Charlie.
I'm on a roll today.
George and I
are like brothers.
(GASPING)
2319! We have a 2319!
(ALARM BLARING)
COMPUTER VOICE (OVER PA):
Red alert! Red alert!
Red alert! Red alert! Red alert!
FEMALE (OVER PA):
George Sanderson
please remain motionless.
Prepare for decontamination.
Get it off!
JERRY:
Duck and cover, people!
Oh, not the CDA.
(SIREN WAILING)
CDA AGENT:
Move! Move! Move!
Coming through, please.
Stand aside.
CDA AGENT 2:
Clear the contaminated area.
(SCREAMS)
CDA AGENT:
This is a 2319 in progress.
Keep the area clear.
Coming through.
Watch yourself.
(GRUNTS)
(WHIMPERING)
Stand back.
Careful.
(METALLIC CLANG)
(DRILLS WHIRRING)
(ALL GASPING)
(MUFF
ED EXPLOSION)
(DRILLS WHIRRING)
All clear.
Situation is niner-niner-zero.
Ready for decon.
Hey, thanks, guys.
That was a close one.
Okay.
(SHEARS BUZZING)
(SCREAMING)
(WHIMPERING)
(RIPPING)
(SCREAMING)
JERRY:
Okay, people, take a break!
We got to shut down
for a half-hour
and reset the system.
An entire scare floor
out of commission.
What else can go wrong?
Oh... what a day.
We're just going through
a rough time, sir.
Everyone knows you're going
to get us through it.
Tell that to the
board of directors.
(SLURPING)
James, this company
has been in my family
for three generations.
I would do anything to
keep it from going under.
Oh, so would I, sir.
Well...
Say, I could use your help
with something.
Anything, sir.
You see, we've hired
some new scare recruits
and frankly, they're...
they're, um... uh...
Inexperienced?
Oh, they stink!
Uh-huh.
And I thought maybe
you might come by tomorrow
and give them a demonstration.
Show them what it takes
to be a top scarer, huh?
I'll start out with the old
Waternoose jump-and-growl.
(GROWLING LOUDLY)
Ha! Oh, oh, yes!
Now, that's my boy!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(RINGING)
JERRY:
Let's go, everybody!
All doors must be returned!
No exceptions!
...Oh, yeah.
...Whoo!
I've never seen anything
like you today.
You were on
a roll, my man.
Another day like this
and that scare record's
in the bag.
That's right, baby!
Uh-huh.
So get this...
As if dinner wasn't enough
I'm taking her to a monster
truck rally afterwards.
Nice.
What's on your agenda?
I'm going to head home
and work out some more.
Again? You know, there's
more to life than scaring.
(SNIFF'
NG)
Whew. Hey, can I
borrow your odorant?
Yeah. I got, uh...
smelly garbage or old dumpster.
You got low tide?
No.
How about wet dog?
Yep. Stink it up.
(GROWLING)
You know, I am so romantic
sometimes I think
I should just marry myself.
Give me a
break, Mike.
What a night of romance
I got ahead of me.
Tonight is about me
and Celia.
Ooh, the love boat
is about to set sail.
(IMITATING SHIP HORN)
'Cause I got
to tell you, buddy
that face of hers,
it just makes my heart go...
Yikes!
Hello, Wazowskl.
Fun-filled evening
planned for tonight?
Well, as a
matter of fact...
Then I'm sure you
filed your paperwork
correctly... for once.
Your stunned silence
is very reassuring.
Oh, no. My scare reports...
i left them on my desk
and if I'm not at the restaurant
in five minutes
they're going to give
our table away!
What am I going to tell...
Schmoopsie-poo.
Hey, Googley Bear.
Want to get going?
Do I ever!
It's just that...
What?
Uh, you know,
there's a small...
I don't understand.
It's just that I forgot
about some paperwork
I was supposed to file.
Mike was reminding me.
Thanks, buddy.
Whoo.
I was? I mean, I was!
Yeah, I was.
Oh, okay.
Let's go then.
We're going!
On my desk, Sulley.
The pink copies
go to Accounting
the fuchsia ones
go to Purchasing
and goldenrod ones
go to Roz.
Huh!
Leave the puce.
SULLEY: Pink copies go to Accounting,
the fuchsia ones go to Roz.
No, fuchsia ones
go to Purchasing.
The goldenrod ones go to Roz.
Man, I have no idea
what puce is.
Oh, that's puce.
Hmm?
Uh, hello?
Anyone?
There's a door here.
Hmm.
(DOOR LATCH CLICKING)
(DOOR CREAKING)
(WHISPERING):
Hello?
Hey.
Psst.
Anybody scaring in here?
Hello?
Yo!
Hmm.
(THUMP)
(SPEAKING BABY TALK)
(SCREAMS)
Whoa! Ah! Ah!
Oh!
(GIGGLING):
Here.
Gotcha!
(YELLS)
(SQUEALS IN DELIGHT)
Eh!
(GIGGLING)
(YELLS)
(GIGGLES)
(GASPS, THEN WHIMPERS)
(SQUEALS IN DELIGHT)
(GIGGLING)
(LAUGHS)
Oh!
(LOUD CRASHING, TOY SQUEAKING)
Yeow!
(GASPS)
(TOY DUCKS QUACKING)
(YELLING)
(QUACKING)
Eww.
(TOY DUCKS QUACKING)
(SIGHS)
(YELLS)
(PANTING)
(TOYS QUACKING AND SQUEAKING)
(SQUEAKING)
Whew.
(SULLEY SCREAMS)
(LITTLE GIRL
SPEAKING BABY TALK)
Kitty!
(SPEAKING BABY TALK)
No, no... stay back.
(STUTTERS IN FEAR)
(GIGGLING)
(SPEAKING BABY TALK)
(WHINE OF DISGUST)
(LITTLE GIRL
SPEAKING BABY TALK FAINTLY)
(WHIMPERS)
(DOOR LATCH CLICKING)
Hmm.
(SPEAKING BABY TALK)
(FAINT SQUEAL
OF DELIGHT)
(SNEEZES)
(MURMUR OF CONVERSATION)
(KNIVES BEING SHARPENED)
PHOTOGRAPHER:
And hold it.
(SHUTTER CLICKS)
ALL:
Get a paper bag!
Mmm.
(LAUGHING)
Oh, Michael, I've had
a lot of birthday...
well, not a
lot of birthdays
but this is the
best birthday ever.
Hmm.
What are you
looking at?
I was just thinking
about the first time
I laid eye on you...
How pretty you looked.
Stop it!
Your hair was
shorter then.
Mm-hmm. I'm thinking
about getting it cut.
(FAINT SQUEAL OF FEAR)
No, no, I like
it this length.
(SIGHS OF RELIEF)
I like everything
about you.
Just the other day
someone asked me who I thought
the most beautiful monster was
in all of Monstropolis.
You know what I said?
What did you say?
I said...
...Sulley?
No! No, no.
That's not
what I was going to say.
Mike, you're not making sense.
SULLEY:
Hi, guys!
What a coincidence,
running into you here!
Uh, I'm just going
to order something to go.
Michael...
Sulley!
I wonder what's good here.
Get out of here.
You're ruining everything.
I went back to get
your paperwork
and there was a door.
What?
(RATTLING)
A door?!
Randall was in it.
Wait a minute.
Randall?
That cheater!
He's trying
to boost his numbers!
There's something else.
What?!
Ook-lay in the ag-bay.
Look in the bag.
What bag?
(SIGHS)
(GASPS)
(GIGGLING)
Oh!
They don't have
anything I like here.
So take care, Celia!
Excuse me, sir.
What's going on?
Celia, please try
to understand.
I have to do something!
Michael?
PHOTOGRAPHER:
On three.
One... two...
(SQUEALS AND GIGGLES)
(SCREAMING)
A kid!
Boo!
(ALL SCREAMING)
A kid!
There's a kid here...
A human kid!
(EXCLAIMING IN BABY TALK)
Oh!
CELIA:
Googley Bear!
(YELLING)
(BLOWS RASPBERRY)
Come on!
(MONSTERS SCREAMING IN TERROR)
MIKE:
Let's get out of here!
CDA HELICOPTER PILOT:
Please remain calm.
This is not a drill.
(SIREN WAILING,
TIRES SCREECHING)
CDA AGENT 1:
We have an 835 in progress.
Please advise.
Michael? Michael?
Oh, Celia.
...Please come with me.
...Ow. Stop pushing.
Hey, get your hands off
my Schmoopsie-poo!
Building clear.
Ready for decontamination.
Well, I don't think that date
could have gone any worse.
(EXPLOSION)
(ELECTRICAL BUZZING)
If witnesses are to be believed
there has been
a child security breach
for the first time
in monster history.
We can neither confirm nor deny
the presence of a human child
here tonight.
Well, a kid flew right over me
and blasted a car
with its laser vision!
I tried to run from it,
but it picked me up
with its mind powers
and shook me like a doll!
It's true!
I saw the whole thing!
It is my
professional opinion
that now is the time
to... panic!
Oh-oh.
(BOTH YELLING)
Oh, it's coming!
It's coming!
(GIGGLING):
Boo!
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(DISTANT SIRENS WAILING)
(DELIGHTED CRY)
(YELLING)
No, no, no, no, no!
Come here, kid.
Whee.
No, don't touch those,
you little...!
Oh, now
those were alphabetized.
It's okay, it's all right.
As long as it doesn't
come near us
we're going to be okay.
(SNEEZES)
(SCREAMS)
(YELLING IN PAIN)
(WHIMPERING IN FEAR)
Wanna ride on it!
Da, da-da.
Da-da-da.
Oh, y-you like this?
Fetch!
(GIGGLES)
(GASPS)
Hey, hey, that's it!
No one touches
little Mikey!
(WHINING)
Mike, give her the bear.
Oh, no.
(PIERCING SCREAM)
(ELECTRICAL BUZZING)
(SCREAMING AND CRYING
CONTINUE)
(BUZZING CONTINUES)
(EXCLAIMING IN FEAR)
Make it stop, Sulley!
Make it stop!
Look!
See the bear?
Ooh, nice bear.
(SCREAMS)
Sulley!
See?
Ooh, bear, ooh.
Oh, he's
a happy bear.
♪ He's not crying,
neither should you ♪
♪ Or we'll be
in trouble ♪
♪ 'Cause they're gonna find us ♪
♪ So please stop crying ♪
♪ Right now. ♪
Good, good, Sulley.
Keep it up.
You're doing great.
♪ Ooh, the happy bear,
he has no... ♪
(SCREAMING)
She touched me!
Sulley, the bear!
The bear!
Give her the...
Whoa!
(GIGGLES)
(SCREAMING WITH LAUGHTER)
(ELECTRICAL BUZZING
GROWS LOUDER)
(LIGHT BULB SHATTERS)
(GIGGLES)
What was that?
(THUMPING)
I have no idea
but it would be
really great
if it didn't
do it again.
(GIGGLES)
Shh, shh, shh.
Shh...
shh.
Ah!
How could I do this?
How could I be so stupid?
This could destroy
the company.
The company?
Who cares
about the company?!
What about us?
That thing is
a killing machine!
♪ La-la-la-la-la-la ♪
I bet it's just waiting
for us to fall asleep
and then wham!
Oh, we're easy prey,
my friend... easy prey.
We're sitting targets.
Okay, look, I think
I have a plan here.
Using mainly spoons, we dig
a tunnel under the city
and release it into the wild.
Spoons.
That's it, I'm out of ideas.
We're closed.
Hot air balloon?
Too expensive.
Giant slingshot?
Too conspicuous.
Enormous wooden horse?
Too Greek!
(SPEAKING BABY TALK)
No plan. No plan.
Can't think.
Flatlining.
Uh, Mike?
I think she's getting tired.
Well, then
why don't you
find someplace
for it to sleep?
While I think of a plan!
Are you sleepy?
You want to sleep?
Is that what you want?
Huh?
(CRUNCHING)
Okay, all right.
I'm making a nice little area
for you to...
(GIGGLING)
No. Hey, hey,
that's my bed!
You're going to get
your germs all over it.
(SIGHING):
Fine.
My chair is
more comfortable anyway.
(YELLS)
What?
(SPEAKING FEARFULLY)
it's just a closet.
Will you go to sleep?
Hey, that looks like Randall.
Randall's your monster.
You think he's going
to come through the closet
and scare you.
Oh, boy, how do I explain this?
Uh, it's empty.
...See?
...Ah!
No monster in here.
Well, now there is
but I'm not going to scare you.
I'm off-duty.
Okay.
How about I sit here,
until you fall asleep?
Go ahead.
Go to sleep.
Now.
Now... go.
Uh, you...
go...
to...
sleep.
(IMITATING SNORING)
(GIGGLES)
(SIGHS IN RELIEF)
(DOOR CREAKS SOFTLY)
Hey, Mike,
this might sound crazy
but I don't think
that kid's dangerous.
Really? Well, in that case,
let's keep it.
I always wanted a pet
that could kill me!
Now, look.
What if we just put
her back in her door?
What?
Mike, think about it.
If we send her back,
it's like it never happened.
Everything goes back to normal.
Is that a joke?
Tell me you're joking.
Sulley, I'd like to think
that, given the circumstances
I have been extremely
forgiving up to now
but that is a horrible idea!
What are we going to do?
March right out into
public with that thing?
Then I guess we just waltz
right up to the factory, right?
I can't believe we are waltzing
right up to the factory.
Sulley, a mop, a couple of
lights and some chair fabric
are not going
to fool anyone!
Just think about
a few names, will you?
Loch Ness, Bigfoot,
the Abominable Snowman...
They all got one thing
in common, pal... banishment.
We could be next!
Don't panic...
We can do this.
Hey, how you doing, Frank?
Hey, guys.
Everything's going
to be okay.
(GASPING)
(EQUIPMENT BUZZING LOUDLY)
Number One wants this place
dusted for prints.
Careful with that.
I got a good view from here.
A little lower.
This was recovered
at the scene.
Don't panic.
Don't panic!
Don't tell me
not to panic.
Just keep it together.
Everything is not okay!
LITTLE GIRL:
Boo.
...could be contaminated.
Gentlemen, safety
is our number one concern.
If there's anything that...
not now, not now.
Oh, hello, little one.
Where did you come from?
Mr. Waternoose!
Ah, James!
Is this one yours?
Actually, that's my, uh,
cousin's sister's daughter, sir.
Yeah, it's, uh...
"Bring an Obscure
Relative to Work Day."
Hmm, must have missed the memo.
Well, listen, James
why don't you stop by
the simulator after lunch today
and give us
that scare demonstration
we talked about, huh?
Oh, oh, sir, uh...
Excuse me,
Mr. Waternoose?
Yes, yes, I'm coming.
All right then, I'll see
you this afternoon, James.
That is, if these gentlemen
haven't shut us down.
Oh, boy.
Oh, a scare demo.
Well, that is great.
Why am I
the last to know?
We can bring your cousin's
sister's daughter along.
She'II be a big hit!
(EQUIPMENT BUZZING LOUDLY)
Halt!
(YELLING)
Stop him!
Hold him down.
Come on,
the coast is clear.
Okay, all we have to do
is get rid of that thing.
So, wait here while
I get its card key.
But she can't stay here.
This is the men's room.
That is the weirdest thing
you have ever said.
It's fine. It's okay.
Look, it loves it here!
It's dancing with joy!
Uh, uh, uh, uh.
I'll be right back
with its door key.
(LAUGHS)
That's a cute little
dance you've got.
It almost looks
like you've got to...
(WHINING)
Oh.
(SINGING IN BABY TALK)
(SINGING STOPS)
Uh, are you
done in there?
(SQUEALS)
Ah! Sorry. Sorry.
(SINGING)
(TOILET FLUSHES)
Okay, you
finished now, right?
Hello?
(YELLS)
Boo.
(GIGGLES)
(SIGHS)
(GIGGLING)
(CHUCKLES)
Where did she go?
Oh, did she disappear?
Did she turn invisible?
(GIGGLING SOFTLY)
I just have no idea.
Gotcha!
Boo.
(GIGGLES)
Hey, you're good.
(SIGHS)
Be relaxed,
be relaxed, be relaxed.
Roz, my tender,
oozing blossom
you're looking
fabulous today.
Is that a new haircut?
Come on, tell me.
It's a new haircut,
isn't it?
That's got to be
a new haircut.
New makeup?
You've had a lift.
You've had a tuck.
You've had something.
Something has been
inserted in your skin
that makes you look like...
(SIGHS)
Listen, I need a favor.
Randall was working
late last night
out on the scare floor.
I really need the key
for the door he was using.
Well, isn't that nice?
But guess what?
You didn't turn in
your paperwork last night.
He didn't... I...
no paperwork?
This office is now closed.
(MIKE SCREAMS IN PAIN)
Ready or not, here I come!
I'm getting warmer.
Any second now.
Fee fi fo...
What are you doing?!
I-I'm looking
for the kid.
You lost it?!
No, no, she was just...
(SQUEALS)
Here she is.
(WHINING)
Hey, what's the matter?
RANDALL: I already told your
buddies I haven't seen anything.
CDA AGENT:
All right, carry on.
(SPLASHING)
Randall!
Thank goodness!
What are we going to do
about the child?
Shh!
Shh, shh, shh.
(DOOR SLAMS OPEN)
The front page!
It's on the front page.
The child...
The one you were after.
Will you be quiet?!
Don't you think I'm aware
of the situation?
I was up all night
trying to find it.
I did a simple
calculation
factoring in the size
of the sushi restaurant.
The child
may have escaped!
Yeah, well, until
we know for sure
we're going to act like nothing
happened, understand?
You just get the machine
up and running.
I'll take care of the kid.
And when I find whoever
let it out, they're dead!
Oh!
Why are you still here?
Come on, go!
Move! Now!
FUNGUS:
Ow, ow! I'm not here.
SULLEY (WHISPERING):
They're gone.
(SQUEAKING AND SPLASHING)
LITTLE GIRL:
Eww.
MIKE:
This is bad.
This is so very bad.
What were they talking
about a machine?
Who cares? Oh!
Look, don't panic...
All we have to do
is call her door down
and send her home.
You're right,
you're right.
We're just two regular joes
on our way to work.
We will blend right in.
Top of the mornin', fellas!
Hey, what's
shakin', bacon?
Did you lose weight?
Or a limb?
You have
her card key, right?
Of course
I have her card key.
I told you
I'd get her card key.
I went and got
her card key
and now I have her card key.
Okay, here we go.
Take care of yourself.
Try not to run
through any more closets.
(GIGGLES)
Mike, that's
not her door.
What are you
talking about?
Of course it's her door.
It's her door.
No, her door was white
and it had flowers on it.
No. It must have been
dark last night
because this is its door.
(POLKA MUSIC PLAYING)
Hey, you hear that?
Sounds like
fun in there!
Okay, send me a postcard, kid.
That's Mike Wazowski, care of
22 Mike-Wazowski-
you-got-your-life-back lane.
Mowki Kowskl.
Very good.
Now bon voyage!
Bye-bye!
Come on.
Look at the stick.
See the stick?
Go get the stick!
Go fetch.
Mike, this isn't
Boo's door.
Boo? What's Boo?
That's what I decided
to call her.
Is there a problem?
Sulley, you're not
supposed to name it.
Once you name it, you start
getting attached to it!
Now put that thing
back where it came from,
or so help me...
Oh, hey!
We're rehearsing a scene
for the upcoming company play
called Put That Thing
Back Where It Came From
Or So Help Me%
(MIKE LAUGHING)
It's a musical!
♪ Put that thing back where
it came from or so help me ♪
♪ Bom-bom, bom-bom,
bom-bom... ♪
♪ So help me,
so help me. ♪
And cut!
We're still
working on it.
It's a work
in progress
but, hey,
we need ushers.
Sulley, I've had enough.
Now say good-bye to...
where'd it go?
What'd you do with it?
(GASPS):
Where is she?
I don't believe it.
She got away
from you again?!
Well, that is just...
Wait a minute.
The sun is coming up.
This is perfect!
She's gone!
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Where are you going?
Sulley, please,
don't blow this.
Not when we're so close
to breaking the record.
Somebody else
will find the kid.
It'll be their problem,
not ours!
She's out of our hair!
What are you
two doing?
They're rehearsing a play.
♪ She's out of our hair! ♪
Can it, Wazowski!
So, what do you think of that
kid getting out, Sullivan?
Pretty crazy, huh?
Oh, yeah, crazy.
Word on the street is the kid's
been traced back
to this factory.
You haven't seen anything,
have you?
Uh, well, uh...
No, no way!
But if it was
an inside job
I'd put my money
on Waxford.
Waxford?
Yeah, the one
at station six.
You know, he's got
them shifty eyes.
Hey, Waxford!
Sulley!
CELIA:
Michael Wazowski!
(WHIMPERS)
last night was one
of the worst nights
of my entire life,
bar none!
(HISSING)
I thought
you cared about me.
Honey, please.
Schmoopsie, I thought
you liked sushl.
CELIA:
Sushi? Sushi?!!
You think this is
about sushi?!
Wazowski!
Michael! Mike...
Men.
(PANTING)
Breathe. Keep breathing.
Whew.
Yikes!
Where's the kid?
Kid? What kid?
It's here in
the factory, isn't it?
You're not
pinning this on me.
It never would
have gotten out
if you hadn't been
cheating last night!
Cheating?
Cheating. Right.
Okay, I think I know how
to make this all go away.
What happens when the whistle
blows in five minutes?
Uh... I get a time-out?
Everyone goes to lunch!
Which means the scare floor
will be...?
Painted?
Empty! It'll be
empty, you idiot!
You see that clock?
When the big hand
is pointing up
and the little hand
the kid's door
will be in my station.
But when the big hand
points down
the door will be gone.
You have until then
to put the kid back.
Get the picture?
(ROARING PLAYFULLY)
Boo!
(GIGGLES)
No.
Hey, you! Halt!
He's the one.
The one from
the commercial!
Affirmative.
That's him.
Can we get
an autograph?
Oh, oh, sure.
No problem.
You can make that out
to Bethany, my daughter.
Yes. Let's see...
"From your scary friend
best wishes..."
So I said,
"If you talk to me
like that again,
we're through!"
What'd she say?
You know my mom.
She sent me to my room.
See you guys later,
take it easy.
Bottoms up!
(GASPS IN HORROR)
No!
(SINGING)
Whoa!
Hey.
(GROWLING)
Oh, well, hello, there.
What's your name?
Mike Wazowski!
(MACHINERY POUNDING LOUDLY)
(GRINDING AND CHOPPING)
(PANTING)
(MOANS)
Sulley!
Oh, Sulley.
Okay, Sulley, come on, enough.
Hey, you guys seen
Sulley anywhere?
Nope. Sorry.
Oh, Sulley!
Boy, Wazowski looks
like he's in trouble.
(SQUEAKING AND QUACKING)
2319!
We have a 2319!
Oh, dear.
Get him!
Sulley? Sulley!
(MOANING)
Sulley!
Oh, great news, pal.
I got us a way out of this mess
but we got to hurry.
Where is it?
(WHIMPERING)
Sull, that's
a cube of garbage.
(SQUEAKS)
Uh-oh.
I-I can still hear
her little voice.
BOO:
Mike Wazowski!
Hey, I can hear her, too.
BABY MONSTERS:
Mike Wazowski!
How many kids
you got in there?
Mike Wazowski!
Kitty!
Boo!
Boo, oh,
you're all right!
I was so worried!
Don't you ever run away from me
again, young lady!
Oh, but I'm so glad
you're safe.
My, what an affectionate father.
Actually, she's
my cousin's sister's...
Okay, Sulley.
That's enough.
Let's go.
Mike Wazowski!
Yeah, yeah.
Step aside, kid.
We're in a...
(SCREAMS IN PAIN)
(SCREAMS WITH LAUGHTER)
(ELECTRICAL BUZZING)
(LIGHT BULBS SHATTERING)
(GASPING)
(BABY MONSTERS SCREAMING
AND CRYING)
Will you stop
making Boo laugh?
I didn't, so come on!
(SCREAMING AND CRYING
CONTINUE)
I still don't understand.
You've got Boo's door?
I'll explain later.
Run.
Okay, let's move,
let's move, let's move.
Come on.
Oh, please be there, please
be there, please be there.
There it is!
Just like Randall said!
Randall?
What a minute.
(CRIES OUT IN FEAR)
Oh, hey.
One, two, three, four!
Get the kid back
through the door!
Hey, hey.
We're going to get
our lives back.
The nightmare is over.
Hey, it's okay, Boo.
What's the matter?
Come on, it's time to move!
Mike, what are you thinking?
We can't trust Randall.
He's after Boo.
Who cares?
Let's go.
This is a limited time offer.
No, no.
I don't like this.
Look, Sulley, you wanted
her door and there it is.
Now, let's move.
No, Mike.
(SIGHS): You want me to prove
everything's on the up-and-up?
Fine! He wants the door,
I get the door...
(WHISPERING):
Mike, wait!
He's a paranoid delusional
furball.
Mike!
(WHIMPERS IN FEAR)
(WHINING)
Shh, shh, shh.
(SMALL CRY OF SURPRISE)
(LUNCH BELL RINGS)
Hey, Sulley,
where you been all day?
Sulley? Sulley?
Huh?
(WHISPERING):
Mike?
Where are you?
You in there?
Where are you, buddy?
Mike?
Hey.
(DOOR THUNKS)
(EXCITED BABY TALK)
Boo, way to go.
(GIGGLES)
It's okay.
(DOOR CLUNKS SHUT)
(PIPES WHISTLING AND VENTING)
(DISTANT VOICES)
RANDALL:
Yes! I got the kid!
FUNGUS:
Oh, huzzah!
That's great news.
Not that I was concerned,
of course.
Just get over
here and help me!
Come on, come
on, come on.
While we're young
here, Fungus!
(BOTH STRAINING)
Kid needs to take
off a few pounds.
(YELPS)
Wazowski?!
Where is it,
you little one-eyed cretin?
Okay, first of all,
it's cree-tin.
If you're going
to threaten me
do it properly.
Second of all, you're nuts
if you think kidnapping me
is going to help you cheat
your way to the top!
(CHUCKLING EVILLY)
You still think this is about
that stupid scare record?
Well... I did, right up
until you chuckled like that
and now I'm thinking
I should just get out of here.
I am about to revolutionize
the scaring industry
and when I do, even
the great James P. Sullivan
is going to be
working for me.
MIKE:
Well
somebody's certainly
been a busy bee.
First, I need to know
where the kid is
and you're going
to tell me.
Yeah, I don't
know anything.
Uh-huh, sure.
MIKE:
I don't.
I mean, I don't.
Oh-oh.
(MECHANICAL CLANGING
AND GRINDING)
What's that?
Come on.
Wait, wait, wait.
Oh-oh. Oh-oh.
Oh, come on.
No, no, no, no, no.
Come on,
hey, hey, hey.
This thing is moving.
I don't like big...
moving things that are
moving towards me.
No! Come on!
Hey, Randall!
Say hello
to the scream extractor.
Hello.
Come on,
where you going?
We'll talk.
Come on,
we'll have a latte!
Come on.
We can talk
about this.
(ELECTRICAL WHIRRING STARTS,
THEN GROWS LOUDER)
What's that thing?
What is that thing?
Wait, wait, wait!
Stop, stop!
No, no!
Come on, hey!
(DEEP, RESONATING WHIRRING)
Help! Help! Help!
Help!
(YELLING)
(NOISE DIES AWAY)
Oh, for...
What did you
do wrong this time?
I don't know.
I calibrated the drive...
Go check the machine!
There must be something wrong
with the scream intake valve.
That's the problem
with these 3250 units...
Huh?
Hmm.
Psst!
Fungus.
You like cars, huh?
'Cause I got a really nice car.
If you let me go,
I'll give you...
a ride in the car.
Please, Fungus?
I'm sorry, Wazowski,
but Randall said
I'm not allowed to fraternize
with victims of his evil plot.
(GASPS)
(CLANGING)
Hmm...
(ZAPPING)
(ELECTRICAL WHIRRING)
(CLANKING, RATTLING, WHIRRING)
(GASPS)
(MUFF
ED SCREAMS)
What happened?
Where's Wazowski?
(MUFF
ED SCREAMS)
(SHUTS OFF MACHINE)
Where is he?!
(WHIMPERING)
(GROWLS)
(SQUEALS)
Come on!
This is crazy.
He's going to kill us!
CDA AGENT 1: Careful.
That could be contaminated.
We got to get out of here now!
We can start a whole new life
somewhere far away.
Good-bye, Monsters, Inc.!
Good-bye, Mr. Waternoose!
No, Mike, wait!
Hey, what are you doing?
Follow me. I have an idea.
No! No, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no...
COMPUTER VOICE (OVER PA):
Simulation terminated.
WATERNOOSE:
No, no, no, no, no.
What was that?
You're trying to scare the kid,
not lull it to sleep.
I was going for a
snake ninja approach
with a little hissing.
(HISSES)
How many times
do I have to tell you?
It's all about presence!
About how you enter the room!
Mr. Waternoose!
James! Perfect timing.
No, no. Sir, you
don't understand.
Ah, now, show these monsters
how it's done.
What? No, no,
I can't...
Sir...
sir, you have
to listen to me.
Pay attention, everyone.
You're about to see
the best in
the business.
Reset the simulator.
But-but, sir!
MOTHER:
Good night, sweetheart.
ANIMATRONIC BOY:
Night, Mom.
Kitty!
No, Boo, no, no!
Now, give us a big, loud roar.
Mr. Waternoose,
there's no time for this.
Come on. What are you
waiting for? Roar!
But-but-but, sir!
Roar!
(GROANS)
(ROARING FEROCIOUSLY)
(SHRIEKING IN TERROR)
(GASPS)
(ROARING FEROCIOUSLY)
(SQUEALS)
(BOO CRYING)
(STUDENTS APPLAUDING)
WATERNOOSE:
Well done.
Well done, James.
Boo?
...All right, gentlemen, I hope you've
learned... Right this way, everyone.
...a valuable lesson
in scaring today.
(FEARFUL WHIMPER)
(WHINES SOFTLY)
Boo.
(NERVOUS GRUNT)
(WHINING)
Boo?
(PANICKED GRUNTS)
(DOOR SLAMS)
Boo, it's me.
(SQUEALING)
(GASPS):
The child!
Sir, she isn't toxic.
I know it sounds
crazy, but trust me.
Boo?
No, no, no, no.
It's okay.
I was just...
(WHIMPERING IN FEAR)
No, no, no, no, no,
don't be scared.
That wasn't real.
It's just a...
I was just...
(CRYING):
No...
(BOO CONTINUES CRYING)
(BOO SOBBING)
Boo.
MIKE: ...and he was
going to test it out
on that sweet,
little girl.
...Boo.
...Now that we have her...
...he is trying
to kill us.
This whole thing
is Randall's fault.
Randall?
Yes. And we can take you to his
secret lab, which is right here
in this factory.
How could this happen?
Oh, how could this happen?
Does anyone else
know about this?
No, sir.
Good.
This company can't afford
any more bad publicity.
Now, before we do
anything else, let's...
take care of the child.
Oh, I never thought things
would come to this...
not in my factory.
I'm sorry you boys
got mixed up in this.
Especially you, James.
But now we can set
everything straight again
for the good of the company.
(WHIRRING)
(THUNK)
MIKE:
Uh...
sir, that's not her door.
I know, I know.
It's yours.
(STARTLED GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
(YELLING)
No!
(GASPS)
(VOICE ECHOING):
Boo!
(GASPS)
No! No!
No! No! No! No!
No!
(DESPERATE GRUNTS)
It's too late!
We're banished, genius.
We're in the human world!
Oh, what a great idea, going
to your old pal Waternoose!
Too bad he was in
on the whole thing!
All you had to do was listen
to me... just once!
But you didn't, did you?
You're still not listening!
(YELLING)
(SULLEY GRUNTING AND GROANING)
Take that!
(GROWLING)
(GASPS IN HORROR)
Welcome to the Himalayas!
(WIND GUSTING)
"Abominable"!
(CHUCKLES)
Can you believe that?
Do I look abominable to you?
Why can't they call me
the Adorable Snowman or...
or the Agreeable Snowman,
for crying out loud?
I'm a nice guy.
Snow cone?
Yuck.
No, no, no.
Don't worry...
It's lemon.
Uh, how about
you, big fella?
Snow cone?
Did you see the way she...
looked at me?
(SIGHS)
Ah, poor guy.
I understand.
It ain't easy
being banished.
Take my buddy, Bigfoot.
When he was banished
he fashioned an enormous diaper
out of poison ivy.
Wore it on his head
like a tiara.
Called himself King Itchy.
Ah, it won't be so hard for
you guys, though, you know.
I mean, how lucky
can you get?
Banished with your
best friend.
He is not my friend.
Oh. I just assumed you
were buddies, you know
when I saw you out
there in the snow
hugging and all that.
Look at that big jerk.
Ruined my life, and for what?
A stupid kid!
Because of you,
I am now stuck
in this frozen
wasteland!
Wasteland?
I think you mean wonderland!
I mean, how about
all this fabulous snow, huh?
Oh, and wait till you see
the local village.
Cutest thing in the world.
I haven't even mentioned
all the free yak's milk.
What... what did you say?
Yak's milk.
Milking a yak
ain't exactly a picnic.
You know, once you pick
the hairs out
it's very nutritious.
No, no. Something
about a village.
Where?
Are there kids in it?
Kids? Sure.
Tough kids, sissy kids,
kids who climb on rocks...
Where is it?!
It's at the bottom
of the mountain.
Around a three-day hike.
Oh, three days?!
We need to get there now!
(THUMP)
(DING)
You want to go to the village?
Okay, rule number one
out here.
Always...
No.
Never go out in a blizzard.
We need to get to Boo.
(GRUNTS, THEN GASPS)
Boo?!
What about us?
(GRUNTS)
Ever since that kid
came in
you've ignored
everything I've said
and now look where we are!
Oh, we were about
to break the record, Sulley.
We would have had it made!
None of that matters now.
None of it matter...
Wa-wait a second.
None of it matters?
(SIGHS)
MIKE:
Okay.
That's... no. Good. Great.
So, now the truth comes out,
doesn't it?
Oh, would you
look at that?
We're out of
snow cones, uh...
Let me... just go outside
and make some more.
Sulley, what about everything
we ever worked for?
Does that matter?
Huh?
And what about Celia?
I am never... never
going to see her again.
Doesn't that matter?
(SIGHS)
What about me?
I'm your pal.
I'm... I'm your best friend.
Don't I matter?
(SIGHS)
I'm sorry, Mike.
I'm sorry we're stuck out here.
I didn't mean
for this to happen.
But Boo's in trouble.
I think there might
be a way to save her
if we can just
get down to that...
"We"?
Whoa, whoa, whoa. "We"?
No.
There's no "we" this time, pal.
I-if-if you want
to go out there
and freeze to death
you be my guest...
because you're on your own.
♪ ♪
(WIND WHISTLES)
Hey, I got more snow cones!
Ohh!
Ahh!
(YELLS)
(GRUNTING AND GROANING)
(WIND HOWLING)
(DISTANT CHILD SCREAMING)
(CHILDREN SCREAMING)
Oh, come on, now, George.
I know you can do this.
I picked out an easy door
for you... in Nepal.
Nice, quiet Nepal.
You know, you're right.
Here, take this.
Go get 'em, Georgie!
Gangway! Look out!
Coming through!
Sorry, George.
Hey, you can't just...
(GASPS)
23...
(GAGGING)
(WHISTLING)
Out of the way!
...Hey!
...Whoa!
Don't!
(GASPS)
(WHIMPERS)
Finally!
I never should have
trusted you with this.
Because of you, I had
to banish my top scarer!
With this machine,
we won't need scarers.
Besides, Sullivan got
what he deserved.
Sullivan was twice the scarer
you will ever be!
(LOW GROWL)
(PANTING)
(CLANGING)
(GRUNTING)
(YELLS WITH EFFORT)
(MECHANICAL WHIRRING)
(GASPS)
Kitty!
(WHIRRING AND HISSING)
(YELLING)
(SHRIEKING)
(ROARING)
Kitty!
Sullivan?
(GRUNTING)
Wh-whoa!
Kitty!
Sorry, Boo.
Stop him!
(GROWLS)
Let's get you home.
(PANTING)
(BLOW LANDS)
Ooh!
WATERNOOSE:
Finish him off!
Oh! Ooh! Oh!
(CLANGING)
(THUNK)
You don't know how long
I've wanted to do
that, Sullivan.
(GRUNTS)
(CHUCKLES)
(PUNCHES LANDING)
Hah!
Ooh!
(SHRIEKS)
(PANTING)
Ooh!
Mike?!
Look, it's not that I
don't care about the kid.
Mike, you don't
understand.
Yes, I do. I was
just mad, that's all.
I needed some time to think.
But you shouldn't
have left me out there.
(THUMP)
I'm being attacked!
No, I'm not attacking you.
I'm trying to be honest.
Just hear me out.
You and I are a team.
Nothing is more important
than our friendship.
I-I-I know, kid.
He's too sensitive.
(GAGGING)
(WHINING CRY)
Come on, pal.
If you start crying,
I'm going to cry
and I'll never get through this.
I'm sorry
I wasn't there for you
but I am now.
Ow!
Sulley, I am baring
my soul here.
The least you could do
is pay attention!
(YELLS IN PAIN)
(SIGHS IN RELIEF)
Hey, look at that...
It's Randall! It's...
Oh.
Come on!
WATERNOOSE:
Get up!
There can't be
any witnesses.
There won't be.
I'm glad you came back, Mike.
Somebody's got take care
of you, you big hairball.
(CELIA SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING)
Ow!
Schmoopsie-poo,
I really can't talk.
Come on!
Michael, if you
don't tell me
what's going on right
now, we are through!
You hear me? Through!
Here's the truth.
You know the kid that they're
looking for... Sulley let her in.
We tried to
send her back
but Waternoose
had this secret plot
and now Randall's right behind
us and he's trying to kill us!
You expect me to believe that
pack of lies, Mike Wazowski?!
Mike Wazowski!
(STARTLED YELL)
I love you, Schmoopsie-poo!
RANDALL:
Move it! Look out, you...
Oh!
...idiot!
(HUFF'
NG)
Look out. Coming through,
here, coming through!
Make way. Move it!
Hurry up, hurry up.
There they are!
CELIA: (OVER PA) Attention,
employees: Randall Boggs
has just broken
the all-time scare record.
Huh?
No, I didn't.
Get out of my way!
(CLAMORING)
Go get 'em, Googley Bear!
(BOO SHRIEKS)
There it is!
RANDALL:
Get off my tail!
Let me through!
Sulley,
what are you doing?
Grab on, Mike!
Are you out of your...?
(SCREAMING)
(WHIRRING)
(MIKE WHIMPERING)
MIKE:
Sulley, what are we doing?
We have to get Boo's door
and find a station.
MIKE: What a plan...
simple, yet insane!
(GROWLS)
Whoa.
...(GASPS)
...Oh, boy.
Hold on!
(MIKE SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING)
(CLINKING)
Wow!
Don't look down!
(TEETH CHATTERING)
(RATTLING)
(STARTLED GASP)
(SCREAMING)
(SHRIEKING)
I'm gonna be sick.
I'm gonna be sick!
Whoa!
(SCREAMING)
Oh, no!
(CHUGGING AND CLANKING)
No!
Aah...
Boo's door?
There it is!
MIKE: How are we supposed
to get to it now?
Oh, it's a dead
end, Sulley!
(GASPS)
MIKE:
There he is.
Make her laugh.
What, Sulley?!
Just do it!
Oh... ow!
(LAUGHING)
(SQUEALING LAUGHTER)
(ENGINES STARTING)
SULLIVAN:
Get it open.
Here he comes.
Give me that kid!
(BIRDS TWITTERING)
(BOO GIGGLING)
Why couldn't we
get banished here?
Come on. We got to
find another door.
(GASPS)
Look, Boo's door!
(GRUNTING)
There he is!
Hurry up, hurry up!
Give me your hand.
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTS)
Come on, it slides,
it slides!
Ooh, right, right, right.
(PANTING)
(GASPS)
Jump!
I'm behind you!
Come on!
Hurry up! Keep moving!
Get inside!
Ooh! That was weird.
(GRUNTS)
Mike?
Oh, sorry, buddy.
(STUNNED MUMBLING)
(GROWLS)
(ELECTRONIC WHIRRING)
Oh!
I hope that hurt, lizard boy!
(LAUGHING)
Great job, buddy.
We lost him.
(SQUEALS)
Boo!
Ha, ha!
No!
(SCREAMING)
Nice working with you!
Get it open!
...I'm trying!
...Open the door!
Come on, get in here!
(BOO CRYING)
(GRUNTING)
Boo!
(PANTING)
There they are!
Sulley, what are you doing?
Sulley!
(SULLEY GRUNTS)
(MIKE GRUNTS)
(YELLS)
Looks like we caught
the express, pal.
Do you see them?
Straight ahead!
No...
(STIFLED CRY)
(GRUNTING NERVOUSLY)
Kitty!
Boo!
(YELLING)
(WHIMPERING)
RANDALL: Look at everybody's
favorite scarer now!
You stupid, pathetic waste!
(THUMP)
You've been number one
for too long, Sullivan.
Now your time is up!
And don't worry.
I'll take good care of the kid.
No!
(YELLING)
(BOO GRUNTING
AND RANDALL GAGGING)
(RANDALL GROANING)
(GAGGING)
(ROARING ANGRILY)
She's not scared
of you anymore.
(ROARS ANGRILY)
Looks like you're out of a job.
(GULPS)
All right, come on,
over the plate.
Let's see
the ol' stuff here, pal.
Come on, now, chuck him,
chuck him, baby. Hum, baby.
Hum, baby,
here's the pitch.
Wait, please, don't,
don't, don't!
No!
And he is...
out of here!
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
BOY: Mama,
another gator got in the house.
Another gator?!
Give me that shovel!
Come here!
(CLANGING, YELLING)
Get him, mama!
Get that gator!
Care to do the honors,
Mikey?
With pleasure.
(THUD)
(BABY TALK)
That's right, Boo.
You did it.
You beat him.
(RASPBERRY)
Come on.
Okay, Boo,
it's time to go home.
Take care of yourself,
and be a good girl, okay?
(GASPS)
Oh, no!
The power's out!
Make her laugh again.
All right, I got a move here.
It'll bring down the house.
Up...
(METALLIC CLANG)
(GROANS SOFTLY)
Oh, sorry, she didn't see that.
What?! What'd you do,
forget to check
if her stupid hood was up
ya big dope?!
(SINGSONG): Uncle Mike,
try not to yell in front of her.
You know we still need her
to laugh.
Right.
(LAUGHS)
Hey, Boo, just kidding. Look!
(GIBBERISH)
Funny, right? Huh?
See what the...
These are the jokes, kid.
Whoa!
What's happening?
SULLIVAN:
Hold on!
When the door lands
in this station, cut the power.
You'd have the child
and the criminals responsible
for this whole mess.
Great.
A welcoming committee!
What are we going to do?!
(ELECTRICAL HUMMING)
(CLANG)
This is the CDA.
Come out slowly
with the child
in plain sight.
Okay, okay.
You got us.
Here we are.
Here's the kid.
I'm cooperating.
But before you take us away,
I have one thing to say:
(GAGS)
Catch!
(ALL SHOUTING):
2319!
We have a toxic
projectile!
Halt! After the suspect!
Cover the area!
Bring in reinforcements!
WATERNOOSE:
Stop him!
(BOO SQUEAKS)
Come on.
Don't let them get away.
What...?!
No, wait, wait!
Come back!
He has the child!
(FRUSTRATED GROWL)
(BOO SQUEAKS)
Sullivan? Sullivan!
Give me the child!
Me not go!
Give her to me!
(PANTING)
(GRUNTS)
(METALLIC CREAKING)
WATERNOOSE: Open this door!
Open this door!
(GROWLING AND POUNDING)
Hey!
Sullivan!
(YELLS)
WATERNOOSE:
Don't do it.
(BEEP)
Come on.
Don't go in that room!
(YELLING)
I think we stopped him, Boo.
You're safe now.
You be a good girl, okay?
This has gone
far enough, James.
She's home now!
Just leave her alone!
I can't do that!
She's seen too much.
You both have.
It doesn't have to be this way.
I have no choice!
Times have changed.
Scaring isn't enough anymore.
But kidnapping children?!
I'll kidnap
a thousand children
before I let
this company die
and I'll silence anyone
who gets in my way!
No!
(CHILD@S VOICE):
Good night, Mom.
(WOMAN@S VOICE):
Good night, sweetheart.
Good night, Mom.
What, wh-what is this?!
What? Who? Huh?
COMPUTER: Simulation terminated.
Simulation terminated.
Well, I don't know
about the rest of you guys
but I spotted
several big mistakes.
But-but-but how-how did...?
How did...?
MIKE:
You know what?
Let's watch my favorite part
again... shall we?
(REPEATING): I'll kidnap a thousand
children before I let this company die.
What...? Wha...?
I'll kidnap
a thousand children before...
(BABY TALK)
Shh, shh, shh, shh!
Shh!
I'll get him.
All right,
come with us, sir.
Wh-what are
you doing?
Take your
hands off me!
You can't
arrest me!
I hope you're happy, Sullivan!
You've destroyed this company.
Monsters, Incorporated is dead!
Where will everyone
get their scream now?!
The energy crisis
will only get worse
because of you!
(LOUD CLANG)
Stay where you are.
Huh?
Number One
wants to talk to you.
Attention!
Hello, boys.
BOTH:
Roz?!
Two and a half years
of undercover work
were almost wasted
when you intercepted
that child, Mr. Sullivan.
Of course, without your help,
I never would have known
that this went all the way up
to Waternoose.
(BABY TALK)
(GASPS)
ROZ:
Now...
about the girl...
I just want to
send her home.
Very good.
(CHIMING TONES)
Bring me a door shredder.
What, you mean... you mean,
I can't see her again?
That's the way it has to be.
I'll give you
five minutes.
(WHIRRING HUM)
Well, so long, kid.
Mike Wazowski!
Yeah.
Ah, Boo,
it's been fun.
Go ahead.
Go grow up.
(DOOR CREAKING)
(SQUEALING IN DELIGHT)
(LAUGHING)
Uh-uh, B-Boo...?
(SPEAKING BABY TALK)
Um... Boo?
Oh, look at that.
Yeah, you know...
Oh, that's cute, yeah.
(BABY TALK)
Uh, Boo, um...
(SQUEAKING TOY)
Well, that's very nice.
(GIGGLING)
Come here, you!
(SQUEALS)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
♪ Oh, he's a happy bear... ♪
(GIGGLING)
(BABY TALK)
Nothing's coming
out of your closet
to scare you
anymore, right?
Mm...
Yeah.
Good-bye, Boo.
Kitty.
Kitty has to go.
♪ ♪
Boo!
(GASPS)
Kitty?
(MOTOR BUZZING LOUDLY)
(CLICKS OFF)
None of this
ever happened, gentlemen.
And I don't want to see
any paperwork on this.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Take him away.
(ALL MURMURING)
I bet we get
the rest of the day off.
You idiot!
They're going to shut down
the factory!
(ALL GASP)
I'm telling you, pal,
when that wall went up
you should have seen the look
on Waternoose's face.
Whoo-hoo! I hope we get
a copy of that tape.
Hey, you all right?
Come on, pal,
cheer up, we did it!
We got Boo home.
Ah, sure, we put the factory
in the toilet, and...
gee, hundreds of people
will be out of work now.
Not to mention the angry mob
that'll come after us
when there's no more power,
but, hey...
at least we had
some laughs, right?
Laughs...
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
(WIND BLOWING SOFTLY)
(DOOR QUIETLY CREAKS OPEN)
(BOY GASPS)
Hey, is this thing on?
Hello?
Testing, testing.
Hey, good evening.
How are you?
Nice to see you.
I tell you, it's good
to be here in... your room.
Where you from?
Never mind.
You're in
kindergarten, right?
Oh, I love kindergarten.
Best three years of my life.
Of my life.
But I love sports.
Dodgeball
was the best.
Oh, yeah.
I was the fastest one out there.
Course I was the ball.
But I...
was the ball, see?
All right.
(RUMBLING)
(RUMBLING GETS LOUDER)
(GURGLING)
Ah...
(HUGE BURP)
Ah?
(LAUGHING)
Hey, thanks a lot.
I'll be here all week.
Remember to tip your waitresses.
(GUFFAWING)
(RIPPLING GURGLE)
(BELL DINGS)
Great job, Mikey.
You filled your quota on
the first kid of the day.
Not bad, huh?
You know, only somebody
with perfect comedic timing
could produce this much energy
in one shot.
Uh-huh, and the fact
that laughter is
ten times more
powerful than scream
had nothing to do with it.
(CLEARS THROAT)
CELIA:
Oh, Googley Bear.
Come here, you.
Schmoopsie-poo!
Googley.
Whoa!
(SNAKES CHITTERING)
(MIKE GIGGLING)
Girls!
Girls, put...
Stop, stop, stop!
Michael,
you're such a charmer.
Hey, did you bring
the magazine?
They just delivered
a whole box.
Let me see it!
(LAUGHING)
Sulley and I
made the cover, right?
(WHISPERING):
I don't believe it.
(SYMPATHETICALLY):
Googley Bear...
I'm on the cover
of a magazine!
Ow!
(CHATTERING)
(JITTERING BLUBBERS)
Oh, this is great!
(HUMMING HAPPILY)
(CHILD LAUGHING UPROARIOUSLY)
(BELL DINGS)
Oh.
(DISTANT LAUGHTER)
(KAZOO WHIRS)
(TOY HORN TOOTS)
MIKE:
Hey, Sulley!
(YELLS)
Hey, uh, Mike.
I was, uh, just...
Well, listen,
if you got a minute
there's something
I want to show you.
But-but-but...
Okay, close
your eyes.
Follow me.
Come on.
I-I-I...
No peeking.
Keep coming, keep coming,
keep coming.
Come on,
Keep coming,
keep coming.
Mike...
Follow the sultry
sound of my voice.
Okay, stop.
Open them.
Ta-da!
Mike...
Is that...?
Sorry it took
so long, pal.
It was a lot of wood
to go through.
You know,
it only works
if you have
every piece.
(WHIRRING HUM)
(CREAKING)
Boo?
BOO:
Kitty!
(BOUNCY BLUES MELODY PLAYS)
SULLEY:
♪ If I were a rich man ♪
♪ With a million or two ♪
MIKE: ♪ I'd live
in a penthouse ♪
♪ In a room
with a view ♪
♪ And if I were handsome ♪
No way.
It could happen.
♪ Those dreams
do come true ♪
♪ I wouldn't have nothing
if I didn't have you ♪
♪ Wouldn't have nothing if I
didn't have ♪
♪ Wouldn't have nothing
if I didn't have ♪
♪ Wouldn't have nothing ♪
Can I tell
you something?
♪ For years
I have envied ♪
You were green with it.
♪ Your grace
and your charm ♪
♪ Everyone loves
you, you know ♪
♪ Yes, I know,
I know, I know ♪
♪ But I must admit it ♪
♪ Big guy, you
always come through ♪
♪ I wouldn't have nothing
if I didn't have you ♪
BOTH:
♪ You and me together ♪
♪ That's how it
always should be ♪
♪ One without the other
don't mean nothing to me ♪
♪ Nothing to me ♪
♪ Yeah, I wouldn't
be nothing ♪
♪ No ♪
♪ If I didn't
have you to serve ♪
♪ I'm just a punky
little eyeball ♪
♪ And a funky
optic nerve ♪
♪ Hey, I never
told you this ♪
♪ Sometimes I get
a little blue ♪
Looks good on you.
♪ But I wouldn't
have nothing ♪
♪ If I didn't
have you... ♪
Let's dance.
Look, Ma,
I'm dancing!
Would you let me lead?
Look at that.
It's true.
Big guys are light
on their feet.
Don't you dare dip me.
Don't you dare dip me,
don't you dare dip me.
Ow. I should
have stretched.
♪ Yes, I wouldn't
be nothing ♪
♪ If I didn't have you ♪
I know what you
mean, Sulley.
♪ Because... ♪
♪ I wouldn't know
where to go ♪
♪ Me, too,
because I... ♪
♪ Wouldn't know
what to do ♪
Why do you keep
singing my part?
BOTH:
♪ I don't have to say it ♪
Ah, say it anyway.
♪ 'Cause we... ♪
♪ Both know it's true ♪
♪ I wouldn't have nothing
if I didn't have ♪
♪ I wouldn't have nothing if I
didn't have ♪
♪ I wouldn't have nothing
if I didn't have you ♪
♪ Wouldn't have nothing
if I didn't have you. ♪
(MUSIC ENDS)
One more time.
(MUSIC BEGINS AGAIN)
It worked!
♪ I don't have
to say it ♪
Where'd everybody
come from?
♪ 'Cause we both
know it's true ♪
Let's take it
home, big guy.
BOTH: ♪ I wouldn't have
nothing if I didn't have ♪
♪ I wouldn't have nothing if I
didn't have ♪
♪ I wouldn't have nothing
if I didn't have you ♪
♪ You, you ♪
♪ A, E, I, O... ♪
♪ That means you, yeah. ♪