♪ Deep in the Hundred Acre Wood
♪ Where Christopher Robin plays
♪ You'll find
the enchanted neighbourhood
♪ Of Christopher's childhood days
♪ A donkey named Eeyore is his friend
♪ And Kanga, and little Roo
♪ There's Rabbit and Piglet,
and there's Owl
♪ But most of all, Winnie the Pooh
♪ Winnie the Pooh, Winnie the Pooh
♪ Tubby little cuddly,
all stuffed with fluff
♪ He's Winnie the Pooh,
Winnie the Pooh
♪ Willy-nilly, silly old bear!
Tigger!
Are you ready for the hive yet?
All I am is ready!
How do I look? I mean,
does this log make me look fat?
Like the best honey tree
a little bee will ever see.
Oh, boy!
Rabbit, what are you doing?
Can't you tell? I'm lullabying
the bees for our big plan!
They seem to like Beethoven.
Eeyore, what are you doing?
I've got to use my big voice
to tell the bees about the new hive.
Buzz, buzz! Great new hive.
Tigger, could you tell me
what you're doing?
I have to hold the fake hive
high enough for the bees to see.
It's the biggest part of the plan.
That's what Tiggers do best.
You do seem bigger than usual.
Hello, Piglet.
What are you all doing?
Harvesting honey, of course.
It's all in the plan.
First, Rabbit will lure the bees
with beautiful music.
Then, Eeyore tempts the bees
into their new hive.
Then Tigger holds up the hive
for the bees to see.
And then comes the best part.
We get honey from their old hive.
Can I help you with your big plan?
Thank you, Piglet,
but perhaps another time.
When we have a bit smaller of a plan.
Or when you're a bit bigger
of a piglet.
I'm sorry, Piglet.
But I'm afraid
this is a very big plan.
Places, everyone.
I've gotten their attention.
Great new hive.
Do the bees know the plan?
Piglet,
don't get in the way of our big plan.
I'm getting kinda itchy
around my knees.
Oh, dear!
Get the little guy!
OK, Rabbit.
We're geniuses!
Sticky geniuses!
Oh my! Oh, goodness!
The sweet taste of success.
Our plan worked perfectly.
Didn't think it would work.
But it did.
Congratulations to us all.
Hooray for Pooh!
- And Rabbit.
- And Eeyore.
- And Tigger, too.
- But I was the...
Oh, Piglet, I'm sorry that you
couldn't be part of our big plan.
But I thought I...
For a minute there, I thought
I was going to break out in hives.
Oh, dear. Even my shadow is small.
♪ It's not as if I want
to rule the world
♪ Or even the forest,
or even one tree
♪ I suppose I could be happy
if I could be helpful
♪ With just a little bit
of noticing me
♪ If I wasn't so small,
I could be like Tigger
♪ Figure out ways
to help some of those in need
♪ Indeed, I could volunteer
♪ As the friend
you would want right near
♪ More like Rabbit and Pooh
and Eeyore
♪ I'd be useful, and helpful
♪ The one you would call...
It'd be nice
if my friends needed me.
Piglet, could you help me
lullaby the bees?
call them to the hive?
Yeah, Piglet! Could you help me
reach higher?
Piglet, we need your help.
♪ I'd be needed, and useful
♪ More each passing day
♪ I may be small
♪ But in the biggest,
helpfulest way ♪
Wonderful honey!
I thought Tiggers hated honey.
They do, to eat. But to stop the
itching, there is nothing betterer.
Did you hear something? I'm afraid
I've got some honey in my ears.
What's that, Pooh? I can't hear you
over all that buzzing.
Whose buzzing?
Bees!
What say we break for lunch?
- What about our honey?
- It's your honey or your life!
- Come on!
- Oh, boy!
Oh, bother!
- Oh, joy!
- Thanks, donkey boy!
- Thanks, Eeyore.
- Any time. You're welcome.
Quick! Make a beeline for Piglet's!
Run faster!
Hurry!
- They're gone.
- Or maybe just pretendering.
Bees are sneaky like that.
I was right.
You got stung out there?
No. I got stung right here,
where I can keep an eye on it.
Is everyone all right?
Tigger's here, Eeyore's here,
Pooh is here, I'm here.
Who am I forgetting?
I don't know. Let's ask Piglet!
- Oh, bother.
- Are you all right, Pooh?
I just landed on my... self.
Say, what do we have here?
Oh, please, Tigger!
It's just a drawing in a scrapbook.
But it reminds me of
the bestest family reunion I ever had.
Oh, look. There's the day little
Piglet caught his first heffalump.
That was no heffalump. That was
just Pooh with a jar on his head.
I forgot how much I look like
a heffalump with a jar on my head.
He captured Rabbit, all right.
Let me see.
That doesn't look a thing like me.
What's next?
What's that tiny pink dot?
I believe it's Piglet.
Where is Piglet?
We must have lost track of him
after we got chased by the bees.
But he's so little.
He could be in big danger.
We have to find him
and make sure he's all right.
But how will we find him?
He could be anywhere.
Think!
You know, since this is
a book of Piglet's memories,
maybe it remembers where Piglet is.
Brilliant deduction there, Pooh boy.
It's a regular Piglet map.
That's the silliest thing
I've heard.
Let's start with page one.
Page one remembers Owl's house.
Way to go, Pooh boy!
Why, I bet that little fella's there
right now. Let's go find him.
Then off to Owl's house we go.
He has an answer for everything.
Not to Owl's!
We'll be there all day.
You can never
get a word in edgeways...
Goodbye, honey.
I may be small,
but in the biggest, helpfulest way!
Eeyore? Where are you?
Tigger? Where are you?
Oh, no! The bees!
What can I do?
Well, I did help you get the haycorn,
and bring you across the river.
Maybe my friends need me.
I have to find them.
Owl, have you seen Piglet?
Piglet? Of course I've seen Piglet.
Many times!
He's about so high,
with little pink ears...
No, we mean now.
Have you seen him this morning?
I can't imagine
that he's changed that much.
This is the part
where Owl goes on for a while.
As a matter of fact,
I just saw him go by.
He was just here?
Come on, let's go.
Or is missing. You could start,
of course, in the obvious place...
As I was saying, I have some great
stories about my second cousin.
Rupert stowed away
on a three-masted...
Eeyore! Come on!
As I was saying,
the great expedition...
What an expedition it was!
I told you this was a silly idea.
But he was just at Owl's.
That scrappety book
does know where he's going.
Well, Owl's house was on page one.
How about page two?
- Which is a picture of...
- Kanga's house.
Well, then, Kanga's house
is where we'll look for Piglet.
I think you must be right, Rabbit.
Piglet has always liked
visiting Kanga's.
Not always.
There was one time, I remember.
Oh, yes. When Kanga and Roo
first moved to the Hundred Acre Wood.
- Remember, Rabbit?
- No, I don't seem to recall.
Here, this'll remind your rememberer.
- No!
- You came up with a big plan, Rabbit.
I told you, I don't remember.
There it is.
You know, if I remember correctly,
this story is really about Piglet.
I just don't like it.
I don't like it at all.
I tell you, we won't be safe
until they're out.
Out of the Hundred Acre Wood.
Isn't it a bit early to be spying?
I've never seen anything like it.
It's actually moving in.
Roo, dear.
Here I am, Mama.
- It's an invasion!
- Do you think they're fierce?
What does fierce look like?
That's what fierce looks like.
She swallowed him whole.
Oh, dear!
He'll be eaten for sure.
Are you all right?
- Don't eat me!
- Why, you must be Piglet.
When Christopher Robin said
you'd be dropping by, I had no idea.
You know Christopher Robin?
Oh, yes. He told us all about you
and Pooh and Rabbit and Tigger.
The ones hiding in the tree
over there.
Hello, dears.
Did you hear that?
She called us "dears".
I'm Kanga and somewhere around here
is baby Roo.
I'm not a baby.
See! I can do this.
Well, it's very nice of you
to go out of your way to welcome us.
Sorry.
Oh, Roo!
Piglet, it's almost breakfast time.
Would you like to come in
for a little bite, perhaps?
I do like the sound
of the taste of that.
No, no, no. We're all due
on the other side of the wood.
And we can't be late.
- Goodbye.
Might I get that little something
to go?
Come on!
Aren't they dears?
One: Pooh will distract Kanga
long enough for...
Two: Tigger and I to take Roo
from her pouch.
And three: Replace him with Piglet.
That is very simple.
Just three little steps and...
What? Replace Roo with me?
You and Roo are the same size.
Kanga won't know the difference.
Not until it's too late.
How much too late?
Until after we say "Aha!"
What do you think?
Haha? Why would we say "Haha"?
Not "haha", Piglet.
Aha!
It's a word to say, "This is how
things are, and were meant to be."
Kanga will know that we know where
Roo is, and we'll only give him back
if she promises to leave the
Hundred Acre Wood and never return.
How is she going to know that
that is what "Aha" means?
Because we'll practice saying it
in just the right way.
We're counting on you, Piglet.
Everyone pretend
that their flower is Kanga.
Ready... set...
There you all are.
Oh, you brought flowers.
What nice new neighbours!
All right, I'm going.
Roo, dear. Time to come inside.
In a minute, Mama.
- Ready, Pooh?
- Yes, except for one small thing.
- What's that?
- What is it I'm supposed to do?
Talk to her very hard,
so that she doesn't notice anything.
Of course!
Come on, Roo. Hop in. Let's go inside.
Kanga!
Talk to her very hard. About what?
Anything!
I was just wondering...
That is... Do you think that...
Is that a fish in that tree?
- Which tree, dear?
- Up there.
Snug as a pig in a blanket.
What are you playing, Mr Rabbit?
That's not a fish, Pooh Bear.
It's a bird.
Yes, but is it a starling
or a mackerel?
It looks kinda wiggly.
It could be a jellyfish.
It's tough to say.
If you'll forgive me, dear,
we really must be going.
Peanut butter and jellyfish.
Ma, look!
Let's do it again. This is a fun game.
Are you all right in there, Roo?
I'm OK.
All right, Roo, dear.
Slow down!
Rabbit! Oh, Roo!
What was that word?
Aha?
That's the word.
Help!
Oh, my, Roo, dear.
You've lost your bounce.
I think it's time for your fishy oil.
Fishy oil? What fishy oil?
It'll help you bounce nice and high.
You don't want to grow up
small and weak like Piglet.
Now, did you have something
you wanted to tell me, Roo?
No...
Down the hatch!
See that? You got your bounce back.
If you're a good little Roo,
I'll let you have another spoonful.
No!
Oh, dear. I'm a goner!
You act like
I'm going to cook you for dinner.
Aren't you?
Why, of course not.
I'm going to give you a bath.
Cook me instead!
But Roo, dear, don't you know by now,
a mother always knows what's best?
♪ It's a mother's intuition
to make a little space
♪ It's her quiet mission
to tidy up her place
♪ A mother's intuition
is like a kangaroo's
♪ She hops around, she mops
the ground, she fusses over you
♪ A mother, with her intuition
♪ Will know just what to do
♪ It's a mother's intuition
to wash her baby
♪ Well, she won't forget
behind the ears
♪ And the extra soap suds on the tail
♪ A mother's into cleaning,
she'll clean until she's through
♪ She's smart enough, she's wise
enough to add up two and two
♪ A mother, with her intuition
♪ Will know just what to do
♪ A mother has a feeling,
she pays special attention
♪ If someone is concealing,
if someone's playing tricks
♪ She rubs and scrubs
and scours the secrets
♪ Until the answer clicks
♪ Then she takes a brush
and polishes your teeth
♪ She'll make you shine and sparkle
new until she finds the real you
♪ Underneath!
Oh, my goodness!
♪ Isn't it charming?
Just Mummy and little Roo
♪ Fresh as a daisy,
sparkling just like new
♪ It's a mother's intuition
♪ It's a mother's intuition ♪
Now, you know what's next.
I'm afraid to find out.
There's always two things you get
after your bath.
A cookie, and a kiss...
Well, it's a very subtle distinction.
But you see, a jellyfish sounds more
like a "Bleugh. Hi, I'm a jellyfish!"
Here, Tigger, Pooh Bear.
Look! Another creature
of the fiercerous kind!
Rabbit was right!
But it's me! Piglet!
Nah! The Piglet we know
isn't half as fuzzy as you.
You can't pull the fluff
over our eyes.
Pooh. Tell him who I am.
Well, I'd love to, whoever you are.
Come to think of it, he might be
a fuzzy fringed thingamawhatsit.
No, no, this is more of the feather
furred frizzamambobble variety.
But can we be sure, Tigger?
I'll prove it to you.
Piglet, where did you come from?
Lucky thing that fuzzy fringed
thingamabob didn't catch you.
- What did you find out?
- Awfully fierce and fiercely awful?
At first I thought so,
but then I found out...
she's very nice.
Hello, dears.
She called us "dears" again!
I could get used to this.
Would you like to come in
for that little something?
I'd love to.
- I love little somethings.
- But what do we tell Rabbit?
Mama, look at me.
You gotta see Mr Rabbit's garden.
You hear that? Mr Rabbit!
He's got carrots and lettuce
and beans, and we played...
Settle down, dear.
Now, what do we say to Mr Rabbit?
Thank you, Mr Rabbit. I had fun.
Well, I certainly enjoyed myself, too.
And you can call me Rabbit.
I like you, Rabbit.
I like you too, Roo.
You're right, Piglet.
This is the way things are.
And were meant to be.
If it weren't for Piglet,
I wouldn't be friends with Roo.
And we'd never have found out
how nice Kanga was.
We'd never have any of Kanga's songs.
Or her hugs.
Or her cookies. Which my nose
is telling my tummy are right nearby.
Kanga! We're so glad you didn't leave.
What are you talking about, Tigger?
How Piglet took a bath for us.
Not just any old buddy'd do something
that brave for his friends.
Don't know if I would.
It was a very biggish thing
for a littlish guy to do.
We're so worried about him, because
we lost him at the honey harvest.
So we're using his book of memories
to find him.
- We hope.
- Oh, dear Piglet!
But he's so small!
He could be in big danger!
Mama, may I help and look for Piglet?
Sorry, Eeyore.
- Can I, Mama? Can I?
- Of course, dear.
Piglet needs your help.
Pooh, would you like a cookie
before you go?
My heart tells me I should
keep looking for Piglet.
But you dears will need something
to keep your strength up.
My tummy says yes!
I just thought Piglet would need
to keep his strength up, too.
- Bye, Mama.
- Bye-bye, dear.
- So, where do we look first?
- The scrapbook will give us an idea.
It's a book of memories.
It remembers where Piglet is.
Try page three.
Page three shows all of us
at the North Pole.
That was the day we made our most
splendiferous discovery of all!
Then that's where we shall look!
This is not the way
to the North Pole.
Last time,
if I reconnoitre correcticly,
the North Pole was 40 minutes
south-easterly in that direction,
this way, magnetically speaking.
No. Last time, we went this way.
No, that would be the northeast pole.
No, no, no and no! I know
what I'm talking about. It's this way!
Perhaps if we told the story, the
story would tell us how to get there.
- Don't forget the part about Piglet!
- Piglet? How does Piglet fit in?
Roo's right. It really is a story
about Piglet, isn't it?
Nine-ety eight, nine-ety nine,
seventy-twosie and thirteen-ety...
and thirty-sixety...
gravity-defiant, Tiggerific bounces!
Look out below!
Hello, Tigger. Hello, Piglet.
What are you doing?
Just waiting for the other shoe
to fall.
I knew it.
These things always travel in pairs.
These are Christopher Robin's
big boots.
That can mean only one thing.
An expedition!
A which-pedition?
Yes, an expedition.
It's when you go off to find a thing.
- What are we going to find?
- The North Pole.
- Is it scary?
- What is it?
Yeah, we never found
one of them before.
Well, it's a thing you discover.
- Are bears good at discovering it?
- And Tiggers?
Everyone will come along. And if you
see the North Pole, shout "Eureka!"
Why would we do that?
Because it means,
"There's the North Pole."
- Eureka!
- Where?
Gesundheit!
Sorry. I was just practising.
We need a marching song.
A marching song to help us along.
- ♪ Sing ho, for the life of a bear!
- That's me!
♪ Sing ho, for the expedition
♪ Sing ho, for the life of a bear
♪ It's a fine day for marching,
there's a tiny little breeze
♪ And when there's honey for the
making, there's a buzz among the bees
♪ Sing ho, for the life of a bear
♪ Sing ho, for the expedition
- ♪ I'm itching and scratching.
- ♪ Scratching and itching.
♪ To find the North Pole!
♪ Finding the Pole may be the goal,
♪ But it's drumming for funning
that makes you sing
♪ Sing ho, for the life of a bear
♪ Sing ho, for the expedition
- ♪ Sing ho, for the expedition.
- This is fun!
♪ Sing ho, for the life of a bear
- ♪ Sing ho, for the expedition.
- One more time!
♪ Sing ho, for the life of a bear
♪ Sing ho, for the expedition ♪
I like that song.
Silly old bear.
- Would you like a haycorn, Pooh?
- No, thank you.
But a cookie would be nice.
Or a banana.
Christopher Robin,
perhaps I could find it easier
if only I were sure...
that is, if I knew
what the North Pole looked like.
Well, it's kind of...
It's sort of...
Well, I suppose we'll know exactly
what it is when we see it.
Are we there yet?
Pooh!
I just fed my tummy
and it's still calling me.
Hey, look at me, Pooh.
- I am.
- Pooh, I'm swimming.
Just a moment, Roo.
I'm talking to my tummy.
Of course you're swimming.
You shouldn't have had
that second cookie.
That's not your stomach, Pooh.
It's Roo.
Oh, my! Roo!
I don't believe expotitions
usually go into the water.
Quick!
Don't panic. Everything's fine.
Nobody's in any kind of...
Specially not Roo.
Do something! Everyone! Do anything!
Don't worry, Roo boy! I'll save you.
Thanks, Tigger.
But I don't think I need saving.
I can help.
Piglet, stay out of the way
while we save Roo.
Don't want to have to rescue
two little guys.
Catch onto my tail, Roo.
I'll pull you out.
Just tell me when you're on.
Rabbit, Roo, are we going swimming?
Maybe we can use this to save Roo.
- Give me a push, Pooh.
- Thank you, Piglet.
Now I've got him.
Faster, Pooh. Faster.
- Pooh?
- Where is he, Rabbit?
Pooh, look the other way.
I can see him perfectly from here.
Are you sure, Rabbit?
You're right.
You can see better from up here.
There he is.
Roo? Are you OK?
I got you, Roo! I got you.
Here he is, Kanga!
Oh, where'd he go?
You can rescue me now.
I'm getting kind of tired.
Use the pole. Use the pole.
No time for fishing, Piglet.
We gotta save Roo.
Grab on, Roo.
Pooh, could you please hold this?
Did you see me swimming? That's
called swimming, what I was doing.
Pooh Bear!
Pooh Bear,
where did you find that stick?
- What stick?
- That stick.
Well, I was standing here
without a stick,
and then I had a stick, so...
maybe the stick found me.
Assembled adventurers,
the expedition is over.
Pooh has discovered the North Pole.
- This?
- That.
Eureka!
Well, I'll be! That's
the North Pole, all right, all righty!
I should have seen it myself.
But... Oh...
Eureka!
Pole-erific! Positively magnetic!
Goodness! Where's Eeyore?
Did you grab on yet, Roo?
Roo?
Somebody?
Anybody?
Hooray for Pooh!
I always liked that story.
It has such a lovely end.
But nobody said hooray for Piglet.
He was so brave.
For someone so small.
And Piglets hate water.
Come to think of it, so do Tiggers.
Thank you, tail!
Thank you, Piglet. Wherever you are.
Look! Piglet's scarf.
That's it! Come on, let's go.
Missed him again.
Oh, my. You know, Piglet's scarf
never goes anywhere without Piglet.
This is more serious than I thought.
Maybe he's in grave danger.
Maybe heffalump's got him.
- Heffalumps?
- Or a woosel!
- Woosels!
- And now, he's out there somewhere.
With this storm blowing in.
Oh, goodness!
Goodness! Do you think
he's going to be all right?
Piglet shall be very all right indeed.
Don't let his small size worry you.
Once, he even made a whole house.
He did?
Do you know the story
of "The House at Pooh Corner"?
- No.
- Oh, yes, it's right here.
Page three.
On page four.
That's after three.
It's a lovely tale.
Don't you think so, Tigger?
Tigger?
- Pooh Corner, remember?
- Is this story about Piglet, too?
Why, yes, Roo, it is.
He seems to be the hero
of every story.
♪ The more it snows
♪ The more it goes
♪ The more it goes on snowing
♪ And nobody knows
♪ How cold my toes
♪ How cold my toes are growing
I was just thinking, Pooh.
Were you thinking
of a way to keep warm?
Actually, I was thinking about how
you have a house, and I have a house,
and Rabbit and Owl and
Christopher Robin all have houses,
but poor Eeyore has nothing.
Well, that's certainly something
we can think about.
Think, think, think.
I've got it!
Got what?
We'll build Eeyore a house of his own.
That's a wonderful idea, Pooh.
But, where shall we build it?
Well...
Right here.
Because this is where I thought of it.
And since this
is where I thought of it,
we shall call this place Pooh Corner.
Pooh Corner?
Pooh, I was thinking along with you.
Yes, that's true, Piglet.
So, we could call this place
Pooh and Piglet Corner.
If Pooh Corner didn't sound better,
which it does.
Being smaller and more like a corner.
So, Pooh Corner it is.
Look, snow somersaults.
Bother!
I tried to stop, but it's snow use!
Get it? Snow use!
So, what you doing?
We're going to build Eeyore
a house at Pooh Corner.
What a Tiggerific idea!
What are you going to build it with?
We haven't decided.
I just bounced by
a humongerous pile of sticks.
They'd be positively perfect
for a donkey house.
Come on! Bounce this way!
Follow the bouncing Tigger.
♪ The wonderful thing about Tigger
is Tigger's a wonderful thing
♪ Their tops are made of rubber,
their bottoms are made of string
♪ But the most wonderful thing
about Tiggers is, I'm the only one! ♪
What did I tell you?
More sticks
than you can stick a shake at!
It's almost as if
someone left them here for us.
I wonder...
Let's get started,
so we can finish in time.
In time for what?
Lunch.
♪ With a few good friends
and a stick or two
♪ A house is built
at a corner called Pooh
♪ With a friend and a stick,
or three or four
♪ A house is built
where it wasn't
♪ Bef-o-o-o-o-r-e
♪ With a window here
♪ And there a door
♪ And a nail and a peg
♪ For the coat of Eeyore
♪ With a few good friends
and a stick or two
♪ A house is built
at a corner called Pooh
♪ With a friend and a stick,
or three or four
♪ A house is built where it wasn't
♪ Bef-o-o-o-o-o-r-e
♪ Dress it down or dress it up
♪ Invite Tigger for tea
♪ And Owl for supper
♪ With a few good friends
and a stick or two
♪ A house is built
at a corner called Pooh
♪ With a friend and a stick,
or three or four
♪ A house is built where it wasn't
♪ Bef-o-o-o-o-o-r-e
There. It's all entirely done.
Let's show old donkey boy
the fruits of our elbow grease.
♪ With a few good friends ♪
Oh, bother.
I suspectorate there's something
wrong with these sticks.
All we wanted was for Eeyore
to have his own house.
You know,
Eeyore could come live with me.
That is very hospititious of you,
Pooh.
Let's go give old donkey boy
the good news.
Oh, dear.
Hello!
Pooh Bear! You are just in time.
Look what I made.
Why, Christopher Robin,
it's wonderful.
What is it?
- Why, it's you, Pooh Bear.
- No wonder he looks so familiar.
It looks just like you.
Except for the donkey head.
Eeyore, were you under there
the whole time?
I suppose I was.
Weren't you awfully cold?
I've been colder. Last night,
for instance, it got downright...
- Freezing.
- So I did it. I built myself a house.
Hear that?
Eeyore built himself a house.
Just a leaky pile of sticks.
Did you say sticks?
- So you have seen it!
- I have? Seen what?
The funny thing about houses is,
they never know if they're coming
or going. So they do.
Well, someone, somewhere,
must know something.
I do!
- What's that?
- A high-stepping pig high-faluter!
I believe it's Piglet on stilts.
Eeyore's house is over there.
Come on, I'll show you.
Toodle-oo.
- Look at that.
- Well, I'll be...
Oh, my goodness!
Welcome home, Eeyore.
It's my house, all right.
But I'm sure this isn't
where I built it.
Where you built it? But I...
I suppose the wind
must have blown it over here.
The wind?
Oh, yeah, the wind!
It's been known to do strange
and windy-like things.
I think the wind had a little help.
Right, Piglet?
The important thing is,
Eeyore has a house.
And here it is.
And it's as good as ever.
- And even never betterer.
- You really think so?
Oh, yes. Much more better than ever,
even, Piglet.
Just one thing bothers me.
Oh, dear. What might that be?
Afraid I'll lose it again.
Don't worry, Eeyore. I put up a sign,
so you'll always know where it is.
Pooh Corner!
Nice.
Hooray for Eeyore's house.
♪ With a few good friends
and a stick or two
♪ We can build a house
at a corner called Pooh
♪ With a friend and a stick,
or three or four
♪ A house is there
where it wasn't before ♪
What?
It's a little crowded. But it'll do.
And that is how Piglet got the idea
that you, Eeyore,
should have your own house.
You mean Piglet built Eeyore's house
all by himself?
Yes, and that's
just how much Piglet cares.
Best house I ever had.
And named it after me.
Oh, dear. We'd better find him soon.
Roo's getting cold.
Perhaps we should look
in the book again.
I just got a Tiggerific idea!
Let's see where the book ends
and go there.
No, if we do this
in an orderly manner,
we'll find him much quicker.
Now, let's see.
We've been there, and there...
But orderlier
doesn't seem to be working, does it?
All I'm concerned about
is finding Piglet.
- I want to find him, too!
- We all want to find him!
Rabbit, look!
- Oh, my!
- You're ruining it.
- I am not.
Hand it over, bunny boy. Finding
Piglets is what Tiggers do best.
It's what rabbits do best.
- Tiggers!
- No, rabbits.
Stop fighting!
Be careful. That's the only way
we have to find Piglet.
There goes our map.
And Piglet's memories.
I only wanted to find Piglet.
We all did.
We'd better go back to Piglet's.
We have to get Roo warm and dry.
I do wish I'd called it
Pooh And Piglet Corner.
♪ The more I look inside
♪ The more he isn't there
♪ What am I supposed to do?
♪ When Piglet is not everywhere
♪ The more I rack my brain
♪ The more I search in vain
♪ I guess I'll have a little snack
♪ And wait for it to start to rain
That's the Piglet I know.
Always glad to see you.
- Always thoughtful.
- Always brave.
Never thinking of himself.
Draw another one, Pooh.
♪ Maybe I will draw a picture
♪ And while I'm busy doing that
♪ My mind will wander off somewhere
♪ And Piglet will reappear
♪ And Piglet will be right here
♪ The more I look inside
♪ The more you're near to me
♪ I see you here, I see you there
♪ Feel you everywhere ♪
- We gotta get Piglet.
- Let's go.
Yes, yes, come on.
Poor Piglet! Oh, goodness!
Piglet!
- Piglet!
Look! Oh, look what I found.
It's one of Piglet's scrapbook pages.
Look, another one.
We can put Piglet's book
back together.
- Then we can find him in no time.
- Let's keep looking.
I found one.
- Me, too.
Eureka!
- I think...
- I found...
Another!
We're getting closer.
- Here's one.
- How many does that make?
- Another.
- Piglet will be so happy.
What's that over there?
Come back, memory!
One more scrappy page
for Piglet's scrappety book.
Hey, look. There it is!
- But how will we get it?
- We need help.
That's gotta be dangerous.
What could he be thinking?
- Who?
- Pooh.
Now, no-one panic!
The first thing we do is not to panic.
Somebody do something! Do anything!
Oh, my goodness!
- What are you doing?
- I'm just getting Piglet's memories.
- Oh, bother!
- Pooh needs help.
Oh, bother, bother!
Rabbit was right.
We could use a little help.
Here you go, buddy boy.
We made you a rescue rope.
- Out of us.
- Me, too.
It's our plan.
- Oh, my!
- Pooh, what are you waiting for?
The rescue rope isn't rescuing.
We need a little bit more.
We just need a little help.
- Who's small enough?
- Oh, dear! Who can help?
Piglet!
You can do it!
My friends need me!
Hang on, Pooh!
Oh, I'm hanging. Piglet!
Oh, Piglet! Your memories!
We never got to tell Piglet
how we feel about him.
Poor Pooh.
Should have told them
when we had the chance.
Here you go, Rabbit.
Something must be very sad.
Well, of course it's sad.
Pooh!
Piglet!
Thank goodness you're safe.
We're so glad to see you.
Glad to see me?
It's so good to have you back again.
We've been following your memories
all over the Hundred Acre Wood.
And they've led us right to you.
Too bad
they're all floating down the river.
- Goodness!
- Oh, no!
Oh, bother!
We're ever so sorry, Piglet.
The scrapbook's not that important.
But it showed us the great things
you've done.
Oh, I've never done anything great.
Well, of course you have!
- Let's tell him, everyone.
- No, let's show him!
I can't stand the excitement.
Here we are.
Go on.
Is that me?
That's you.
I'm so big!
- Well, of course you are.
- Why, you're double XL!
If it weren't for you, Piglet,
I wouldn't be friends with Roo.
Yeah, and thanks for saving me
with the North Pole.
Piglet...
Pooh Corner's not a bad place to live.
I'd say this calls for a celebration.
Come on, chase me.
Here I come. Watch out.
Come on, you can do better than that.
Get him, Roo!
That's funny.
- Look!
- Piglet, can I try?
Oh, my!
Do something, everyone.
Good one, Piglet!
- It's carrot cake.
- Rabbit, you're a natural!
Delicious!
- Where's Pooh?
- Piglet!
I have one more thing to show you.
- But Pooh, your cake.
- It can wait. Hurry, Piglet.
We shall have something
right after I show you
a little something, Piglet!
It's right over here.
Pooh and Piglet Corner!
Yes, Piglet. It's the least
we could do for a very small Piglet,
who's done such very big things.
Thank you, Piglet.
♪ With a few good friends
and a stick or two
♪ A house is built
at a corner called Pooh
♪ With a friend and a stick,
or three or four
♪ A house is built where it wasn't
♪ Bef-o-o-o-o-o-r-e
♪ With a window here
♪ And there a door
♪ And a nail and a peg
♪ For the coat of Eeyore
♪ With a few good friends
and a stick or two
♪ A house is built
at a corner called Pooh
♪ With a friend and a stick,
or three or four
♪ A house is built where it wasn't
♪ Bef-o-o-o-o-o-r-e
♪ Dress it down or dress it up
♪ Invite Tigger for tea
♪ And Owl for supper
♪ With a few good friends
and a stick or two
♪ A house is built
at a corner called Pooh
♪ With a friend and a stick,
or three or four
♪ A house is built where it wasn't
♪ Bef-o-o-o-o-o-r-e
♪ Ah aaaah aaaaaah
♪ With a few good friends
♪ Ah aaaaaah aaaaaaaah
♪ Ah aaaaah aaaaaaaaah
♪ With a few good friends ♪
♪ Sing ho, for the life of a bear
♪ Sing ho, for the expedition
♪ It's a fine day for marching,
there's a tiny little breeze
♪ When there's honey for the making,
there's a buzzing from the bees
♪ Sing ho, for the life of a bear
♪ Sing ho, for the expedition
- ♪ Itching and scratching
- ♪ Scratching and itching
♪ To find the North Pole
♪ Finding the Pole may be the goal
♪ But it's drumming for funning
that makes you sing
♪ Sing ho, for the life of a bear
♪ Sing ho, for the expedition
- One more time!
♪ Sing ho, for the life of a bear
♪ Sing ho, for the expedition ♪
♪ When the heart
of the Hundred Acre Wood is beating
♪ And time is passing through
♪ There's a shadow
looking like a rainbow's halo
♪ And there I'm resembling you
♪ More than fame, a name on a tree
♪ More than power or might
♪ Sweeter than the treats
of a honey bee
♪ I'll be here through the night
♪ It's comforting to know
♪ Silent as the moon at dawn
♪ Soothing as a bed filled with hay
♪ Strong as a hero in the land of old
♪ I'll be here through the day
♪ It's comforting to know
♪ You only get a few good friends
in this life
♪ Who are devoted and true
♪ And right here in this now and here
♪ It's clear that it's all of you
♪ I'll find you
when you're hard to see
♪ I'll look for you everywhere
♪ You'll know
just how I'm feeling when
♪ I show you that I care
♪ It's comforting to know
♪ It's comforting to know ♪