[Orchestral music plays]
NARRATOR: The story
always ends the same:
Peter Pan shouts...
PETER PAN: Good-bye, Wendy!
NARRATOR: And then Wendy
shouts back to him...
I'll always believe in you,
Peter Pan!
NARRATOR: And Wendy
did believe always...
even as she left
childhood behind...
and came to have
children of her own:
There it is, Jane--
second star to the right...
and straight on to morning.
-Never Land!
-[Coos]
/ The second star
to the right /
/ Shines in the night
for you /
/ To tell you that
the dream you plan /
/ Really can come true /
/ The second star
to the right /
/ Shines with
a light that's rare /
/ And if it's
Never Land you need /
/ its light
will lead you there /
[Chiming]
NARRATOR: Our story begins
in diffilcult times:
England is threatened
with war...
and many men have been asked...
to leave thelr famllles
to protect their country.
I'll be home
before you know it. I promise.
Now, now. What's all this?
I want to go with you.
I need you here to take care
of your mom and Danny.
Can you do that for me?
[Sniffles] Mm-hmm.
That's my big girl.
Be safe, Edward.
Look after each other, now.
Good-bye, Daddy! I love you!
I love you all!
MAN: Drive off!
NARRATOR: But the war
lasted much longer...
than anyone
could have imagined:
Bombs fell from the sky...
and tore at the very heart
of London.
Don't cry, son.
All aboard!
NARRATOR: in an effort
to protect its children...
the government decreed...
that they all be sent to the
countryside for safekeeping.
-Good-bye!
Good-bye!
-I love you!
-Good luck, sweetie!
NARRATOR:
in times such as these...
it is no wonder some
discard childish things...
like Peter Pan and Never Land.
[Pants]
[Woof woof]
What is it, Nanatwo?
[Woof woof woof woof]
-[Splashes]
-Ha ha ha!
[Vocalizes]
We don't have time,
you silly dog.
We have to get this home
to Danny.
-[Air raid siren]
-Oh, no! Quick, Nanatwo!
[Woof woof woof]
[Gasps]
Mommy, where's Jane?
Don't you worry, Danny.
She'll be along.
WENDY : All right, now.
Here we go.
Into the bomb shelter.
[Gasping]
MAN: Bring the lights up!
[Clacking]
[Woof woof woof woof]
-[Growls]
-What is it, girl?
[Sniffs]
Oh, my gosh!
-[Barking]
-[Bomb whistles]
[Howls]
[Explosion]
Nanatwo, we're not
out of the woods yet.
We have to get back out there!
[Vocalizes]
-Look, who's in charge here?
-[Woof]
[Giggles]
Don't be silly. I am!
Now, come on!
[Whooshing]
[Overlapping yelling]
[Marching in rhythm]
-[Explosion]
-[Gasps]
Mommy, I'm scared!
I don't like planes and bombs.
Is that what it is?
For a moment, it sounded
like cannons on a pirate ship.
[Gasps] You're right!
It's Captain Hook!
Uhh!
A hero! He's coming!
WENDY: Jane!
[Panting]
DANNY: Jane!
Oh, Jane!
Where have you been?
Why didn't you--
Mother, I'm fine!
DANNY: Jane, you made it
past the pirates!
Daniel, careful!
-What's that? What's that?
-Whoa!
-Uhh!
-Uhh! Hey!
It's for me, isn't it?
Let me see! Let me see!
All right!
Happy birthday, Daniel.
Yippee!
[Rustles]
Socks. Two of 'em.
Jane, dear, how very practical.
Got them a size large
so he can grow into them.
[Sighs]
Look, Danny, Pan and Hook, see?
[Wendy imitates Hook]
Curse you, Peter Pan!
Oh, Mother.
I want to hear
a Peter Pan story!
[Woof woof woof woof]
Shh! Nanatwo!
WENDY: All rlght, then.
How about the time
Peter and the Lost Boys...
captured Hook's ship
right from under his nose?
DANNY: Ooh! That's a good one!
WENDY: it was late
one misty evening...
and Hook was sure once again...
that he'd found
Peter's hideout.
Hook and hls bloodthirsty crew
went ashore...
leaving the Jolly Roger
unguarded.
That's when Peter Pan arrived!
He and the Boys
slipped aboard...
and there they found it--
Hook's remarkable treasure!
DANNY: Wow!
WENDY: Peter told
the Lost Boys they'd hide it...
and Hook would have to hunt
them down to get it back.
it was all a great game
for Peter, and then...
from out of the mist,
he was there--
the evil Captaln Hook!
A fierce and ferocious
sword fight was fast underway.
[Thunder]
Ha ha!
-[Gasps]
-[Whines]
-Give up, boy!
-Never!
WENDY: And at that moment...
a shimmering magic
covered the ship.
DANNY: Tinker Bell!
WENDY: Yes!
And the Jolly Roger...
lifted into the sky...
as Peter and the Boys
escaped with the treasure.
[Bonk]
[Sputters]
Aah! You've not seen
the end of me, Peter Pan!
HOOK: I'll get you for this
if it's the last thing I do!
WENDY: So you see, Danny...
Hook will never win...
as long as there's faith...
trust, and pixle dust.
Poppycock!
Aah! Slow down,
you old codfish!
[Gasps] Oh, my notebook!
-[Thunk]
-Ow!
JANE: Daniel!
DANNY: Come on, Jane!
We'll beat old Captain Hook
together!
Daniel, please.
I've no time for fun and games.
You used to.
You got to be the very first
Lost Girl ever.
That was a long time ago.
Yeah. Back when you were fun.
Nnhh!
JANE: Honestly, Mother, I don't
know why you fill his head...
with those silly stories.
But they're not silly, Jane.
They're--
[Knock on door]
Take care of Danny, will you?
[Knocks]
Go on. I'll be right there.
Yes?
Evacuation, mum.
Your children are scheduled
on the morning train:
[Gasps] So soon?
But I haven't even told them.
The sooner the better,
if you ask me. Good night, mum.
WENDY: Yes. Uh...good night.
[Whines]
WENDY: Jane, dear.
Will you promise me something?
Promise you'll
watch over Danny...
whatever might happen.
What?
[Sigh] You and your brother
are going away for a while.
Away? Where?
WENDY: All the children are
being evacuated to the country.
It's so dangerous here...
but you'll be safe there,
both of you.
I'm not going!
I'm staying here!
WENDY: But dear,
an order has been issued.
Every chlld must go.
But Daddy said
that I'm supposed to--
I know, dear, but you
can take care of Danny.
Tell him Peter Pan stories.
He needs them, Jane,
and so do you.
Please, dear. Promise me.
JANE: No! I will not promise!
Oh, Jane!
We'll be together again.
-You must have faith.
-Faith?
Trust? Pixie dust?
Mother, those are just words
from your stories.
They don't mean anything.
DANNY: Yes, they do.
Peter Pan says
they'll make you fly.
JANE: Daniel,
story time is over!
Look! lt's a war.
Peter Pan isn't real,
and people don't fly!
They do too!
JANE: Oh, come on, Daniel!
Grow up!
It's just a lot
of childish nonsense!
You're lying!
WENDY: Jane, how could you
treat your brother that way?
You think
you're very grown-up...
but you have
a great deal to learn.
[Whines]
[Whimpers]
Uhh!
/ I am not a child now /
/ I can take care of myself /
/ Mustn't let them down now /
/ Mustn't let them
see me cry /
/ I'm fine /
/ I'm flne /
/ I'm too tlied to listen /
/ I'm too old to belleve /
/ All these childish stories /
/ There is no such thing
as faith /
/ And trust /
/ And pixie dust /
/ 'Cause I try /
/ But it's so hard
to believe /
/ I try /
/ But I can't see
what you see /
/ I try /
[Air raid siren]
FlREMAN:
I don't know if it's going!
is that water pressure up?
[Indistinct yelling]
[Sighs]
Peter Pan...
pixie dust...
childish nonsense.
[Crying]
[Gulls cry]
[Clack]
[Groans]
[Gasps]
[Creak]
Hello, Wendy.
-[Gasps] Uhh!
-My apologies, Miss.
-[Jane screams]
-[Air raid siren]
-[Snap]
-Uhh!
Curses! Bring her down!
-Hurry, Smee!
-Oh!
-Uhh!
-Oh, come on, now. Don't fuss.
JANE: Oh! Oh! Oh!
Cast off, ya mangy dogs!
Arrgh!
[Clanks]
[Thud]
[Clacking]
Eeh! Hoist anchor!
[Grinds]
[Boom]
[Crash]
[Bam]
[Engines roaring]
[Muffled] Ohh!
Oh, my gosh!
-[Clang]
-Arrgh!
[Bell tolls]
[Bang]
[Montage of indistinct
talking, music, sounds]
[Whimpers]
I've got a little surprise
for you, Peter Pan.
[Gasps]
PIRATE: Drop the mainsails!
PIRATE:
Prepare to drop anchor!
[Hook chuckles]
HOOK: This is simply perfect!
Yes, Mr: Smee,
with Wendy as balt...
we shall lure Peter Pan
to his doom! Ha ha!
Summon the beast!
Yes, sir, Captain. Right away!
/ Oh, yo ho ho, another plan /
/ To try to capture
Peter Pan /
/ Captaln Hook's
a brilliant man /
/ Who else could think
of the perfect crime /
/ And bumble
and fumble it every time /
-Smee!
-Whoa!
[Slosh]
[Bubbling]
Set the bait!
[Jane whimpering]
Make no doubt, Smee.
That wretched boy will be
but a notch in me scabbard.
PETER:
Only lin your dreams, Hook!
HOOK: Pan!
[Rip]
Ha ha ha!
I didn't know a codfish could
talk, did you, Tinker Bell?
[Tinkles]
Blast him!
Ha ha!
Take your best shot, Captain.
-[Whee]
-Come on!
You're gonna have to do
better than that, boy!
[Blam]
-[Swooshes]
-Whoa! Uh-uh-uh!
Three strikes and you're out!
-Aah!
Eww!
Come down here, boy.
I've a little something
for you.
A present for me?
Aw, you really shouldn't have.
Call it a token
of me affection.
You see, it is
a certain friend of yours.
-Who?
-[Hook chuckles]
Wendy.
Wendy?!
Let her go, Hook!
You black-hearted scoundrel!
You want her? Ha!
Well, go and get her!
[Jane screams]
[Growling and thrashing]
[Tinkles]
[Growling
and thrashing weakens]
[Splash]
[Ship creaks]
[Quiet bubbling]
I did it. I did it!
I can't believe it. I'm free!
Free of Peter Pan forever!
Ha ha ha ha!
[Giggles]
-[Honk]
-HOOK: Mr. Smee...
who is the most brazen, bold,
and brilliant buccaneer...
who ever sailed the briny blue?
Um...Blackbeard?
-[Sighs]
-[Bonk]
[Groans]
Boys?
-Ehh...
-Hook!
-Hook! Hook!
Thank you, thank you.
I was good, wasn't I?
-[Crows]
-[Gasps]
Did you miss me, Captain?
How did you escape the beast?
[Tinkles]
[Bubbling]
[All gasp]
Eeh!
[Tinkles]
[Swipe]
[Gulps]
[Whistling air]
[Thud]
Aah! Help...me!
[Gasps]
[Smacks]
Yum!
[Chatters]
[Slurps]
HOOK: Now, now, stay away!
No! No, no, no!
Aah!
Ohh!
No, no! No!
Wha--Smee! Aah! Aah!
[Whimpers]
Aah! Oh, Smee!
Hang on, Captain.
[Clank]
Here I come!
Aah! Smee!
-Aah!
[Whistling through air]
Ow!
[Cat yowls, chickens cluck]
HOOK: Mr: Smee, be a good
fellow and fix the plank...
so I can make you walk it!
Aye-aye, Captain.
Eww!
[Peter Pan laughs]
Easy does it, Wendy.
Ha! You should have seen...
-Hook's face when I--
-[Smack]
Ow!
Ow! Ow! Ow, ow, ow!
[Jane kisses her hand]
[Gasps]
[Gasps louder]
[Gasps louder still]
-Whoa!
-Oh!
Peter Pan?
Uhh! You're sure not Wendy!
[Tinkles]
Tinker Bell?
Oh, I get it. I'm dreaming.
You're not real.
-[Boom]
-[Gasps]
-Huh? Look out!
-[Crash]
HOOK: Pan,
you double-crosslng pipsqueak!
Come back here
to fight like a man!
Come and get me,
you old codfish!
Ha ha! Come on.
We gotta fly out of here.
Aah!
Wait!
-What are you doing?
-[Blam]
Aah!
If you're not Wendy,
who are you?
I'm her daughter Jane!
PETER: Huh! Well,
if you're Wendy's daughter...
you're gonna love it here!
[Tinkling]
[Flapping]
[Clacking]
[Tinkling]
Uhh!
Huh?
[Jangles]
-Aah!
-[Splash]
Hey, this is great!
You can stay here forever!
-Uhh! Aah!
-Ha ha ha!
[Tinkles]
JANE: Help!
Ahh!
JANE: She did that on purpose.
Aw, she's just jealous.
All girls get like that
around me.
Oh, really?
How very nice for yo--aah!
[Screaming]
-Uhh!
Ha ha! That was fun, huh?
Lost Boys, fall in!
[Whooping]
[Gasps]
Oh, careful!
You're going to fall!
[Clatter]
[Boys laugh]
[Claps]
[Tinkles]
PETER: Sound off!
-Slightly!
-Nibs!
The Twins!
-[Thud]
-Ow!
Cubby.
And that's Toodles!
Ooh!
[Squish]
Ew!
PETER: Boys, this is Jane.
She's gonna stay here
and be our new mother...
-and tell us stories.
-What? I--
What do you mean by--
-Yay!
-Stories!
Tell stories! Come on!
Um...actually...
I'm afraid I'm not very good
at telling stories.
Ah, that's OK.
We're not very good
at listening to stories.
-Ooh!
-[Laughter]
I know.
Let's play a game instead.
Red Rover!
-Nah, something else.
-CUBBY: Let's play...
"The no more hitting Cubby
on the head" game.
-Ha ha!
-PETER: Hey!
-How about a treasure hunt?
-NIBS: Good idea!
Yeah! A treasure hunt!
Heh. I hid it really good
this time.
You guys'll never find it.
[Struggling]
Sure we will!
[Overlapping chattering]
-Rubies!
-Treasure!
-Diamonds!
-Yeah, come on!
[Yelling and laughing]
Ooh!
-Let's go!
-No!
JANE: No, no, no...
and no!
You remind me
of someone I know.
Ohh.
[Sighs]
I have to go home.
[Tinkling]
What's the matter with her?
I don't know.
She acts kinda like a...
grownup.
TOGETHER: Eww!
-Whoa!
-[Startled yelps]
I've got to get out of here.
[Gulls cawing]
[Popping]
HOOK: Smee!
SMEE: Coming, Captain!
[Seal-like barking]
[Popping]
[Hook groans]
HOOK: Oh, my back!
[Chuckles]
Oh, dear, dear, dear, Captain.
A nice massage
is just the ticket for you.
Now, you just forget
about old Peter Pan.
[Cracks]
[Sighs] Perhaps you're right.
-Ooh!
-[Crunching]
Ooh! Ahh! Ooh!
[Muffled groans]
All in the past, I say.
All in the past.
Ah, the past.
Likes when he stole
your treasure.
-[Cracks]
-Wah! Oohh!
My treasure?
And then laughed in your face.
-Ha ha!
-Laughed in my face.
SMEE: Or today, for example...
tricking that there sea monster
into pulling down your pants.
Wahh ohh!
Right in front of the crew, too.
Right in front of the crew!
We've got to find him!
-[Cracks]
-HOOK: Whoa-oh!
[Rhythmic popping]
-SMEE: Catchy.
-[Popping continues]
Smee, listen!
[Popping]
[Shrieks]
[Crash]
Great scott!
No sooner do I rid meself...
of that cursed crocodile,
and now this!
[Wails]
Oh, there, there.
He's just a playful
little sea urchin is all.
I swear, Smee, this is
propelling me to delirium.
I detest cephalopods.
[Pop]
Thank you.
[Blows]
[Sniffles]
[Shrieking]
Smee!
Save me!
Oh, you big brute, you!
Off with you.
Go on, now. Shoo, shoo.
And take your arms with you.
You ought to be
ashamed of yourself.
-[Squirt]
-[Coughs, sputters]
[Gasps] Hmm!
At least the crocodile
had manners.
[Popping]
Blast that scurvy boy!
This is all his fault.
Mr. Smee, pipe up the crew.
We're going ashore
to find Peter Pan!
[Tinkles]
PETER:
Tink, what is she doing?
It looks like she's leaving.
[Tinkling]
Shh!
Half-dozen bananas...check.
Ten coconuts...check.
Two oars...
-Hey, Jane.
-Aah!
How come you want
to go home so bad?
I have to get back
to my family.
Why?
Well, um, I don't want
to talk about it.
Why not?
If you must know,
we had a fight.
Why?
[Sighs] Oh.
I told my little brother
you weren't real.
What?! Why?
[Sighs] Well, oh, I don't know.
But I have to get back
and set things right.
Why?
Because!
That's why!
[Gulls cry]
[Sighs]
Well, you know,
you can't get home that way.
I--I've got to try.
[Sniffles] Well...good-bye.
It was nice meeting you,
Peter Pan.
Duty calls.
[Sighs]
[Grunts]
Oh!
Oh, dear!
Oh, no!
Wah!
Whoa-oh!
[Coughs]
You OK?
I just want to go home.
Well, you know, the only way
out of here is to fly.
Come on, I'll show you how.
Ohh!
HOOK: Step softly...
you worthless dogs!
Set your sights for Peter Pan!
Oh, goodness.
Haven't we searched the island
a thousand times before?
I beg your pardon, Mr. Smee?
[Stammering] I said that, uh,
searching for Pan is, um, uh...
fun galore.
[Nervous chuckle]
[Sighs]
There'll be no rest until
we have that boy in irons.
Ohh.
[Groans]
-Hey!
-Watch it, Cubby!
JANE: Oh, no, Peter.
I really don't think this wo--
Uhh. This is ridiculous.
I can't fly!
Well, of course you can't.
But I can!
I guess I'm just
smarter than you.
Ohh.
I highly doubt that.
-Braver.
-[Snorts] Right.
Stronger!
[Chuckles]
Oh, yeah, that's it.
Well, then,
it must be my good looks.
Or maybe
you're full of hot air.
Wah! Hey!
Look, anybody can do it.
Tink?
Yeah! All it takes is faith...
Trust...
And, uh, something else.
Pixie dust?
That's it! Ooh!
-[Grunts]
-Ow!
OK, Tink, let her have it.
[Tinkles]
Tink...
[Sighs] Gosh, Tink,
if she can't fly home...
I guess she'll have
to move in with us.
[Tinkles]
Ooh. Oh!
Ah. [Gasps]
That's enough!
[Sniffles]
[Coughs]
JANE: Ahh.
Ah-ah-ah-choo!
Oh!
-[Rattles]
-Yow!
Ohh!
[Laughter]
[Gasps]
Hot's fish, what's that?
-OK, Jane.
-Don't even think about it.
-Ready or not...
-[Screams]
-I got her!
[Overlapping yells]
[Thud]
I thought you said you got her.
[Jane grunts]
Oh, how will I ever
get back home?
So, the girl can't fly,
yet she wants to go home.
Smee, do you know
what this means?
Six more weeks of winter?
No, you imbecile.
[Chuckles]
We'll get me treasure...
and the boy.
Hey, what's this?
Oh, give that back.
It's my list!
Things to do, places to be--
important things!
Huh? That stuff's no fun.
No wonder you can't fly!
JANE: Give it back, Peter.
Ha ha! Slightly, catch!
[Laughing]
PETER: Keep away from Jane!
[Laughter]
-I got it!
-You boys are horrid!
Come on, come on, over here!
You're ripping it!
CUBBY: Why don't you guys
ever throw to me?
No, stop it!
JANE: This isn't funny!
-SLIHTLY: Whoo hoo!
-I've got it!
-[Gasps]
-[Mumbles, gulps]
[Belches]
[Boys laughing]
Ha ha ha!
This is just a game to you,
isn't it?
[Exhales]
Well, I'm tired of playing.
Gosh, Jane, we didn't mean
to make you mad.
Oh, grow up. You did so.
You're just a bunch
of silly, ridiculous children.
[Tinkles]
No, no, leave me alone!
Oh, I don't believe
in any of this!
And I especially don't
believe in fairies!
[Boys gasp]
Good-bye!
Oh, yeah? Well, good riddance!
-[Tinkles weakly]
-Hmm.
CUBBY: Uh, Peter?
I think
there's something wrong...
with Tinker Bell.
[Sighs]
[Blows]
[Coughs]
[Sighs]
[Owl hooting]
[Storm rumbling]
Ohh.
[Gasping]
[Thunder]
[Bird chirping]
EDWARD: I need you here...
to take care of
your mom and Danny.
Can you do that for me?
[Sniffle] Mm-hmm.
That's my big girl.
I love you!
[No audio]
[Rain falling]
[Crying]
[Weak tinkling]
Ooh.
Looks kinda bad.
Kinda bad?
Kinda?
Oh, it's hopeless!
Poor little Tinker Bell!
[Cubby wails]
Hey, put a cork in it!
-[Wails]
-Shh!
-[Tinkling]
-Uh-huh.
-[Tinkles]
-What?
-What did she say, Peter?
If we don't get Jane
to believe in fairies...
Tink's light's gonna go out.
[Gasping together]
Well, let's just go
and make her believe!
PETER: Hang on a mlnute.
Ow!
You can't just make somebody
believe in fairies.
-TWINS: But we believe.
-Yeah, it ain't hard for us.
That's it!
We gotta make Jane one of us!
TOGETHER: But she's a girl!
You want to help Tink,
don't ya?
TOGETHER: Uh-huh.
We gotta do it!
[Hocks, spits]
[All hock, spit]
Don't worry, Tink.
We'll save you.
[Hook moaning]
[Crying]
[Sobbing]
[Gasps]
-Stay where you are!
-Please, go right ahead.
Run me through.
You'd be doing me a favor.
[Hook cries]
All right. I give up.
What's your problem?
[Sniffles]
All I've ever wanted...
was to get away
from this dreadful place.
And home
to my dear, sweet mother.
But blast it all...
Peter stole my treasure,
and my men would mutiny...
if I so much as tried
to leave without it.
So here I am.
[Blows]
Stuck in this absurd place.
Oh, oh, oh.
My...sources...
tell me you wish
to return home as well?
Huh, you got that right.
[Sighs]
I guess we're in the same boat.
[Gulps] The same boat!
That's it!
[Gasps] W-what's it?
I'll give you passage home
on my ship...
and you can help me
recover my treasure.
Oh, don't you see?
The treasure's
useless to Peter.
He's not sensible
like you and I.
He's just a boy
who'll never grow up.
Hmm. Tell me about it.
HOOK: And, really,
what other cholice do you have?
It's not as though
you could fly home.
Hmm, well, I suppose.
If it is rightfully yours.
And if it's really
no use to Peter...
Splendid, splendid!
-Wait!
-Hmm?
You must swear
not to harm Peter.
Me? Actually harm Peter Pan?
Perish the thought.
It's all a game, you see.
I shan't harm him.
You have my word.
"I, Captain James Hook...
"do hereby swear...
"not to harm a single hair
on Peter Pan's head."
HOOK: You see?
Ironclad, unbreakable.
[Mwah]
Leave the light on, Mommy...
your baby boy's coming home.
Now, when you've
located the treasure...
just give this a wee toot.
HOOK: You're doing
the right thing, my dear.
I'm your only way home.
[Tinkles weakly]
Jane!
Jane, come on back!
Jane?
[Muffled] Jane!
[Chattering]
[Angry chatter]
Jane!
[Cracking] Jane!
-Jane!
-Jane! Jane!
Jane!
JANE: Peter!
Hmm?
Peter Pan!
Ohh!
-BOTH: There you are!
-[Both chuckle]
BOTH: I've been looking
all over for--
-I, uh--
-I, uh--no, no, no--
-BOTH: You.
-[Muffled]
PETER: I'm awful sorry
for wrecking your book.
Me and the Lost Boys,
we want to do something...
to make it up to you.
We want you to feel like--
well, like you're one of us.
We'll do anything for you.
Ha ha. Honest.
Anything?
Anything at all!
You just name it.
Well, um...
why don't we play a game...
like, maybe...treasure hunt!
Treasure hunt?
That's a great idea!
But you'll have
to think like a Lost Boy.
-Uhh...
-And have fun like a Lost Boy!
[Chuckles]
Tell me what to do.
[Peter crows]
TWIN: Well...
to be one of us...
Yes?
There are some things to know.
What's that?
/ We like to dream all day /
/ And then at night we play /
/ We swing on limbs of trees /
/ Till we wake up the bees /
/ These are the things
we Lost Boys do /
[Buzzing]
/ We swing from rope to rope /
/ We have no use for soap /
/ With open mouths we chomp /
/ On mud ples from the swamp /
/ And then we top it off! /
/ With pudding from a trough /
/ These are the things
we Lost Boys do /
/ We're rolllng in dirt /
/ And we won't
change our shirt /
Ha ha!
/ We're marchlng around /
/ To see what makes a sound /
-[Trumpets]
-[Bonks]
[Bent twang]
[Musical roar]
[Bubbles]
-Eww!
-[Tweets]
[Steel drum notes]
[Honking and drumming]
Dare you to throw that rock!
I'll get a triple skip!
PETER: Dare you
to explore that cave!
JANE: I'll have
an overnight trip!
/ And if you're
feeling scared /
/ I'll have my friends
right there /
/ These are the things
we Lost Boys do /
[Gasps]
[Chuckling]
Ooh!
The treasure!
I found--
HOOK: Now, when you
reach the treasure...
just give this a wee toot.
[Grunts]
PETER:
Ha! Hey, Jane! You did it!
Lost Boys!
Jane found the treasure...
in Dead Man's Cave!
[Boys whooping and yelling]
[Laughs]
Atten-tion!
Ha ha ha!
PETER: Fall in!
[Laughing]
In honor of your downright
unbelievable skill...
at finding hidden treasures...
I now proclaim you, Jane,
a Lost Boy!
[Gasps]
Uh, I mean, a Lost Girl. Ha.
Me? [Gasps]
The very first Lost Girl?
What's the matter?
Don't you want to be?
[Grunts]
Oh, yes.
I'd like that very much, Peter.
SLIGHTLY:
Let's hear it for Jane!
[Cheering]
/ Now that you're one of us /
/ Feel free to sing along /
/ We are so proud of you /
/ That you can do no wrong /
/ And we don't even care /
/ if you pull on our hair /
/ These are the things
that Lost Boys-- /
that Lost Girls-- /
/ These are the things
we love to-- /
[Toot]
[Gasps] No, wait! No!
-Whoa!
-Ohh!
[Evil laughter]
[Pirates whooping and yelling]
The treasure is ours!
[Pirates laughing and yelling]
-Ow!
-Hey!
Let me go!
[Pirates yelling and laughing]
HOOK:
Ha ha! it's time for you...
to meet your maker, Peter Pan!
Stop it! Please!
Sorry, no can do.
And thank you, milady.
I couldn't have done it
without you.
Jane?
I never meant--
Oh, my. Have we let
the kitty out of the bag?
No, wait!
You said no one would get hurt.
You gave your word!
HOOK: And Captain Hook
is a man of his word.
I promised...
I wouldn't harm
a single hair on his head.
-And...
-Ow!
This is the one I won't harm!
Here, you keep it.
The rest of him is mine!
[Pirates laughing]
I didn't do it, Peter!
I never agreed to this.
You're a traitor, Jane.
You lied to me!
And because
you don't believe in fairies...
Tink's light is going out!
[Gasps] Tinker Bell?
[Pirates laughing]
JANE: No.
Peter, I...
I'll save you, Peter! I will!
My dear,
no one can save him now!
[Hook cackling]
[Grunts, gasps]
[Tinkles]
[Panting]
[Weak tinkling]
Tinker Bell!
JANE: Tinker Bell!
Tink! Tink!
[Gasps] Tinker Bell!
It's true.
/ I can flnally see it /
/ Now I have to believe /
Oh. Oh, no.
[Crying]
This is all my fault.
/ All those precious stories /
/ All the world
is made of faith /
/ And trust /
[Sniffles] I'm so sorry.
/ And pixie dust /
[Sobbing]
/ So I'll try /
/ 'Cause I finally believe /
/ I'll try /
/ 'Cause I can see
what you see /
/ I'll try /
/ To fly /
[Crying]
[Chimes tinkling]
Tinker Bell?
Oh, this is wonderful.
Wait until Peter--
Oh, my gosh. Peter.
PIRATE:
Aye: Keel haul the brats!
He's fooled now!
Hey, he's like a pinata!
HOOK: Look at him, Smee.
He's nothing but a child...
and I loathe children.
Cut him down.
Aah!
[All gasp, Peter hits deck]
Any last words, boy?
Let the Lost Boys go.
Oh, they'll go--
right after you--
one by one...
off the end of the plank!
[Pirates laughing]
PETER: Be brave, lads.
Don't let them see you cry.
[All sobbing]
Say your prayers, Peter Pan.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha!
JANE: Not so fast,
you old codfish...
or you'll have to answer to me.
ALL: Hooray!
Jane?
Good heavens! Run!
Run for your lives!
It's...a little girl.
Ah ha ha!
[Laughter]
[Tinkles]
Tinker Bell! You're alive!
Oh, and look, Captain,
a fairy, too. Ha ha ha!
[Pirates laughing]
Heh heh! Oh. Ooh.
[Cow bell rattles]
Ohh!
Don't just stand there,
you fools.
Get the girl. Oh!
Destroy them young tykes!
ALL: Aah!
Smee!
SMEE: I got 'er, Captain.
I got 'er.
-Oh, watch your head.
-Waah!
-Aah!
-Nyaah!
[Pirates yell]
Rarrgh!
I've got you now--Oh! Ohh!
-ALL: Huh?
-[Cheering]
LOST BOY: Yay!
[Pirates growling]
Ohh!
Gimme! Mine! Mine! Big shiny!
Aah!
[Water splashes]
ALL: Hmm?
[Pirates yell]
ALL: Aah!
HOOK: Get her off!
Get her off me!
Waah!
[Wood creaks]
Oh!
Captain?
[Tinkling]
Oh!
Aah!
Aah! Ohh.
-Ha!
-Aah!
I've had just about enough
of your childish games!
HOOK: Unh!
Jane, look out!
-HOOK: Ha ha!
-Aah!
[Gasps]
Unh!
Give up, girl.
[Tinkling]
Never!
Don't you see, Hook?
You'll never win.
Not as long as
there is faith, trust...
and pixie dust.
HOOK: Odd bodkins!
[All cheering]
[Tinkling]
Unbelievable.
Ha ha! Mere child's play.
[Both laugh]
Huh?
[Gasps]
Good show.
Ha! Looks like
I've got the upper hook now.
Game's over, Hook.
I win! Ha!
Waah!
Hey, Captain,
you forgot your anchor.
Waah! Ow! Ooh! Oh! Eee!
Ooh!
[Octopus grunting]
[Moans]
[Bubbling shriek]
Ooh! Ooh! Aah! Ow!
[Loud thud]
Abandon ship!
[Lost Boys yell]
HOOK: Whoa!
[Growling]
Yaah!
Ooh! Uhh! Ha.
Ooh. Ay!
[Gargling moan]
-[Thud]
-Aah!
[Gasps]
Ooh!
HOOK: Help me, please!
Aah!
You know the rules, Hook.
A good captain always
goes down with his ship.
I don't want to be
a good captain!
[Muffled screaming]
OCTOPUS: Uh-oh.
[All gasp]
Look!
HOOK: Smee!
MEN: Uhh!
Uhh...
Ohh!
[Gargling wheeze]
[Octopus slurping]
ALL: Aah!
[Popping]
LOST BOYS:
The codfish! The codfish!
-Hooray!
-Whoo-hoo!
-All right!
Yay!
[Both crow]
LOST BOYS: Yay!
Let's hear it for Jane!
TWINS: The one and only...
ALL: Lost Girl!
Thank you. Thank you.
[All spit]
[Spits]
ALL: Yay!
[Tinkling]
What's wrong, Peter?
Aw, you can fly now.
You can go home.
I can go home.
SLIGHTLY: But...
But...
-But...
-[Pbbt]
-Ha ha ha!
-We'll miss you.
Yeah--a lot.
And I'll miss you--
all of you.
But there's someone
back home who needs me.
And besides...
now I've got great stories
to tell him...
and they'll all be about
Peter Pan and the Lost Boys.
BOYS: Yeah! All right!
Hey! ln that case,
Mademoiselle...
it would be my pleasure
to escort you back to London.
[Laughs] The pleasure
will be all mine, good sir.
Whoa!
Hey!
[Tinkling]
Well, it's a long way home.
Give me your best shot, Tink.
[Tinkling]
[All laughing]
Whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
[Tinkling]
[Bell tolls]
[Gasps]
Oh, my gosh!
Mother. Mother!
Darling, what's wrong?
-JANE: Mommy!
-What is it? Oh!
Oh, you were right.
He is most remarkable.
Who, dear?
Oh, Mother, I'm so sorry.
Oh, if only
I'd listened to you.
[Door opens]
I had a bad dream.
Did you now?
Was it Hook again?
Were those pirates
up to their old tricks again?
Whoa! Hey! [Laughs]
What's going on?
I know how to take care
of that old codfish.
We can do it together, Danny.
-DANNY: We can?
-JANE: The two of us.
-Really?
-I saw him, you know.
Captain Hook kidnapped me.
Stuffed me into
an old dirty bag, he did.
He took me off to Never Land...
and tried to feed me
to a giant octopus.
-[Gasps] Wow.
-[Woof woof]
JANE:
There were pirates everywhere.
[Chimes tinkling]
DANNY: You saw Tinker Bell?
JANE: Uh-huh,
but her light almost went out.
You see, you have
to be very careful.
[Tinkling]
Shh!
Huh?
[Gasps]
Wendy?
Hello, Peter.
You changed.
Not really.
Not ever.
-[Gasps]
-[Tinkling]
Hello, Tinker Bell.
Hmm.
[Tinkling]
[Gasps]
Oh, Tink.
[Both laugh]
Heh.
Madam.
Ha ha ha!
Good-bye, Wendy.
Good-bye, Peter.
Wow, look at him!
It's Peter Pan!
[Woof woof]
[Sighs] I'll always believe
in you, Peter Pan.
[Truck arrives]
DRIVER: Here we go, then.
EDWARD: Thanks, mate:
I appreciate it.
JANE: Daddy?
-Daddy!
-Edward.
JANE: Daddy's home!
[Excited chatter]
[Dog barks]
-Come on, Tink. Let's go home.
-[Bell rings]
[Tinkling]
[Chime rings]
[Music playing]
/ Do you believe in magic /
/ in a young girl's heart /
/ How the music can free her /
/ Whenever it starts /
/ And it's maglc /
/ if the music can move you /
/ And hold you so tight /
/ That it never can lose you /
/ Your feet start tappin'/
/ And you can't seem to find /
/ if it's really real /
/ Or just a state of mind /
/ if you believe in magic /
/ Just close those big eyes /
/ And think all the wonderful
thoughts that arise /
/ And maybe /
/ if you dream it just right /
/ Your toes will be over
the treetops tonight /
/ And you'll be flyin'/
/ And from there you can see /
/ How the magic's in you /
/ That the magic's in me /
/ if you believe in magic /
/ Come along with me /
/ We'll dance until morning /
/ Till it's just you and me /
/ And maybe /
/ if the music is right /
/ I'll meet you tomorrow
so late at night /
/ And we'll go dancin', baby,
then you'll see /
/ How the magic's in music /
/ And the music's in me /
/ Belleve in the magic
of a young girl's soul /
/ Believe in the magic
of rock and roll /
that can set you free /
/ Oh /
/ Dream on,
dream on, dream on /
/ Talkin' about maglc /
/ Dream on, everybody /
/ Do you believe in magic /
/ Dream on,
dream on, dream on /
/ Do you believe, believer /
/ Dream on, everybody /
/ Oh, talkin' about magic /
/ Dream on,
dream on, dream on /
/ Do you believe in magic /
/ Dream on, everybody /
/ Do you believe, believer /
/ Dream on,
dream on, dream on /
/ Talkin' about magic /
/ Dream on, everybody /
/ Do you believe in magic /
/ Dream on,
dream on, dream on /
/ Do you believe, believer /
/ Dream on, everybody /
/ Talkin' about magic /
/ Dream on,
dream on, dream on /
/ Do you believe, believer /
/ Dream on, everybody /
/ I am not a child now /
/ I can take care of myself /
/ I mustn't
let them down, now /
/ Mustn't let them
see me cry /
/ I'm flne /
/ I'm too tired to listen /
/ I'm too old to believe /
/ All these chlidish stories /
/ There is no such thing
as faith /
/ And trust /
/ And pixie dust /
/ I try /
/ But it's so hard
to believe /
/ I try /
/ But I can't see
what you see /
/ I try /
/ My whole world is changing /
/ I don't know where to turn /
/ I can't leave you waiting /
/ But I can't stay
and watch the city burn /
/ Mmm, watch it burn /
/ 'Cause I try /
/ But it's so hard
to believe /
/ I try /
/ But I can't see
what you see /
/ I try /
/ I try and try
to understand /
/ The distance in between /
/ The love I feel
and the things I fear /
/ And every single dream /
/ I can finally see it /
/ Now I have to believe /
/ All those precious stories /
/ All the world
is made of faith /
/ And trust /
/ And pixie dust /
/ So I'll try /
/ 'Cause I finally believe /
/ I'll try /
/ 'Cause I can see
what you see /
/ I'll try /
/ I wlll try /
/ To fly /