Old Yeller, Old Yeller
Old Yeller
Here, Yeller
Come back, Yeller
Best doggone dog in the West
Old Yeller was a mongrel
An ugly lop-eared mongrel
Fancy-free without a family tree
But he could up and do it
And prove there's nothin' to it
And that's how a good dog should be
Here, Yeller
Come back, Yeller
Best doggone dog in the West
Old Yeller was a hunter
A rarin', tearin' hunter
In any chase he knew just how to run
And when he hunted trouble
He always found it double
And that's when Old Yeller had fun
Here, Yeller
Come back, Yeller
Best doggone dog in the West
Old Yeller was a fighter
A rootin', tootin' fighter
In any scrap he knew just what to do
Knew what to do
A rough and ready feller
Although his coat was yeller
His bold Texas heart was true blue
True blue
Here, Yeller
Come back, Yeller
Best doggone dog in the West
Here, Yeller
Come back, Yeller
Best doggone dog in the West
Best doggone dog
In the west
- What's Pop gonna sell our steers for?
- For money, of course.
- What's money?
- It's what you buy things with.
What do you mean by "buy things"?
Well, if you got money,
you give it to people for stuff.
They say you can get anything for money.
Anything? What's it look like?
Well, I never seen but one piece,
a dollar bill Papa had. It's paper.
- What'd Papa get with this dollar?
- Nothin'. It wasn't no good.
But you just said you could
get anything with money.
Well, ya can.
But Papa's was Confederate.
- What's Confederate money?
- Confederate money?
Well, it's...
- Well?
- Don't you ever run outta questions?
I wish you didn't have to go.
Right now I feel
sorta the same way, but...
I put 100 head of our steers
in that pool herd
and in Kansas, we can get, maybe,
$4, $5 a head for 'em.
- Cash money, too.
- I know, but...
Ain't nothin' to be sad about,
Katie girl.
When you think on it, we're lucky.
There's us and the young 'uns,
good land,
plenty of water, game for the killin'.
Cash money is all we need
to get a tight tail-hold on the world.
Will you really be gone three months?
All of three months, maybe four.
Now, honey,
it ain't nothin' to cry about.
It's just that we've
never been separated before.
You know what I'm gonna do
when I sell them steers?
What?
I'm gonna get you a store-bought dress.
The first one you've had
since we come to Texas.
Let's see.
Is this about the right size?
Papa! I aim to go with ya!
You better stay here
and take care of your mama.
Aw, gee, Papa.
But I wanna go. I tell ya, I wanna go!
- I wanna go! Wanna go!
- Arliss.
- You ride a piece with me, Travis.
- All right, Papa.
I wanna go! But I wanna go!
I can ride them old cows same as you.
You can't go on no cow drive, boy.
Them Injuns would scalp you for sure.
- You think so, Papa?
- I'm certain.
Good-bye, Katie.
Good-bye, Jim dear.
Well, son, while I'm gone,
you'll be the man of the house.
Yes, sir.
There'll be the pigs to mark,
fresh meat to shoot.
And mainly, there's the corn patch.
If you don't work it right,
we'll be without bread this winter.
It's sure enough a man-sized job.
Think you can handle Old Jumper
when he's hooked to a plow?
I'll handle him,
or I'll bust his jawbone with a club.
Well, all right, boy.
I'll see you this fall.
- Papa, you ain't forgettin' the horse?
- What horse?
Now, Papa, you know I've been
achin' all over for a horse to ride.
I told you time and again.
Well, what you're needin'
worse than a horse is a good dog.
Yes, sir, but what I'm wantin' worst
is a good horse.
All right, boy. You act a man's part,
and I'll bring you a man's horse.
Wanna shake on it?
Whoa.
Whoa!
Whoa, Jumper! Whoa!
Whoa! Whoa, Jumper!
Get away from that mule!
Let that mule alone!
Papa ain't gone a full day
and look what a mess.
- It's not your fault, son.
- Maybe not, but...
Get, you crazy fool dog! Get!
I know one thing.
That old dog better not come around
here while I got me a gun in my hands.
- Who busted down the fence?
- Where have you been?
Bear huntin'. Who busted the fence down?
- Danged old stray dog.
- Dog? Where is he?
You won't ever see him.
I done rocked him clean off this place.
But I need me a good huntin' dog.
Arliss, go wash up
before supper's all cold.
- Aw, Mama.
- Go on!
- What do you got in that pocket?
- Nothin'.
- Let's see what you got this time.
- Aw, Mama.
Come on. Come on.
Oh, Arliss! How can you even
touch those ugly things?
They aren't ugly.
Look it here at his belly,
how soft and smooth and pretty it is.
I know. Everything you catch is pretty.
But take him outta here.
You can't keep him in the house.
You mean I gotta throw him away?
And everything else
you got in those pockets.
My frog, too?
Arliss, what all have you got
in those pockets?
Aw, Mama, it's just
a little old garter snake.
I don't care. Get it out of here!
Arliss, if you don't stop catchin' things
and bringin' 'em into the house,
I'm gonna switch you good.
And don't you ever,
ever pick up a snake again.
- Ya understand?
- Yes'm.
Now, go out there
and wash up for supper.
Little old garter snake ain't harmful.
If he'll pick up one kind of snake,
he'll pick up another.
Next time it could be a rattler.
I wish he did have a good dog,
like Old Bell.
When you were little, Old Bell
wouldn't let you near anything harmful.
Ain't another dog in this world
like Old Bell was.
Sure would've made short work
of that old, yeller stray.
Mama.
I was just thinkin'.
About your papa.
I guess he's eaten his breakfast by now.
Probably wanted to get an early start.
I wonder how far they got yesterday.
Oh, I don't know.
Papa says 15 mile a day
is a long haul for a trail herd.
I guess he made about 10 mile.
Mush is about ready.
If you want middling meat with it,
better go out and cut some down.
All right.
Mama, what happened
to the middling meat?
Why, you no-account, thievin' rascal!
Get outta here!
A dog!
All right!
You hit my dog
and I'll wear you to a frazzle.
Travis, Arliss, whatcha doin' out there?
- Let go of my stick!
- Arliss! Arliss.
Don't you dare hit your brother.
He was tryin' to kill my dog.
He's not your dog,
and I never even touched him.
Where on earth did he come from?
He's that same stray dog
that wrecked the fence.
Stole that big side
of middling meat there too!
He's my dog.
Ain't nobody gonna try to hurt him.
Well.
Looks like we've got us a dog.
Mama, you don't mean we're gonna
keep that old, ugly yeller dog
after what he done?
He isn't a ugly yeller dog.
He's a pretty yeller dog.
Come on now.
Come on.
Why not let Arliss claim him?
And have him stampedin' Jumper again?
You could break him of that.
He's a thief, Mama!
He'll steal us blind.
Most creatures will steal
when they're hungry enough.
All right, but I still don't want him!
Now, Travis, you're not bein' fair.
You had a dog when you were little,
and Arliss has never had one.
He's too little for you to play with.
He gets lonely.
After breakfast, you can
take to the woods and get us a deer.
And, Travis, do some thinkin'
on what I said
about Arliss and that old, yeller dog.
Come on, boy.
Jumper, you jug head!
A bunch of bobwhites,
and you act like you ain't got the brains
of a blind goose in a hail storm.
Arliss, get that dirty,
old dog outta our drinkin' water!
Aw, mind your own business!
Get outta there!
You quit rockin' my dog!
Quit chuckin' them rocks at me!
Stop it, Arliss! Stop it!
You rock my dog again
- and I'll bust your head open!
- Arliss!
Arliss!
Travis, what are you doin'
to your little brother?
Him and that dirty, old, yeller dog
were wallowing in our drinkin' water.
He was rockin' my dog!
Look here, young rooster.
If you wanna keep outta trouble,
you start minding your big brother.
You mean I gotta mind him?
He ain't my papa.
You start mindin' him just the same.
Now go inside
and take off those wet clothes.
What I oughta do is get me a sprout
and give him one good thrashing.
Take it easy, son.
He's only a little boy.
Papa wouldn't want that old dog
in our drinkin' water.
Papa wouldn't have started
a rock fight with Arliss either.
I never started no rock fight. He...
Arliss rocks me. Mama blesses me out.
And you. You get off scot-free.
What I oughta do is
run you clean off this place.
You touch a bite of this meat,
and come mornin' I'm gonna
shoot you right between the eyes.
I'll be dogged.
Mama? Did you
feed that old dog anything?
Well, no, I forgot to.
Been so long since we had a dog.
Well, he's sure gone
and rustled up some grub somewhere.
He ain't touched a bite of that venison.
You might know
he'd be too smart for that.
You could've put it on the ground
and he wouldn't have touched it.
You better get dressed if you want
an early start cuttin' fence posts.
Yes'm.
Come on, Yeller boy, get him!
Get him, Yeller! There he is!
There he goes, over there!
Missed him!
That's got him! Good for you, boy!
Mama! Mama, look at the fish
that I caught! Ain't he a whopper?
Oh, Arliss!
You're all wet and muddy again.
- But, Mama, I had to.
- Had to?
Had to dive way down
deep under to catch this fish.
He was way down deep under
where there was this cave
and it was real dark and muddy.
And there's about a million other
fish and they all tried to eat me.
And I had to throw rocks at 'em.
And then there's
these two big snakes and...
Sounds like that cottontail
you roped this mornin'.
But I did rope him, didn't I, Mama?
He came runnin' by,
and I roped him right by the ears.
Well, you certainly brought home
a rabbit, and now this big catfish.
You're gettin' to be
as good a hunter as Travis.
Here, Mama.
Come on, Yeller! Come on, boy!
Yeah!
Mama, you know them
is just big windies Arliss is tellin'.
Now, Travis, let him
tell his stories the way he wants to.
But, Mama, I just seen that old,
yeller dog catch this fish.
Arliss is just a little boy
with a big imagination.
Won't hurt him to let him use it.
We keep that old, yeller dog much longer
and it's gonna make
Arliss the biggest liar in Texas!
Here, boy, come and get some bread.
Here.
Come on.
A little closer.
Come on. I'll give you some more bread.
Come on.
Come on. Come on.
What's that?
Come on, boy.
Arliss, turn it loose!
Arliss, watch out!
Turn it loose!
Go on, ya old fool, before she kills ya.
Oh, you crazy, wonderful dog!
He acts like it's a great big romp,
doesn't he, Travis?
Crazy as a bull bat.
But he's a heap more dog
than I ever had him figured for.
Just listen to those
songbirds this mornin'...
Singin' their heads off.
It's like the year
your Papa and I settled here.
We meant to build over
at the Salt Licks settlement
where it would've been safer
from the Indians, but...
That last day, we camped by the spring.
And the bee myrtle was in blossom
and full of singin' birds, like now.
And it was all so pretty,
I just couldn't go on.
And I said to your Papa,
"Jim, this is it.
"This is home."
Hello, the house!
It's Bud Searcy and Lisbeth, too.
You might know he'd land
right at mealtime.
Howdy, Miss Coates. Howdy do?
Howdy, boy. How's everybody?
- Hello, Mr. Searcy.
- Slide down, child.
Hello, Lisbeth.
Just dropped over to see
if there's anything I could do.
Travis, take this pony to the corn crib
and strip the saddle gear off him.
- Yes, Mr. Searcy.
- Might feed him a bit of corn
while you're at it, boy.
Won't you come and set a while?
Well, I believe I will shade
up for a spell, Miss Coates.
Come on, Lisbeth. Hot, ain't it?
We don't get some rain pretty soon,
this country's gonna burn up bad.
Corn crop ain't gonna be worth nothin'
more than a whirlwind nubbins.
Some folks'll be scrapin' the bottom of
their meal barrels come wintertime.
This here's hanged too long.
Lisbeth, honey, run down to the spring
and fetch your poor old pappy
a bucket of fresh water.
I'll tell you, Miss Coates...
It's a heavy responsibility
ridin' herd on the settlement
while the menfolks is gone.
Wears a man right down to a frazzle.
But I ain't complainin', though.
I was chose for this job
and I'll get her done.
I, kinda figured to head up
that cow drive to Kansas myself.
But when man after man
called me all spoke private like...
Beggin' me to stay behind,
look after you womenfolks
and the young ones, I seen my duty.
Knowed I was bein' called on
for a bigger job.
Jim said you were gonna protect us all.
Mighty lucky thing I done it, too.
Know what happened the other day?
That fool kid of Jed Simpson's
shot at a bunch of javelina hogs
and wounded one of 'em.
Set it too squealin'. Ha! Be dogged
that the rest of them didn't tree that boy.
Kept him up there too till I happened
along and seed what a pickle he was in.
Of course I couldn't chase
them pesky javelinas off.
But I did go tell that boy's Mama where
he was, so she could rest easy
till the varmints left out
and give him a chance to climb down.
Yep. Lookin' out after you womenfolks
and the young ones
sure keeps a man a-hoppin' around.
Biggest bother I've had, though, lately
is the thievin' what's been
goin' on at Salt Licks.
Meat stole out of smoke houses.
Hen's nests gettin' robbed.
- Mama, I'm hung...
- Hush, baby. Mr. Searcy's talkin'.
Womenfolks losin' bread what they
set out in their windows to cool.
- Sounds like some varmint.
- There ain't no varmint that clever, boy.
Mama, I'm hungry.
- When we gonna ea...
- Arliss.
I told you, don't butt in.
Mr. Searcy's talkin'.
That's all right, Miss Coates.
Ain't nothin' like a little old boy
to know when it's time to eat.
Well, I guess it is gettin'
on toward dinnertime.
Travis, will you go down to the corn
patch and pick us some roastin' ears?
Now, just a minute, Miss Coates.
That boy need help to tote all that corn.
Yes, sir.
Lisbeth, go along with Travis.
Be sure you pick out ears
what is sweet and juicy.
Why, coons been in this corn!
Them thievin' rascals!
You'll have to take to
doggin' 'em overnight.
I got me just the dog for it.
Old Yeller will wipe up the ground
with them pesky varmints.
You think he can't do it?
Oh, no. It... It ain't that.
Well, I didn't wanna
tell you at the house, but...
It was him what done it.
What done what?
What stole all them eggs
and bread and meat and stuff.
You mean Old Yeller?
I seen him suck a batch of eggs.
Seen him swipe a pan of
Grandma's corn bread too.
- But I ain't gonna tell.
- I bet you do.
No, I won't.
Wasn't goin' to even before
I knowed he was your dog.
How come?
Because Miss Priss is gonna have pups.
Your dog'll be their papa.
And I wouldn't want him
to get shot for stealin'.
Just an old arrowhead I picked up.
Comanche, Papa said.
Well, you can have it.
I won't never, never tell.
When you git right down to hogs,
just about the best eatin' there is alive.
And I reckon just about the meanest
critter alive go after his meat.
Cut you 14 different ways
before you can get fixed to rot.
They scare me to death.
Always dread the time when Jim
comes to do the markin'.
Yep, hogs is bad, mighty bad. I had me
an uncle once down in east Texas,
tangled a bad hog, he did.
Got cut all to pieces.
Kill him?
Kill him? Why, it killed him
deader than a doornail.
Mr. Searcy, I roped me a rabbit once.
Arliss, be quiet. Mr. Searcy's talkin'.
Well, I did. A mean old bitin' one.
Well now, boy,
that's really doin' some ropin'.
You know, speakin' of ropin', I always
done my hog work from up a tree.
Heap safer that way.
How can you work hogs from a tree?
Why, it's strict as a whistle, boy.
Pick you out a tree with a low
hanging limb, but still out of hog reach.
Get your dog to rally
them hogs around the tree.
Reach down your loop,
pull up your pig and go to work on him.
By golly!
That sounds like it might work.
Work? Why, of course it works!
Them old hogs can fuss and charge
around all they please, but up a tree
you're as safe as at home in bed.
Travis, boy, you go fetch my pony,
and we'll be pullin' out for home.
I've got a powerful lot to do
before supper time.
It was right neighborly like
of you to feed us, Miss Coates.
Now, don't you fret yourself at all
while your man's gone.
We'll be lookin' in on you again before
you know it. Bye, boy. Bye, Miss Coates.
Bye, Lisbeth.
Bye.
No wonder they don't want him
on no cow drive.
By the time he finished eatin' and visitin'
with everyone this side of Abilene,
them cows would be dead of old age.
Mama, Lisbeth says it's Old Yeller
what's been doin'
all that stealin' out in Salt Licks.
Claimed she catched him at it.
Why, the old rogue.
We'll have to break him of that,
or else everyone
in Salt Licks'll be mad at us.
Somebody'll shoot him! Yeller!
Come here!
You old rascal. You been stealin'!
Maybe we better
take to pennin' him overnight.
I reckon we won't
have to bother for a while.
Listen! I'm gonna keep you
so dang busted busy
you won't have time to go off prowlin'!
No, you don't!
We're stayin' right here and
keepin' them coons run out, you hear?
Look at all them stars, Yeller.
Bushels of 'em.
I wonder if maybe Papa's lying out there
on the trail somewhere,
lookin' at 'em, too.
I wish I was with him,
way off yonder,
up in Kansas...
Seein' all that...
Big...
Country.
Get 'em, Yeller!
Wipe up the ground with 'em!
Yeller sure has been givin'
them coons the mortal fits.
- You tired, son?
- No, ma'am.
Where's Old Rose?
She didn't come up last night.
I figured she hid out somewhere
and had her calf.
I guess I better go hunt her up.
Come on, Yeller.
Remember now, if she's had her calf,
she'll be on the fight.
Come on, Yeller!
Quiet, Yeller! Don't rile her!
That's gettin' her, boy!
Get her, Yeller! Bust her again!
Try it again, sister,
and Old Yeller'll bust you wide open.
All right, Yeller, get her home.
All right, old sister, you take it easy.
I aim to milk you if I have to
break every bone in your body.
So now, Rose, you know
as well as I we're not gonna hurt ya.
Now, Rose, you take it easy.
You ain't got a chance, sister.
You're done milked
and you don't know it.
I know what!
Here, Yeller.
Son, you bring that dog in here
and Rose will go crazy.
All right, Yeller, hold her there.
Well, if that don't beat all.
I never saw such a dog.
And you won't never see
another one like him.
Hello, the house!
I thought maybe it was Papa.
Mornin', ma'am. I'm Burn Sanderson
from down near San 'Tone.
Runnin' me a few head
of cattle over on Devil's Creek.
Yes, Mr. Sanderson?
Bud Searcy told me about an old,
stray dog you had.
Sounded like it might be the one I lost.
You mean a... Big, yeller dog?
That's him all right.
The worst egg-sucker
and camp-robber you ever laid eyes on.
Steal you blind while you're watchin'.
But there never was a better
cow dog born, or a hog dog either.
Travis, go call Old Yeller to the house.
- But, Mama...
- Travis!
Yes, Mama.
Won't you get down, Mr. Sanderson?
Thank you, ma'am.
Arliss.
- What do you want?
- Bring Old Yeller to the house.
- What's the matter?
- You'll find out.
Ma'am, you and the boys
don't have much protection out here.
Bad as I need that old dog,
I could give you a loan of him
till your man comes home.
No, Mr. Sanderson. If he's
your dog, better take him now.
Well, maybe you're right, ma'am.
Come on, boy.
Why, you prowlin' old rascal.
Well, good-bye, ma'am.
I'm sure much obliged.
Come on, Yeller.
That's my dog! You can't take my dog!
You can't take my dog!
- Whoa, boy!
- You can't take my dog!
Arliss, aren't you ashamed,
throwin' rocks at that man?
I'll bust him with another
if he takes my dog off!
Arliss!
Maybe he's right, ma'am.
Man comes to take my dog off,
I'd throw a fit too.
Let me talk to this boy a minute.
Well, boy?
Go on, Arliss.
Go on.
Whatcha got in that pocket?
Come on. Let's take a look.
Why, ain't he a jim-dandy.
- Finest lookin' horned toad I ever seen.
- What about my dog?
You mean you really want
that thievin', old, yeller dog?
I sure do.
Well, then maybe we can
do some swappin'.
I've been wantin' mighty bad to get me
a big horned toad like you got there.
You mean you'd swap me Old Yeller
for this here horny toad?
Well, now, that's a fine horny toad,
and I want him bad.
But on the other hand,
he ain't hardly as big as a dog.
- Seems like I oughta get a little to boot.
- Like what?
Well, I'll tell you how it is.
I've been in that cow camp
starvin' on my own cookin' so long,
I don't hardly throw a shadow no more.
Now, if you could talk your mama
into feedin' me one,
big woman-cooked meal,
why, I figure it and that
horned toad would be worth
at least a lop-eared Yeller dog,
don't you?
Well, I guess so.
Will you feed him, Mama?
Of course I will.
All right, I'll swap ya.
Here, boy!
He's all yours, boy.
Come on, Yeller. Come on, boy.
Hey. What about my toad?
Come on, boy.
Come on.
I haven't ate like this...
Since the time I splurged on a big feed
at the Menger Hotel in San 'Tone.
Well, I'm happy you enjoyed it,
Mr. Sanderson.
Well, ma'am, I guess
I better be gettin' back to camp.
Come with me, boy,
while I get my horse settled.
Yes, sir.
When Mr. Coates gets back,
I want you to come and see us.
I want him to meet ya.
That's mighty nice of ya, ma'am.
Thank you.
Good-bye, boy.
Take good care of that old, yeller dog.
Yes, sir. And you take care
of my horny toad.
I will. Bye, ma'am.
Good-bye.
Didn't tell your Mama this.
Didn't want to fret her.
But there's a plague of hydrophobia
in these parts.
Hydrophobia? You sure?
I've done shot two wolves,
a fox and a skunk that had it.
I wanted to warn you
not to take any chances.
Well, I don't know if I could tell
if a critter's got the sickness.
You can't hardly tell at first.
Not until they get to the point
of slobberin' and staggerin' around.
You see a critter in that fix,
you know for sure.
But you wanna watch
for others that ain't that far along.
Now you take a bobcat and a fox...
You know they'll run
if they get the chance.
But when one don't run,
or maybe makes fight at you,
why, you shoot him and quick.
After he's bitten you, it's too late.
You done with your
hog markin' for this year?
No. I'm aimin' to start tomorrow.
You watch them hogs same as everything.
I know your papa left you
in charge of things while he's gone.
And I figure you're
man enough to handle the job.
Don't scare you, does it, boy?
No, sir.
Well, yes, sir,
it scares me a little bit,
but I'll sure do like you told me.
That's a way a man talks, son.
Hog tracks, Yeller! Get 'em, boy!
Hold 'em, boy!
All right, Yeller.
Fetch 'em right under here.
Over bit the right ear.
Under slope the left.
All right, pig,
now you're wearin' the Coates' mark.
Easy.
Whoa-ooo!
Yeller! Yeller!
Yeller.
Yeller!
Oh, Yeller.
Oh, Yeller. You're all cut to pieces.
You're gonna be all right, ya hear?
I'll get Mama.
Mama'll fix you up for sure.
Come on, boy. Gonna put you in here.
Come on, Yeller. Want them hogs
to come back and get ya?
You gotta stay here till I get back.
I mean it, boy. I'm comin' back.
I promise.
Come on now.
I'll help you to bed.
Mama, we gotta go back after Old Yeller.
You're not goin' any place until that leg
gets well. I've doctored hog cuts before.
This one of yours could be as
dangerous as a rattlesnake bite.
Mama, you don't understand.
I promised Old Yeller, and I'm goin'!
Travis!
- Travis!
- I aim to go after Old Yeller.
He'll die without help!
All right, then. We'll all go.
Mama, them buzzards ain't got him!
What's a matter with Yeller, Mama?
Who stopped him up in this hole?
We've come to get him out, baby.
But first, I wonder if you'd
do somethin' for me.
- What?
- Go catch me a green-striped lizard.
We passed one back there a piece.
Prettiest I ever saw.
Sure, Mama. I'll catch him.
We're gonna have to hurry
if we wanna get him patched up
before Arliss gets back.
Oh, Travis.
I didn't know it was gonna be this bad.
Them hogs would've never touched him.
He was keepin' 'em off of me.
We'll have to sew him up.
Go jerk me a hair
out of Old Jumper's tail.
Yes, Yeller.
Take your ax and go cut
two long poles for a litter.
The sooner we get him home, the better.
Mama, I got your lizard.
- Ain't he pretty?
- Ooh, yes. He really is.
Now if you'll just keep him for me until
we get home. We're gonna play a game.
- What kind of a game?
- We're playin' Old Yeller is sick.
- You're gonna take care of him.
- Is that why he's all wrapped up?
That's right. Now, you're gonna
ride here and hold him.
Like we was two sick injuns?
And you make sure he don't fall off.
On account of
he's a sicker Injun than me?
That's right. Now remember,
don't lean on him
and don't play with him.
He's a very, very sick Indian.
Come on, Jumper.
Mama?
Them prickly pear roots
gonna make Travis well?
I hope so, son.
Mama?
When you're done, will you play with me?
I'm sorry, Arliss. I'm too busy now.
You go out in the backyard and play.
But I tell you, there ain't nothin'
to do out in that old backyard.
Now, Arliss, you stop it,
and go outside this minute.
Hello, the house!
It's Mr. Searcy!
Ain't he pretty? Is he for me?
Partly. Mostly he's for Travis.
But Travis can't play with no puppy.
He's sick.
- Sick?
- Him and Old Yeller. Hog cut.
Good mornin', Mr. Searcy.
Hello, Lisbeth.
What's this about that boy of yours
gettin' hog cut?
- Whatcha doctorin' with?
- Prickly pear root.
Miss Coates, I brung somethin'
for Travis. Can I take it to him?
Go right in there, honey.
Now if you'll excuse me, Mr. Searcy,
I'm makin' up some new poultice.
You know, it's right providential
I come along when I did.
'Tain't nothin' better
than a prickly pear poultice,
providin' a body knows how to fix it.
You hurt pretty bad?
I'm all right. It'd take more
than them old hogs to kill me.
Well, I... I brung you a surprise.
One of Miss Priss' pups.
Thems was born in a badger hole.
Seven of 'em.
This 'un's the best of the bunch.
See? He don't holler
when you hold him up by the neck hide.
Papa says that means he's a good dog.
That don't mean nothin'.
If his mouth's black inside,
that's what counts.
Well, anyhow, I...
I brung him to ya.
Well, I got me a dog. Old Yeller.
Well, why don't you give him to Arliss?
He'll like him.
Here, you can have him.
Golly!
- Golly!
- That's the secret, Miss Coates,
a-beatin' them roots
till they're all soft and squishy...
Mama, look at the little,
bitty puppy Lisbeth give me.
Oh.
Sure cut up, ain't ya, boy?
Clean to the bone, looks like.
That there poultice is sure the stuff
to suck out the poison,
provided, of course,
he ain't got hydrophoby.
- "Hydrophoby"?
- Could be. It's all over the countryside.
Stuff dyin' like flies.
Foxes, wolves, polecats, hogs...
- Hogs?
- Hogs can get it.
Same as that there boy
or that old, yeller dog there.
Seen either one of them foamin'
at the mouth, shown any signs of fits?
- Fits of temper?
- Of course not!
Well, you better keep a close watch
on them. Liable to show up at any time.
Recollect had me an uncle once
down in east Texas.
Got mad dog bit, he did.
Knowed he was bound to die.
Chained himself to a sweet gum tree.
Stayed right there
till sickness took ahold.
Mr. Searcy, please.
But it's the gospel truth, Miss Coates!
He went to snarlin' and snappin'
at everything in sight.
He run at his woman
and young 'uns, tryin' to bite 'em.
He'd have done it too
if that chain hadn't held him back.
Stayed right there
till he died of the slobberin' fits.
They buried him
under that sweet gum tree...
Mr. Searcy, that's enough!
Not another word!
Biggest, nicest funeral you ever did...
What do you mean,
tellin' an ugly story like that
to a boy who's just been hog cut?
Now, Miss Coates, I was just
tryin' to give a word of warnin'.
Reckon if I can't be
of no more help around here,
I'll be makin' tracks for home.
Help. There are plenty of ways
a man could help around here.
By doin' what, Miss Coates?
Like hitchin' up the mule
and gatherin' in the corn crop
before the deer eat it up,
or the blowin' rain rot it in the field!
Now, don't you fret yourself
at all about that corn crop, Miss Coates.
I'll be glad to take care
of that. Lisbeth?
Yes, Papa?
Lisbeth, honey, Miss Coates here,
she's in kind of a bind.
Ain't got her corn in the crib yet.
Figured I'll leave you behind
to help her with the job.
Mr. Searcy, Lisbeth's nothin'
but a little girl.
Yeah, well, she ain't much for size,
but she's just like her old pappy...
Stout and willin'!
Now, don't you forget, Miss Coates.
If there's any other thing I can do for you,
don't you be bashful about tellin' me.
I'm on call day or night.
Bye! Bye.
Oh!
I do believe you are cooler.
Mama, don't let
what Mr. Searcy said bother you.
I'm gonna be all right!
I'm sure you will be.
I know, Mama. Mama, I know.
I got a good look at them hogs.
Now, them hogs was mean,
but they weren't mad.
Travis, we got lots of corn.
Me, Mama and Lisbeth.
Ain't that Old Rose I hear bawlin'?
She's been actin' flighty lately,
like she was scared of her own shadow.
And this mornin' she wouldn't
let her calf suckle neither.
I think, maybe,
she's got a bit of pea vine.
No, Mama, it can't be pea vine.
Not this late in the year.
Oh.
The poor thing.
She's blind sick.
Mama, that cow's got hydrophoby.
Hydrophoby? Oh, no, Travis.
Mr. Sanderson said when they stagger
and slobber around, you know for sure.
I'll go get my gun.
Let's get finished
and go burn the carcass.
If the varmints get at it,
could be that might spread the disease.
I'm hungry.
Well, I'll go rustle you up
some bread and milk.
- How come you shot Old Rose?
- She was sick.
Well, you were sick too.
How come they didn't shoot you?
Well, that's somethin' different.
Where'll Rose go now she's dead?
Nowhere, I reckon. She's just dead.
- Will she go to heaven?
- I don't much reckon.
Ain't there no cows in heaven
for the angels to milk?
Well, how do I know?
Here's your supper.
How fer off is heaven?
Oh, I don't know. A fer piece, I guess.
Is heaven as far off as Papa went?
A heap further than that.
- Where'd Papa go to?
- Kansas.
Arliss, quit eatin'
with that nasty old pup!
Well, he's hungry too!
Travis! Bring your gun!
That's Mama! What's the matter with her?
You stay in this house,
Arliss, you hear?
Travis! Travis!
Travis! Bring your gun!
Travis! Travis! A wolf!
Mama!
- Don't let Arliss come down here.
- I'm comin', Arliss!
- What happened?
- It was so sudden, I don't hardly know.
- The wolf came leapin' out at us.
- Lucky you had Old Yeller.
It was lucky for us, son,
but it weren't lucky for Old Yeller.
He's chewed up some,
but he ain't bad hurt.
No wolf in his right mind
would've jumped us at the fire,
not even a loafer wolf.
That wolf was mad.
I'll... Shoot him...
If you can't.
But either way, we've got it to do.
Mama, listen.
Old Yeller just saved your life,
and Lisbeth's too!
And he saved mine and Arliss'! We can't!
We don't know for certain.
I'll pen him up where he can't get out.
And then we'll wait.
We can't just shoot him
like he was nothin'.
Don't you understand?
All right, son.
If you think there's a chance.
Hear that?
Well, now, that sounds
like a healthy dog to me.
Take a look at him, Mama.
See for yourself.
He sure looks fine, all right.
Two whole weeks,
and nary a sign of a thing.
Think we could let him out?
No, son, not yet.
They say sometimes
it takes a month to tell.
Now, I told you,
if everything's all right,
we'll let Old Yeller out come Saturday.
But, Mama, why not now?
No, we've waited this long.
I guess we can stand it
another couple of days.
Aw, Mama.
Here we are, boy. More grub.
Yeller?
What's the matter, boy?
Come on. It's time to eat.
- How is he tonight?
- All right, I reckon.
- Are you sure?
- I said he was all right, didn't I?
I guess you wouldn't like it, either,
if you had to stay shut up in a corn crib!
You ain't gonna keep my dog
locked up in that crib no more!
You stay away from that dog.
You understand?
It's time for you to go to bed, Arliss.
- Aw, Mama.
- Do as I say.
Yes'm.
Don't you worry, boy.
I'll get you outta here.
- Where's Arliss?
- I don't know.
Arliss!
Arliss! Don't open that door!
Arliss! Keep away from that door!
Arliss!
No, Mama.
There's no hope for him now, Travis.
He's sufferin'.
You know we've got to do it.
I know, Mama.
But he was my dog.
I'll do it.
Hello, the house!
Papa! Ya done came home!
Hiya, boy.
Ain't them injuns scalped you yet?
- Papa, what'd you bring me?
- I brought you somethin', all right.
Just hold your potatoes
while I go kiss your Mama.
Jim! Oh, Jim!
What'd you bring me home, Papa?
Where is it?
Hear this, Katie? Money. Cash money.
First we've had since the war.
That ain't all.
- What?
- I got that dress.
- Prettiest thing you ever seen.
- Oh!
And a fancy pair of shoes to go with it.
- Gee-whiz!
- Put it on, son.
There you are.
All right, Chief. Let's hit the warpath.
Come on, boy!
Oh, Jim!
It's lovely.
I been achin' to see it on you.
Where's Travis?
I wanna get a look at his face
when he sees the horse I brung him.
Him and Lisbeth Searcy
are over at North Hill...
Burying Old Yeller.
Old Yeller?
Come in the house
and I'll tell you about it.
Travis?
If you could just come
to like the pup...
He... He's part Old Yeller.
He may be part Old Yeller,
but he ain't Old Yeller.
Your mama told me about the dog.
Come sit down, son.
That was rough, son.
As rough a thing as
I ever heard tell of.
But I'm mighty proud
of how my boy stood up to it.
Couldn't ask no more of a grown man.
Thing to do now is... Try and forget it.
Go on bein' a man.
How, Pa? How you gonna
forget somethin' like that?
I guess I don't quite mean that.
Reckon it's not a thing you can forget.
Maybe not even a thing you wanna forget.
What I'm tryin' to say is...
- Life's like that sometimes.
- Like what?
Well.
Now and then, for no good
reason a man can figure out,
life will just haul off
and knock him flat.
Slam him again' the ground so hard
it seems like all his insides is busted.
But it's not all like that.
A lot of it's mighty fine.
And you can't afford to waste
the good part frettin' about the bad.
That makes it all bad.
You understand
what I'm trying to get at?
Yes, sir.
It's just that...
Yeah, sure, I know.
Sayin' it's one thing
and feelin' it's another.
But I'll tell you a trick
that's sometimes a big help.
You start lookin' around
for somethin' good
to take the place of the bad.
As a general rule, you can find it.
- Brought you that horse I promised.
- Yes, sir.
I reckon you ain't in no shape
to take pleasure in him yet.
No, sir.
We'll just keep him a while.
Maybe you'll come to
feel different later on.
Your mama was fixin' supper
when I left the house.
Might hurt her feelings
if we're not there on time to eat it.
Leave that alone! You get outta here!
Put it down! Put it down!
Why, you thievin', little wretch!
Who's that beatin' my dog?
You can't beat my dog!
Hold it, Chief. I think you're
fixin' to raise the wrong hair.
Mama was tryin' to kill my dog.
- I never even touched him.
- Of course, she didn't.
Ooh, whee! Supper ready?
- Ready and waitin'.
- Good.
Looks like it's about time
I started learnin'
this old pup to earn his keep.
Don't look like to me he's hardly
big enough to learn nothin' yet.
He's big enough to learn
if he's big enough
to act like Old Yeller.
Young Yeller is a puppy
A little ol' lop-eared puppy
It's plain to see he's got a family tree
The image of his pappy
He's frisky and he's happy
- And that's how a good pup should be
- Frisky and happy
Here, Yeller
Come back, Yeller
Best doggone dog in the West
In the West
Here, Yeller
Come back, Yeller
Best doggone dog in the West
Best doggone dog
In the West