Arf! Arf!
¶ He was the
shaggiest dog ¶
¶ he was the
¶ he was the spookiest dog
I ever did see ¶
arf! Arf!
Arf!
Go on, get outta here!
Go on!
Git!
¶ I saw that dog
upon a stair ¶
¶ I looked again
and he wasn't there ¶
¶ I looked once more
and what did I see ¶
¶ that great big shaggy dog
a-grinnin' at me ¶
¶ he was the shaggiest dog
I ever met ¶
oh, what a pet ¶
¶ he was the spookiest dog
I ever did see ¶
¶ how do I know
well, give a listen to me ¶
¶ he was the
shaggiest dog ¶
¶ he was the spookiest dog
I ever did see ¶
¶ how do I know
well, give a listen to me ¶
¶ I'll catch that dog
one happy day ¶
¶ I'll tie him up
I'll make him stay ¶
¶ I'll make him fetch
I'll make him heel ¶
¶ I'm gonna prove
to all the world
he's really real ¶
¶ he's the shaggiest
raggiest, spookiest dog ¶
¶ in town ¶¶
- arf! Arf!
This is a
shaggy dog story.
It could have happened anywhere
or to anyone.
It so happened that
it happened to Wilson Daniels,
a man who loved people
but hated dogs.
Go on, get out of here!
Go on! Git!
Go on,
get out of here!
Morning, dear.
- Good morning,
dear.
Blast!
Yes, dear?
That's ridiculous! Of all
the sickly sentimentality!
Giving a medal to a dog!
Don't get the paper
in the butter, dear.
Making a big hero
outta him!
- What'd he do?
He dragged a baby
from a burning building.
Who couldn't do that?
Don't upset yourself,
Wilson.
Dogs!
Yapping and snapping
at a man's heels!
"Man's best friend."
If I ever find the idiot
who said that...
Most people love dogs.
I suppose I'm some kind
of freak because I don't.
It's nothing to be
ashamed of, dear.
Frankly, I think...
That dogs don't like mailmen
because sometimes they bring
bad news.
Animals sense
those things, you know.
Ahh!
Frieda, I am proud
of the 20 years I've spent
in the mail service.
Neither snow, nor rain,
nor sleet, nor dogs ever kept me
from my appointed rounds.
But those
blasted dogs tried!
You were very brave.
Where are the boys?
They had breakfast
early.
They're in the cellar
tinkering with something.
What with this time?
I'm not sure.
Is there something called
an "issle interceptor"?
"Issle interceptor"?
- Mmm.
You must mean
"missile interceptor."
Frieda,
I've been thinking.
As long as you're not taking
a firm hand with wilby, I've
got to do something about it.
What do you mean, dear?
For one thing, that mess
he got us into last week.
Which mess was that?
The one where...
He had the police throw the
new Dean of the divinity school
into jail as a public enemy.
Oh, well, that was
because of the picture
on the bulletin board...
In the
post office.
- Yeah.
It did look a little
like the new Dean.
What I propose to do
about wilby is...
Missile interceptor!
Grandmother hessy's
China!
Maybe you better
switch it off, wilby.
How can I switch it off?
I haven't switched it on yet.
Maybe we better take it
out to the launching site.
Yeah, hurry!
Never mind.
It's too late!
Get the upstairs area
cleared. Hurry up!
Pop, could you and mom
come outside now and
sort of hurry, please?
Well, save something!
Moochie,
where's wilby?
He's still
in the basement.
Still in the...
Come on, wilby!
Well, I guess we've
officially entered
the rocket age,
eh, pop?
It would be great to be
up there riding it,
wouldn't it, pop?
I wish I was on it
right now.
Wilson!
Pop sure was
sore.
- Yeah, I know.
I always seem
to rub him the wrong way.
Wilby?
Pop, how'd you
get up here?
I piled up some boxes.
I'm sorry to have
to say this to you,
but I want you...
To get rid of all that
junk in the basement.
All, sir?
All of it! I want you
to dismantle the workshop,
bury those chemicals,
and give away all those
mechanical gadgets.
- Yes, sir.
I want you to
lose or give away
or do something...
With all the mice,
hamsters, bats, crickets,
bugs, snails...
And heaven knows what other
plagues of mankind lurk there.
Yes, sir.
Now, get down off this roof,
both of you, before you fall off
and ruin the flower beds.
Be careful.
Those boxes look
kind of rickety.
- Thank you.
I'll do all right.
Thank you.
We better get down
from here!
Hi, Allison!
Ohh!
That's old knothead for ya.
Always showing off!
The flowers!
That's just what
pop said not to do.
You all right,
wilby?
- Sure, I'm fine.
Buzz, may I talk to you
for a moment?
Excuse me.
Look, wilby,
I'm in a hurry.
What about my seven bucks?
What about it?
- Cough it up.
Pop pulled the plug
on my allowance.
Look, I'm sorry.
You know how it is.
I've got a date with Allison.
I'm sick and tired
of financing
your romances.
I'd like to take
Allison out myself.
Y-you want a date
with Allison?
- And why not?
Wilby, have you ever
taken a girl,
any girl,
out on a date?
Well... not exactly.
Now you want to move
right in on the most
popular girl in town.
Buzz, are we or are we not
gonna play tennis?
Coming.
Excuse me.
- Just a minute,
buzz.
Great sufferin' cats!
Ah, chiffon.
J'adore tes yeux bruns,
mon petit chou...
Tu es chou
toi maintenant.
Wha...
What's she sayin'?
Ne pense pas a te sauver,
tu comprends?
Baby.
Frieda, what are you doing?
Just having a look at
the new neighbors, dear.
They're moving into that
gloomy, old coverly mansion.
You ought to be ashamed.
Give me my glasses.
Who are they, anyway?
He's the new
assistant curator at
the county museum,
a man by the name
of andrassy,
Dr. mikhail andrassy.
Doctor, huh?
- My reports
aren't in yet,
but Murphy Jones, who
leased the place, told me...
I'd rather not know how
you get your gossip,
but what else
do you know about them?
Well,
he's supposed to be
a well-known art expert.
He spent some time in
a prison camp after the war.
Reason, unknown.
He worked in the
famous uffizi museum
in Florence, Italy.
There is a daughter,
seventeen years old.
Been studying art
in Paris.
How dare they bring
a camel into this neighborhood!
No... it's a dog!
A blasted, dratted dog!
One
bratislavian sheepdog.
Supposed to be
a very rare breed.
I'm going to have to move
into the back bedroom.
Don't start falling apart.
That dog thing
is all in your mind!
All in my mind?
I itch, my sinuses
are ballooning up,
my throat is constricting
so I can hardly breathe.
Those old pekingese wounds
on my ankle are throbbing
like bongo drums.
You say it's all in my mind!
If you say so, okay!
Come along, Wilson.
Lie down and
rest for a while.
Wait a minute.
What about
my seven bucks?
What do you know?
I think he likes me.
That's his problem.
I'm more interested in
the little mam'selle
who owns him.
You shouldn't be running across
the street like that, dog.
You're liable
to be hurt.
- By golly,
you're right!
I'll bet she's
worried about him.
I better take him back.
Come on, pooch.
Wait a minute.
This dog came to me.
All right, come on along.
Maybe ol' buzz
can teach you something.
Well, of all the nerve!
Yes?
- We brought back
your dog.
- The mam'selle's dog.
- Qui est-ce, Stefano?
Deux jeunes gens.
Ah, chiffon, qu'as-tu fait?
D'ou viens tu, vilain.
Et qu'est-ce
que je peux faire
pour vous?
Um, uh, me...
Uh, bring...
Uh, dog... you.
Him, me...
We do this.
What is it,
franceska?
Chiffon ran away and
these two nice Indian boys
brought him back.
Indians,
this far east?
We're not...
I mean,
we're not Indian.
I didn't know
you spoke English.
But, of course!
- My daughter speaks
seven languages.
- - How many do you speak?
My name is franceska,
and this is my father,
Dr. andrassy.
How do you do, gentlemen.
Bring that over here, please.
I'm buzz Miller.
This is wilby Daniels.
He lives
down the street.
Then we're neighbors!
Won't you come in?
You'll have to excuse the house.
We're just moving in, you know.
Boy, look at all
the stuff!
Some of it is stuff,
but some of it
is rather priceless.
Look.
Here's a titiano.
A tintoretto, a rodin
and a vecchini.
This is a very
fine piece, a forzini,
early 16th century.
Probably worth,
oh, three or four
thousand dollars.
I believe there's an
El greco over there
in the music room.
That's another
tintoretto.
I'd better put it
out of the way.
Well, look at that!
I've never seen chiffon
take such a fancy to anyone!
He sure is friendly!
Who's she?
- Lucretia borgia.
You remember the borgias,
of course!
Oh sure. Who?
The borgias were
notorious during
the dark ages in Italy.
Some people say the borgias
dabbled in black magic.
Black magic?
Hey!
The dog in the picture,
isn't he the same kind
as this one?
Yes, a bratislavian
sheepdog.
The breed has mostly
died out now.
Chiffon is one
of the few left.
It's very lonely for him,
poor petit chou.
Excuse me, franceska.
Would you be good enough
to take the orsini artifacts
to Dr. Howard at the museum.
He's waiting
for them.
Certainly, father.
Why don't I drive you down?
My car's right outside.
Wait, we'll both
take you.
I'll get my purse.
What's the big idea?
I thought my driving
made you nervous.
The only thing about you
that makes me nervous...
Is my $7, if you know
what I mean?
All right, if you
want to come along,
glad to have you.
- Thank you.
What a sweet
little museum!
Yeah, it's not bad.
I put in quite a bit
of time around this place
studying the arts.
Then how come you
got lost gettin' here?
Say, that's not
a bad-looking deal!
C'est charmant.
Personally, I go in for
the old Egyptian stuff
like that.
That figures.
Franceska?
Buzz?
Buzz!
Eh! Eh!
You scared me, professor.
You ought to be.
Serves you right.
You shouldn't be wandering
around here until
the exhibit is open.
I've worked day and night
to get it ready.
I'm sorry, professor plumcutt.
I was looking for
some friends of mine.
You know me?
Why of course!
It's wilby Daniels,
isn't it?
- Yes, sir.
I used to deliver
your paper.
- So you did!
Or did you?
Come to think of it,
I don't recall getting
my papers lately.
No, sir. I gave up
my route two years ago.
Oh! Oh, well.
That just goes to show
how often I read a newspaper.
Nothing interesting happens
to people these days.
Now, in the delightfully
evil days of the borgias,
something interesting
happened to people
every day.
Yes, sir.
I guess they did, sir.
I'd better...
Wilby, do you realize
that this civilization
knew all about sorcery,
even about shape-shifting
and the casting of spells?
What's shape-shifting?
Shape-shifting
was the medieval art...
Of borrowing
somebody else's body
to live in for a while.
A most interesting practice.
You've heard all about
people being changed...
Into cats, dogs
and other creatures,
haven't you?
Ah, professor, you don't
believe in this stuff, do you?
Well, it may surprise you
to hear, my boy, that I do.
I know people laugh
at these things today,
but if they were honest,
they'd admit that there
are moments...
On dark and lonely nights when
something stirs within us...
And reawakens ancient
fears and beliefs.
I'd better be going now.
I have to find my friends.
Yes, come in
and see me again.
Look out!
Sorry.
- No, no.
It's all right.
Oh, look, wilby.
Run along now, will you?
I-I'll take care
of these.
Are you sure
it's all right?
Yes, please. Please.
Well, they say
it takes all kinds.
Then it's a date?
- It's a date.
Good deal!
I wonder what happened
to wilby?
Don't worry about knothead.
He loves museums.
Bye, now.
- Au revoir.
Hi, wilby!
Who gets the mice
and the hamsters?
Pete hammers.
He always wanted 'em.
Mickey Warren gave me a buck
for your chemistry stuff.
I promised to throw in
Harry the bat for free.
What about
old Zachary here?
I couldn't unload him.
Nobody wanted him.
Poor ol' Zack.
I know just how you feel.
Come on, wilby.
Quit feelin' sorry
for yourself.
Pop'll get over it.
Yeah, pop'll get over it,
but I won't.
I'll still be
the same mixed-up guy
I've always been.
All right, boys.
Time for bed.
If you haven't finished,
be sure and finish tomorrow.
Be right up, pop.
You comin', wilby?
- In a minute.
What the heck is this?
How do you suppose...
Oh, I know. It must have
fallen in when I knocked over
the professor's case.
"In canis corpore,
transmuto."
Sounds like Latin.
Wish I knew more than
just first-year Latin.
Canis? Canis?
That's "dog."
Dog... into dog,
something... transmuto.
"In canis corpore,
transmuto."
It's a transmuto,
and away we go...
With a Doe-see-Doe.
Wait a minute!
What's going on here?
Stop! Now wait,
somebody, whoever you are.
I was just kidding!
Wilby!
Wilby, come on now.
It's getting late.
No. No!
- No-o-o!
- Wilby?
Yipe!
- Wilby.
Ohh!
Wilby, come on up now.
It's getting late.
Okay, pop.
You catching a cold?
Your mother told you
to wear a sweater down here.
A sweater?
I've got a sweater.
Well, come on up now.
Oh, poor pop.
This'll kill him.
What'll I do?
Gosh, what'll I do?
Professor plumcutt!
He'll know.
Now, to get by pop.
¶¶
Professor plumcutt?
Hello, fellow.
I've gotta
talk to you.
You know, dogs are
not allowed in here.
I'm not a dog.
I'm wilby Daniels.
Wilby Daniels!
Are you really?
Well, well!
You know,
I'm not surprised.
The first time I saw you
I said to myself, "that boy's
a potential shape-shifter."
Is that what
happened to me?
- Of course!
How on earth
did you manage it?
I think this ring had
something to do with it.
The borgia ring!
Where did you find it?
I've looked everywhere for it.
Well, uh, it fell in
the cuff of my trousers.
Thank you very much
for returning it.
It's a very rare
and unusual ring.
Professor!
- What's the matter?
- What about me?
- What about you?
I don't wanna be
a dog!
- You don't?
No, of course not.
Can't you help me?
Yes, but... how?
Apparently you've become
involved with some old spell
cast upon this ring...
Probably by
one of the borgias.
It sounds
just like them.
How do I get out of it?
Don't ask me, my boy.
How should I know?
There are all kinds of spells.
Some of them break themselves
after a while,
while others come and go
like a headache.
Come and go?
- Yes. Sometimes
you'll be a dog...
And sometimes you'll be a boy
for hours at a time,
sometimes longer.
You never can tell.
That's what makes it
so interesting.
Well, how can I
break the spell?
An act of heroism
might break the spell.
Heroism?
Of course! Why didn't
I think of it first?
Heroism has always been
an important and most potent
factor in breaking spells.
Do you remember
"the hound of Florence"?
"Hound of Florence"?
No, sir.
- It's the famous story
of a young man...
Who was changed into a dog,
just as you have been.
He was in love with
a beautiful girl, and one night
got into a terrible fight...
Defending her against the
intentions of an evil Duke.
The Duke grabbed the dagger
and plunged it into the dog.
The dog fell to the ground,
and as the poor animal
lay there with the dagger
deep in his heart,
he suddenly changed back
into a man again.
Dagger in
the heart?
- Yes.
That'd kill me!
No, no. You, you don't
grasp the point of the story.
What I was trying to say
is that it is possible
to break such a spell.
Now, you must excuse me.
I have work to do.
Isn't there anything
I can do?
Yes. Be happy...
And keep a stiff
upper lip.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
One-l-two-nine, code six,
one-a-seven-nine, no warrant.
One-two-four-nine, Roger.
All units out at once.
Stand by.
- Oops, sorry.
Oh, that's all right.
What'd you say?
- Hmm?
I said, I'm sorry.
That's what
I thought you said.
Kelly?
Yeah, what's the
matter with you?
You see a dog
just then?
Yeah, why?
Did you hear...
Hear what?
Forget it.
Forget it, I said.
Forget it!
All right, then.
I'll forget it!
¶¶
Wilby, moochie!
Time to get up!
Be right with ya,
pop.
Hey, wilby, I had
the funniest dream last night.
I dreamed that
you were a dog.
Come on, wilby.
Wake up.
It was the greatest dream.
You came in this room
as a big ol' shaggy dog.
Hey, wilby,
wake up.
Oh boy!
How'd you get in here?
How did I get in here?
I live here.
You talk
just like wilby.
- I am wilby.
No, you're a dog.
Where you goin'?
Dog?
Oh! It can't
be true! No!
Do you think pop
will let me keep you?
Shut up a minute.
Let me think.
I'll be good to ya,
honest I will.
Boy, we'll have
great times together.
Great times together?
What are you talkin' about?
What's the matter?
Uh-oh.
I hope pop
won't shoot you.
- Huh?
He swore that the
first time he caught a dog
in this house he'd...
You two better be outta
bed when I get up there.
And open that door!
Yipe!
Here he comes.
Hurry!
Get under there.
Come on!
All right,
come on, you birds.
Good morning, pop.
Good morning,
moochie.
How are you
this morning?
Very fine, thank you.
Wilby?
- Pop!
Listen to this.
Very nice.
Now stop playing it
and get dressed.
But, pop,
I just learned it.
Very good.
Now, get dressed.
Wilby, I want you
out of that bed right now!
And you
brush your teeth.
Oh, that was
a close one.
Don't worry, boy.
Gosh, why did this
have to happen to me?
It's just terrific, wilby.
How'd it happen?
I don't know exactly.
Remember,
we were down in
the basement last night?
Uh-huh.
Morning, dear.
Good morning,
dear.
Frieda, have you seen
any dogs around here?
Of course not.
They wouldn't dare.
Are my eyes
getting puffy?
You've always had
puffy eyes, dear.
I know that, but they feel
like they're getting puffier.
Frieda, if I thought
for a moment that...
- Frieda, I hope I can trust you.
- What do you mean?
You're always telling me
how much moochie wants a dog...
Yes?
I know you two wouldn't
gang up on me, but...
Sometimes I get the feeling
that you're not in sympathy
with my problem.
Wilson, I think
you'd better eat your eggs.
Did professor plumcutt
say...
You had to stay a dog
all the time?
- He didn't exactly know.
- Gee, I hope so.
- You what?
Gosh, you know how much
I always wanted to have a dog.
I'm not gonna be
your dog!
I'll teach you all kinds
How to sit up,
beg, roll over...
And all that stuff!
Cut it out, will ya?
Boys!
Stay here. I'll tell him
you're not hungry.
Hungry? I'm starved!
- You like nice, meaty bones?
- You know what I like. Hurry!
Don't worry, boy.
I'm gonna take
good care of you.
Take care of me!
Hmph!
Psst! Psst!
Pop?
- Hmm?
What's this ad?
It's a sale
on lawn mowers.
Interesting,
isn't it?
Yes, uh-hmm.
How did you
get in here?
Shoo! Shoo!
Go home!
Don't you know
it isn't safe for
a dog in this house?
- Go home!
- My toast!
Toast coming up.
Shoo!
Frieda?
- Yes?
Is there a dog
in the kitchen?
A dog?
Yes, dog.
D-o-g.
- Dog.
What kind
of a dog?
That's all
I wanted to know!
Pop, where you goin'?
To the
hall closet.
What for?
To get my shotgun.
You can't shoot
your own...
My own what?
Your own
neighbor's dog!
Oh, can't I?
Pop, you can't shoot
that dog.
Ohh!
That's right, run,
you cowardly fleabag!
Next time you come
on my property, I'll...
I'll...
Well, I just will!
I just don't
understand it!
He's never stayed out
all night before.
I'm sure, mademoiselle,
he will return for his meals.
If you'd watch
him more carefully,
these things
wouldn't happen.
I'm sorry,
mademoiselle.
There you are!
Where have you been all night,
you wretched beast?
Chiffon,
get down from there!
Oh, chiffon, mon petit.
I've been so worried about you.
What have you been up to,
vilain?
You're all forgiven.
Come on.
How 'bout
some breakfast?
Well, since when do you
eat at the table?
I'll get you breakfast.
Come on.
Stefano, the door.
Yes?
Dr. andrassy is expecting me.
My name is thurm.
Yes, Mr. thurm.
Come in.
Please, follow me.
What's the matter?
I thought you were hungry.
Well, go on!
Oh no, you don't.
Get back in the kitchen.
A la cuisine.
Stefano?
- Mademoiselle?
Take chiffon.
See that he doesn't
run away again.
Do you understand?
Oui, mademoiselle.
You're always causing
me trouble, aren't you?
Get in there.
I don't have time to
watch you every minute.
Now, let's see you
get out of there!
It's me!
Here, wilby.
Wilby!
Here, wilby!
Wilby! Here, boy!
Wilby!
Here, boy.
Here, wilby!
Wilby?
- What do you think
you're doin'?
Ah, gee!
What's the matter?
You're not a dog
anymore.
You were gonna put
this dog collar on me,
weren't ya?
Don't get sore about it.
Forget it. I'm through
with that dog business.
You sure?
No.
Where's pop?
He's in there
cleaning his gun.
Well, I guess I'll have
to hide these for a while.
Did you wash
your hands?
- Yep.
Wilson, if you don't mind,
we'll have dinner early
tomorrow night.
We're all going to
the country club dance.
Is my good suit
clean?
- Had it done
last week.
Wilby, why don't you
take a girl to the dance?
Wilby?
He's a little young
for dating, isn't he?
Nonsense!
Just because you
didn't go out with girls
until you were twenty-three.
That's not true.
I was twenty.
Besides,
I was shy.
Well, anyway, wilby
can't exist in a vacuum.
Besides, you've already
taken all his hobbies
away from him.
I'd say it was a big jump
from birds' eggs to girls.
There is nothing wrong
with girls.
They're character building.
Wilby, why don't you ask
Allison to the dance?
Allison?
Buzz takes her
to all the dances.
Oh. Well, then,
someone else.
There must be dozens
of lovely girls who'd be
delighted to go with you.
Why's he have to take a girl?
Why can't he go with me?
That's a great idea,
that is!
Why don't you take that
new girl down the street,
Dr. andrassy's daughter?
Franceska! No, I wouldn't
have a chance with her.
See who that is,
will you, wilby?
Wilby, could I talk to you
in private for a second?
You know, knothead,
uh, wilby, you're
the best friend I have.
Uh-uh, buzz.
Not a cent!
Oh, wilby,
I don't come to see you
just when I need money.
All right,
I'm sorry.
The point is, I, uh,
I do have a problem.
I'm supposed to take Allison
to the country club dance.
I know.
Well, I happened to mention
the dance to franceska.
You know how it is.
She's a smooth worker.
Before I knew it,
I asked her to go too.
What do you want me to do?
All you have to do
is come along and make
a foursome out of it.
You don't have to be
with anybody.
- I don't get ya.
Don't ya see?
I'll handle it
so that both girls
think they're with me.
Then everybody's happy.
I don't see how that
makes me happy.
Well, sure you do!
It's fun.
We're playing a harmless
little joke on the girls.
Well,
what do you say?
Anything's better than going
with my little brother.
I just don't see how
it's gonna work.
You just come along...
And watch the ol' master
at work, huh, buddy, pal?
Oh!
Say, I'll need gas
for tomorrow night.
You don't happen to have
a buck on you, do you?
How nice you look,
wilby.
- Thank you.
So do you.
Don't bother getting out.
I'll get your date for you.
Imagine, taking the
prettiest girl in town
to the dance!
Oh. Oh, well,
you know.
Franceska certainly seems
to find you attractive.
You really think so?
Of course, I'm not as
sophisticated as she is,
but there is something
about you lately,
something unusual.
You girls know
one another.
- Of course.
Hello, wilby.
- Hi, franceska.
You both better
ride in front with me.
The wind in the back
is murder on the hair.
You're so thoughtful, buzz.
Et tres charmante,
n'est-ce pas?
Sorry, I don't
speak French.
- Oh.
¶¶
Allison, will you do
something for me?
What is it?
You know, this is wilby's
first dress-up date...
And he's scared stiff.
Scared of what?
- Franceska!
That's silly.
She's his date,
isn't she?
Sure, but you know
how shy he is,
and franceska's
kind of spectacular.
It's got him
tied up in knots.
- So?
I thought if
you could dance the
first dance with him...
You're old friends.
It might break
the ice for him.
Since when are you
so concerned about wilby?
Well, I like to see
everyone happy.
Thanks, Allison.
You're a real doll.
Wilby, aren't you
and Allison gonna have
the first dance?
Well, sure.
How 'bout it, Allison?
Wanna dance?
Love to.
Shall we?
- Mais oui.
¶¶
They're sweet together,
aren't they?
Yeah, that's what
makes it so tough.
What does?
Wilby's got a tremendous crush
on Allison.
Trouble is,
he's so shy.
Allison goes more for
the sophisticated type.
She can't see wilby
for sour apples.
Poor wilby.
He is very nice,
isn't he?
Don't you worry.
There's nothing
you can do about it.
Buzz?
- Hmm?
I have a rather
amusing idea.
- What's that?
Suppose I make a fuss
over wilby and pretend
to be interested in him.
You mean,
make Allison jealous?
Oh, just a little bit.
You're a genius!
I never would have
thought of that
in a million years!
The next number will be
a lady's tag dance.
¶¶
Tag dance.
- Pardon?
It's customary.
The custom,
is it not?
¶¶
What's the big idea?
You told me to break
the ice, didn't you?
Fine, break it.
Don't melt it!
Excuse me.
¶¶
You know, it's amazing.
All those pretty girls,
they actually seem to enjoy
dancing with wilby.
And why not?
I'd have bet anything
he was gonna be the
all-American wallflower.
There are a lot of things about
your son that you don't know.
The next number is
a "Paul revere"!
¶¶
Shall we, dear?
- Love to!
Excuse us, moochie.
No more cake,
sweetheart.
¶¶
Wilby!
What's the big idea?
Get down!
Don't give me trouble.
You got trouble.
Look at yourself.
Oh no! Not here!
Not now! Please!
Wilby, are you all right?
Oh boy,
you're a dog again!
What are you
so happy about?
Gosh, you know you're
a lot more fun as a dog
than you are as my bro...
Ah, shut up and
get me outta here.
Okay, boy.
I don't want anything
to happen to you now.
Come on.
Sneak out that way.
Chiffon!
What in the world
is he doing here?
Who?
- Chiffon.
Chiffon!
Get him, buzz.
- O-oh yeah!
Ahh!
There's that blasted
dog again! Get away!
What's he doing here?
See ya later, boy.
Look out!
Come here,
you mangy mutt!
Come here!
Come on, moochie.
Time for bed, dear.
Hello? Wilby,
where are you?
Pop!
- Just a minute.
It's late.
Isn't it time you
were getting home?
Is he all right?
Yes, he's all right.
We wondered what
happened to you.
I suppose you went chasing
after that girl's dog too.
Is it all right if you
stay at buzz's tonight?
It's all right, pop.
Yes, it's all right,
wilby.
Hey, Kelly,
you got a dime
for the phone?
Whoops!
Sorry, officer hanson.
Bye!
Kelly, here's your dime.
Can we go now, please?
I thought you were
gonna call home.
- I changed my mind. Let's go.
- You said it was important.
- I know what I said.
It was a whim.
Sometimes I'm just full
of little whims.
Can we go now, please?
But you...
Forget it, I said.
Forget it!
All right,
I'll forget it.
Don't bother, buzz.
Good night, franceska.
I hope you find your dog.
Thank you, Allison.
Good night.
In the words of your
charming other date,
"don't bother!"
- Oh, wait!
I can explain
everything.
- Good night!
Well, that's gratitude
for you!
I beg your pardon?
Here I almost break my neck
trying to catch
that dog of yours,
he drags me all over a parking
lot and you won't listen to me.
So?
Besides that, I've got
a deep cut over my eye...
And it'll probably be infected
by the time I get home.
Oh well, I...
I guess I don't blame you.
Oh, come on inside.
I'll clean your scratch.
Now you're talking!
Agh!
What the...
Oh, what a night.
Is chiffon here?
Yes, mademoiselle.
He's in the kitchen.
I'm quite displeased
with you, Stefano.
I distinctly asked
you to keep chiffon
locked up tonight.
I left him in the kitchen,
carefully locked the door.
Still he escaped.
We won't
discuss it now.
Please, go in and sit down.
I want to see if chiffon is all right.
Will you forget about
that mutt for once?
It was all wilby's fault
that I got into this mess.
Wilby's?
Yeah, it's all
his fault.
Because I have
a soft heart, and was
trying to do him a favor.
Ouch, that stings!
There.
It's all done now.
Wilby didn't have enough nerve
to get himself a date,
so he cooked up this thing.
Why are you blaming this
all on wilby?
Oh, don't let him fool you.
He's not as dumb as he looks.
Why, behind
that simple face...
Well, I don't want to talk
about my best friend like that.
Let's talk about us.
You know, franceska,
I've never met a girl like you.
No, I'm not kidding.
There's something
about you that...
Chiffon!
There you are.
What a bad dog
you've been, mon chéri.
Running away again and
scaring poor franceska
half to death!
Bad boy.
I sure hate to see you
waste all that on a mutt.
Why?
What do you mean?
I mean, forget about tonight.
Forget wilby and the whole mess.
Like I said before,
let's talk about us.
You know, franceska,
the first time I saw you...
I said to myself,
"buzz, there's just
the girl for..."
Does he have to keep
looking at me like that?
Look, fella, I've had just about
enough trouble for one night.
Now beat it!
Will you get lost?
Buzz!
Hey, what's
the big idea?
Get off, will ya?
Franceska!
- Chiffon, stop it!
- He's flipped his lid!
Let go!
Ca suffit!
- Get him off!
What has gotten into you?
Stop it this instant!
I think you'd
better leave, buzz.
I'm beginning to get the point.
Your dog doesn't like me.
- I'm sorry.
- That's okay.
I'll just find
my own way out.
Bad dog, you.
Good night.
- Good night.
You behaved very badly
tonight, chiffon.
Buzz is really
a nice boy.
A little, shall we say,
conceited? Come on.
Yes?
I just wanted to say
good night, father.
- Did you have a pleasant time?
Yes, thank you.
But the odd thing was,
I found chiffon
at the dance.
Chiffon was there?
I don't understand how he
keeps getting out of the house.
May I leave him
with you tonight?
Certainly, dear.
I'm sure he won't
get away from me.
Good night,
franceska.
- Good night.
Now you
behave yourself,
you stupid,
wonderful dog.
Mm-mmm!
Thurm, what is
the meaning of this?
You were asked not
to come here at night!
It's most urgent, doctor.
I dared not use the phone.
Is anything wrong at
the missile plant?
On the contrary.
Good news. I've been
transferred to section 32.
Section 32.
Excellent!
With what I've
already given you,
this should be
all you need.
- How soon can you get it here?
Taking all precautions,
I'd say tomorrow night by 8:00.
That means that the
complete mechanism...
Of the undersea hydrogen
missile will be in our hands.
Yes, sir.
Now we must get it out of
the country, immediately.
Oh, no you don't.
No you don't, my friend!
You're not getting out
of this house tonight.
All right,
up on the couch. Up!
Good night, thurm.
I'll expect you
tomorrow night at 8:00.
I certainly would
like to know what has
gotten into you lately.
Spies!
I've gotta
tell somebody.
I've gotta get
outta here.
The laundry chute!
Well, here goes.
Aaah!
Easy, easy.
Yeah.
Whoa!
What'll I do now?
Hi, pop.
- Hi, son.
Wilby home yet?
No, sir.
What's this
you're reading?
"How to train your dog"?
Gosh, pop,
I thought someday you might
change your mind about dogs.
Let me tell you something,
young man.
As long as I've got a mind,
there'll never be a
dog in this house!
"How to train..."
There.
Hey, mooch!
Is that you, wilby?
- Well, now,
who'd you think it was?
Gosh, I've been
worried about you.
Will you stop patting me?
I don't like it.
Where you been?
Mooch, we've gotta
get some help, and fast!
That house is
full of spies.
Spies? Oh, swell,
that'll be fun playin'!
This isn't a game.
It's serous!
Ah, wilby.
They're stealing something
from the missile plant.
The missile plant?
I don't know
what it is exactly,
but they call it
section 32.
They're sending it
out of the country tonight.
Wow!
I'd better tell pop.
Pop?
- Sure, he'll know
what to do.
Now, you just
stay outta sight.
- Okay.
Pop, pop! Can I talk
to you for a minute?
Certainly. What is it?
Will you please
put down that paper?
It's very urgent.
- All right.
I just found out somethin'.
What did you
find out?
You know those people
down the street,
Dr. andrassy and them?
Yeah.
- They're spies.
Spies, huh?
Well.
Pop, I'm not kiddin'.
They're stealing somethin'
from the missile plant,
somethin' called
section 32.
Section 32, huh?
That's very interesting.
But pop,
you gotta believe me.
We gotta do somethin'
about it.
Moochie, I'm surprised at you.
I knew we had one wooly-headed
son in this family...
wilby isn't wooly-headed.
He's the one that
heard 'em talkin'.
Oh, he's the one that heard 'em.
That explains the whole thing.
Run along now,
huh, moochie?
But pop, we can't just
let 'em get away!
Moochie, run along.
Pop.
Moochie.
No soap.
Hmm, I guess I'll have to
give him the shock treatment.
Poor pop.
Uh, where's the gun?
In the hall closet.
I got the key.
Well, here goes.
Pop?
- Yes, wilby?
I've got something to
tell you, but I'm afraid.
You never have to be afraid
to talk to me, wilby.
Maybe sometimes I'm
a little impatient with you,
but that's because
you're my son.
I want you to be
something special.
Yes, sir?
So you just tell me
what's troubling you.
I'm sure it can't be
anything too serious;
but whatever it is,
I promise you I'll understand.
Really, pop?
You can bank on it,
wilby.
Shake on it?
- Certainly
I'll shake on it, wilby.
No!
- Oh, that did it.
Frieda!
- Wilson?
- Wilson,
is that you?
What are we
gonna do now?
We've gotta
get help.
- Look!
The police!
I'd like to report
some spies, please.
All right,
what's the name?
Moochie...
Montgomery Daniels.
Daniels?
You any relation to that kid
who tipped us off about
that gangster last week?
Yes, sir.
Wilby's my brother.
But he didn't know
it was the new Dean
at the divinity college.
Remember, Kelly? Last week,
when I used to be a sergeant.
No kidding,
officer.
We need help.
Who are you?
Uh, wilby Daniels.
Wilby Daniels.
I knew it.
The first time that dog spoke
to me, I said to my wife...
Easy now, hanson.
It's all right.
It's probably some kid
dressed up in a dog suit.
That's right,
officer.
Sure, that's how he
spied on the spies.
All right,
take off the dog suit.
Can't. I don't have
anything on underneath.
You see, Kelly?
He can't.
You ought to know that.
Now that's enough.
Stop bothering officer hanson...
Before we take you
down to the station.
Fine, let's go!
Yeah, let's go.
Oh, no you don't.
- Not in this car.
- But they're spies!
Now, I'm afraid they're
gonna have to keep.
You see, there's a landing
of invaders from Mars
over by the stockyards,
and I'm afraid we're gonna
have to get over there.
Gosh, wilby, 2:00.
We've gotta think
of somethin'.
- Yeah.
I got it!
Here you are,
you miserable beast!
You can't take him!
He's my broth...
Your what?
My, my pal.
This is the last time
you'll ever get away.
I can promise you that!
Come on, you devil.
Come along before I...
Come on!
No.
- Wilson.
Wilson?
No, no.
- Now, don't
you dare move.
I'll get the spirits
of ammonia.
- No.
Pop, snap out of it!
We've gotta get movin'!
No, moochie. Moochie,
is it true about wilby?
Did I see and hear
what I thought I saw?
You sure did!
Wilby's a dog now.
No... my own boy,
my own flesh and blood.
Somehow, someway
I failed him as a father.
How did it happen?
I'll tell ya later.
Hurry!
Are we going
somewhere?
Don't you understand?
We gotta get help.
We gotta stop
those spies.
What spies?
Remember?
I told you about 'em.
Spies!
That's right, you did.
Don't you worry about a thing.
I'm with you all the way.
We'll have to get
some help!
- Not that way, this way!
Wilson Daniels,
you are not stepping
a foot from this house.
Frieda, you stay outta this.
This is a job that
calls for cool heads!
Come on, moochie.
Oh, here, this way.
Calm down,
Mr. Daniels.
I just want to get
this thing straight.
Oh.
Now, you say that
this information
came from your son.
Yes, my older son.
He was there and he
heard them talking.
- And they knew he was there?
- I'm sure they knew
he was there...
Doesn't that strike you
as rather odd, Mr. Daniels,
that they'd speak of such
confidential matters...
In front of your son?
No, it's not
odd at all.
They probably didn't pay
any attention to him.
You see, my son
happens to be a dog.
Your son is a dog?
Yes. Now don't
get me wrong.
He's not a dog all the time,
just part of the time.
Oh, I see.
Thank you for coming,
Mr. Daniels.
We'll look into
the matter.
You don't believe me. Ow!
I'm sorry.
I just don't happen
to have my shoes on.
Don't you believe me?
Of course.
Then aren't you going to do
something about it now?
We must proceed with
caution, Mr. Daniels.
Dr. andrassy is a
well-respected man.
- But you
haven't got time for caution!
Don't you understand?
This thing that they stole,
whatever it is,
is being shipped out of
the country tonight!
I don't suppose you have
any idea precisely what
this thing may be?
No, all I know is that it's
something called section 32,
or something like that.
Section 32?
- That's right.
Are you sure?
That's what the dog said.
Well, my son.
Please sit down again,
Mr. Daniels.
I should think so.
All right.
Now, uh,
you still insist...
A dog told you
about this.
- Yes.
Why don't you ask my
younger son, moochie?
He's the dog's brother.
Just now it's you I'm
interested in, Mr. Daniels.
Me? You don't think I had
anything to do with this?
Now, you listen to me.
I came here in good faith.
I told you a simple,
straightforward story.
And just because I happen
to have a son who's a dog,
you look at me as though...
You look at me as though I had
wheels in my head or something.
Just you remember,
I'm a government man myself.
We have the utmost respect
for the members of...
The United States
post office department.
I wonder if you'd mind
repeating your story to
one of my colleagues.
I'd be glad to.
All I ask is that you gentlemen
keep an open mind...
- no, no, no.
Not them,
Mr. Daniels.
Would you step into the hall
with these gentlemen, please?
Well, yes.
Excuse me.
It's fantastic, but he
knows about section 32.
How could he?
That's what
I've got to find out.
Meantime, check every man,
every sketch,
every piece of equipment
in that department.
That'll take time.
Get moving.
All right, Mr. Daniels,
this way, please.
I think you'll like
Dr. Galvin.
- Doctor?
Oh, uh, it's a kind of
honorary title.
Well, now,
just a minute, you...
I've just returned
from the museum.
I have our plan
worked out.
Come upstairs.
I'll go over it with you.
Yes, sir.
Is my daughter at home?
No, sir, not yet.
She went shopping.
Good.
The girl
must know absolutely nothing
of what is happening here.
I understand, sir.
- As it is,
with matters coming to a head,
I don't quite know what
to do about her.
It is unfortunate
mademoiselle happens
to be your daughter,
otherwise a solution
would be quite obvious.
In any case, Stefano,
the problem is mine.
I'll decide what to do
when the time comes.
This is a sketch
of the packing case
containing the small fossils.
Understand me clearly.
From here on, the slightest
hitch will be disastrous.
- You can depend on me, doctor.
- When thurm arrives...
With the components of
section 32, take them to
my office at the museum.
There you will find...
The packing case containing
the etruscan fossils.
Suppose the authorities
open the case?
They may, but I doubt if they
will tamper very much...
With such a fragile
and priceless collection...
Dispatched to such
a distinguished man.
The packing case will be
shipped on the midnight plane,
consigned ostensibly
to the museum in Rome.
Anders himself will
pick up the shipment?
Silence!
You have instructions
never to mention his name!
What harm can it do?
Save for the dog downstairs,
we are alone in the house.
Now, suppose we go over what
you must do, point by point.
What are you
doing here?
Here?
O-oh, here.
Well, as a matter of fact,
I'm glad you asked me.
I was wondering if you could
give franceska a message for me.
There's going to be a barbecue
at Dawson's grove next Saturday,
and I was
thinking of...
I know what you heard,
and I know how to
make you forget!
No, not now.
- What else can we
do with him?
I said, not now!
Tie him up and lock him
in the dressing room.
You've gained access to
certain secret information.
Now, fearful of
the consequences,
you transfer the burden of
guilt to your second self,
a submerged second identity
known only to you.
What sec...
What second identity?
Now this is very important,
Mr. Daniels.
Do you often visualize
yourself as a dog?
- What?
Now, let's be honest.
Do you often stand in front
of your shaving mirror,
and instead of
your own face...
You see a shiny, moist,
black shoe-button nose,
a strong,
intelligent head?
No!
Excuse me, sir,
it's getting awfully late,
and mom will be
worried about us.
I don't see any reason
why you can't go.
- Well, good.
I've had enough of this.
No, I was referring
to the boy.
I'm afraid I'll have
to ask you to remain
a while longer, Mr. Daniels.
Just a few more questions.
Why don't you ask him
a few questions?
He knows more about
this thing than I do.
He'll tell you
I'm telling the truth.
Perhaps we should
question the boy.
There may be a heredity factor
present between father and son.
Can it wait, sir?
I ought to be going.
Yes, they say heredity sometimes
plays a role in lycanthropy.
Who are you
calling a liar?
Lycanthropy is the alleged
practice of turning humans
into witches and werewolves.
Don't be ridiculous!
My son isn't any werewolf.
He's just a big, baggy,
stupid-looking shaggy dog!
Pop, I'm worried about wilby.
He may be in trouble.
What do you think
I'm in?
Now just a few
questions, my lad.
It won't do you
any good, sir.
I don't know anything
about all this.
Moochie!
What did you say?
I said, I don't know anything
and I'd like to go home, please.
Moochie!
Then you don't believe
your brother is a dog?
Gosh, sir,
would you?
Moochie!
And your father made up
this entire story about the dog.
It was his idea.
Pop's a great
storyteller.
Kids come from all around
just to hear him.
Moochie!
Sorry, pop.
I had to do it.
Betts,
I'm letting the boy go.
Please see that he gets home
in a company car.
Yes, sir.
All right, son.
Moochie.
You go back to my office,
and Mr. betts will
take care of you.
Go ahead.
Moochie.
May I, doctor?
Oh, of course.
Now, Mr. Daniels, we've had
our little joke about the dog.
Suppose
we get down to cases.
I want to know just how,
when and where...
You found out about
section 32!
Did you get it?
Yes, I have it.
Section 32,
complete.
Good!
- But we're
in trouble.
Something's gone wrong
at the plant.
What do you mean?
An investigation.
I had to answer a few ticklish questions.
You knew the right answers.
Of course, but I didn't
like the sound of them.
You know, I'm not even sure
that I wasn't followed here.
We'll have to use
the emergency plan.
The other is too risky now.
What about the boat?
It's tied up at Walker's dock, ready to go.
Very well.
Bring the sedan around.
What about
the boy?
We'll be out of the country
before they find him.
I don't understand
what could have gone wrong.
You're sure that...
Yes, what do you want?
I wanted to say I'm going
out with buzz Miller.
I'm sorry, franceska,
but I've been called away
for a few days and I would
like you to come with me.
Well, isn't this
rather short notice?
Where are we going?
I've no time for questions.
Please get ready!
Well, if you don't mind,
I think I'd prefer to stay here.
You'll do
as I say!
What is this?
Franceska,
you're an intelligent girl.
I don't believe I have to
make any needless threats.
Take her
to her room.
See that she takes
what she needs. Hurry!
Here you are, son.
- Thank you
very much, sir.
I don't want to
attract attention.
Drive at
a normal speed.
All right.
Wilby!
Here, wilby!
Wilby. Here, wilby!
Wilby!
Here, wilby!
In here, moochie!
In here!
In here, wilby!
Wilby,
what's goin' on?
Come on!
They're gettin' away!
They're headin'
for Walker's dock!
Hey, look out!
Someday I'm gonna
murder that dog!
Hey, you mangy cur,
come back with my car!
Wait, stop!
Stop!
Officer! Officer!
Officer, get him!
Get him! That shaggy
dog just stole my car!
Shaggy dog.
It's no use, Kelly.
I've just gotta face it.
I gotta face it.
Follow that dog!
Hey, wait!
Wait for us!
Never mind, buzz,
here comes my pop!
Pop, pop!
Follow that police car!
Montgomery, don't you
ever speak to me again!
You can't let 'em get away!
You don't know what
you're asking me to do.
Do you know what I've gone
through for the last few hours?
But, my car!
Look, please,
I'm not a well man.
Chicken.
Patrol car 12, hanson.
Code 22.
We are pursuing stolen car
headed west on highway 16
at high rate of speed.
Request other police units
be notified.
Patrol car 12.
We are pursuing stolen car...
Traveling west
on highway 16.
Description of suspect
as follows:
Large, shaggy dog.
Dirty white,
brown patches.
Unknown.
Have him repeat
that description.
Car 12, repeat description
of suspect. Over.
Repeat, description
of suspect as follows:
Large, shaggy dog.
Dirty white
with brown patches.
Hanson, this is captain scanlon.
What's the matter with you?
Patrol car 12,
hanson.
We are pursuing
stolen car.
Suspect identified
as large, shaggy dog!
Out!
Hanson, answer me!
Answer me!
Answ...
Hanson! Hanson!
Do you hear me?
Report in here immediately.
Hanson!
Patrol car 7, patrol car 7.
Mercer, are you there?
Patrol car 7,
Mercer. Over.
Mercer, there are two
loonies by the name of
hanson and Kelly...
Masquerading
as police officers.
Now they're
headed your way.
Pick 'em up and bring 'em
in here immediately! Over.
Patrol car 7, Mercer.
Message clear.
Acknowledge and out.
Poor old hanson.
There he is!
Now get out
of there!
No, you don't.
There.
Right over here.
Bend over that hood.
Hanson!
What are you...
Well, it's possible,
isn't it?
- Look out!
- Ouch! Ouch!
- He bit me!
- I don't see anything.
No, Kelly!
That's our car!
We're being followed.
Open it up!
That wasn't hanson.
Patrol car 7, Mercer.
Request additional
instructions. Over.
You've got your instructions.
Bring in hanson and Kelly!
Mobile unit assigned to
officers hanson and Kelly...
Passed this point
a moment ago.
Officers hanson and Kelly
were not in it. Over.
Really? Well,
may I ask who was in it?
A large,
shaggy dog, sir.
Description as follows:
Dirty white,
brown patches.
Was driving
the mobile unit.
Would you have them send
my car around, please?
That is, unless it's been stolen
by a purple kangaroo...
Wearing a checkered vest!
Yes, sir.
No! No! No!
No, no, no,
you idiots!
No, no, no!
Well, well, if it isn't
hot-rod hanson speeding.
And you, who used
to be a sergeant.
All right, Mercer,
very cute. Come on...
Sorry, we're to
bring you in.
Ed, I can't go back
without that dog.
Sorry, I got the word from
scanlon, loud and clear.
Ed, please, for the love
of a fellow officer.
We were rookies together.
I married your sister, felice.
I loaned you my
dress uniform for the
shriners' convention.
Ed, don't these things
mean anything to ya?
All right,
I'll take a chance, hanson.
But you just better pray
you know what you're doing.
Cast off,
thurm!
Aaah!
Get down from there!
Chiffon,
let go of me!
You devil, you!
I'll fix you.
Chiffon, look out!
Stop it, you...
Chiffon, stop it!
Aaah!
Mercer, call the harbor police!
Have 'em stop that boat!
Oh!
What's the matter,
Mr. Daniels?
- Go ahead.
I'm all right.
I've just broken my foot.
Did they get away?
Where's wilby?
Apprehend 32-foot speed cruiser,
headed towards keeley's point.
Over.
You all right?
- Buzz.
There, there, now.
Everything's under control.
But how in the world
did you get here?
The last thing
I remember, chiffon...
Don't you worry your
pretty little head.
Old buzz got here just
in the Nick of time.
But buzz...
don't thank me.
It was nothing.
Nothing at all.
Hey!
Franceska!
Hey, what's the big idea?
What's the matter with you?
Let go of me!
What are you mad at me for?
I didn't do anything.
Chiffon, let go,
you silly moth-eaten mutt!
Ouch! Stop it!
You cut it out!
That's the man, captain.
That's him!
No, I'm innocent!
No, no!
Look, I'm innocent!
I haven't done
anything wrong.
I'll explain the whole
thing to you again.
You see,
my boy's a dog...
"Just got here
in the Nick of time."
A great big hero,
are ya?
Wilby!
- Good old buzz, huh?
Right in the Nick
of time, are you?
The great big hero, eh?
Wilby, will you lay off?
I don't know what you're
talkin' about. Wilby!
You don't know what
I'm talking about?
I bet you don't!
Chiffon!
Oh, it was you.
You saved my life.
What a wonderful,
beautiful dog.
Mon Beau chien.
My hero.
Je t'aime de mon coeur.
Over here with that.
Mr. Daniels, you're in the way.
Do you mind?
No, not at all.
This stuff will clutter
up the picture.
Would you mind
holding these, please?
Thank you very much.
Ed, get ready
for a picture.
Now, Mr. Daniels,
a picture for our
Sunday follow-up story,
a human interest angle:
How your love for dogs made this
whole thrilling thing possible.
Oh, fine.
Now, Mr. Daniels,
if you'll just sit on
the arm of the chair.
Oh, right here?
All right, boy,
up in the chair.
Now just a minute!
I will not have that dog
up on my good chair with
his big, dusty feet!
Don't worry about it, honey.
A dog can't hurt anything.
How about me with my arm
around him, like this?
Fine, fine.
This all right?
That's fine, fine.
Now, how about one
with your son?
Oh. Well,
why not?
Come here, son.
Not you, the little fella.
Come on, wilby,
let's take a walk.
You stay just
like that. Good.
Mr. Daniels, you'll be
looking at your son.
All right.
Anyway,
it sure was nice of franceska
to give us the dog.
That old house is sure
gonna seem empty with
her gone back to Paris.
Yeah, swell girl.
Oh well, I guess
it's all for the best.
I was gettin' kind
of tired of all that
French lingo, anyway.
You wanna know somethin' else?
I don't think we've been
quite fair to Allison.
She's a swell girl too.
Yeah, good sport,
real good sport.
Anyone else
might've gotten sore.
Hi, Allison!
You know them?
Oh, just a couple of
neighborhood children.
Let's get the medal
in this picture.
Medal? What medal?
Valor award!
- Mm-hmm.
Well!
No, Mr. Daniels,
the medal is for the dog.
Oh.
There.
- That's
good.
Well, I finally
got a dog!
What do you mean,
you've got a dog?
We've got a dog!
Arf! Arf!
Arf!