Man: Ther e's a story told in
the town of Big Lake, Texas --
a story of the town's
beginnings.
It's the story
of the Santa Rita Number One,
birthplace
of West Texas Oil.
Now, as with
most Texas legends,
ther e was a man who thought oil
was right beneath his f eet.
And as with
most such stories,
no one else believed him.
Ex cept in this case
f or two nuns,
who in 1923 met the man
and believed so much in him
and his dr eam
that they invested money
no one knew they had.
Now, when the nuns told
their parish priest
about the man's dr eam
and their investment in it,
now, he counseled them
to try and get their money back.
Sheepishly, they admitted
that it was too late,
that the money
was alr eady spent.
Well, the priest, he sighed,
shook his head,
and off er ed just
one small bit of advice --
bless the site
with rose petals,
and invoke the help
of Saint Rita,
patron saint
of impossible dr eams.
And while the workers
waited f or the oil
that would eventually come,
they played baseball.
Oil worker:
He's outta here.
Played baseball so well
that some wer e able to give up
the dirt and the despair
and went on to play
major-league ball
in the glory days
of Ruth and Gehrig.
[ Indistinct talking ]
Come on!
I've heard and told
that story on many occasions,
but that was long bef or e
Saint Rita decided
to bless our little town
just one mor e time.
-- [ Bat cracks ball ]
-- Yeah!
First game
in the big leagues,
and Jimmy Morris
has a no-hitter going.
Agh, Jimmy,
don't throw it so hard.
My hands ar e cold.
[ Grunts ]
Agh!
What ar e you doing?
Waiting till Spring,
that's what I'm doing.
Jimmy...
Your f ather and I
need to talk to you.
I hear Virginia's
r eal nice --
at least that's what
the Navy f olks told your f ather.
Isn't that right, Jim?
We'll just be moving
again.
It's my job
to decide when we move.
It's your job
to make the best of it.
Jim, please.
Who knows? Maybe it won't snow
so much in Virginia.
Jimmy: "Jimmy Morris,
"with another masterf ul
pitching perf ormance,
"well on his way
to another
World Series title."
[ Fence rattles ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Panting ]
Jimmy...
Your f ather and I
need to talk to you.
[ Sighing ]
[ Indistinct talking ]
Man: Come on, Jimmy.
[ Sighs ]
[ Crowd cheers ]
Hey.
Jimmy.
[ Indistinct talking ]
Hey, partner.
How you doing?
Hey.
Hey, Dad.
Jimmy.
Hmm?
I had a good game --
13 strikeouts.
Did you win?
I just f ound out
there's a chance we may be
restationed again.
-- How much of a chance?
-- It's in West Texas.
The Navy wants me to be
a recruiter there.
Texas? When?
Thr ee weeks.
But, Dad...
We still got
half our season to play.
I'm awar e of that.
Well, maybe I could stay
with the Johnsons.
Unh-unh.
We move as a f amily.
I don't have a choice
in this.
What kind of baseball
do they have?
They don't.
I hear they might be starting
some summer ball.
Yes, sir.
[ Door opens, closes ]
Kael:
What are those things?
Jimmy: What?
Those things moving up
and down.
Oil rigs.
When those things
are moving up and down,
it means times are good.
Looks like times ar e good.
Shoot.
[ Sighs ]
We must have left some of them
back in Florida.
Left what?
I packed a couple of box es
with socks and things.
I could've sworn --
Jimmy, did you find
that one box?
Oh, no.
It's okay, Mom.
Don't worry, honey.
We'll find it.
I've never known a boy
to get so upset about
losing his socks.
His glove was in ther e.
His what?
His glove was in there.
Oh, quit moping
and grab a box.
Did you hear me?
Ther e ar e mor e important things
in lif e than baseball.
The sooner you figure that out,
the better.
[ Bell jingles ]
[ Door cr eaks, closes ]
[ Distant conversation ]
Man:
This Lee lvaco-cocus guy,
I guarantee you,
within two years,
three years tops,
he's gonna run that company
right out of business.
Ain't that right,
young man?
Eileen?
Eileen!
I guess she gone to lunch.
Help you find
something, son?
Socks.
Socks we have --
in contrast to common sense,
which we seem to be running
a little short on today.
I'll be right down.
Don't look at my dominoes.
All right, sir, we got
white socks with red stripes,
black stripes, blue stripes.
Over ther e you got
all your solids
in black, blue,
brown, and gray.
Just take your pick.
That's a r eal nice pair
right ther e.
You visiting?
We just moved her e.
Oh, well,
then I'm Henry Sampson.
Nice to meet you.
Jimmy Morris.
Welcome to Big Lake,
Mr. Jimmy Morris.
You know, son, I can probably
tell you wher e it is
a whole lot quicker
than you can find it.
Got any baseball stuff?
Oh, baseball stuff.
Don't get much call
f or baseball stuff
around these parts.
Now if it was football,
that'd be a whole different
story. [ Chuckles ]
You know something,
though?
I got a catalogue over here
that just might
help us out some.
Let's take a look at that.
[ Exhales deeply ]
Yeah, I think we might find
something in here.
You know, if you'r e inter ested
in baseball,
ther e's a story that people her e
in this town tell
that you probably
ought to hear.
Thought you said nobody her e
car ed about baseball.
Oh, they car e about this.
It all started
with a couple of nuns
and a piece of ground
not too f ar f rom here.
[ Scraping ]
[ Engine turns over ]
[ Indistinct conversations ]
-- Morning, Esther.
-- Morning, Jimmy.
Any more rattlesnakes
on the playground?
Yeah. Two this morning.
I swear those things show up
every time
the oil business goes bad.
-- They gonna bring
the kids in?
-- They're thinking about it.
Don't these f amilies
have enough to worry about?
Hmm.
Coach.
Counselor.
[ Exhales sharply ]
Don't r eport that, Esther.
I never do.
"Sum" means
that we'r e adding.
We have at least two items.
Don't make this hard,
but what ar e we adding
her e --
protons and...
Neutrons?
Neutrons.
So, David...
These protons
and these neutrons,
they're inside of...what?
The nucleus?
Well, don't say it
like a question, son.
If you think you know it, just
say it like you know it.
The nucleus.
That's right --
the nucleus.
[ Laughter ]
So, congratulations.
Go home tonight
and tell your par ents
that you figur ed out
the mass number of an atom.
Nat "King" Cole:
## Chestnuts roasting... ##
Jimmy: Frank, ain't it
a little late to be
playing this song?
-- It's 8:30.
-- It's March.
Well, that song's too good
to play f or only one month.
-- Hunter, you gonna want
cheese on that?
-- Yes, sir.
Cal: Besides, he smoked
three packs a day.
Henry: Who?
Nat "King" Cole. He thought
it'd make his voice deeper.
Frank: Oh, and Frank Sinatra
was the poster child
for vocal care?
Who died in his 50s?
You take care of yourself,
things work out.
Oh, is that right, is it?
Well, what about Jimmy, ther e?
I mean, he took
r eal good car e of himself,
and, uh, how many surgeries
was it, Jimmy -- f our?
Hunter:
They put this thing
f rom his ankle up
to his shoulder.
Ow.
We'r e talking about singing,
not pitching.
And, Hunter,
do us all a f avor
and don't tell us that bit
about the ankle anymore.
-- Mel Torme in June.
-- What in the world ar e you
talking about now?
Mel Torme wrote
"The Christmas Song"
on a beach somewher e.
There wasn't no Jack Frost
nippin' at anybody's nose
that day.
-- Daddy...
-- Yeah?
Your arm ever hurt
anymor e?
Only when I have to
drag you out of bed
in the morning
f or school.
No, I'm just kidding
you, bud.
It hasn't hurt
in a long time.
How long?
Why do you want to know?
Just wondering.
Oh, let's see.
[ Exhaling ] Uh...
It never hurt
when I was in high school,
'cause we didn't have
a baseball team.
And it never hurt
when I was in junior college,
'cause, well, that's why
I got drafted.
And then, uh...
I don't know.
Just started hurting.
Is that why
you didn't make it?
It's never one thing.
[ Fence rattles ]
[ Rattling continues ]
[ Baby crying ]
[ Groans ]
[ Sleepily ] Mmm.
[ Inhales deeply ]
I'll get her.
Is that a r eal
"I'll get her,"
or ar e you just
waiting f or me to say,
"Go back to sleep"?
I haven't decided yet.
Go back to sleep.
[ Crying continues ]
Mm, baby...
Aww...
Oh...
What's all that
crying about?
[ Crying continues ]
[ Sighs ]
I think it's my turn.
No.
It's your turn to sleep.
Shh.
Okay.
You sur e?
Yeah.
Here we go.
Come on, baby.
There we are.
Good night.
Mmm.
Ther e we go.
Shh.
Mmm.
Ther e we go.
Wack: Hey, Rudy, when was
the last date you had --
what, like a year ago?
Rudy: Not me, man.
Come on, man.
Who you kidding?
You, too, Rudy.
Don't be laughing.
All set, coach.
Give me a ball.
Owls player: Hey, coach,
I forgot my glove.
-- Check the bag.
-- [ Sighs ]
-- 10 players, 9 gloves.
-- Yeah.
-- How do they look?
-- Couple of holes.
All right, get one.
Thanks, man.
Hey, coach...
They putting down any grass seed
in the field this year?
Man, it's a goat track
out her e.
Just waiting
f or the seed to take.
Uh-huh?
-- What seed?
-- [ Chuckles ]
Ain't no seed
out her e, man.
Wack!
How come we get dirt,
and the f ootball field looks
like Tiger Woods' backyard?
They don't even play
f or six months.
Just let me worry
about the field, all right?
You plan on worrying
anytime soon?
-- All right, Wack.
-- [ Laughter ]
You can get your running done
early today.
All right, I'll get
my running in early.
Lookin' good.
Okay, bring it home!
[ Exhales deeply ]
Hey, coach...
you want to throw?
You know, I seen you
out there at the Old
Legion Field at night.
You know,
sometimes it helps
when you throw
if you got somebody
catching f or you.
A ball, a glove --
that kind of thing.
-- I'll throw a couple.
-- Really?
All right.
How come you throw out there
all by yourself?
Helps me relax.
I've been doing it...
a pr etty long time.
Coach, back when you
wer e r eally throwing,
how f ast wer e you
bringing it?
I don't know.
85, 86.
Well, that's not bad.
Well, it is when
the other guy's
throwing 90.
Coach, come on.
Let's see you bring one.
Can't.
Promised too many doctors.
Come on, coach,
one is not gonna kill you.
Now, come on.
Feed me.
Yeah, Dad.
Bring the heat.
Feed me, coach.
[ Air whooshes ]
Wow!
Coach...
Wher e'd that come f rom?
Forgot how good
that sounded.
Yes!
[ Air whooshes ]
[ Chuckles ]
[ Hunter laughing ]
[ Air whooshing ]
[ Grunting ]
Unbelievable.
Coach, how f ast do you
think those were coming?
-- Oh, not as f ast
as you think.
-- Oh.
Hey, uh, do me a f avor,
all right?
Let's just keep this
between you and me.
Okay.
Hunter: You could barely see
that last one.
And that goes f or you too,
all right?
-- No telling Mom.
-- Why?
[ Sighs ]
Because I said so.
Good night, Ray.
I know why
your grass isn't growing.
[ Crickets chirping ]
Usually get thr ee or f our
out her e every night.
So I put the seed down,
they pick it up.
Once it comes in,
they don't like it as much.
That's why the f ootball field
looks so good.
Yeah?
Maybe those f ootball guys
ar e paying off these deer
with all the big budget money
they got.
[ Laughs ]
Hey!
Go on! Get out of here!
I thought deer
wer e supposed to be skittish.
[ Allison Moor er singing
"Tumbling Down" on ster eo ]
Need me
to top that off?
Nothing like wine bought
with a Chevron cr edit card.
Well, I know what a demanding
consumer you can be.
Mmm. Yeah?
Yeah.
[ Sighs ]
I thr ew today.
To Joel...
after practice.
You thr ew?
I thr ew.
How hard?
Pr etty hard.
Uh, don't worry.
If it starts to hurt,
l-l'll stop.
All right? Promise.
I gotta check on
the kids.
Joe David: Wack, got
the muffler changed,
buddy -- the jeep.
Can't hear me coming three
miles away, can you, there?
Owls player:
Ray, check out the screwball!
Ladies loving the jeep.
Come on, man.
Give me the rock.
All right,
bring it in f or some b.p.
We can't.
Rudy's not her e.
-- Well, wher e is he?
-- Locker room.
Something to do
with only having one shoe.
Somebody grab a bat.
You'r e throwing
batting practice?
Yeah.
-- [ Laughter ]
-- I'm up first, man.
Wack: I hit the Lotto!
Joe David: Come on, Wack!
Send it, baby!
Send it!
What do you say, Wack?
[ Laughs ]
-- Whoo!
-- Yeah!
Looks like that one's
gonna land in another
time zone, coach!
You might want to r eset your
watch bef or e this next one.
You see that?
Yeah, it's...
Come on.
Joe David: Yeah!
[ Laughs ]
[ Inhales deeply ]
-- [ Grunts ]
-- [ Air whooshes ]
What was that?
Man!
Wait till he warms up.
[ Laughs ]
[ Rudy and Joe David
laughing ]
Let me see
another one of those.
Nope. It's batting practice,
not pitching practice.
[ Chuckles ]
All right.
[ Laughing ] Oh, my God!
Cal: I'm already down
two bits.
How many of them
job applications you plan on
sending out, Jimmy?
Many as it takes, I guess.
So the little boy
coming into my stor e to buy
socks after a dozen moves
is planning on making
a move of his own now?
Well, this is diff er ent.
[ Laughs ] It always is.
I hear you diagnosed
that problem with that
baseball field of yours.
You mean
his potential field.
Well, "diagnosed" part's right.
It's the "curing" part I'm
having trouble with.
I'll take five.
You know, I had the same
trouble out at my place
a few Springs back.
You did?
What'd you do?
Oh, hell.
Give me five, too.
Let me ask you something --
how many games
you got on that field
next couple of weeks?
Well, we -- we play ther e
next Friday,
but then we'r e not back
till the end of the month.
You think you can keep
your boys off the field
f or that length of time?
Now, I'm talking about no
practice, nothing whatsoever.
Henry...
why do I get the f eeling
this is something
I don't want to know about?
I'm gonna take back
two of them old ones
if that's okay with everybody.
I'll tell you what you do.
You give me thr ee weeks,
and I'll have that field
Iooking gr eener than Dublin
on Saint Patty's Day.
50 cents, fellas.
[ Coins rattle ]
Woman: All right, boys.
Get a hit.
Cal: [ On P.A. ]
Rudy Bonilla, hoping to
spark a Big Lake rally.
Come on, Rudy!
Be a hitter!
Owls player:
Keep your eye on it.
Strike thr ee!
Cal: Strike three called,
and the Owls drop
their season opener.
It's all right.
It's okay. Good eff ort.
It's only one.
If we don't start hitting,
it's not gonna be the only one.
Opposing player: Good game.
Good game, buddy.
Cal: Drive safely
on your way home now, folks.
Good game.
[ "Baby, I Ain't Gotta Do That
No Mor e" plays ]
[ Humming ]
Wher e do you keep
your brooms, Cal?
Closet.
Right her e, sweetheart.
Owls player: Come on, Cory.
Give it a ride.
-- Give it a ride, now.
-- [ Smooches ]
Matt: Get ready, Cory.
Owls player #2:
Guy couldn't throw a fit...
Come on, Cory!
-- Yeah!
-- Oh!
Joel: Play's at second,
Miguel!
-- [ Sighs ]
Blue!
Time!
Cal: [ On P.A. ]
And the Owls are down 10.
Not your day, Rudy.
Not my year.
Looks like
coach Jimmy Morris
is making a pitching change.
Owls player:
Shake it off, Rudy!
Cal: Just a reminder, folks --
the concession stand
is still open.
Jimmy: Anybody want to tell me
how we lost that game?
Hmm?
No?
How 'bout taking a look
at the numbers
on that scoreboard
out there?
What do those numbers
tell you?
How to get ahold
of Bo's Tir e Barn?
[ Laughter ]
You quit.
You quit out there.
You quit on me, and worse,
you quit on yourselves.
Now, what is it?
Think people don't car e about
baseball around her e?
Think the school's gonna
drop the program?
You're just making it easy
for 'em.
Sad part about it is,
I see it and you don't.
Look, guys...
Most of you...
[ Exhales sharply ]
You'r e gonna
finish up school her e,
you'r e gonna work the rigs,
you'r e gonna work at
Bo's Tir e Barn,
you'r e gonna raise a f amily
and r etir e,
and you'r e gonna do all that
right her e in Big Lake.
And ther e's nothing wrong
with that.
A lot of r eal good people have
done that.
I'm doing it.
But if you're looking for
something more
after you're done here,
you better give
some serious thought
as to how you'r e gonna play out
the r est of this season.
What diff er ence
does it make?
I mean, it's not
like any of us ar e
getting scholarships.
I'm not talking about
college.
I'm talking about
wanting things in lif e.
having dr eams.
And all that starts
right her e.
Okay? Right here.
You don't have dr eams,
you don't have anything.
Joel: Coach,
what about you?
I mean,
you talk about our dr eams.
I... [ Sighs ] I mean,
I've been catching yours --
Joel, we ar e not talking
about me.
Yeah, come on, coach.
Every time you throw,
I got to ice my hand --
every time.
Y-you'r e the one
who should be
wanting something mor e.
And the sad part is,
I mean...
We see it and you don't.
Now, listen,
I've had my shot, all right?
Just... [ Sighs ]
Look, we got practice
tomorrow.
Let's go.
-- So you take another shot.
-- It doesn't work like that.
It does if
you throw hard enough.
I don't throw hard enough,
all right?
-- Now let's hit the shower.
Come on.
-- N-Now wait a minute.
We start winning,
you try out again.
[ Scoff s ]
[ Exhales deeply ]
Last time I checked,
scouts ar en't looking f or
high-school science teachers.
Well, not many science
teachers throw like you.
-- No kidding.
-- Yeah.
-- No lie.
[ Sighs ] Take a heck of a lot
mor e than a couple of Wins
to get me to make
a f ool of myself.
All right.
What if we win district?
Huh?
What if we win district
and go to state playoff s? Then?
Ar e you serious?
Yeah, absolutely.
Yeah.
And all I have to do is just
find some kind of tryout
somewher e?
That's it, man.
[ Clears throat ]
All right.
-- Yeah!
If...
-- If you win district.
-- Yeah!
Come on, man,
we can do this!
-- Right on, man.
-- Yeah, coach!
We can take it!
Whoo!
Let's do this, man!
I don't get to tell Mom
about this, do l?
[ Guy Clark and Rodney Crowell's
"Stuff That Works" plays ]
[ Crickets chirping ]
## I got an old blue shirt,
and it suits me just fine ##
[ Brakes squeaking ]
## I like the way it feels,
so I wear it all the time ##
## I got an old guitar,
won't ever stay in tune ##
## I like the way it sounds
in a dark and empty room ##
## I got an old pair of boots,
and they fit just right ##
Hmm.
## Well, I can work all day,
and I can dance all night ##
## I got an old used car,
and it runs just like a top ##
## I get the feeling
it ain't ever gonna stop ##
## Stuff that works ##
## Stuff that holds up ##
## ls the kind of stuff
you don't hang on the wall ##
## Stuff that's real ##
## That stuff you feel ##
## ls the kind of stuff
you reach for when you f all ##
## Stuff that works ##
## Stuff that holds up ##
-- [ Vehicle passes by ]
-- ## ls the kind of stuff
you don't hang on the wall ##
## Stuff that's real ##
## That stuff you feel ##
## ls the kind of stuff
you reach for when you f all ##
## The stuff that works ##
-- [ Grunting ]
-- ## The stuff that holds up ##
## The kind of stuff
you don't hang on the wall ##
-- [ Scraping ]
-- ## Stuff that's real ##
-- [ Br eathes deeply ]
-- ## That stuff you feel ##
## ls the kind of stuff
you reach for when you f all ##
[ Br eathes deeply ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Clicking ]
Cal: You sure about this,
Henry?
Yeah. Deer get
a whiff of human hair,
they just keep on moving
till they don't smell it
no mor e.
I figur e we put us
a circle
all the way
around the field her e.
This is a lot of hair.
[ Chuckles ] Well,
f rom the looks of things,
contrary to popular opinion,
Cal ain't been cheating
nobody down ther e at his shop.
[ All laugh ]
[ Indistinct talking ]
It helps if you actually
wear those goggles,
Ms. Martinez.
Uh, coach...
[ Chuckling ]
Joel: Yeah, baby.
Is that what
I think it is?
That, gentlemen, is
Bermuda Hybrid Number Five.
We'r e gonna have
a baseball field.
[ Doorbell rings ]
Maybe he's not home.
But he said
he'd be her e.
[ Doorbell rings ]
Hey, Grandpa.
Hunter.
I was r eading in the paper
this morning
that someone in your f amily
is having a birthday.
That's a kid joke,
Grandpa.
Kid joke? No kidding?
Jimmy.
Sir.
Whoa!
It's kinda big.
Oh, you'll grow into it
f aster than you think.
Look, Dad, it doesn't have
any fingers.
That's 'cause
it's a first-baseman's mitt.
Uh...is that wrong?
Well, you know, l-l probably
got the r eceipt somewher e.
Uh, we can just --
we can get another one, huh?
One with fingers.
That's okay, Grandpa.
I like first base.
Can I go outside
and play, Dad?
[ Clears throat ] Yeah.
What do you say first?
Thank you, Grandpa.
I r eally like it a lot.
Oh.
[ Chuckling ] Oh.
Stay in the yard.
If he decides he wants
one with fingers...
I'll take car e of it.
[ Sighs ]
I didn't know
you had these.
Oh, yeah.
Your mother gave me a f ew.
Hmm. She'd be the one
to have 'em.
## Happy birthday to you ##
## Happy birthday,
dear Hunter ##
## Happy birthday to you ##
Make a wish. Oh!
Jessica!
Lorri:
Hey, don't worry, baby.
Your wish still counts.
-- [ Whistle blows ]
-- Charles...
Do you think that
that ice-cream machine
is gonna start
spinning itself?
[ Noisemaker blows ]
Oh, I gotta go get
a knif e.
I'll help you, Mom.
I think we need plates,
hon, too.
-- [ Grunts ]
-- [ Pop ]
Seems like
five minutes ago
I was watching you
blow out those candles.
Ar e you trying to
make me f eel old?
Come talk to me
in 20 years.
Hunter says you spent
some time at your f ather's
today.
Yeah.
You know wher e
I'm going with that.
Yes, ma'am, I do.
Lorri says he's trying
r eal hard
to be a good grandf ather.
Yeah, well...
Lord, Jimmy, I swear,
the one thing you got f rom him
is his stubborn side.
-- That's not true.
-- [ Sighs ]
Well, what do you
want me to do,
pr etend everything
was perf ect?
You've been blaming your f ather
f or too many things
f or too many years.
I just call 'em
like I see 'em, Mom.
[ Chuckles ]
Jimmy, you can sell that story
someplace else, 'cause
I ain't buying.
You got your shot
at baseball.
You got hurt.
Simple as that.
It had nothing to do
with your f ather.
You think
he didn't have dr eams?
[ Sighs ]
That why it didn't work out
with you two?
[ Chuckles ]
I'm gonna need a longer str eet
f or that talk.
Jimmy:
Okay, let's get two.
[ Bat cracks ball ]
Come on, Wack!
Come on, coach, how long
we gotta practice her e?
Just a couple
of more days.
Joe David:
Getting old out here, coach.
Playing in a gravel yard.
Okay, Wack.
Come on in f or
batting practice.
Owls player: This is
not a ball field.
-- Come on, let's go.
-- Okay, okay.
[ Metal squeaks ]
Okay.
Nice, easy swings.
Turn your hips.
Throw your hands
at the ball.
Come on, coach, l-l mean,
if we'r e gonna start winning,
we need to see
some better pitching.
-- Rudy: Yeah.
You gonna help us or not?
Come on, coach,
right here.
Joe David: Yo, let's see
some action.
[ Sighs ]
Joe David: Come on, Wack.
[ Elvis Pr esley's "Run On"
plays ]
## Ooooh ##
## Well, you may run on
for a long time ##
-- ## Run on for a long time ##
-- [ Air whooshes ]
## Run on for a long time ##
## Let me tell you, God
Almighty's gonna cut you down ##
-- ## Go tell that
long-tongued liar ##
-- [ Whooshing continues ]
## Go tell that midnight rider ##
## Tell the gambler,
the rambler, the backbiter ##
## Tell them God Almighty's
gonna cut them down ##
## You may throw your rock
and hide your hand ##
## Working in the dark
against your fellow man ##
## As sure as God made
the day and the night ##
## What you do in the dark
will be brought to the light ##
## You may run and hide,
slip and slide ##
## Trying to take the mote
f rom your neighbor's eye ##
## As sure as God made
the rich and poor ##
-- ## You gonna reap
just what you sow ##
-- [ Bat nicks ball ]
Rudy: Man!
[ Laughs ]
Hey, right on, man.
Got a piece of that one!
Now...get all of it.
-- You're the man, Wack.
-- Come on, Wack.
Joe David:
Catching up, coach.
-- [ Air whooshes ]
-- [ Bat cracks ball ]
[ Crowd cheering ]
Two, Wack! Two!
Go, go, go, go, go!
Stay up!
Stay, stay, stay!
Attaway, Wack!
-- [ Crack ]
-- Hustle!
[ Cheering continues ]
[ Crack ]
Run, boy, run!
[ Indistinct cheering ]
Pick it up! Pick it up,
pick it up, pick it up!
Umpire: Out!
[ Crack ]
-- Take it, Joel!
-- Got it!
Run, run, run,
run, run, run!
-- Yeah!
-- Yeah! Whoo!
-- Whoo!
-- Yeah!
[ Cheering continues ]
Ther e you go, Joel!
Ther e you go, baby!
Hit it, Wack!
Eye on the ball, buddy!
[ John Hiatt's "Slow Turning"
plays ]
[ Cheers ]
## When I was a boy ##
## I thought it just came
to ya ##
## But I never could tell
what's mine ##
## So it didn't matter anyway ##
Cal: [ On P.A. ] How 'bout that
for an outstanding double play?
## My only pride and joy ##
## Was this racket down here ##
## Bangin' on an old guitar... ##
Cal: The Owls win again,
and that is five in a row.
## ...lt's been a slow turnin' ##
Let's go.
## From the inside out ##
[ Cracking ]
-- ## A slow turnin', baby ##
-- All around, all around.
## But you come about ##
Strike thr ee!
## A slow learnin' ##
-- Whoo! Yeah!
-- ## But you learn to sway ##
Yeah, baby!
-- ## A slow turnin', baby ##
-- Come on,
get some def ense going!
## Not f ade away,
not f ade away... ##
Joe David: He's taking second!
-- Strike thr ee!
## ... Time is short, and here's
the damn thing about it ##
-- He's out!
-- ## You're gonna die,
gonna die for sure ##
## And you can learn to live
with love or without it ##
## But there ain't no cure ##
## There's just
a slow turnin'... ##
[ Crack ]
Cal: Going...going...
Gone!
## ...A slow turnin' ##
Whoooo!
## But you come about ##
-- The Owls clear the bases.
-- ## A slow turnin', baby ##
-- [ Cheers ]
-- ## But you learn to sway ##
## A slow turnin' ##
-- Yeah!
-- ## Not f ade away,
not f ade away ##
## Not f ade away... ##
[ All shouting ]
Hey! Hey!
Hey, hey, hey!
Keep it down now,
or f olks ar e gonna think
that f ootball season's
started alr eady!
-- Yeah!
Now, a lot of coaches
would say
that they'r e r eally proud
of you right now,
and I am.
-- Yeah!
A lot of coaches --
a lot of coaches would say
that it's amazing
that we won this many
games in a row,
and it is.
-- Yeah! !
But! But!
But, but, but,
but, but...
I am not gonna say
that I do not car e about
tomorrow's game,
'cause I do.
So let's finish
this thing up.
[ Owls cheer ]
[ Chanting ] State!
State! State! State!
State! State! State! State!
Quite a group
you got there.
-- Well, thanks.
-- I'm Steve Dearborn.
-- I'm with the Barton School
District in Fort Worth.
-- Oh.
I was hoping we might be
able to talk about that
application you sent us.
Uh...sur e.
[ Cheering continues ]
[ No audio ]
They'll understand.
[ Sighs ] I got most of 'em
coming back.
Jimmy, you'r e always gonna have
kids coming back.
Not these kids.
It's Fort Worth.
High-school coaching jobs
don't get any better.
You get to coach,
you get to teach...
And not that it's the most
important thing in lif e,
but...it is twice the money,
Jimmy.
We sur e could use it.
I know.
Well, I am done telling you
to sleep on it,
because that sur e
ain't working.
[ Exhales deeply ]
[ Clears throat ]
Thr ee years ago,
this program ended the season
with only one win.
Two years ago...
one win.
Last year...same story.
This year...
We have won 16 games.
And, gentlemen...
We need 17.
Anybody got any questions?
Hmm?
Wack: Coach...
Coming back next year?
Wack...
Why don't we worry about
this year first, all right?
All right, gentlemen,
hats off.
Lord, we humbly thank You
f or bringing us her e
this season without injury
and inspiring us...
[ "Star Spangled Banner"
playing ]
Henry: [ On P.A. ]
## And the rockets' red glare ##
## The bombs bursting in air ##
## Gave proof
through the night ##
## That our flag
was still there ##
## Oh, say, does that
star-spangled banner yet wave ##
## O'er the land of the f ree ##
## And the home of the brave ##
[ Cheers and applause ]
Cal: [ On P.A. ]
A stirring rendition
f rom Big Lake
Rotary President,
Henry Sampson.
All right, all right.
We're a different team
than last time
we played these guys.
They'r e ripe
f or the pickin' .
Just...let's not be nervous
out ther e.
[ Panting ]
Nothing to be nervous about.
Let's play baseball.
[ Cheers ]
[ Cheering ]
Go! Go! Go!
Go all the way!
Coach: Wave him home!
Home! Home! Home!
Safe!
Yes! Yeah!
Come on, guys.
Guys, come on.
Settle down.
Owls player: Shake it off,
baby. Shake it off.
Wack!
Give me the ball!
Damn!
Boys f rom Big Lake
ln an early hole --
2 to naught.
Keep your heads up.
Get this thing back to even.
Wack: It's all right.
Joel: Come on, boys.
It's the first inning.
All right, Brandon,
grab some wood.
Joe David, you'r e on deck.
This guy's f astball stinks,
so be looking out f or his curve,
all right?
Umpire: Batter up!
All right, one hit at a time,
one swing at a time,
one run at a time.
Come on, now.
Watch him! Let's go!
What do you say, Miguel?
Wack: All right, Miguel.
Come on.
Joel: Let's get a hit.
Let's get a hit.
Umpire: He's out!
[ Groans ]
Damn.
Owls still with that zero
up on the board.
Rowley player: Throw him out!
Out!
A scorcher that dang-near
took our boy's head off.
[ Applause ]
[ Cheering ]
Whoo!
Come on, slide!
Saf e! And that puts Big Lake
ln scoring position.
You all right?
Owls player: Whoo!
Cal: Rudy Bonilla coming
to the plate.
[ Cheering continues ]
Come on, baby!
Come on!
Owls player: Come on!
Let's go!
Owls player #2: Come on!
Send him home!
[ Cheering ]
Saf e! Saf e!
Yeah!
A suicide squeeze,
and the Owls
ar e on the scor eboard.
Go, ball, go!
Yeah!
[ Cheering ]
Spectacular catch, and the Owls
are hanging in there.
Come on, Wack!
Cal: Joe David
is still on first base.
I see it! I see the f ear
in his eyes, Wack!
Come on, baby!
Come on, baby! Just do it!
Let's go, baby!
Joel: Let's go, Wack!
Come on!
Come on, now!
Come on, Wack!
Go, Wack!
Let's go, Wack!
Come on, baby!
[ Cheering ]
[ Whistling ]
Go! Go!
Go! Come on!
Stay! Stay!
Whoa! Whoa!
Whoo!
No!
Saf e!
Yeah!
Whoo!
Joe David!
Yes!
Big Lake takes the lead.
Rudy Bonilla
working with a f ull count.
Ruff neck runners
on first and second.
Owls player:
Smoke it by him!
Come on, 'Necks!
You can do it!
[ Grunts ]
Ball f our.
[ Groans ]
Bases now f ull of Ruff necks.
[ Cheering and applause ]
Owls player: Right here, Rudy!
Right here, right now!
Owls player #2: We got him!
Owls player #3:
Let's go, Rudy!
Let's get this out!
Look him down, Rudy!
Look him down!
Cal: Last year's District MVP
Cory Jones coming to the plate.
Rowley player:
All right, Cory!
Rowley player #2:
'Necks all the way!
Owls player:
Throw him some heat, Rudy!
Woman: Yeah! Whoo!
[ Cheers and applause ]
Umpire: Ball!
[ Booing ]
Come on, baby!
Joe David:
Come on, Rudy!
What do you say now?!
Aw, come on, now, Rudy!
Come on, baby!
Get this last out!
-- Come on!
-- Strike him out, Rudy!
Come on!
Strike him out!
Jimmy: Here we go!
Here we go!
Owls player: He's got nothing!
He's got nothing!
Joe David: Look alive!
Man: Come on! Tighten up, now!
Tighten up!
Strike!
[ Cheers and applause ]
Oh, he is having
to dig deep now.
One-and-one count.
[ Grunts ]
[ Gasping ]
Go. Go.
Goin' f oul! Goin' f oul!
Foul ball!
[ Sighs ]
Goin' foul! Yeah!
Ball.
Let me tell you, folks,
they don't make foul balls
any scarier than that one.
Come on, Rudy!
Let's go!
You can do it!
Bear down, baby!
Bear down!
[ Cheering continues ]
We need another strike,
Rudy.
What do you say, Rudy?!
Come on!
He can't hit you!
-- He got nothing on you!
-- He can't hit you!
Come on, now, rapid-fire, baby.
Rapid-fire.
-- It's just a long strike now.
-- You can do it, Rudy!
You own him, Rudy!
Come on, baby!
You got to do this one!
This punk can't hit you, Rudy!
Come on!
He got nothing on you!
Dig deep, Rudy.
One time, f or all the marbles.
Let's go, baby.
Joe David: Come on, Rudy!
What do you say?!
Strike this guy out!
Come on!
[ Grunts ]
Strike thr ee!
[ Cheering ]
Owls win!
Owls win! Owls win!
[ Cheering continues ]
Whoo-hoo!
Yeah!
Owls win!
[ "Jump Around" by House Of Pain
plays on ster eo ]
[ Owls continue cheering ]
## Pack it up, pack it in,
let me begin ##
## I came to win,
battle me, that's a sin ##
## I won't tear the sack up,
punk, you'd better back up ##
## Try and play the role
and then the whole crew
will act up ##
## Get up, stand up,
come on, throw your hands up ##
## lf you've got the feeling
jump across the ceiling ##
## Muggs is a f unk fest,
someone's talking junk ##
## Yo, I'll bust 'em in the eye,
and then I'll take the punks
home ##
## Feel it, f unk it, amps
in the trunk, and I got... ##
Hey.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
-- Settle down, fellas.
-- [ Music stops ]
Wack: Yeah, come on, guys.
Quiet down.
To the man who taught us
about wanting something mor e.
Coach Jimmy Morris
of the District Champion
Big Lake Owls!
[ Cheering ]
We wanted it,
and now we got it! Yeah!
[ Cheering and applause
continues ]
stops ]
Now it's your turn,
coach.
It's your turn, coach.
Your turn, coach.
[ Baby crying ]
Her e you go.
[ Smacking ]
Eat your cereal.
Come on.
[ Smacks ] Come on.
First day
of summer r egistration.
I'm gonna have to skip
br eakf ast.
Mommy, you can take
some Mister Crunch
with you if you like.
He's a captain, Jessie.
Don't go bustin' rank on him.
Thanks anyway, hon.
You got anything
going today?
Me?
No.
-- We need to go see
the r eal estate guy.
-- [ Cries ]
He's been a captain f or ever.
Why don't they make him
something better?
Like, you mean, like,
like Admiral Crunch?
Just say, "Yes, ma'am, "
so I know you heard me.
Yes, ma'am.
Take 'em all with you
if you go.
[ Smooching ]
You kids mind your daddy.
Remind me not to forget Jamie
if we go anywhere.
[ Brakes squeak ]
They got lots of players,
Daddy.
[ Sighs ]
[ Engine stops ]
Man: Sign right here.
Have your players get in line,
coach.
Everybody signs in.
Jim Morris.
Dave Patterson.
I saw you when the Br ewers
drafted you.
Must have been, uhh...
Awhile back.
Yeah.
How ya doing, Dave?
Good.
You, um...
You still looking
at players?
Oh, well, the looking's
the easy part.
It's the finding
that gives me trouble.
-- Mm.
-- You bring some kids...
Besides your own?
Uh, I'm --
I'm her e f or me.
For you?
Uh-huh.
Well, all right, then.
All right.
-- Good to see you.
-- That's good.
-- Uh-huh.
Sign her e.
[ "Nothing I Can Do About It
Now" by Willie Nelson plays ]
## I've got a long list
of real good reasons ##
## For all the things
I've done... ##
Come on. Let's go.
Oops.
Oops. Ex cuse me.
## ... Of what I've lost
and what I've won ##
## I've survived
every situation ##
## Knowin' when to f reeze
and when to run ##
## And regret is just a memory
written on my brow ##
## And there's nothing I can do
about it now ##
## I've got a wild
and a restless spirit ##
## I kept my price
through every deal ##
## I've seen the fire
of a woman scorned... ##
Daddy,
you can be X's this time.
Okay.
## ...l've got the song
of the voice inside me ##
## Set to the rhythm
of the wheel ##
## And I've been dreamin'
like a child ##
## Since the cradle
broke the bow ##
## And there's nothin'
I can do about it now ##
[ Crying ]
Now, now.
That's the last diaper.
Well, it's okay.
We'r e outta her e just as soon
as Jamie's set to go.
But, Dad --
No "But, Dads," okay?
I'm dealing with enough butts
her e as it is.
Hold on, honey.
Daddy's almost done.
[ Jamie continues crying ]
Hunter...
...Look,
I promised to try out,
but ther e's nothing
I can do if they won't
take a look at me.
Jimmy!
Come on. You'r e up.
[ Jamie continues crying ]
Just a second.
I'm not doing it.
All right, look, look, look.
You just stay right her e.
You look after your sister,
all right?
Come on. Let's go.
[ Jamie crying ]
Sit!
Be right back.
Who do we got her e?
All right. All right.
Need to warm up?
Uhh...no.
I'm good.
Don't hurt yourself.
Whenever you're ready.
Whenever I'm r eady.
[ Exhales deeply ]
[ Scraping ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Air whooshes,
ball slaps mitt ]
[ "Blue Moon Nights"
by John Fogerty plays ]
## Help me, fellas,
I'm feelin' kinda weak ##
## The way I'm livin'
just ain't right... ##
[ Grunts ]
[ Whispering ]
## ...All my blue moon nights ##
[ Grunts ]
## I want a girl to take me
by the hand ##
[ Grunts ]
## Follow me
right down the line ##
## Hold me gently
while we dance... ##
[ Grunts ]
You want me to keep going?
Couple mor e.
[ Grunts ]
## ...Help me, fellas,
it's gettin' kinda late ##
## Runnin' outta precious time ##
## She might pass me... ##
[ Grunts ]
## ...All my blue moon nights ##
## Heaven only knows I don't
want to be just a fool ##
[ Giggling ]
## Passin' through ##
## Won't you send an angel
to walk with me?
## All my blue moon nights ##
## All my blue moon... ##
[ Grunts ]
## ...All my... ##
That's good, Jim.
Pitch.
Man, you wer e bringing
some heat out ther e.
Aw, come on.
You had 'em talking.
Good job, man.
[ Horn honks ]
That was Jessica.
Jim.
Man: You did good,
though, man.
How f ast wer e you throwing
15 years ago?
Slow enough that scouts stopped
using the word "f ast."
Jim, how f ast
wer e you throwing?
I don't know.
85, 86.
Why?
You just thr ew
98 miles an hour.
Nah.
Dozen straight pitches.
Thr ee radar guns.
Same thing on all of 'em.
Nah, D-Dave,
ther e's no way that I --
I've been a scout
a long time now,
and Rule Number One is arms
slow down when they get older.
Listen, Jim,
I call the office
and I tell them I got a guy her e
almost twice these kids' age,
I'm gonna get laughed at.
But if I don't call in
a 98-mile-an-hour f astball,
I'm gonna get fir ed.
I'm just letting you know
that there's a chance
you might get a call
on this.
You figur e out what I saw out
ther e today,
you let me know, okay?
Okay.
[ Beep ]
Jimmy: Hey, hon,
don't fix dinner.
We're getting some pizza.
Oh, thank God.
[ Beep ]
Man: Jim, this is Dan Jordan
with the Tampa Bay Devil Rays.
I'll try you back later.
[ Beep ]
Man #2: Jim, Mark Raf us with
the Tampa Bay Devil Rays.
Dave Patterson told me
about this afternoon.
I'll try you first thing
in the morning.
[ Beep ]
Dave: Hey, Jim, this is Dave.
Listen, uh...
We're gonna have you throw
again in a couple of days
just to make sure.
They're gonna send out
some of the boys f rom Tampa.
[ Brakes squeak, engine stops ]
Mommy!
Daddy told me
to give you the pizza
and not say anything else.
Thank you, sweet pea.
I'm sur e that's exactly
what he told you.
[ Jamie cries ]
All right.
All right, go. Go ahead.
Hunter: There was, like,
a thousand players,
and it was so hot.
And Daddy was pitching
really hard.
-- Oh, yeah?
Jessica: Yeah.
-- And it was really hot,
but it was f un.
-- Yeah.
-- And I got my nose burned
really bad.
-- Yeah.
Hmm.
Jimmy: The guy thought that the
damn radar gun was broken.
Do you know how many guys
can throw the ball
98 miles an hour?
Not many.
You can count 'em
on one hand.
I still don't believe it.
I mean, those ar e major-league
scouts on our message machine.
I know.
[ Chuckles ] It's gr eat.
Um, listen, honey, w-why didn't
you tell me about all this?
Well, I just...
thought you'd laugh at me.
Oh, come on.
It was just this --
it was this thing to get
the kids to start playing.
I thought I'd just go ther e,
I'd throw a f ew pitches,
then I'd be done with it.
So...
are you considering this?
I-l don't know.
I -- I-l don't know.
I...l have never thrown
that hard bef or e.
What?
Hmm?
Y-you don't seem
too ex cited.
No, I am.
Really.
[ Dishes clinking ]
[ Water running ]
Announcer: [ On television ]
It's a tough decision.
Do you go ahead and call in
your set-up man
to try to counter
the left-handed batter
with the
lefty middle-reliever?
Announcer #2: [ On television ]
That's right, Tom.
They have Johnson available
as well as Bisou,
who did work one f ull inning
on Tuesday night.
Yup, now it appears they've
made up their minds...
And they're gonna go
the set-up route.
And here comes Gray
out of the bullpen,
making the traditional run
through the outfield
to the mound.
You know, Jim, I'm sure
no matter how many times
you've made that run,
it still has to be
quite a thrill.
Right you are, Jim.
Back to the action.
[ Television turns off ]
[ Remote control drops ]
[ Rain f alling ]
[ Sloshing ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Slap ]
Ain't nothing wrong
with that one right ther e.
[ Grunts ]
[ Slap ]
So much f or his arm
f alling off, huh?
[ Slap ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Sloshes ]
[ Engine running ]
[ Engine stops ]
Jimmy?
Yeah -- yes, sir.
[ Clears throat ]
I was just driving by.
I saw that...
Your light was on.
It'll be on
f or a f ew mor e hours.
You want to come in?
Oh, no.
That's all right.
I was, um --
I got to be heading back.
I just, uh, wanted to,
um...
[ Clears throat ]
-- Uh --
-- Lorri called.
Yeah?
Guess the scouts saw
what they wanted to see.
Well...
I don't know what to do.
[ Chuckles softly ]
Give it some time.
[ Sighs deeply ]
I haven't got
a lot of that.
You'r e asking me?
[ Clears throat ]
[ Smacks lips ]
[ Sighs ]
Yes, sir.
Your grandf ather
once told me
it was okay to think about
what you want to do,
until it was time to start doing
what you wer e meant to do.
That may not be
what you wanted to hear.
[ Clears throat ]
Good night, Jimmy.
Good night.
I swear, sometimes I think
he lies in bed at night
just figuring out the one thing
that he can say
that hurts the most.
I was this close
to thinking
he was gonna give me
some good advice.
Maybe he did.
What?
Oh, boy. [ Sighs ]
Listen, Jimmy, I love you.
Lord knows I think it's gr eat
you going out ther e
and showing up the kids
at the tryout.
But I'm a little concerned that
you might be losing sight
of the f act you have a f amily
who needs you
and a pretty decent job waiting
for you up at Fort Worth.
For the r ecord, all right,
I never said
I was gonna do this.
Oh, come on, Jimmy.
I know you.
Although I was hoping f or
a little bit mor e support
on the home f ront.
Oh, so this doesn't concern
me...or the kids?
You can't eat dr eams,
Jimmy.
And they don't pay f or clothes
or shoes or gas or babysitters.
Now, I do not want to be
the bad guy in this,
but somebody around here
has got to start
being rational.
You know what?!
That's all I've been
my whole lif e!
Yeah,
what about my lif e?!
I was there, too,
remember?
Every time you got hurt,
I got a f ront-row seat
to watch you shut yourself off
f rom the r est of the world...
And f rom me.
Truth is,
I was happy when you quit.
Happy.
Yeah...
Because I don't want to see you
get hurt again.
[ Clears throat ]
[ Exhales deeply ]
[ Footsteps approaching ]
[ Sighs ] Kids down?
For a while, at least.
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
Me too.
[ Exhales deeply ]
I've been thinking --
So have l.
I think you should do this.
No. No.
You wer e right.
No. I don't think so.
We've got an 8-year-old boy
inside this house
who waited all day in the sun
and the rain
to see his daddy
try to do something
that nobody believed
he could do.
Now, what are we telling him
if --
if you don't try now?
[ Smacks lips ]
I can't leave you her e
with all this.
Jimmy Morris,
I'm a Texas woman.
Which means I don't need
the help of a man
to keep things running.
Okay?
Okay.
[ Sighs ]
Gr eat.
[ Chuckles softly ]
[ Kisses ]
See you soon, little man.
[ Sighs ]
[ Indistinct conversations,
laughter ]
Ex cuse me.
You the old guy?
I'm the old guy.
Man: Come on, Rays,
you're on a roll!
Man #2: Hey, Big Time.
You use a walker
to get to the mound,
or do the other players
carry you?
Man #3: Hey, Pitch, who'd you
come up with, the Senators?
Man #5:
What are they paying you?
Man #5: They ought to pay us
to come see you!
Welcome to last place!
[ Laughs ]
Hey, Skipper!
I didn't know it was
"Bring Your Dad To Work" night.
[ Cheering ]
Woman: Way to go!
Man: Way to bring up
his average!
Coach: Time!
Announcer: [ On P.A. ]
Pitching change for Orlando.
Now pitching, number nine,
Johnny Morris.
Check that -- Jimmy Morris.
And now, f ans, it's time
to guess the winning car!
[ Cheering ]
And a big crash
at the first-base line!
Number one will win it
this time.
Man: Who is this guy?
Work f ast.
We got a long bus trip.
Let's go, Stingrays!
[ "Wooly Bully" plays on P.A. ]
## Wooly bully ##
## Watch it now, watch it,
watch it, watch it ##
## You got it, you got it,
you got it ##
[ Music stops ]
Whoa!
[ Laughter and boos ]
Man: Hey, Pitch! Do I look like
a strike zone to you?!
-- You stink!
-- You can't play ball!
Lorri: I can't believe they let
you pitch your first game.
Well, how'd you do?
Not bad.
[ Sighs ] I had a f ew of 'em
get away f rom me.
Did the f ans all yell
when you ran in?
Yeah. Oh, yeah,
they wer e yelling, all right.
Oh, honey,
that's just gr eat.
Hey, let me get the kids.
Uh, no. Um...
Just tell them I'll call them
tomorrow f rom...
Wherever we're going.
Okay, I will.
[ Chuckles softly ]
I love you.
I love you, too.
Take care.
[ Sighs ]
[ Grunts ]
-- [ Slap ]
-- Strike!
[ Crowd cheering ]
-- [ Grunts ]
-- Strike!
Out!
[ Slap ]
[ Crack ]
Blue!
Jimmy: Okay,
what's four times four?
Hunter: 17?
No, it's not 17.
You're guessing.
Just add it up.
16?
It's 16.
You got to be able to look at
f our times f our,
and just know that it's 16
without even having to think
about it, all right?
Now let's do your fives.
Aw, Daddy,
I already done my fives.
-- What's --
-- [ Knock ]
Well, if you want to learn
how to multiply,
you'r e gonna have
to practice, bud.
Okay.
-- Hey, Dad.
-- Yeah, partner?
Told you when you'r e going
to the big leagues yet?
[ Sighs ]
Could you put your mom on?
Okay?
Okay.
All right.
Oh, thanks, hon.
Hey.
Jessie says they left you in
one too many pitches.
Jessie needs to learn how to
keep a secr et with her f ather.
-- How ar e things going?
-- Things are good.
Hunter's got a field trip
on Friday,
and the rest of us
are talking about --
Honey,
that's not what I meant.
I know.
It's not bad.
We'r e a little behind.
[ Groans ] How much?
Well, they took the bed,
but they left the nightstand.
[ Sighs ]
You all right?
I'm just tired.
[ Smacks lips ]
I love you.
Love you, too.
Good night.
Okay. Good night.
[ Sighs ]
Listen, man...
This is the only
long-distance phone
we have her e at The Ritz.
You see someone waiting, you
keep it to 10 minutes, okay?
What?
Now you all talked out?
Use it all up
on your girlf riend?
It was my son.
He needed help
with his homework.
[ Sighs ]
[ Crack ]
Get out of her e.
It looks like a little screen
time's coming for Kenny Justin.
[ Crack ]
Jim!
Hey, Jim,
come here a minute.
Jim, I want you to meet
Tim Stewart f rom "ABC News. "
Hey, Jim. It's a pleasur e.
Thanks f or taking some time
with us.
You want to sit down?
I got a jersey for you.
Can you believe that?
I go four-for-five last night
and look where they got
the camera.
Man's been pitching good enough
to talk about it.
Dude's old enough.
He needs to talk
about retiring.
Player: Come on, let's go.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Player #2:
Hey, grab my magazine.
Old Man River,
you'r e moving kind of slow.
Yeah.
Six hours on a bus.
Yeah?
Never mind.
Come on, man.
Look, I got just the r ecipe
to loosen them bones up.
[ Rock music plays ]
Waitress: Here you go.
Gentlemen...
To the diet that put Babe Ruth
in the Hall Of f ame.
Hey, River, what was it like
watching The Babe play?
Mm-hmm. Okay.
You sur e
you want to start this?
How many f ans
did you guys lose
when you raised ticket prices
to 50 cents?
Not as many as we lose
when you pitch.
Ohhhh!
And this game is over, baby!
River, I swear, if you were
this f unny all the time,
nobody'd say nothing --
About what?
What do you mean?
What ar e they saying,
Brooks?
Look, some of the guys figur e,
you know,
the way the team's pushing
your story and all, that --
Oh. What? Do they think I'm some
kind of publicity stunt?
[ Sighs ]
Is that
what they'r e thinking?
They think
I'm taking somebody's spot?
What do you think, Brooks?
You'r e too f ast f or me.
That's all I know.
[ Crack ]
Player: Go, Brooksie!
That's in the gap!
Go, go, go, go, go!
Player #2:
All the way, Brooks!
Boy: Come on, Brooks!
Umpire: Safe!
Time!
You want to warm up?
Player: Nice job, Brooks!
Yeah.
Vendor: Peanuts!
Vendor #2: Get your programs!
Announcer: [ On P.A. ]
Now batting for the Bulls,
number 38,
Kenny Bryerson.
Vendor:
Get your ice-cold soda!
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Mac, we both know
it's gonna be Brooks.
I've had mor e than one player
called up bef or e.
Anybody my age?
So, what ar e you thinking?
I got a...pile of unpaid bills
at home.
I got a good job there.
I only make $600 a month
here.
And I got a f amily I haven't
seen in thr ee months.
We still got
some season left.
Somebody, uh, once told me
that it's okay to think about
what you want to do
until it's time to start doing
what you wer e meant to do.
Just so you know,
you wer e my best r elief pitcher
this past month.
Thanks, Mac.
Hunter: Jessica, give me
that back! It's mine!
-- [ Telephone ringing ]
-- Jessica: No, Hunter!
I'm gonna tell mommy!
Shh-shh-Shh.
Jamie's asleep.
You're gonna be
in big trouble.
-- Hello?
-- Jimmy: Hey.
Hey! I didn't think I'd hear
f rom you till tomorrow.
I'm coming home.
What? Did you get hurt?
No.
I'm fine.
Um...it's just time.
You called Fort Worth,
didn't you?
Uh-huh. Uh, I told them I'd be
ther e in, uh, two weeks.
So, pitch f or two weeks.
Mm, no. T- T- There's, uh,
too much to do.
I'll take car e of it.
-- We've been okay
for three months.
-- Lorri?
-- We'll be okay
for two weeks.
-- Lorri?
No, no, I'm --
I'm wasting my time out her e.
[ Sighs ] Listen, Jimmy.
Lord knows I am r eady
f or both sides of the bed
to be warm again.
But if you'r e gonna do this,
you make sur e you'r e doing it
f or the right r easons
because you'r e the one
that's gonna have to live
with it, okay?
I'll be fine.
You still love it?
Just think about that,
okay?
[ Indistinct conversations ]
[ "Holding Pattern" by Dave Hole
plays on jukebox ]
Charles Gibson:
[ On television ]
Finally tonight,
dreams that don't die.
In 1983,
the Milwaukee Brewers
drafted a pitcher
named Jim Morris.
You've never heard of him --
arm troubles.
He quickly dropped out of
baseball, married, had kids,
taught high school chemistry.
Pitching batting practice
to the high-school kids,
he found he was throwing
the ball 95 miles an hour --
f aster than he could throw it
years ago.
He doesn't know
how that happened.
But guess what it did
to his dr eam?
Here's Aaron Brown.
Aaron Brown: [ On television ]
Jim Morris is af raid
to tell his mother
he quit his old job
as a high-school teacher
for his new one, a relief
pitcher in the minor leagues.
He is really old --
too old to be in the minors --
but he's also throwing harder
and better
than he did
as a 20-year-Old kid,
and so he's back in that
strange and wonderf ul land
called minor-league baseball,
where the bull snorts smoke
on every home run,
and f uture stars
run the bases between innings.
Jimmy: [ On television ]
I made a challenge to the guys
to, uh, follow their dreams.
Really, it was something to...
to motivate them.
And, uh, they turned it around
on me
and, uh, told me I wasn't
f ollowing my own dr eams.
## ...And washed
the spider out ##
Be quiet.
Listen to Mr. Morris.
Jimmy: Uh, l-l grew up here.
I had a lot
of really good support
f rom my f amily and f riends
and townspeople around there.
This game, it's been the true
love of my life,
other than my wife Lorri,
uh, since, uh,
I was a little boy.
I had a dream as a little boy
of playing
professional baseball.
I used to pitch
and imagine myself, you know,
Iike every other kid
in this country,
of being in the World Series,
pitching in the seventh game,
ninth inning,
big-league ballpark.
Ther e's drama in it.
Ther e's, uh, suspense.
Ther e's a camaraderie
with the other players,
the f ans in the stadium.
You add that to it.
It's -- It's a great game.
[ Cheering and applause ]
[ Applause ]
[ Indistinct conversations,
cheering ]
Man: Heads up out there!
Heads up!
Man #2: Energy up, now.
Come on, boys!
[ Indistinct shouting ]
Woman: Ready to play!
Man: Come on!
Riv!
[ Hands slap ]
You know what we get to do
today, Brooks?
We get to play baseball.
[ Slap ]
Two!
[ Cheering and whistling ]
Announcer: 0 and 2
the count on Williams.
Morris really on top
of his game.
Coach is r eally bringing it
tonight.
[ Air whooshes ]
Strike!
Called strike three.
Caught him looking
with a f astball.
That's Morris's third strikeout
of the evening.
[ Cheers and applause ]
[ Air whooshes ]
[ Crack ]
Infield! lnfield!
I got it! I got it!
Yeah!
[ Cheers and applause ]
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Thanks f or cleaning up my mess
tonight.
Hey, you pitched
seven good innings.
I wouldn't call that a mess.
Jimmy.
Uh, go ahead
and close the door.
Jimmy, I just got off the phone
with the big club.
They'r e calling up Brooks.
That's gr eat.
He won't be back.
He respects you and...
I thought you might want to be
the one to tell him.
Sur e.
Being as that you'r e going,
too.
They'r e calling me up?
Two of you fly out of here
tonight.
You catch up with the team
tomorrow.
[ Inhales sharply ]
Wher e?
Well, they're on the road
right now...
In Texas.
[ Br eathes deeply ]
[ Telephone ringing ]
Hello?
Hey, Lorri.
Hey, you.
Hey.
Uh, um, do you know that blue
sport coat that I never wear?
[ Water bubbling ]
Oh, hang on a sec, hon.
I'm boiling over.
[ Sighs ]
[ Chuckles ]
Now, what about the blue sport
coat you never wear?
Would you mind bringing it
to Arlington tomorrow?
Arlington?
I thought you wer e in --
You tell me right now,
Jimmy Morris.
Uh, appar ently...
Ther e's a dr ess code
in the major leagues.
Lorri?
[ Voice br eaking ]
Yeah, I'm her e.
[ Laughs ]
They'r e flying me out
in an hour.
Can you tell everybody?
Sur e. You just have to tell
one person first.
Hunter?
Your daddy's got something
he wants to tell you.
Hunter: Hey, Dad.
Hey, buddy.
Hey, guess what?
What?
Um, your daddy is gonna be
a major-league pitcher.
Really?
Yeah, really. What do you
think about that, huh?
Cool.
I can't believe it.
Who are you gonna play for?
They're called
the Devil Rays.
What's a devil ray?
Uh, it -- it's a fish.
What color is it?
Black.
Can you eat it?
I don't know, bud.
It's got a stinger.
That's cool.
My daddy's
a big-league pitcher.
[ Indistinct shouting,
horns honking ]
Joel:
Coach Morris made it!
Rudy: Coach Morris
made it to the bigs!
Wack:
He's a big-leaguer now!
[ "Ther e ls A Light"
by Duane Jarvis plays ]
## There is a light
at the edge of the shadows ##
[ Indistinct conversations ]
## Show a little f aith
and try and believe ##
## Better days
around the corner ##
## Droppin' on your knees
before you plead ##
## There is a light
at the edge of the shadows ##
## There is a light ##
[ Music f ades ]
Team won't be her e
f or a couple of hours.
Feel f r ee to look around.
[ Sighs ]
We ain't in Kansas anymor e,
ar e we, Riv?
Announcer: [ On P.A. ] Good
evening, ladies and gentlemen,
and welcome to The Ballpark
in Arlington.
It's baseball time in Texas.
Tonight's game,
the Tampa Bay Devil Rays
against your Texas Rangers.
[ Air whooshes,
ball slaps mitt ]
[ Indistinct talking ]
[ Air whooshes,
ball slaps mitt ]
[ Slaps ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Air whooshes ]
-- Hmm...
-- [ Chuckles ]
[ Slaps ]
[ Air whooshes,
ball slaps mitt ]
[ Fan whistling ]
Jimmy!
Jimmy Morris!
Hunter: Dad!
Man: Let's go, Rangers!
Boy: Come on,
let's play ball!
Jessica: Hi, Dad.
[ Chuckling ] Hi.
You look gr eat.
Kids, doesn't your daddy
look gr eat?
-- Yup.
-- Yeah.
Hey.
[ Laughing ]
I can't believe it.
[ Giggling ]
Hi, sweetheart.
Hi, Daddy.
-- You'r e so big.
-- Yeah.
Hey, partner.
I missed you.
Me too.
P.A. announcer:
Here are the starting lineups
for tonight's game.
Well, kids, we'd better
let your daddy get to work.
See ya after.
[ Man shouting indistinctly
in background ]
[ Chuckles ]
Okay.
Come on.
Radio announcer:
Down at The Ballpark,
the Devil Rays went down
1-2-3 at the top of the first,
and now the Rangers try to get
their high-scoring offense
on track in the bottom
of the first.
P.A. announcer:
Leading off for the Rangers,
the center fielder,
number 2 5, Tom Goodwin.
[ Cheers and applause ]
Radio announcer: Three balls
and a strike, one out.
The pitch on the way.
It is low. Ball four.
Runners at first and second --
a scoring chance for Texas.
P.A. announcer: ...Page 2 5
in your souvenir program.
Here's tonight's...
Radio announcer: Here's
the pitch. It is swung on
and lined to center field --
-- [ Cheers and applause ]
-- A base hit.
A run will score.
-- You see Daddy?
He's right ther e.
-- Runners at first and second.
It's 1-0, Texas,
and the Rangers have
a 1-0 lead.
There's a swing
and a base hit to right field,
and this game
is now a 1- 1 tie.
[ Organ plays f anf ar e ]
-- Charge!
Radio announcer:
Last half of the 5th inning
about to get underway.
It's the Rangers 1
and the Devil Rays 1.
[ Slap ]
-- The pitch in the dirt again,
the third one he has thrown.
-- [ Telephone rings ]
And we're about to get
some action, it appears,
in the Tampa Bay bullpen.
Pitching coach:
Blanton, Miller.
[ Telephone hangs up ]
The pitch is on the way.
Swung on, and a shot to the gap
in right-center field.
It looks like extra bases.
One run is home.
Two runs are home.
The throw cut off.
The play at third --
out at third base!
Rangers 3, Devil Rays 1,
here in the bottom of the 6th.
P.A. announcer: ... On this day
in baseball history.
Radio announcer:
Runners at first and second --
a golden chance
for the Rangers.
Here's the set.
The pitch on the way.
A swing and a smash up
the alley in left-center field.
That will score two.
It's the Rangers 5,
the Devil Rays 1.
Texas has broken it open.
[ Cheers and applause ]
P.A. announcer:
The Devil Rays and Rangers
also play on Sunday night.
Game time is 7 :05,
and it's Cap Night.
-- [ Telephone rings ]
-- All f ans 13 and under
receive a Rangers cap.
Game time Sunday is 7 :05.
Morris!
Start warming up.
Mommy.
Hmm?
It's daddy in the bullpen.
Oh, my Lord.
Cal: Hey. Hey, guys.
-- Is that him?
-- Ther e he is.
Ther e he is.
-- Look, he's in the bullpen.
-- [ Frank chuckling ]
There he is.
Yep, he looks good.
Come her e.
Her e, have a look-see.
Radio announcer:
Blanton trying to
get out of a bases-loaded jam.
There's a swing and a smash
right back at him.
He retrieves the ball
in f ront of the mound,
-- [ Cheering ]
-- Throws to first.
And he throws it away.
Another run will come home.
Two runs for Texas
on the play,
and the Rangers have
busted this game wide open.
And Blanton
may have been hurt
on that rocket
right back to the mound.
-- [ Air whooshes ]
-- Jim Morris continues
to throw in the bullpen,
-- Mmm. Mmm-hmm.
See? It's coach.
-- The left-hander
f rom Big Lake, Texas.
P.A. announcer: ... Gift shops
and novelty stands located
throughout the ballpark...
Let's go! Come on!
Get loose, coach!
Get loose!
Radio announcer:
The Tampa Bay trainer
-- [ Telephone rings ]
is on his way
out to the mound to check.
It appears the Devil Rays
might have to make
a pitching change.
Morris!
You'r e in!
[ Cheering ]
Go, coach Morris!
Whoo!
[ Whistles ]
[ Cheering continues ]
Let's go, coach!
Just three months ago,
he was grading chemistry tests.
And now Jim Morris
finds himself on the mound
in a major-league ballpark.
-- [ Organ plays ]
-- Little louder
than back home?
Well, then let's not
make this too hard.
You r emember that f astball you
wer e showing me bef or e the game?
-- I think so.
-- Well, I need thr ee of 'em.
P.A. announcer:
Ladies and gentlemen,
your attention please.
Coming in to pitch
for Tampa Bay,
a fellow Texan making his
major-league debut, Jim Morris.
[ Indistinct talking,
papers rustling ]
Radio announcer:
Morris will be f acing
Ranger shortstop Royce Clayton.
Royce has had
a very strong second half,
and has not cooled off any
here in the month of September.
Come on, Dad!
[ Scraping ]
[ Cheering and whistling ]
[ Br eathing heavily ]
[ Sighs deeply ]
[ Cheering intensifies ]
-- [ Grunts ]
-- [ Air whooshes ]
-- Yeah!
Yes!
[ Cheers and applause ]
Devil Rays player:
One more time!
Come on, baby!
[ Air whooshes ]
Strike two!
Oh, what?
Yeah! Whoo!
[ Cheering continues ]
Come on, get him!
Get him!
Come on, Jimmy! Whoo!
-- Whoo!
-- Yeah!
Whoo!
[ Scraping ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Inhales deeply, grunts ]
[ Exhales sharply ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Air whooshes ]
[ Cheers and applause ]
-- Yeah!
Yay!
Whoo!
Good job!
Congratulations, man.
-- Thanks, man.
-- Gr eat job.
[ Laughing ]
[ Indistinct talking ]
Reporter: Jimmy? Jimmy?
What pitches did you throw
to get that strikeout?
Um...f astball...
-- Mm-hmm.
...Fastball...
And...f astball.
-- [ All chuckling ]
-- Reporter #2:
How'd it feel --
pitching in the major leagues?
Just like I hoped it would.
How's the arm f eel?
Oh....
Uh, could you ex cuse me
f or just -- f or one second?
Could you ex cuse me?
Sir...l-l didn't know
you wer e her e.
Wasn't missing this one.
Watching you tonight...
...Not many f athers
get a chance to do that.
I guess I let too many
of those things get away.
[ Sighs deeply ]
S-so did l.
[ Chuckles softly ]
Well, then...
[ Sighs ]
Hey, Dad?
Yeah?
Thanks f or coming.
[ Footsteps departing ]
Does this mean I don't
get a baseball?
Oh...
[ Both br eathing heavily,
moaning, smooching ]
That's all I got left.
Well, a girl
could do worse.
[ Chuckles ]
So, how did it f eel
to be the oldest rookie
in the last 30 years?
Oh...l don't know.
I'm -- I'm tir ed.
[ Chuckles ]
So, where are --
where are the kids?
Hunter is with Henry,
and Jessie's with Cal.
Oh, don't tell me you
left Jessie with Cal.
Oh, Cal had a little help.
[ Cheers and applause ]
Jessica: Daddy!
Hunter: My daddy!
[ Cheers and applause continue ]
[ Indistinct talking,
car doors closing ]
[ Clanking ]
[ "Some Dr eams"
by Steve Earle plays ]
## When I was a little guy ##
## My daddy told me ##
## "Mister, don't ever try
to climb too high ##
## "'Cause it's the f all
that gets you ##
## "And some dreams
can never come true ##
## They'll never come true" ##
## Well, I heard
every word he said ##
## But I don't guess
I listened ##
## But every time
I banged my head ##
## Against the wall or system ##
## Yeah, some dreams
don't ever come true ##
## Some dreams ##
## Don't ever come true ##
## But some dreams do ##
## lf you just hang on ##
## And your heart is true ##
## And your hope is strong ##
## Well, just because
you've been around ##
## And had your
poor heart broken ##
## Ain't no ex cuse
for lyin' there ##
## Before the last word's
spoken ##
## 'Cause some dreams
don't ever come true ##
## Some dreams ##
## Don't ever come true ##
## Oh, but some dreams do ##
## When you're feelin' low ##
## And you think
you're through ##
## That's when you will know ##
## Yeah, when you
wish upon a star ##
## Buddy, don't you miss it ##
## Catch it 'fore
it f alls too f ar ##
## And keep it
with your secrets ##
## 'Cause some dreams
don't ever come true ##
## Some dreams ##
## Don't ever come true ##
## But some dreams do ##
[ "Shining"
by Eileen Rose plays ]
## Sore head,
and I'm calling rain ##
## Full stop --
home to meet my mama's pain ##
## Cry like she does ##
## Try like she does ##
## Oh, the world
still loves a dreamer ##
## Keep on, keep on, keep on,
keep on, keep on shining ##
## Ooh ooh-ooh ##
## Keep on, keep on, keep on,
keep on shining ##
## Ooh ooh-ooh ##