This is Berk.
It's 12 days north of hopeless
and a few degrees south
of freezing to death.
It's located solidly
on the meridian of misery.
My village. In a word, sturdy.
It's been here for seven generations,
but every single building is new.
We have fishing, hunting,
and a charming view of the sunsets.
The only problems are the pests.
You see, most places
have mice or mosquitoes.
We have...
Dragons.
Most people would leave. Not us.
We're Vikings.
We have stubbornness issues.
My name is Hiccup.
Great name, I know.
But it's not the worst.
Parents believe a hideous name
will frighten off gnomes and trolls.
Like our charming Viking
demeanor wouldn't do that.
Morning!
- What are you doing here?
- Get inside!
- What are you doing out?
- Get back inside!
Hiccup! What is he doing out?
What are you doing out? Get inside!
That's Stoick the Vast,
chief of the tribe.
They say when he was a baby,
he popped a dragon's head
clean off of its shoulders.
Do I believe it? Yes, I do.
What have we got?
Gronckles. Nadders. Zipplebacks.
And Hoark saw a Monstrous Nightmare.
- Any Night Furies?
- None so far.
Good.
Hoist the torches!
Nice of you to join the party!
I thought you'd been carried off!
Who, me? No, come on,
I'm way too muscular for their taste.
They wouldn't know
what to do with all this.
They need toothpicks, don't they?
The meathead with attitude
and interchangeable hands is Gobber.
I've been his apprentice ever
since I was little. Well, littler.
We move to the lower defenses.
We'll counterattack with the catapults.
Hurry!
See? Old village,
lots and lots of new houses.
Fire!
Let's go!
That's Fishlegs, Snotlout, the twins:
Ruffnut and Tuffnut,
and...
Astrid.
Their job is so much cooler.
Eh!
Aw, come on. Let me out, please.
I need to make my mark.
You've made plenty of marks,
all in the wrong places.
Please, two minutes. I'll kill a dragon.
My life will get infinitely better.
I might even get a date.
You can't lift a hammer.
You can't swing an ax.
You can't even throw one of these!
Okay, fine, but this will throw it for me.
Oh!
See? Now this right here
is what I'm talking about!
- Mild calibration issue...
- Hiccup!
If you ever want to get
out there to fight dragons
you need to stop all this.
But you just pointed to all of me.
Yes, that's it! Stop being all of you.
Oh.
Oh, yes.
You, sir, are playing a dangerous game.
Keeping this much raw
Vikingness contained?
There will be consequences!
I'll take my chances.
Sword. Sharpen. Now.
One day, I'll get out there.
Because killing a dragon
is everything around here.
A Nadder head is sure
to get me at least noticed.
Gronckles are tough.
Taking down one of those
would definitely get me a girlfriend.
A Zippleback?
Exotic. Two heads, twice the status.
They found the sheep!
Concentrate fire over the lower bank.
- Hurry up!
- Fire!
And then there's the Monstrous Nightmare.
Only the best Vikings go after those.
They have this nasty habit
of setting themselves on fire.
Reload! I'll take care of this.
But the ultimate prize is the dragon
no one's ever seen. We call it the...
Night Fury!
Get down!
Jump!
This thing never steals food,
never shows itself and...
never misses.
No one has ever killed a Night Fury.
That's why I'm going to be the first.
Man the fort, Hiccup.
They need me out there.
Stay. Put. There.
You know what I mean.
- Where are you going?
- Yeah, I know!
- Hiccup!
- Be right back!
Let's get him!
Mind yourselves!
The devils still have some juice in them!
Come on. Give me something to shoot at.
Give me something to shoot at.
Oof!
I hit it. Yes, I hit it!
Did anybody see that?
Except for you.
Ugh!
- Do not let them escape!
- Right!
You're all out.
Oh, and there's one more
thing you need to know.
Sorry, Dad.
Okay, but I hit a Night Fury.
Whaa! It's not like the last few times,
Dad! I really, actually hit it!
You guys were busy.
I had a very clear shot.
It went down off Raven Point.
Let's get a search party...
Stop!
Just stop.
Every time you step outside,
disaster follows.
Can you not see that I have
bigger problems?
Winter is almost here and I have
an entire village to feed!
Between you and me,
the village could do
with a little less feeding,
don't you think?
This isn't a joke, Hiccup!
Why can't you follow the simplest orders?
I can't stop myself.
I see a dragon and I have to just kill it.
It's who I am, Dad.
Agh... You're many things, Hiccup.
But a dragon killer is not one of them.
Get back to the house.
Make sure he gets there.
I have his mess to clean up.
Quite the performance.
I've never seen anyone mess up that badly.
That helped.
Thank you, thank you. I was trying.
Ow!
- I really did hit one.
- Sure, Hiccup.
- He never listens.
- It runs in the family.
When he does,
it's with this disappointed scowl,
like someone skimped
on the meat in his sandwich.
"Excuse me, barmaid.
I'm afraid you brought me the wrong offspring.
I ordered an extra-large boy with beefy arms,
extra guts and glory on the side.
This here, this is a talking fishbone."
You're thinking about this all wrong.
It's not so much what you look like,
it's what's inside that he can't stand.
Thank you for summing that up.
Look, the point is, stop trying so hard
to be something you're not.
I just want to be one of you guys.
Either we finish them
or they'll finish us!
It's the only way we'll be rid of them.
If we find the nest and destroy it,
the dragons will leave.
They'll find another home!
One more search before the ice sets in.
Those ships never come back.
We're Vikings. It's an occupational hazard.
Now, who's with me?
Count me out.
- Today's no good for me.
- I have to do my ax returns.
All right.
Those who stay will look after Hiccup.
- To the ships!
- I'm with you, Stoick!
That's more like it.
Right, I'll pack my undies.
No, I need you to stay
and train some new recruits.
Oh, perfect. And while I'm busy,
Hiccup can cover the stall.
Molten steel, razor-sharp blades,
lots of time to himself.
What could possibly go wrong?
What am I going to do with him, Gobber?
Put him in training with the others.
- No, I'm serious.
- So am I.
He'd be killed before you let
the first dragon out of its cage.
- You don't know that.
- I do, actually.
- No, you don't.
- No, actually, I do.
No, you don't.
Listen, you know what he's like.
From the time he could crawl,
he's been... different.
He doesn't listen.
He has the attention span of a sparrow.
I take him fishing and he goes
hunting for... for trolls!
Trolls exist. They steal your socks.
But only the left ones.
What's with that?
- When I was a boy...
- Here we go.
...my father told me to bang my head
against a rock and I did it.
I thought it was crazy,
but I didn't question him.
- And you know what happened?
- You got a headache.
That rock split in two.
It taught me what a Viking
could do, Gobber.
He could crush mountains,
level forests, tame seas!
Even as a boy, I knew what I was,
what I had to become.
Hiccup is not that boy.
You can't stop him, Stoick.
You can only prepare him.
I know it seems hopeless,
but the truth is,
you won't always be around to protect him.
He's going to get out there again.
He's probably out there now.
Oh, the gods hate me.
Some people lose their knife
or their mug. Not me.
I manage to lose an entire dragon.
Ow!
Oh, wow. I did it.
Oh, I did it.
This fixes everything! Yes!
I have brought down this mighty beast!
I'm going to kill you, dragon.
Then I'll cut out your heart
and take it to my father.
I am a Viking. I am a Viking!
I did this.
Agh...
Hiccup.
Dad... Uh...
I have to talk to you, Dad.
I need to speak with you, too, son.
- I don't want to fight dragons.
- It's time you learn to fight dragons.
- What?
- Uh... You go first.
- No, you go first.
All right.
You get your wish.
Dragon training, you start in the morning.
Oh, man, I should have gone first.
'Cause... Uh...
I was thinking, you know,
we have a surplus
of dragon-fighting Vikings,
but do we have enough bread-making
Vikings or small-home-repair Vikings?
You'll need this.
I don't want to fight dragons.
Come on. Yes, you do.
Rephrase. Dad, I can't kill dragons.
But you will kill dragons.
No, I'm really very
extra-sure that I won't.
- It's time, Hiccup.
- Can you not hear me?
This is serious, son.
When you carry this ax...
you carry all of us with you.
Which means you walk like us,
you talk like us,
you think like us.
No more of... this.
You just gestured to all of me.
- Deal?
- This conversation feels very one-sided.
Deal?
Deal.
Good.
Train hard.
I'll be back.
Probably.
And I'll be here.
Maybe.
Welcome to dragon training!
No turning back.
I hope I get some serious burns.
I'm hoping for some mauling,
like, on my shoulder or my back.
Yeah, it's only fun
if you get a scar out of it.
Yeah, no kidding, right?
Pain. Love it.
Oh, great. Who let him in?
Let's get started!
The recruit who does best
will win the honor
of killing his first dragon
in front of the entire village.
Hiccup already killed a Night Fury,
so does that disqualify him or...
Can I transfer to the class
with the cool Vikings?
Don't worry. You're small and weak.
That'll make you less of a target.
They'll see you as sick or insane
and go after the more
"Viking-like" teens instead.
Behind these doors are just
a few of the many species
you will learn to fight!
- The Deadly Nadder!
- Speed 8, armor 16.
The Hideous Zippleback.
Plus 11 stealth. Times 2.
- The Monstrous Nightmare.
- Firepower 15.
- The Terrible Terror.
- Attack 8, venom 12.
Can you stop that?
And the Gronckle.
Jaw strength 8.
Whoa!
Wait, aren't you gonna teach us first?
I believe in learning on the job.
Today is about survival.
If you get blasted... you're dead!
Quick!
What's the first thing you'll need?
- A doctor?
- Plus 5 speed?
- A shield.
- Shields. Go!
Your most important piece
of equipment is your shield!
If you must make a choice between
a sword or a shield, take the shield!
Whoa!
- Get your hands off!
- There are a million shields!
Take that one. It has a flower.
Girls like flowers.
Oops, now this one has blood on it.
- Tuffnut, Ruffnut! You're out!
- What?
Those shields are good for another thing.
Noise! Make lots of it
to throw off a dragon's aim!
All dragons have a limited
number of shots.
How many does a Gronckle have?
- Five?
- No, six!
Correct, six!
That's one for each of you!
Fishlegs, out!
Hiccup, get in there!
By the way, I moved into my parents' basement.
Come by sometime and work out.
You look like you work out.
Snotlout! You're done!
I guess it's just you and me, huh?
Nope, just you.
One shot left!
Hiccup!
And that's six.
Go back to bed, you overgrown sausage!
You'll get another chance,
don't you worry.
Remember, a dragon will always,
always go for the kill.
So why didn't you?
This was stupid.
Why don't you just fly away?
All right, where did Astrid
go wrong in the ring today?
I mistimed my somersault dive.
It was sloppy.
- It threw off my reverse tumble.
- Yeah, we noticed.
No, no, you were great.
That was so "Astrid."
She's right.
You have to be tough on yourselves.
Where did Hiccup go wrong?
- Uh... He showed up.
- He didn't get eaten.
He's never where he should be.
Thank you, Astrid.
You need to live and breathe this stuff.
The dragon manual.
Everything we know about
every dragon we know of.
Hmm...
No attacks tonight. Study up.
Wait, you mean read?
While we're still alive?
Why read words when you
can just kill the stuff
the words tell you stuff about?
I've read it, like, seven times.
There's this water dragon
that sprays boiling water at your face.
And there's this other one...
Yeah. That sounds great.
- There was a chance I'd read it...
- But now...
You guys read. I'll go kill stuff.
Another one has spines, like, trees.
- So I guess we'll share?
- Read it.
Ah... All mine, then. Wow.
So, okay, I'll see you...
...tomorrow.
"Dragon classifications.
Strike class. Fear class. Mystery class."
"Thunderdrum. This reclusive dragon
inhabits sea caves and dark tide pools.
When startled, the Thunderdrum
produces a concussive sound
that can kill a man at close range.
Extremely dangerous. Kill on sight."
"Timberjack. This gigantic creature
has razor-sharp wings
that can slice through full-grown trees.
Extremely dangerous. Kill on sight."
"Scauldron. Sprays scalding water at its victim.
Extremely dangerous... "
Agh!
"Changewing. Even newly hatched
dragons can spray acid. Kill on sight."
Gronckle. Zippleback. The Skrill.
Bone Knapper. Whispering Death!
Burns its victims. Buries its victims.
Chokes its victims.
Turns its victims inside out.
Extremely dangerous.
Kill on sight. Kill on sight.
Kill on sight.
Night Fury.
Speed unknown. Size unknown.
"The unholy offspring
of lightning and death itself.
Never engage this dragon.
Your only chance:
hide and pray it does not find you."
I can almost smell them.
They're close.
Steady.
Take us in.
Hard to port. For Helheim's Gate.
Hard to port!
Steady!
Hey, you know, I just happened to notice
the book had nothing on Night Furies.
Is there, like, another book or a sequel?
Maybe a little Night Fury pamphlet?
- Whoa!
- Focus, Hiccup!
You're not even trying!
Today is all about attack!
Nadders are quick and light on their feet.
- Your job is to be quicker and lighter!
- Whoa!
I'm really beginning to question
your teaching methods!
Look for its blind spot!
Every dragon has one.
Find it, hide in it, and strike!
Ugh!
Do you ever bathe?
If you don't like it,
then just get your own blind spot.
How about I give you one?
Blind spot, yes.
Deaf spot, not so much.
Hey, so, how would one
sneak up on a Night Fury?
No one's ever met one and lived
to tell the tale. Now, get in there!
- I know, I know, but hypothetically...
- Hiccup!
Get down.
Watch out, babe. I'll take care of this.
The sun was in my eyes, Astrid.
What do you want me to do,
block out the sun?
I could do that but
I don't have time right now!
They probably take the daytime off, right?
Like a cat.
Has anyone ever seen one napping?
Hiccup!
- Ooh... Love on the battlefield.
- She could do better.
Let me... Why don't you...
Well done, Astrid.
Is this some kind of a joke to you?
Our parents' war is about to become ours.
Figure out which side you're on.
Huh. Toothless.
I could have sworn you had...
...teeth.
Uh... Uh... I... No, no, no.
I don't have any more!
Ugh!
Uh...
- Mmm...
- Hmm?
Mmm-hmm.
Hmm.
Ugh!
Hmm?
And with one twist,
he took my hand and swallowed it whole!
I saw the look on his face.
I was delicious.
He must have passed the word,
because it wasn't a month before
another one of them took my leg.
Isn't it weird to think your hand
was inside a dragon?
Like if your mind was still
in control of it,
you could've killed the dragon from inside
by crushing his heart, or something.
I swear, I'm so angry. I'll avenge your
beautiful hand and your beautiful foot.
I'll chop off the legs of every
dragon I fight, with my face.
Uh-uh! It's the wings
and the tails you really want.
If it can't fly, it can't get away.
A downed dragon is a dead dragon.
All right, I'm off to bed.
You should be, too.
Tomorrow, we get to the big boys,
slowly but surely
making our way up
to the Monstrous Nightmare.
But who'll win the honor of killing it?
It's gonna be me.
It's my destiny. See?
Your mom let you get a tattoo?
It's not a tattoo, it's a birthmark.
I've been stuck with you since birth,
and that was never there before.
Yes, it was. You've just never
seen me from the left side.
Hey, Toothless.
I brought breakfast.
I hope... I hope you're hungry.
Okay, that's disgusting.
We've got some salmon,
some nice Icelandic cod
and a whole smoked eel.
No, no, no, no, no!
No, it's okay.
Yeah, I don't really like eel much, either.
That's it.
Just stick with the good stuff.
And don't you mind me.
I'll just be back here,
minding my own business.
It's okay.
Agh!
Okay.
Huh!
That's not too bad. It works.
Whoa! Whoa!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
Oh, my! It's working!
Yes, yes! I did it!
Yeah!
Today is about teamwork.
Now, a wet dragon head
can't light its fire.
The Hideous Zippleback is extra tricky.
One head breathes gas,
the other head lights it.
Your job is to know which is which.
Razor-sharp serrated teeth
that inject venom for pre-digestion.
Prefers ambush attack,
crushing its victims...
Will you please stop that?
If that dragon shows either of his faces,
I'm gonna...
There!
Hey, it's us, idiots!
Your butts are getting bigger.
We thought you were a dragon.
Not that there's anything wrong
with a dragonesque figure...
Wait.
Oh, I'm hurt!
I am very much hurt!
Chances of survival are dwindling
to single digits now.
Oh... Wrong head.
Fishlegs!
Now, Hiccup!
Oh, come on.
Hiccup!
Back, back, back!
Now, don't you make me tell you again!
Yes, that's right.
Back into your cage.
Now, think about what you've done.
Okay, so are we done?
'Cause I've got some things I need to...
Yep, I'll see you tomorrow!
Hey!
I've never seen a Gronckle do that.
I left my ax back in the ring.
You guys go on ahead. I'll catch up with you.
Meet the Terrible Terror.
Ha! It's like the size of my...
Get it off!
Oh, I'm hurt! I am very much hurt!
Wow! He's better than you ever were.
Hmm!
Oh, great.
Hiccup.
Hiccup? Are you in there?
Astrid. Hey.
Hi, Astrid. Hi, Astrid. Hi, Astrid.
I normally don't care what people do,
but you're acting weird.
Ow!
Well, weirder.
- Uh, I trust you found the nest, at least?
- Not even close.
Huh. Excellent.
I hope you had a little more
success than me.
Well, if by success, you mean that your
parenting troubles are over, then yes.
Congratulations, Stoick!
Everyone is so relieved!
Out with the old and in
with the new, right?
No one will miss that old nuisance!
The village is throwing
a party to celebrate!
- Come over here.
- Hurry!
- He's gone?
- Uh...
Yeah...
Most afternoons, but who can blame him?
The life of a celebrity's very rough.
He can barely walk through the village
without being swarmed by his new fans.
Hiccup?
Who would have thought it, eh?
He has this way with the beasts.
Okay, there, bud.
We're gonna take this nice and slow.
Here we go. Here we go. Position...
three. No, four.
All right, it's go time. It's go time.
Come on, buddy! Come on, buddy!
Yes, it worked!
Sorry!
That was my fault.
Yeah, yeah, I'm on it.
Position four. Uh, three.
Yeah! Go, baby!
Yes!
Oh, this is amazing!
The wind in my... Cheat sheet!
Stop!
No!
Oh, gosh! Oh, gods! Oh, no!
All right, okay, you've gotta
kind of angle yourself.
Okay, no, no, no.
Come back down towards me!
Come back down...
Ow!
Yeah!
Come on.
Uh... No, thanks. I'm good.
Not so fireproof on the inside, are you?
There you go.
Everything we know
about you guys is wrong.
Dad! You're back! Gobber's not here so...
I know.
- I came looking for you.
- You did?
You've been keeping secrets.
Uh, I have?
Just how long did you think
you could hide it from me?
I don't know what you're...
Nothing happens on this island
without me hearing about it.
Oh?
So...
let's talk...
about that dragon.
Oh, gods. Dad, I'm so sorry.
I was going to tell you.
I just didn't know how to...
You're... You're not upset?
Uh... What? I was hoping for this!
- Uh... You were?
- And believe me, it only gets better!
Just wait till you spill a Nadder's guts
for the first time!
And mount your first
Gronckle head on a spear!
What a feeling!
You really had me going there, son!
All those years of the worst Viking
Berk has ever seen.
Odin, it was rough.
I almost gave up on you.
And all the while you were
holding out on me!
Oh, Thor Almighty!
Oh! With you doing so well in the ring...
we finally have something to talk about.
Oh! Here, I brought you something
to keep you safe in the ring.
Wow. Thanks.
Your mother would have wanted you to have it.
It's half of her breastplate.
Huh...
Matching set.
It keeps her close, you know.
Wear it proudly. You deserve it.
You've held up your end of the deal.
- I should really get to bed.
- Yes, good. Okay, good talk.
- I'll see you back at the house. Great.
- We should do this again.
Uh... Thanks for stopping by
- and for the... breast hat.
- I hope you like the hat. Ahem!
Well... Yep. Good night.
Stay out of my way!
I'm winning this thing.
Good. Please, by all means.
This time, this time, for sure!
No! No, son of a half-troll,
- rat-eating, munge-bucket!
- Wait, wait.
- So, later.
- Not so fast.
- I'm kind of late for...
- What?
Late for what, exactly?
Quiet down! The elder has decided.
You've done it! You've done it, Hiccup!
You get to kill the dragon!
That's my boy!
Yeah. Yes. I can't wait. I am so...
Leaving! We're leaving.
Let's pack up. Looks like you
and me are taking a little vacation.
Forever.
Oh, man.
Whoa! What the...
Um... What are you doing here?
I want to know what's going on.
No one just gets as good as you do.
Especially you.
Start talking!
Are you training with someone?
Training?
It better not involve this.
I know this looks really bad,
but you see...
Whoa!
You're right. You're right. You're right.
I'm through with the lies.
I've been making outfits. So you got me.
It's time everyone knew.
Drag me back, go ahead. Here we go.
Ow! Why would you do that?
That's for the lies.
And that's for everything else.
Oh, man.
Get down!
Run, run!
No! It's okay! It's okay.
She's a friend.
You just scared him.
I scared him?
Who is "him"?
Astrid, Toothless. Toothless, Astrid.
Uh... We're dead.
Whoa! Where do you think you're going?
Whoa!
Oh, great Odin's ghost!
Ah! This is it!
Agh!
Hiccup, get me down from here!
You have to give me a chance to explain.
I am not listening to anything
you have to say!
Then I won't speak.
Just let me show you.
Please, Astrid.
Now, get me down.
Toothless, down. Gently.
See? Nothing to be afraid of.
Whoa!
Toothless!
What is wrong with you?
Bad dragon!
He's not usually like this. Oh, no.
Toothless, what are you doing?
We need her to like us!
And now the spinning.
Thank you for nothing,
you useless reptile.
Okay, I'm sorry! I'm sorry.
Just get me off of this thing.
All right, I admit it.
This is pretty cool.
It's amazing.
He's amazing.
So, what now?
Hiccup, your final exam is tomorrow.
You know you'll have to kill...
...kill a dragon.
Don't remind me.
Toothless, what's happening?
What is it?
Get down!
- What's going on?
- I don't know.
Toothless, you gotta
get us out of here, bud.
It looks like
they're hauling in their kill.
Ugh! What does that make us?
What my dad wouldn't give to find this.
It's satisfying to know that all of our food
has been dumped down a hole.
They're not eating any of it.
What is that?
All right, bud,
we got to get out of here... now!
Oh, it totally makes sense.
It's like a giant beehive.
They're the workers
and that's their queen.
It controls them. Let's find your dad.
No! No.
No, not yet. They'll kill Toothless.
Astrid, we have to think
this through carefully.
Hiccup, we just discovered
the dragons' nest,
the thing we've been after
since Vikings first sailed here,
and you want to keep it a secret?
What? To protect your pet dragon?
Are you serious?
Yes.
Okay. Then what do we do?
Just give me until tomorrow.
I'll figure something out.
Okay.
That's for kidnapping me.
That's for... everything else.
What are you looking at?
Hiccup! Hiccup! Hiccup! Hiccup!
Well, I can show my face
in public again!
If someone had told me
that in a few short weeks,
Hiccup would go from, well, being...
Hiccup
to placing first in dragon training,
well, I would have tied him to a mast
and shipped him off
for fear he'd gone mad!
And you know it!
But here we are.
And no one is more surprised
or more proud than I am.
Today, my boy becomes a Viking.
Today, he becomes one of us!
Be careful with that dragon.
- It's not the dragon I'm worried about.
- What are you going to do?
Put an end to this. I have to try.
Astrid, if something goes wrong,
just make sure they don't find Toothless.
I will.
Just promise me it won't go wrong.
It's time, Hiccup. Knock 'em dead.
Yeah! Show 'em how it's done.
Hiccup! Hiccup! Hiccup! Hiccup!
I would have gone for the hammer.
I'm ready.
Go on, Hiccup. Give it to him!
What is he doing?
What is this?
Hey, it's okay. It's okay.
I'm not one of them.
What is he thinking?
- Stop the fight.
- No!
I need you all to see this.
They're not what we think they are.
We don't have to kill them.
I said, stop the fight!
Out of my way!
Hiccup!
This way!
Agh!
Night Fury!
Right, Toothless, go.
Get out of here.
Go, go!
Stoick, no!
Dad, he won't hurt you!
No, don't!
You're only making it worse!
Toothless, stop!
No! No!
Get him!
No, no! Please just don't hurt him!
Please don't hurt him.
Put it with the others.
I should have known.
I should have seen the signs.
- Dad?
- We had a deal!
I know we did. That was before.
Oh! It's all so messed up.
So everything in the ring, a trick? A lie?
I screwed up. I should have
told you before now. I just...
Take this out on me, be mad at me,
but please, just don't hurt Toothless.
The dragon?
That's what you're worried about?
Not the people you almost killed?
He was just protecting me!
He's not dangerous.
They've killed hundreds of us!
And we've killed thousands of them!
They defend themselves, that's all!
They raid us because they have to.
If they don't bring enough food back,
they'll be eaten themselves.
There's something else on their island, Dad.
It's a dragon like...
Their island? So you've been to the nest?
- Did I say "nest"?
- How did you find it?
What? No, I didn't. Toothless did.
Only a dragon can find the island.
No, no, no. No, Dad.
No, please, it's not what you think.
You don't know what you're up against.
It's like nothing you've ever seen.
Dad, please.
I promise you, you can't win this one!
Dad. No.
For once in your life,
would you please just listen to me?
You've thrown your lot in with them.
You're not a Viking.
You're not my son.
Ready the ships!
This way.
Set sail!
We head for Helheim's Gate.
Lead us home, devil.
It's a mess.
You must feel horrible.
You've lost everything:
your father, your tribe, your best friend.
Thank you for summing that up.
Why couldn't I have killed that dragon
when I found him in the woods?
- Would have been better for everyone.
- Yep. The rest of us would've done it.
So why didn't you?
- Why didn't you?
- I don't know.
- I couldn't.
- That's not an answer.
Why is this so important
to you all of a sudden?
Because I want to remember
what you say right now.
For the love of... I was a coward.
I was weak. I wouldn't kill a dragon.
You said "wouldn't" that time.
Oh... Whatever! I wouldn't!
300 years, and I'm the first Viking
who wouldn't kill a dragon.
First to ride one, though.
So?
I wouldn't kill him because
he looked as frightened as I was.
I looked at him, and I saw myself.
I bet he's really frightened now.
What are you going to do about it?
- Uh... Probably something stupid.
- Good, but you've already done that.
Then something crazy.
That's more like it.
Sound your positions.
Stay within earshot.
- Here!
- One length to your stern.
Listen, Stoick, I was overhearing
some of the men and, well, some of them
are wondering what it is we're up to here.
Not me, of course.
I know you're always the man
with the plan. But some,
not me, are wondering if there is
in fact a plan at all
- and what it might be.
- Find the nest and take it.
Of course. Send them running.
The old Viking fallback.
Nice and simple.
Shh!
Step aside.
Bear to port.
If you're planning on getting eaten,
I'd definitely go with the Gronckle.
You were wise to seek help
from the world's most deadly weapon.
Uh... It's me.
- I love this plan.
- I didn't...
You're crazy. I like that.
So, what is the plan?
That's not very encouraging.
Oh!
Ha! I was wondering where that went.
Stay low and ready your weapons.
We're here.
Uh-uh.
- Wait! What are you...
- Shh. Relax.
It's okay. It's okay.
Ha...
Where are you going?
You're gonna need something
to help you hold on.
When we crack this mountain open,
all hell is going to break loose.
In my undies.
Good thing I brought extras.
No matter how this ends,
it ends today.
Is that it?
We've done it!
This isn't over!
Form your ranks! Hold together!
- Get clear!
- Agh!
Beard of Thor! What is that?
Odin help us.
Catapults!
- Get to the ships!
- No! No!
- Smart, that one.
- I was a fool.
Lead the men
to the far side of the island!
Gobber, go with the men!
I think I'll stay, in case you're
thinking of doing something crazy.
I can buy them a few minutes
if I give that thing someone to hunt!
And I can double that time.
- Here!
- Oh, no! Here!
Come on! Fight me!
No, me!
Ruff, Tuff! Watch your backs!
Move, Fishlegs!
Look at us! We're on dragons.
We're on dragons! All of us!
Up! Let's move it!
Every bit the boar-headed,
stubborn Viking you ever were!
- Fishlegs, break it down!
- Okay.
Heavily armored skull and tail
made for bashing and crushing!
Steer clear of both. Small eyes, large nostrils!
Relies on hearing and smell!
Okay, Lout, legs! Hang in its blind spot,
make noise, keep it confused!
Ruff, Tuff, find out if it has a shot limit!
Make it mad!
That's my specialty!
Since when?
Everyone knows I'm more irritating! See?
Just do what I told you!
I'll be back as soon as I can!
- Don't worry! We got it covered!
- Yeah!
- Troll!
- Butt elf!
Bride of Grendel!
Um... This thing doesn't
have a blind spot!
There!
Go help the others!
Okay, hold on. Hold on.
- It's working!
- Yeah, it's working!
I've lost power on the Gronckle!
Snotlout, do something!
I'm okay!
Less okay!
Agh!
I can't miss! What's wrong, buddy?
Got something in your eye?
Agh!
Yeah! You're the Viking!
Whoa!
Dad?
You got it, bud.
Hiccup!
I'm sorry... for everything.
Yeah. Me, too.
You don't have to go up there.
We're Vikings.
It's an occupational hazard.
I'm proud to call you my son.
Thanks, Dad.
He's up!
Get Snotlout out of there.
- I'm on it!
- I'm on it first!
- Hey, let me drive!
- I'm ahead of you.
No, this way.
- Don't push me!
- I'll take your teeth out!
I can't believe that worked!
Night Fury!
Get down!
Did you get her?
Go.
That thing has wings.
Okay, let's see if it can use them!
You think that did it?
Well, he can fly.
Okay, Toothless, time to disappear.
Come on, bud!
Here it comes!
Watch out!
Okay, time's up! Let's see if this works.
Come on! Is that the best you can do?
Stay with me, buddy. We're good.
Just a bit longer.
Hold, Toothless.
Now!
No.
No!
Hiccup!
Son!
Hiccup.
Oh, son.
I did this.
Oh, son, I'm so sorry.
Hiccup!
Ha! He's alive.
You brought him back alive.
Thank you for saving my son.
Well, you know, most of him.
Hey, Toothless.
I'm happy to see you, too.
Oh! Ugh! Huh?
I'm in my house.
Uh... You're in my house.
Does my dad know you're here?
Uh... What? Okay, okay.
Toothless, no. No, Toothless.
Toothless! Oh, come on.
Agh!
Okay. Thanks, bud.
Oh!
- Toothless, stay here.
- Come on, guys. Get ready!
Hold on tight! Here we go!
What?
I knew it. I'm dead.
No, but you gave it your best shot.
So, what do you think?
Hey, look, it's Hiccup!
It's Hiccup!
Turns out all we needed
was a little more of... this.
You just gestured to all of me.
Well, most of you.
That bit's my handiwork.
With a little Hiccup flair thrown in.
You think it'll do?
I might make a few tweaks.
- Ow!
- That's for scaring me.
What, is it always going to be this way?
'Cause...
I could get used to it.
Welcome home.
- Night Fury!
- Get down!
You ready?
This is Berk.
It snows nine months of the year
and hails the other three.
Any food that grows here
is tough and tasteless.
The people that grow here
are even more so.
The only upsides are the pets.
While other places have
ponies or parrots...
we have...
dragons!