Long ago, in ancient China,
The Peacock rules over the Gongmen city.
They brought great joy
and prosperity to the city
For they have invented fireworks.
But their son, Lord Shen
Saw darker path in the fireworks.
What has brought color and joy
Can also bring darkness and destruction.
Shen trouble parent consult to a Soothsayer.
She foretold that if Shen continue
down to this dark path,
He will be defeated by the warrior
of black and white.
The Young Lord set out to change his fate.
But what he did next, only sealed.
Shen returned to his parents for a prize.
But in their faces, he saw only horror.
He was banned from the city forever.
But Shen swore revenge.
Some day, he will return and all
of China will bow at his feet.
Almost done, Lord Shen
But we ran out of metal.
Search the fartest villages,
find more metal.
China will be mine soon.
And then the Dragon warrior joined
the Furious Five.
And then we became the most
awesome Kung Fu team ever.
Enough talk.
Let's fight.
Listen! You can hear the Dragon warrior
is training right now.
33.... Stop.
It's too dangerous.
Stay focus.
36.....37....
How did he do it. This is freak?
38 dumpling.
Yeah! New record.
You monster.
Keep going, Hit 40
-He never hit 40.
You guys, don't worry.
I'll go to 40.
- Do it.
- No problem.
Wait a moment.
Yeah!
Yoooo...ho....!
He did it.
Well done Po.
Hus....ha...!
Your training is paid off.
Oh! Master Shifu.
Gotta go, See you later.
Whoo...ho! Yeah.
You said that to me right.
Inner peace.
Master Shifu.
Master Shifu. What do we got?
Pirates?
Vandals of the volcano mountain?
Whatever it is I will take them down.
Because I'm in mood
I need to get something done,
you know what I mean?
Ah! What are you doing?
One of Master Oogway final teaching.
Oh! Oh!...Awesome.
How did you do that?
Inner peace.
-Inner peace, that cool!
Inner peace of what?
It is the next phase of your training.
Every master must
find his path to inner peace.
Some choose to the meditate for
50 years in a cave just like this
Without a try to taste the food or water.
Or?
some find true a pain and suffering as I did.
At thoes day you was chosen
to be Dragon Warrior
...was the worst day of my life.
By far...
Nothing else came close.
It was the worst most painful,
mind destroyed horrible moment.
Okeay!
I have ever experienced.
But once I realized the problem was
not you, but within me
I found inner peace, I was able to
honest full of the universe.
So that's it,
I just need inner peace.
My inner is already super super peaceful
So I only need to do,
is just get this thing going.
Inner peace, You going down.
Now show me what you
were doing now with your feet,
I served you fancy food thing.
Po!
Bandit!
Approaching the musician in the village.
Dangerous. Tell thoes musician to start
play some action music.
Because it is on.
Don't worry Shifu, I will master
inner peace as soon as I get back.
No snack up this time.
Hus...Ha....Snack up.
Wait, are you serious?
Aah...!
Take all the metal you can find
Grap the metal.
Help! help! help!
That's everything.
Let’s get out of here.
Wings of justice.
Yeah..!
The Dragon warrior.
Panda?
That's impossible.
My fist tangled for justice.
This was my fist.
Get them.
Come on.
Whoo!
Yeah!
Take that.
Po, incoming.
Thanks, Mantis.
Tiger, double death strike.
Fist of fury
Tiger!
Monkey!
Viper!
Mantis! Bunny!
What? oh sorry.
Crane! go
I’m on it.
Everyone is ok?
Yeah! Awesome!
I got this.
Po!
See you again,
Hus...Ha!
Are you okay?
What happened?
I think I saw...
I think...
I gotta go
Thank you for coming to
Dragon Warrior Noodles and Tofu.
More tea? Lemon sauce?
If you need anything, just ask.
Thank You!
Five Furious.
That Dragon Warrior's mop.
He must be very poor
Ah! No touching,
You'll get them up dirty.
He will waiting on me.
Awesome!
- Yeah! I have a stand to prove it.
- Hey! Where is the Dragon Warrior?
He doesn't work here anymore.
He's busy out there.
Protecting the valley
The Dragon Warrior!
Po!
Yeah!
Here, Ok
Good. My son.
You should have told you will come.
Hi dad!
I would have saved you some Tofu.
-Ah!
Dad, can I talk to you?
Of course son.
In honor of my son: Free Tofu desserts
for everybody...
Yeah!
Oh! with purchased.
So good to see you,
Po.
Have you lost weight?
I could almost put my wings around you.
Oh! Well maybe a little.
Poor you, you must feel weak,
Let me get you some soup.
Oh! No. That's ok dad.
I’m not hungry.
Not hungry?
Po, you alright?
Yeah! Yeah!
I'm fine, I Just…
Today, I was fighting bandit.
Nothing too dangerous
I mean they was just… you know...
Yeah!
And then, a strangest thing happened,
I have a crazy vision.
I think I saw my mom.
And me as a baby.
Mom? a Baby?
Hmm...Dad?
What he talking about?
How can I say this?
Where did I come from?
Well you see, my son.
A baby come from a little egg.
Don’t ask me where the eggs come from.
Dad, it is not what I mean.
I know it's not.
I think it is time to told you something
that I should told you a long time ago.
Ok!
You might have been kind of....
....Adopted.
I knew it.
You knew? Who told you?
No one.
I mean…. come on dad.
But if you do,
Why didn't you ever say anything?
Why didn't you say anything?
How did I get here dad?
Where did I come from?
Actually...
You came from this.
It was just another day at the restaurant,
Time to make the noodle
I went out to the back. Where the
vegetables has just been delivered
Chinese cabbage, radish, turnip ...
There were no vegetables
Just a very hungry baby panda.
There was no one.
Of course you could eat meet.
I've been waiting for someone to come
looking for you
But no one did.
I brought you inside
Fed you
Gave you a bath
And fed you again,
And again,
I were trying to put some pants on you.
And then I made a decision would
change my life forever.
To make my super delicious soup.
And to raise you as my own son.
Po,  My little panda.
And from that moment on,
both my soup and my life
Have been that much sweeter.
My little Po, Is this the end of the story.
Look at me.
No, don't look at me.
That's it
That can't be it.
That have to be more dad.
Well, There were the time you ate
all my bamboo furniture.
It was important too.
One dumpling please,
Dragon Warrior size.
Oh Po, your story may not have such
a happy beginning, but look how it turn out
You got me, you got Kung Fu,
and you got noodles.
I know, I just have so many questions.
Like how I ever fit in this tiny basket.
Why didn't I like pants?
And who am I?
Good, watch your position.
Good
Shen?
Good afternoon, gentlemen.
Now we got my parent out of their way,
Please leave my house.
Your house?
Yes,
didn’t you see the peacock in the front door?
They were so sad,
It seems your fortune are
not as good as you thought.
We shall see, Shen
You shall see goat, well well
What do you want Shen?
What is right!
Gongmen city.
Gongmen is under reasonability of
the master council. And we will protect it.
Even from you.
I'm so glad you feel that way.
Otherwise that case is open up.
What's in the box, Shen?
Want to see it?.
It's a gift.
It is your parting gift.
I mean it will part you.
Part of you here, part of you there,
and part of you way way there on the wall.
You insane fool.
Show off, That is a warning.
You are no match for us in Kung Fu.
I agree, but this is.
Are you familiar with the master of Gongmen city?
Master thunder Rhino as I know.
Son of the legendary Flying Rhino?
Yes.
And the slayer of ten thousands surface
in the valey of gold.
He's dead.
That, that is impossible.
Rhino horn defend is imperial to any technique.
There were no technique.
Lord Shen has created a weapon.
One the breed firer and spread metal.
Unless he is stopped, This could be
the end of Kung Fu.
But I just got Kung Fu,
And now you must save it.
Go destroy the weapon, and bring
Lord Shen to justice.
Ok here we go.
here we go.
Whooo! Whooo! Wait, Wait a second,
how can I do this
I mean how can Kung Fu stop
something that stop Kung Fu.
Remember Dragon Warrior,
Anything is possible when you have inner peace.
Inner Peace.
Peace on
Po!
I get your things back.
I brought your food for week, cookie, bun
vegetables, and even all your action finger.
See!
Oh! I don’t know what those are.
Never seen them before in my life.
Dad, you make a scratch on my doll tiger
I also pack your painting, the best
time together, just in case you get lonely.
That me and you making noodles,
and that me and you eating noodle.
And that me giving you a piggy back ride.
That's cute, and the second thought
I hang out this one.
Hey! Dad.
They are waiting for me.
Of course, you have a job to do.
Far from home.
A strange city, filled with strange
people and strange noodles.
Facing horrible danger from
would you might never return.
Don’t go Po.
I got to go, I'm the Dragon Warrior,
It kind of my job to save Kung Fu.
And if I don’t.
What am I?
You are my son.
Right?
Po, it's time to go.
Goodbye.
Don’t worry, Mr Ping, He will be back
before you can sell noodles.
Noodles.
Come on guys, let's go.
Yeah!
Yeah! Yeah!
Mamma!
Mom? Dad? is that you?
Mom? Dad?
Oh! Ah!
Hey! Son, you are back.
Honey, what are you doing here?
But I thought.
We replaced you dear with a lovely radish.
Radish?
He is quite, polite, and frankly
does better Kung Fu.
No. No.
Wait!
Radish!
Inner peace.
Inner Peace! Inner Peace!
Oh! I'm training.
The mask is not a worrior opponent.
I'm ready.
Okay!
So. Seriously all you...
Hus...Ha!
I think I preferred the mask.
Apology I used to punch the iron wood tree
by the palace in training
Now I feel nothing
That is really cool
Again.
Hus..!
So this punching iron wood tree,
how long have you do that.
20 years.
Oh 20, 20 years.
Is there any faster way? You know
until to don't feel anything.
No. Side.
I don't think hard style is your thing.
Po. Why do you really out here
I just found out my dad,
he isn't really my dad
Your dad? Goose.
Must have been quite a shock.
Yeah!
And he is bother you?
Are you kidding me?
We are warrior right?
Nerves of steel. Soul of Platinum.
Like you.
So hard core you don't feel anything.
Hus!..ha! Yeah!
Whoo!
I was...
So what are you talking about?
Nothing! Nothing!
Po, is having daddy issue.
I'm so lucky,
I don't have any problem with my dad
Because my mommy eat his head
before I was born.
No. No. No
Mantis, it isn't about you,
Po, is the one freaking out.
I'm not freaking out
Po!
I'm freaking in
What?
We are here, Gongmen city.
My father Throne.
He used to let me play here.
a side him.
promised so some day...
this thron will be mine.
A little to the left.
But this is so heavy, Master.
Thirty years,
I was waiting for this moment.
Everything must be exactly
how I have visualized
and my visualized is,
a little to the left.
Perfect.
With the weapon,
by my...set a little bit more.
With the weapon, by my side,
all China will be bowed before me
We move out in 3 days, when the moon
is full and the tide is high.
You old goat,
why don't you tell me my...
Fortune?
The future,
I was going to say the future.
Looking to your bowl,
And tell me what glorious await
If you continue on your current path...
You will find yourself...
At the bottom of the stair.
I see....
I see...pain.
And anger.
How dare you,
That is the finest suit in the kingdom.
Followed by deny,
This is not fortune telling.
You just say what is happening right,
No.
The most important time is now.
But if you really want to see the future ...
What do you see?
A peacock.
Be defeated by a warrior of black and white.
Nothing has changed.
That is impossible.
And you know it.
It is not impossible.
And he knows it.
Who?
Lord Shen. I saw a pandas.
- A Panda?
A Kung Fu warrior,
he fought like a demon.
Big and fury, soft and squeachy.
Kind of cluching.
There are no more panda.
Even with the poor eye sight,
he can see the truth.
Why is that you can not?
Find this panda and bring him to me.
Yes Sir!
One panda live,
that is not make you right.
You are right,
being right make me right.
Then I will killed him and make you wrong.
Will you stop that ...
Wooh!
Oh!
That must be Shen places in
the other side of the city.
Great, we match in the town
quickly and claim
We are the Dragon Warrior and Furious Five
and we are here to bring you justice.
What are you doing?
This place is crowling with wolves.
Hey is that the guy
who hammer you in the face.
I do not like the guy...
We need to get to that tower without
being spoted by those wolves.
Got it.
Stealth Mode.
Where are they now?
Hello. I just ...
OK.
Anyway what was that?
Where is Po?
How can you lose a guy that big?
Guys, guys?
So that was stealth mode huh?
That beyond is not one my stronger mode.
You have more gold.
Come on.
This rice is raw,
You stole my mental pot.
Either you cook my rice or
I'll cook you.
Po, do something.
How Am I suppose to help cook rice
without getting caught.
Wait. I have a better idea.
One hey?
hey?
We are here to liberate the city
and bring Shen to justice.
You will need help
Thank you, brave sheep.
But too dangerous I can't let you...
Oh, not me. Not safe to talk here.
- Right.
I'm talking about Master Ox and Croc.
They are in Gongmen jail,
At the Black Dragon area.
What, they are still alive.
They must be in that jail to gathering
intelligent hatching a...
...plot to use their awesome
net to defeat the weapon.
OK, let's go.
Thanks sheep.
Hey ... Stop it ...!!
Alright, Go.
Catch them.
Take back
Keep moving.
Faster.
Be careful.
Now.
Got you ...
Where he go?
Spread out, Search everywhere,
Who is that over there,
It like a part of everywhere
Lets search there.
They must be close, I can feel a Kung Fu
chill is riding up
Sorry, Po. It just me.
Look, Gongmen jail.
Oh it cute?
Cute? huh?
Nice work, Po.
At the first sight of trouble,
I will give you a signal.
Ka..Ki..!
You mean like Crane?
Excuse me,
when I have ever made that noise.
Master Ox! Master!
Master Ox that great?
Master storming Ox Hey...
I can't belive,
I'm rescuing actual legend of Kung Fu.
We will free you from this,
No problem, gotta be a key arround here.
No, they won't leave a key arround here.
Yesh!
Oh good, you found it.
Come on you guys,
We are coming for you Shen.
Woosh...Oh!
Guys, are we going or not?
Do you wanna do later? I mean you
do wanna take back your city right?
Of course we do,
but if we stand up againt Shen.
he will turn the weapon on the city.
Listen to yourself,
You protect Gongmen city by not protect Gongmen city?
If we all fight together.
Then the weapon would kill everyone.
Oh yeah, So we use a sneak attack.
We get inside and then,
and then you will be stopped.
By an unstoppable weapon.
No thing is unstoppable except for me
When I'm stoping you
from telling me some thing unstoppable.
Master Ox,
I will not let you stay in the cell,
I like to see how you get me out.
You guy see that,
It called being awesome.
Come on,
what happen to be a hero,
The only hero in this town is the dead one.
Like I said,
you are not getting me out of the cell.
Yeah! Alright,
lets go.
I'll get the top.
Now is the time to surrender, panda.
Kung Fu is dead.
Kung Fu is ....dead? Fine!
You stay in your prison of fear,
with all the hopelessnest
And when you get all three meal a day
of shame. With desperate dessert
We take on Shen, And prove for all
those was hungry for justice and honor
That Kung Fu still live.
Monkey.
Ka...Ka!
You, You are mine.
I'll tell you what is gonna be your.
My fist and two super guard here.
Get him
Get me out of here.
Yes sir.
Stop him.
Faster.
Po go!
Po there.
Viper.
Hang on.
Watch out.
Try this.
Friends ....
Maybe something small.
No. No.
Rabbit in my face. Pig .. Step aside ...
Fire.
We lost them.
Again.
Crane, catch this.
catchable ...
Guys guys, give me a shot.
Mantis, now.
Is that all you got. Because I fell
it like a fight of beatles.
This about to bring thunder.
Your turn.
Why are so many signs hanging?
Come here.
I like wall.
Yes. Taste of a defeat.
Let me tell you something,
Next time you measure a plan
you better bring a whole lot
There is no body told you.
You mess with a wolf, you get a pack
I hit you twice, what are you gonna do now?
We surrender.
You can chain my body but you will
never chain my warrior spirit.
Dont forget the little guy.
Hey you just calm.
Po, what are you doing?
Trust me, I got a plan.
No way, eight point akupressure cuff.
Just the one that held Tailong, the
more you move the tier they get.
These are the best cuffs.
Greeting Panda, At last we meet.
We meet, at last. Yeah that's it.
Greeting Panda, we meet at last.
You are afraid for a reason.
I am not afraid.
He is coming to me in chained.
Have anyone should be afraid?
You.
Don't even think about it.
I hope this turn out better
than your new plan
than to cook rice and your stomach
by eating raw and drinking boiling watter.
This plan is no thing like that plan.
How?
This is the one gonna work.
Keep moving.
Ah ... My old enemy
Stairs.
Thanks for carying me.
Last few flied. I'm ok.
I try to climb up to the third floor.
Someone might want to clean that up.
Greeting Panda, we meet at ..
Hey, how are you doing?
Hey..!
You grow up bigger than I thought.
Do not look too hard.
Strong. And healthy.
Look! I don't know who you are
but please stand a side sir.
That is a lady.
Oh sorry, the beard make me
kind of miss leading.
Enough, Bring the prisoners to me.
I'm sorry ma'am. Get ready guys,
Keep your eyes for the weapon.
Sparrow kick
We did it. I just Kung Fu, did you
guys see that? I was..
Do you actually believe this is the
warrior destined to defeat me.
I do not. I know he is.
Ha ha, look at him
A life time to plan his revenge,
then he come to be on his knee.
What a life time....wooh! Wooh!
I did not have a life time.
We heard about master Rhino 3 days
ago, and we came here to revenge him.
You come to revenge nothing else?
Oh! Yes, All the pots and pants that
you stole. I want those back.
Nothing else?
you probaly did some evil steps for long away,
i dont know what else did you do
You don't know?
Know what?
What so funny?
Funny thing that you clearly do not know.
Ok, enough for this,
Would you guys spin the bin.
First you know, we come in,
and the weapon is tiny, Supprise it's big.
And the lady over here,
I think she's a guy.
He's got...
The only reason you're still alive ...
That I find you stupid.
Oh! Thank you,
But I find you evil and extremely annoyed.
Who do you think you are, Panda?
Who do you think I am, peacock?
Hus!...Ha!
Why are we laughing?
Take him
Fire.
Well light that thing.
Well I did.
Get the weapon
Hus!...Ha!
Get the weapon.
Tiger.
Lord Shen.
Yeah!
You...you were there.
Yes. Yes I was
You just let Shen get away
But we destroyed the weapon
Fire.
No he got more.
My wings ...
Help! Help!
Coming.
Watch out!
Help me out.
No! Get him down.
Use the rope.
Run run little panda.
Po, come on, we need you to focus.
I got it. I got it.
Bring him down
We're trapped.
This way ...
Hus!...Ha!
Goodbye.
Fire
Get back
The only way out is up
Follow me. Come on.
Where did they go?
To the top, come on
Here we go.
You idiot
My Nose ...
Call the wolves, all of them,
I want them ready to move
The year of the peacock, begin now
Right now?
Because it is middle of year.
So you only get a half of the year of peacock.
And this is year,
of course the year of peacock,
Happy New Year, Sir.
Get the wolves ready,
We load in ship now.
Now ...!!!!
Now, now, now.
Move move move.
This way.
Come on.
You...
What did you do?
It is chaos out there,
What happend to stoping Shen?
Yeah!
Guys, come on,
Give me a litle of credit.
I made form to get away.
Cause it's a trick of a plan.
I was thinking,
figure out his plan more.
That make no sense.
Yeah!
Po, The truth,
you have Shen. What happend?
What you talking about?
I don't know what you are talking about.
Yeah!
Ok he got me of course
The truth
Fine
They will keep you far from danger.
Real far
What?
You stay here.
Wait.
I have to go back.
You are staying here
I'm going and you can't stop me
Wooh!
Ok I wasn't ready that time.
Guys don't...
Ready
Look!
Stay down.
I have to get to him.
Then tell me why?
He was there ok. The peacock was
there the last time I saw my parent
He know what happened,
Where I came from? Who I am?
Look I'm going.
I have to know.
The hard core can't understand.
Tiger, no.
The hard core do understand.
But I can't watch my friend be killed.
We are going
Hey maybe you can watch me be killed.
Stopping a words.
And she is back
Don't worry kid.
You better are here.
You were wrong, Ziener,
We sail to victory tonight.
Your magic panda, clearly a fool.
Are you certain it is panda
who is the fool?
You just destroyed your ancestor your home,
Shen.
A trivial sarcify,
when all of China is my reward.
Then you will finaly be satisfied.
The destruction of the whole world,
finaly make you feel better.
This is not. Maybe I built
into the dungeon.
The cup you choose to fill have no bottom.
It is time to stop this madness.
Why on earth would I do that?
-So your parent can rest in peace.
My parents hate me.
Do you understand?
They feel wrong to me,
But I will make it right.
They love you, they love you so much
that having to send you away.
but that exit in the past.
And I must extend to the future.
Set SoothSayer free,
She is not use to me.
Good bye Shen, I wish you happiness.
Happiness?
must be taken.
and I will take mine.
Hurry up...
If all of those weapon leave the building,
China will fall
We bring down the building.
Hey guys, how a bout this.?
Oh this will work,
-Alright, let's go.
I can't feel my face.
Damn you peacock.
Hey!
Keep it cool.
You ...
Where are you going?
On your feet,
and get off stupid on your faces.
Move you dogs, faster faster.
Load the boat.
Greeting Panda.
Tell me what happened that night?
What night?
That night.
Oh, that night.
Yes!
Yes, I was there.
I watch that your parent abandon you,
as a terrible thing
I believe it went something like this.
Happy New Year, kid.
Hope you like it,
because you can't return it, hus...ha!
Po, What is he doing here?
Return it, return it.
Now you willing to die for
finding the truth.
You better tell me who I am.
Before...I prefer not to...
Yeah!
We got the Po.
Looking for me?
I said that to soon, didn't I?
Po!
Po, get away from him.
I'll get him.
No more running Shen.
So I see.
Now answer.
Oh you want to know so badly
You think no one willing to heal you huh?
Fill some crater in your soul.
Here are your answers:
Your parent didn't love you.
But here.
Let me heal you.
Ha..!
No...!
Yeah, I like you can make me
drink that....ha..
If I wanted you dead, I would have
left you in that river.
Why save me,
so you can fulfill your destiny.
What are you talking about?
Where am I?
What is this place?
I'm supprised you remember so little.
But you was so little
When it happened.
Perhape you do remember.
You know what,
it just a stupid nightmare
Nightmares or memories?
This was the windy village.
YOUNG SHEN,
was in line to rule Gongmen city.
But he wanted more.
I foretold that someone will standing his way,
a panda.
But I never could have foretold
what came next.
Kill them all!
Take our son,
and run away, Go
Stop fighting. Let it flows.
Your story may not have a such happy beginning
But that doesn't make you who you are
It is the rest of your story.
Who you choose to be.
So, who you are, panda?
I am Po!
And I'm gonna need a hat.
Such sad sad faces.
But now is the time only for joy.
You are going to be part of something beautiful.
Once you reach the habor,
it is in front of the world
You and your favorite Kung Fu will die.
then, China will know to bow before me.
Set sail.
You guys,
I never thought I would die like this.
I thought I will meet a nice girl.
Sit down, and she eat my head. So sad.
We can not give up hope,
Po, would warn us to remain strong.
Hard core, right?
Tiger?
Lord Shen,
what about the bridge?
Nothing stand in my way.
Fire.
You coward
Po!
How many time do I have to kill that
fat stinky panda?
Shen!
A panda stand between you
and your destiny.
What?
Prepare yourself,
for a hot...
What?
And now, free the Five.
leave of this destruction.
Okay!
Take him.
Ready.
This way, that way
Yeah!
You can't folow me.
Just get him.
Yeah! Here we go.
Come on
Yeah! hus...ha!
No, don't shoot.
No shoot.
Don't shoot.
You don't shoot, don't shoot.
Dont shoo't, stop fire
Attack.
Capture of freedom.
Monkey.
Impressive, Dragon Warrior.
What your plan?
Step 1 free the Five.
What is step 2?
Honestly I didn't think I could make this far.
How?
Stop Shen before he get to the habor.
Oh! Nice.
Tiger, Puppet of deadth.
Tiger
Master Ox
And Croc, Vengeance is served
Your friend there, is very persuasive.
Master Shifu.
Quickly,
use their boat to block the way.
Crane.
Wings of justice.
What?
I love you guys.
Why aren't we firing.
They have taken all our guns sir,
They are getting close.
Fire, fire at them.
But sir, that will kill our own.
I said fire at them, fire.
No!
Po!
Tiger?
Hus...ha!
Make your wish.
Let finish this.
Fire.
Inner peace.
Again.
Yeah!
Kill him,
somebody kill him.
Hus..ha!
Yeah!
Fire!
No!
Keep firing, keep firing.
Skadoosh it.
How did you?
How did you do it?
You know, just keep your elbows up,
and keep your shoulder loose.
Not that. How did you find peace?
I took away your parent, everything.
I scared you for life.
See that the thing Shen. Scars heals.
No they don't. Wound heals.
Oh yeah, What do scars do?
They phase I guest?
I don't care what scars do.
You should Shen, You gotta let go
that stuff of the pass,
because it just doesn't matter.
The only thing that matter,
is what you choose to be now.
You're right.
And then I chose this.
That was pretty hard core.
Wow. Don't ever do that again please.
It seem you have found inner peace
At such a young age.
Oh I have a pretty good teacher.
Yeah!..woo!
What do you mean he is not here.
It my son birthday, all he want is
just meet the Dragon Warrior.
How about some birthday
tofu cake instead huh?
You know,
maybe I think we should try another time.
When do you think he will be back?
I don't know, Ok I don't know.
Maybe never.
I'm been worried Ok.
That is my job,
I'm his dad, I was his dad.
Why do he have to go save China.
I know why.
But why?
He's just one litle panda.
Yeah!
So, how did it go?
Did you save China?
Yep!
I know you could.
That why I have a new sign made.
My son save China, you too can save
buy one dumpling with one free
Hey! That is pretty good deal.
Would you like to try one?
Maybe later.
There is something I should tell you
While I was gone,
I found the village where I was born
I found out how I ended up
in that radish baket.
You did?
I know who I am.
You do?
I'm your son.
I love you dad.
I love you too son.
Delicious fat radishes, You probaly
hungry, let me cook something for you
What are you talking about?
I will cook.
No, No, I'll cook.
Dad!
That atleast something
I can do for who save China.
No, that atleast I can do,
You raised me.
Po!
Dad! Okay!
Ok, lets both cook.
Together.
No, I'll cook.
My son is alive!