(COINS SLIDING IN MACHINE)
(BEEPING)
RJ: No!
Come on!
(GRUNTING)
Come on, baby.
Grab it!
- (BOING)
- (SIGHING)
All right.
(WHOOSHING)
What?
Ow!
Vincent.
No, no, bad idea.
Bad idea!
(STOMACH GRUMBLING)
(GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
(SNORING)
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
Hmm?
(SIGHING)
(GROWLING)
(SNORING)
(CLANGING)
(BEAR SNORING)
(SIGHS)
Just take what you need.
Just take
what you need.
(RATTLING)
Mmm-hmm.
- (THUD, RATTLING)
- (BEAR SNORING)
What's...
(SIGHING)
Mmm.
(CHUCKLES)
- (HISSING)
- Huh?
(GASPS)
- RJ?
- No?
The moon's not full.
You woke me up a week early?
Oh, no.
Don't tell me you're dumb enough
to actually try and steal my stuff.
RJ, I'm gonna
have to kill you.
Please, I'm just a desperate guy
trying to feed his family.
- You don't have a family.
- I meant a family of one.
Okay, wait, wait, wait, wait!
Look, it's still in the cave.
So, technically, not stolen.
- (YELPS)
- Oh, no!
No!
- Slow!
RJ: Stop!
- Whew!
- (CHUCKLING)
That was close.
(STAMMERING)
(GROWLING)
Vincent, wait!
I can get it all back!
That's right! If you eat me,
you'd have to do it.
But I can get it. All of it!
- My red wagon?
- Redder!
Ow.
- The blue cooler?
- Blue cooler. On my list!
- Gotta be blue?
- Yes!
And I want my Spuddies.
I love those things.
'Cause with a Spuddie,
enough just isn't enough.
So true. Painfully true.
And I'll tell you what.
I'm gonna get you the giant
picnic pack, family-fun size.
- They have that?
- I'm pretty sure.
All right, RJ. I'm going
back to sleep.
When that moon is full,
I'm waking up.
And all my stuff had better be
right back where it was.
But that's just one week!
That's impossible for one guy!
(GRUNTING)
A week's perfect.
I'll get some helpers.
Full moon, all my stuff. And don't
even think about running away.
Because if you do, I will hunt
you down and kill you.
(PANTING)
Okay! Okay, buddy! You just
rest easy, all right, 'cause I'm on it.
Hey, in a week from now,
we're gonna be laughing about this thing.
(CHUCKLING)
(GRUNTING)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
- (HORN HONKING)
- (GASPING)
(SINGING) How great I am
Gotta tell myself
Yeah, I'm the man
Looks grim right now
But pretty soon
we'll be laughing about it
Ooh, and it's all right
Yeah, it is
I swear, you'll see
It's not, really
Yeah, and it's all right
'Cause I've always
got my family of me
(WIND GUSTING)
It's not a first
Might be the last
Yeah, I'm sure I must've
been through worse
But, ooh, it's all right
Got a paddle and a creek
Yeah, and it's all right
Because I've always
Got my family
Of me
(GASPS)
Boy, that's cold! That's cold!
The one place
I didn't have a shell.
Wow.
Spring.
That means there's only
274 days left till winter.
Everybody, wake up!
Hibernation's over.
Morning!
- Morning, Hammy.
- I gotta go wee-wee!
Not in the lake we drink from!
Let's go, all right,
the rest of you. It's spring!
That means
we gotta get to work.
Finished. No, wait!
Come on, everybody. Wake up.
Don't make me come in there.
STELLA: Y'all better listen.
I've been holding
something in all winter,
and I'm about to let it out.
- I'm up, I'm up!
- She means it. Let's go!
Thank you, Stella.
I can clear a room, Verne.
Come on, that much I can do.
- Good morning.
- Good morning, everyone!
- How'd you guys sleep?
- Just a super-duper morning.
Jeepers.
Not lookin' so good
around the eyes there, hon.
Bucky and Quillo were up
every three or four weeks.
And Spike kept poking me.
Yeah. Well, he's kinda pokey.
Yup, he's the sharpest
of the bunch there.
You know what? How 'bout
I take the day shift?
Lou, that'd be just super.
All right, kids,
you heard your mother,
and now, you listen
to me. Shape up there.
Oh, boy.
This is what I was afraid of.
Where's the food? Is there any left?
I'm really hungry, so is there any left?
We ate all the food, Hammy.
During the winter?
So, we gotta go
get some more now.
Right! I buried some
nuts in the woods,
and I know where they are.
I'll be right back. Bye!
(GASPING)
(LAUGHTER)
Dad, it was just snow.
But it could have been
a predator.
Isn't playing dead
a little weak?
Heather, how many times
must I say it?
Playing possum is what we do.
We die so that we live!
Kids, I'm the boss of you, okay?
So just calm down.
That's what we need to find you
this year, don't you know?
A good fella.
- A good fella? A good fella?
- Uh-oh. Jeepers, here we go.
Why does everyone think
I need a man?
I look like a nest
and smell like a swamp.
So, when you find
a fella who's decent,
good with kids and has
no sense of smell, call me.
(GASPS)
- VERNE: Hello?
- I don't care who started it.
Uh... (CLEARS THROAT)
Look, food.
Well, I think you know
what this means.
- Verne.
- Just a minute, Hammy.
This means we were nine berries
away from starvation.
- (ALL EXCLAIMING)
- Sorry. That was a little intense.
I meant,
really serious hunger pains.
Verne!
Not finished, Hammy.
Morning, Lou, Penny.
- Thanks.
- Hey, kids.
- So, what I want to tell you all is...
- Verne!
I'm not done, Hammy.
If you have to go again, just go.
Okay. So, all I'm saying
is we cut it a little close.
So, this year we need to make
sure that we fill the log...
- All the way to the top.
- Exactly. All the way to the top.
- Because, what are we?
- Foragers!
VERNE: And what do we forage?
ALL: Food!
- VERNE: Right.
- Super, Verne, really super.
- Okay, Hammy.
- Huh?
- What is it?
- What is what?
What is it you want
to tell me?
Mmm? Oh. Uh. Oh!
What was it, what was it,
what was it, what was it?
Wait. Right on the tip
of my tongue. Yeah!
There's a weird thing
over there I've never seen before.
It's really scary. Follow me.
Okay. Meeting called
on account of weird, scary thing.
Let's go.
Hmm. Foragers.
Hammy, what weird thing?
Oh.
That weird thing.
(GULPS)
(GASPS)
HAMMY: It never ends!
Whoa!
Hey!
It never ends that way too!
PENNY: Jeepers, Lou.
LOU: Yeah, jeepers
is the word there, hon.
I've never seen anything like this.
HAMMY: Man, that's big.
- What is this thing?
- Heather, no!
- I'm scared.
- Me too, Mama.
(SHUSHING) It's okay, it's just a...
What is this thing, Lou?
I... Well, it's a... It's...
Verne?
Well, it's, it's obviously...
Some kind of bush?
I'd be less afraid of it
if I just knew what it was called.
- Let's call it Steve!
- Steve?
- It's a pretty name.
- Steve sounds nice.
Yeah, I'm a lot less
scared of Steve.
Great and powerful Steve!
What do you want?
VERNE: I don't think it can speak.
WOMAN:
I heard that, young man!
- (ALL SCREAM)
- (GASPS)
- You get over here right now!
- Okay.
Hammy, get back here.
- But, Steve is angry!
- It came from the other side of Steve.
I mean the bush.
I mean... Jeez!
(SIGHING)
Look, there's only one way
we're gonna find out what this thing is,
and what this is all about.
I'm gonna go check it out.
(GULP) Aah!
- (ALL SCREAM)
- Ay yai yai.
Uh... Aah!
Steve ate Verne!
All right, Steve,
you brought this on yourself.
Stella, don't! I'm not eaten,
I just tripped.
(CLEARS THROAT)
I'm gonna go over there.
Just don't anybody move.
(SHUDDERING)
WOMAN: Kids, come on, hurry up!
You'll be late!
(CAR ENGINE STARTING)
WOMAN:
Gary, come on, breakfast!
(DOG BARKING IN DISTANCE)
What is this place?
Hey there, little...
(SIZZLING)
Fella?
(SHUDDERING)
Oh! (GASPS)
Hi.
Aah!
Oh!
(GASPS)
(PANTING)
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa!
Ow.
Whoa! Ohh!
(SCREAMING)
(RINGING)
Operator. Can I help you?
No, I can talk. I'm just
driving.
(BICYCLE BELL RINGS)
- (QUAVERING)
- (YELLING)
Aaah!
(GRUNTING)
- HAMMY: Verne's back.
- Verne's back.
- Verne!
- Jeepers!
Come on, let's get him.
PENNY: Help him up.
- OZZIE: What was over there?
- Freaky pink primates!
They must have come
while we were hibernating.
It was awful.
They had wheels
on their feet,
and these sticks,
and they were
whacking me with these sticks
like it was some sort of sick game.
You should have died!
You should have laid down and died.
- Dad.
- That's not the worst part.
Half the forest is gone.
The oak trees,
and the berry bushes,
they're just...
they're just gone.
Jeepers.
What'll we do for food?
How are we gonna live?
I don't know.
But here's what I do know.
We will be fine as long as
no one goes over Steve again.
It's called a hedge, and it is not
to be feared, my amphibious friend.
It is the gateway
to the good life.
I'm a reptile, actually.
But, you know,
it's a common mistake.
And you are?
Where are my manners. I'm RJ.
Please don't think I'm prying,
but I couldn't
help overhearing,
and I can shed a little light
on what this whole
hedge situation is about.
You see, what was
once mere wilderness
is now 54 acres of man-made,
manicured, air-conditioned paradise.
Except for that little-bitty
speck. You are here.
(ALL GASPING)
No, no, that's a good thing.
You're hibernators, right?
You gather up a bunch of food,
store it away for the winter?
Uh-huh. We fill the log!
VERNE: Hammy.
Really? This log?
This cave-like log?
- All the way to the top.
- Ozzie.
Let me ask ya,
how long's it take?
- You know, to fill the log?
- Two hundred and seventy-four days.
Oh!
- Ever done it in a week?
- That's impossible.
Not if we work together.
You see, you've got the food
gathering skills, I've got the know-how,
- and they have the food!
- How much food?
Loads of food. Heaps of food.
Food out the wazoo!
Well, you know, whatever
kind of food comes out of a wazoo,
I really don't think
we're interested in eating.
I don't know, the guy's making
a lot of sense to me.
- I think we should listen.
- Yeah, I'm okay with wazoo food there.
No, you're not.
The tail is tingling.
- Why didn't you say so?
- Hold on, hold on. The what is what?
When something doesn't feel right,
my tail tingles. Let me tell you something,
everything you've said so far
is driving my tail crazy.
Listen. Verne, right? This isn't
something you need to be afraid of.
Well, I am.
And for good reason.
This is not a birthmark.
That's because you went over
there without a guide, Verne.
Whatever. Thanks for stopping by.
We're not interested.
Not interested in the most delicious
food you've ever tasted?
- No!
- Come on.
Not interested!
Okay. I get it.
I understand.
This is something
that you're just not open to.
- Wow!
- (GASPS)
- Whoa!
- (MOANING)
- My!
- Jeepers.
What is that?
That, my friend, is a magical
combination of corn flour,
dehydrated cheese solids,
BHA, BHT and good old MSG,
a.k.a. the chip.
Nacho cheese flavor.
Over here! Toss me one of those!
More, please! More.
Yeah, Verne, those were good!
It's all good. And we're going
over there. Tonight!
Yeah!
Welcome to Suburbia.
PENNY: Look at that!
(ALL GASPING)
Hey, Mom, look at us!
Look at us!
LOU: My! Hon, look at this.
Jeepers.
How's that tail, Verne?
Listen, if anybody
in this family gets hurt,
I'm holding you
personally responsible.
They're having
a good time.
I'll take
responsibility for that.
- This is neat.
- Look at that.
Hey, Spike, look at that.
Hey, Verno,
I took a few clippings
out of my quills
to do a little comparison.
Look at this, the grass seems
to be greener over here.
Verne, are you certain
you came to the same place?
Yeah, 'cause
the raccoon says...
Okay, enough about him.
I get it.
So, he can do
a couple of tricks.
I mean, it's not like
he can walk on water.
Hey, everybody!
This way to the food!
- That thing's huge!
- What is that?
That is an SUV.
Humans ride around in it
because they are slowly
losing their ability to walk.
- Jeepers, it's so big!
- How many humans fit in there?
Usually? One.
Hi, this is Gladys Sharp.
Your president?
Of the homeowner's
association? Right.
- Jeepers.
- What is that?
Easy, easy, don't worry.
That's just a human being.
And they are just as scared
of us as we are of them.
Now, if a human does happen
to see you, just lay down,
roll over and give your privates
a good licking. They love it.
The homeowner's charter,
which you signed,
says the grass is supposed
to be two inches,
and according to my measuring
stick, yours is 2.5.
Could we just
get the food and go?
Really,
do they have it, or not?
Didn't you see it?
It was in the box.
They've always got food with them.
We eat to live,
these guys live to eat.
Let me show you
what I'm talking about.
The human mouth
is called a "pie hole."
The human being
is called a "couch potato."
That is a device
to summon food.
- (DOORBELL RINGING)
- That is one of the many voices of food.
That is the portal
for the passing of the food.
That is one of the many
food transportation vehicles.
Humans bring the food,
take the food,
ship the food,
they drive the food,
they wear the food!
That gets the food hot.
That keeps the food cold.
That... I'm not sure
what that is.
- (CHILDREN CHEERING)
- Aah!
Aah!
What do you know? Food!
That is the altar
where they worship food.
That's what they eat when
they've eaten too much food.
That gets rid of the guilt
so they can eat more food.
Food! Food! Food! Food!
Food!
So, you think
they have enough?
Well, they don't. For humans,
enough is never enough!
(GASPING)
And what do they do
with the stuff they don't eat?
They put it in gleaming,
silver cans,
just for us.
PENNY: Sweet jeepers.
RJ: Dig in!
(ALL CHEERING)
- Good, isn't it?
- Okay.
- Share there, everyone, share.
- Come on, come on, come on.
That's a diaper.
And that does come out of a wazoo.
So, what do you think?
Was I right or was I right?
And these things
are just the scraps!
Wait'll you see
what comes in the boxes,
and packages and cans!
I'm telling you, folks, stick
with me, and in one week
we will gather
enough food to...
- To feed a bear.
- What?
Just a figure of speech.
(BEEPING)
Halt! Intruders! Intruders!
Get out, all of you.
What is it, baby?
(SCREAMING)
- What are you doing?
- You said we should lick our...
No! Nix that! Run!
- HAMMY: Run! Run!
- Get outta here!
Run!
Shoo!
RJ: To the hedge!
Get out of here!
I just mopped this patio!
Filthy vermin!
(ALL PANTING)
STELLA: Verne's right,
that was horrible.
- You kids okay? Hon, you all right there?
- Stay close.
We'll find
other food, right?
See what I mean?
That's what I was talking about.
These humans don't
want us around.
So, we scared her,
and she overreacted. No biggie.
No biggie? That is what
we call a biggie.
Come on,
think about the food.
It was worth it
for that food, huh?
That stuff is to die for!
- (GASPS)
- (GROANING)
Let me rephrase that.
No, to die for.
You nailed that part.
Look, maybe our little forest life
looks primitive to a guy with a bag.
- What?
- But I think I speak
for the whole family
when I say we want nothing
to do with anything
that's over that hedge.
Come on!
STELLA: I'm done.
You haven't even tried doughnuts yet!
You wanna store fat?
That is the way
to store some fat.
You'll be sweatin'
through the winter!
HEATHER: We'll eat
the bark, right?
Okay, all right, you guys
sleep on it!
Good idea. I'm gonna
check back with you.
Shoot!
Almost had 'em.
VERNE: Good night, Heather.
HEATHER: Good night, Verne.
VERNE: Good night, Ozzie.
OZZIE: Good night, Verne.
VERNE: Good night, Lou.
LOU: Yeah, good night there, Verne.
VERNE: Night, Penny.
PENNY: Good night, Verne.
VERNE: Good night, Hammy.
HAMMY: Good night, Verne.
VERNE: Good night, Bucky.
BUCKY: Good night.
VERNE: Good night, Spike.
SPIKE: Good night, Uncle Verne.
VERNE: Good night, Quillo.
QUILLO: Good night, Uncle Verne.
VERNE: Remember, when we wake up,
only 273 days left till winter.
STELLA: That's enough, Verne.
VERNE: Good night, 273.
(MUMBLING)
Spuddies...
Cooler... Wagon...
Redder wagon.
Time's up, RJ.
But I have
six more days! No!
No!
(GASPING)
Okay. Four paws, fur.
Still alive, still alive.
GIRL 1: What are you saying?
You want me to take 'em to his house?
GIRL 2: No.
GIRL 1: Then what are you saying?
GIRL 2: Jimmy was pushing me
on the bus.
GIRL 1: He likes you.
GIRL 2: No way, he's a creep.
GIRL 1: Next time he shoves you,
beat him up.
Yes!
(GRUNTING)
Okay, kids, dive in.
There it is. Bark for breakfast!
- I want a doughnut!
- I want pizza.
PENNY: No, you don't.
(BUZZING)
(GROANING)
(CRUNCHING)
Okay. This is great.
Granted, it takes
some time to chew.
But that...
(SWALLOWS)
That was very satisfying.
And, by the way,
lots of fiber in there too.
Mmm!
- Lots.
- I gotta admit, that does look tasty.
(SPITS)
What are you doing here?
I'm here to help you
with your foraging thing.
Look, Verne,
you said a word yesterday
about your little gang here.
It starts with an F,
do you remember what it was?
- Family?
- Right, right, that.
You know,
that got me right here.
You see, Verne,
I used to have all of that.
My own place,
surrounded by loved ones,
universal remote.
But then all that
went away with...
The weed hacker incident.
Oh, God.
Come here.
Yeah, that feels good,
doesn't it?
- Oh, brother.
- Jeepers, Verne.
We could always use
the extra hand there, you know.
The weed hacker, Verne.
The weed hacker.
Okay.
(SNIFFLES)
Not your problem.
I'll just go.
This is me...
Going.
- Been nice.
- Don't hit.
Really nice getting
to know you.
Hey, I'm sure I'll see you
around the forest.
- Take care.
- All right, all right.
Hey, RJ?
(SOBBING)
You can...
you can stay.
- (RJ LAUGHING)
- (VERNE SCREAMING)
Come here, ya big lug!
VERNE: No.
I knew beneath this hard,
crispy outside
there was a soft,
nougat-y center in there.
Do you mind
if I call you Uncle Verne?
With every
bone in my body.
Great. Hey, can I
work with Hammy?
You wanna help me
find my nuts?
Very tempting, Hammy,
very tempting.
But first, I want to
show you this.
(SNIFFING)
You like this cookie?
Ohh, ho, ho, ho!
- Well, this cookie's junk!
- I like a cookie.
Easy, easy. Don't worry.
I know where we can get
some cookies so valuable
that they are hand delivered
by uniformed officers.
- And the Doyles' is the yellow house.
- They only ordered one box.
RJ: And there they are.
America's most coveted cookies.
Love Handles, Skinny Mints,
Neener Neeners, and Smackeroons.
And guess what?
They're all yours!
Hoo-hoo! Aah!
Whoa, Hamilton.
Hold on there, fella.
I love your energy,
but you just can't take 'em.
- But, you said they're mine.
- They will be,
if we successfully marry
your manic energy to my brilliant plan.
- You with me, kid?
- I... I... I...
The I's have it!
Let's ride.
GIRL 1: I thought Mrs. Johansson was
allergic to chocolate.
- Really?
- Yeah, if she eats it,
- her face like, explodes or something.
- That is, like, so unfair.
Wait, wait. How many boxes of...
HAMMY: Hey!
You stay away from those
cookies. They're mine!
- (TAPPING) Ahem!
- Aah!
Hey, this guy's not coming, is
he? I don't want him to.
We have so much
work to do.
Come on, step into my office.
Now, listen up.
What we're going for here is a vicious,
man-eating, rabid squirrel.
- Can you handle that?
- Um. Excuse me?
Yes... Hammy.
Okay. Rabbits aren't vicious.
They're all cute and cuddly, so...
Rabid, not rabbit.
Oh...
What?
Okay. So, first we're gonna
muss the hair.
Ow, ow, ow!
That's looking good.
All right, now we're gonna...
(SPITS)
We're gonna
mat the fur a little bit.
A little puff on the tail...
Stop it! Puffier.
Liking that a lot.
Show me that wild look
in your eye, boy. Come on!
Oh! Oh!
I can burp my ABCs!
(BURPING)
Hammy!
I just really need you
to focus right now, okay?
- Okay.
- Thank you.
Let's see. There we...
Hang on a minute.
Not that, not that. No, no.
Aha! Nice!
Hammy?
(GULPS)
(CHUCKLING)
Done! Now, come on.
I'll be right behind you.
Go on, get out there.
Shoo, shoo!
I am a crazy rabid squirrel!
I want my cookies!
(BABBLING)
I'm rabid!
I'm foaming at the mouth.
I'm foaming,
very scary rabid squirrel.
- Rabies!
- Hey, it's working!
- Behind you!
I know.
You're right behind me...
Got it! Stand back!
- No, no, no, no! No!
- Take that!
(SCREAMING)
Walk it off!
Walk that one off!
What's going on?
Is that Hammy?
Everything's under control.
Just go back to the hedge.
You call that under control?
- He's under attack!
- He's working!
I'm coming, Hammy!
RJ: Verne! No!
What are you doing? Watch out!
(GIRL SCREAMING)
- Hold still! I got it! Stay still.
- Help me! Get off of me!
- Yuck!
- Gross!
- Nasty!
- Oh, my God, this is so gross!
RJ: Verne!
That was great!
You, my friend, are a natural.
Or, should I say, au naturel.
Huh?
Oh.
Hammy, you were awesome,
my man!
You had me scared. I was about to come
out and beat you with a book myself.
You're all right,
aren't ya?
Of course, you are.
You are Hammy!
Those bruises
are gonna heal.
You know what?
Chicks dig scars.
- There! It was over there!
- It was right over there!
GIRL 1: That's where the
squirrel attacked us!
He has like, rabies
or something.
GIRL 2: There was this gross,
naked, amphibian thing.
- Reptile.
- It's okay, girls.
Go inside, have a cookie,
turn on the TV and calm down.
Thanks, Mom.
I'm sorry, Janis, did I just hear
them say "rabid squirrel"?
I think they might
just be overreacting.
But, what if they're not?
What if we have
a potential pandemic on our hands?
Vermin running loose,
spreading disease,
and lowering
our property values?
Yeah. I have a casserole
in the oven. Gotta run.
Fine. You worry
about your casserole,
and I'll worry about the end of
suburban peace and tranquility!
RJ: That's right. Don't push.
Plenty for everybody.
Got a box right over here
for ya, Penny.
Jeepers, that is good.
Kids, eat up!
Anything that tastes this good
has to be good for you.
You feel that buzz
in the back of your skull?
- Yeah.
- That's called a sugar rush.
It's what keeps humans going,
it's why they don't hibernate.
You top that off
with a little of this,
and what usually takes you
all summer will only take us a week.
I like it! I like it!
Hold on, Hamsquad. The last
thing you need is caffeine.
That's right.
Come on, dig in.
Because this, my friends,
is just the beginning.
What?
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(SINGING) Follow me
into the great unknown
Where pink flamingos grow
Diet soda flows
And what you take
magically regenerates
On supermarket shelves
The ovens clean themselves
You don't pay the tab
'til the last drop
- Up, down! Up, down!
- He's getting away!
Yeah! Come on!
'Cause this train never
stops
Ohh!
We make a good team
me and you, we do
You can scratch my back
And I'll scratch my back
too
Read it and weep.
People, more is more
Ah, we all want more
You don't pay the tab
'till the last drop
So we all ride for nothing
'Cause this train never
stops
(SPITS)
(PHONE BEEPING)
Hello? I need every business
listing you have under "exterminator."
You don't stop
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
- (THUMP)
Ozzie!
BOY: Mom! You hit a possum.
WOMAN: My goodness.
Do you think it's dead?
(GASPS)
Oh, no!
- Wow!
- Touch it.
Can I poke him?
WOMAN: No!
These poor little creatures.
GIRL: What's going on?
BOY: Come check it out.
Debbie? I don't remember
seeing a permit out for a gathering.
Groups of more than one
who wish to get... (SCREAMING)
Timmy, get the shovel
from the car.
(GASPS)
Lights fading,
limbs growing cold.
- I see a tunnel.
- Oh, no.
(SQUEAKING)
Mother, is that you
beckoning me into the light?
Must move toward the light.
(SQUEAKING)
What do you think he's doing?
Maybe we knocked his brains
loose, or something.
I'm telling you,
you went too far this time.
Let's get out of here,
and leave this...
This...
(GRUNTS)
Nice catch, Verne.
OZZIE: Yes! Yes!
- You're dangerous. You're insane!
- Sweet music, I'm going home!
(COUGHING)
Goodbye, cruel world!
Ooh! Ooh!
(WHISPERING)
Rosebud.
(WHEEZES)
- Now can I poke him?
- No!
You see? This is exactly why
I called the exterminator.
To kill them before
they get hurt like this.
Everybody,
get out of here right now!
Right! Kids, grab those handles.
Get the stuff.
- What?
- Here we go. I threw out my back.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
- Let's go.
- Get down.
(SQUEAKING)
Oh, no.
I believe someone phoned
about an animal problem?
The solution is
standing before you.
Dwayne LaFontant is here.
Where have you been?
I'm throwing a "Welcome to
the Neighborhood" party tomorrow,
and so far Debbie's car has
killed more animals than you have.
Stand down, sister.
I personally guarantee
that there will not be
a living thing at this party.
The Verminator is on the job.
Leave it. Leave it!
What do we have here?
(SNIFFING)
Didelphis marsupialis
virginianus.
Approximately 10 pounds.
(SNIFFS)
Male.
- I think he's dead.
- Really?
Do you, in fact, have
an associates degree from Vermtech?
I think he wants you
to think he's dead.
- Go! Go!
- Move, move!
- That's it! Run! Go!
- ...voluntary shock state.
Look at him closely.
You can see him breathing.
I certainly hope
he's not in any pain.
(CHUCKLES)
- What the...
- Kill it! Kill it!
Thank you all for coming!
You were a great audience!
Man!
All right, what am I
up against here?
(SNIFFING)
Possum, porcupine,
skunk, squirrel, raccoon...
(SNIFFING)
Amphibian.
- Reptile.
- No.
Reptile.
That's what I call
a super-duper performance there.
- OZZIE: I wanna do it again!
- Beyond super.
They were riveted, man.
You were awesome!
BUCKY AND QUILLO:
All right!
Dad. I just gotta say, that was...
That was pretty good.
Props for the Ozman!
- Ozman!
- Yeah! Yeah!
But let's not forget
our brilliant leadership,
RJ.
ALL: RJ!
BUCKY AND QUILLO: RJ!
Brilliant!
Hey, RJ, come this way.
We wanna show you something.
- Yeah, sure.
- Sweet.
What a team!
STELLA: That raccoon knows what he's doing.
LOU: You're my
hero there, fella.
- Over here, this way.
- RJ, come on!
Yeah, we wanna show you
something. Come on, hurry!
Check it out.
Your new home!
And look, we got
a place for you right here!
That's for me?
Yeah, is this anything
like what you had, RJ?
This isn't anything
like what I had, Lou.
- Here, I'm not supposed to drink this.
- Thanks.
- (SLURPING)
- (CLEARS THROAT)
- Is that my bag?
- Yeah, we brought it in here
so you wouldn't have
to sleep up in that tree.
Really? Wow.
Hey, RJ, check this out!
We totally hooked up the TV.
- I hot-wired the HD converter.
- We get like, 1,000 channels!
Here, can you take the remote
before my dad does?
Wow. A universal remote?
This is nice, guys.
Really nice.
ANNOUNCER: (ON TV) We now
return to A Scoundrel Among Us.
WOMAN: You should be
ashamed of yourself.
We let you into our family,
and you've deceived us.
MAN 1: I gave you my heart,
and you ripped it into a million pieces.
MAN 2: Get real, Kevin.
'Cause when you feel like a dirtbag,
it's because
you're a dirtbag. Right?
So, just own it, just say it
out loud. "I am a dirtbag."
Dirtbag. I don't think that
guy's a real doctor.
What do you
think there, RJ? RJ?
(RAPID BREATHING)
Whoa. Whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, RJ.
What are you doing, man?
You are getting in way too deep.
Just get the food.
Feed the bear. Get the food.
Feed the bear.
Where's the food?
Where's the food? Where's the food?
(WHEELS SQUEAKING)
(GROANS)
Verne. What are you doing?
I'm getting things back
to the way they were.
- No, don't. How about I just leave?
- Good.
You leave, and I return this
stuff to the rightful owners.
What? Why?
Because we've
angered the humans.
And we don't wanna end up
like that rabbit.
Hence, I'm giving this back
so they won't kill us.
Verne, you don't understand!
We need this stuff!
No, we don't!
You can't take it!
Yes, I can!
- Let go!
- You let go!
- I have to have it.
- No!
Stop!
(GASPS)
Verne. Move slow, keep your
voice low and follow me.
- What?
- Shh!
No.
Shh!
No. I'm not falling
for any more of your smooth talk!
I don't know
what you're up to,
but my entire
shell is tingling.
And you know what?
I'm listening to it this time,
- and I'm putting my foot down.
- No, no.
(CHEW TOY SQUEAKING)
Play?
Huh? Oh! Huh?
Play!
Play! Play! Play!
Play! Play!
Aaah! Oof!
Play!
(GROWLING)
DOLL: Let's play!
Play!
Jeez...
Aah!
Play! Play! Play!
RJ: Down, boy. Sit. Roll over!
DOG: Play!
- RJ: Play dead!
- Play!
Attaboy, Verne. Save the food.
I'll lose the dog.
- Play.
- Huh?
Play, play, play, play.
No! No, no, no, no.
RJ: You're dropping
all the food, man!
Here, catch.
DOG: Play!
Are you hungry? Look, food.
(SCREAMING)
- MAN: My back!
- Whoa!
Look, people! Play with them!
MAN: Look out!
WOMAN: Stop! What's he doing?
- What was that?
- Play, play, play, play.
I'm all right, I'm fine.
It's okay. It's...
Verne, unhook the chain.
Play!
Whoa!
No.
Yes.
Bad.
- Oh, boy.
- Wow!
(GRUNTING)
(MISFIRING)
Verne, I told you to
unhook the chain.
Garbage cans are not to be
on the curb before eight...
Oh!
Aah!
- (BOTH GASPING)
- (BLOWING)
You're the devil.
(SCREAMING)
- (LEAVES RUSTLING)
- BOTH: Ow! Oh! Ow!
(CHUCKLING)
No! No!
Verne, you all right there?
- Gimme a hand, Oz.
- Sure, sure.
- What the heck happened?
- What happened?
It's gone.
The food! Gone!
- What?
- Gone?
- How's it gone?
- Ask him!
- Verne?
- I returned it
to its rightful owner.
LOU and OZZIE: What?
We, like, worked
our tails off, you know?
Like, a lot. And the food
we gathered was totally...
You know. And you're...
You're all, whatever.
Yeah, Verne, what were you
thinking? The log was full!
- Full of junk.
- So, what are you saying there?
That the food
we gather our way
isn't as good as the food
we gather your way?
Your way?
You mean his way.
Can't you see RJ is
just using you?
(GASPS)
Verne! Shame on you.
RJ wouldn't do that.
You have got to trust me on
this. Don't you understand
there's something
wrong with this guy?
My tail tingles
every time I get near him.
So we're supposed to go hungry
because your butt's vibrating?
I'm starting to think that little tingle
of yours is just you being jealous.
- Jealous? Of him?
- Yeah.
He's embracing
the future there,
and you're just
holding us back.
I hold you back, all right.
From extinction.
See what you've
done here?
If they listened to
half the stuff you're telling them,
they'll be dead
within a week.
You are only interested
in taking advantage of them
because they're too stupid
and naive to know any better.
I'm not stupid.
Okay, I didn't mean...
I meant ignorant.
To the ways over...
over there.
Come on, you guys.
You know I didn't mean it like that.
Don't... don't do this.
Stella? Ozzie?
Hammy? You know I didn't...
- Hammy...
- I'm not stupid.
Please.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(SINGING) I must
Give the impression
That I have the answers
For everything
You were
So disappointed
To see me unravel
So easily
It's only change
It's only every
Thing I know
It's only change
And I'm only changing
- Good night, Uncle RJ.
- Good night, kiddo.
La da, la da
La da da da da da
La da...
Moon's full, RJ.
See ya in the morning.
La da, la da
La da da da da da
La da
La da da da-da-da da
You want
Something that's constant
And I only wanted
to be me
But watch
Even the stars above
Things that seem still...
(SNIPPING)
MAN: This'll cut you down to size!
(LAUGHING)
La da, la da
I got ya!
(CHUCKLING)
(GASPS)
- Is it done?
- Affirmative.
Did you put this one in?
This Depelter Turbo?
That's a contraband item,
ma'am,
as it is illegal in every state,
except Texas.
I don't care if it's against
the Geneva Conventions.
I want it!
(CHUCKLING)
I thought you might.
So I took the liberty
of installing it for you.
(LASERS HUMMING)
Adios, animal infestation.
(BEEPING)
- Aah!
- (SLICING)
Oh, my.
(LAUGHS)
La da, la da
La da da da da da
La da, la da da da da da
(SIGHING)
What have I done?
- VERNE: Shouldn't have taken all that food.
- What?
I shouldn't have
taken all that food.
I was just trying to return things
to the way they were, that's all.
I was just being cautious.
'Cause that's what I am.
I'm naturally tentative.
There's even places
in my shell I haven't been.
You, on the other hand,
you're like... cool.
And crazy and fearless.
I think they're right.
I think I'm just jealous.
Verne, believe me,
you should not be
jealous of me.
You got a good thing here.
You're trying to do
what's best for your family.
And I think you're
what's best for them now.
What about your tail?
My head says
listen to my tail,
my tail says listen
to my head, and I just...
end up with an upset stomach.
That's why you need
to be in charge now.
- You don't know what's going on here.
- And you do.
- So, what's the problem?
- This, Verne, is the problem.
- You see this?
- I'm listening.
- (BEEPING)
- Just...
Uh-huh?
Just hang on a second.
All right?
MAN: I...
- You the lady throwing the party?
- Yes. Just to the right.
There are protective booties
for you to put on over your shoes.
Yes! Yes!
- What is this?
- What?
- Oh. That...
- Mmm-hmm?
...is a
list of all the stuff
that you lost, Verne.
- Really?
- It's a big, long list. You can see that.
You're an organized little guy,
aren't you? Nice job.
But, you know what?
I know a place so chock-full of food,
we could get it
all back in one night.
Great. Let's go.
Where is it?
- Inside that house.
- What?
Aah!
- What is the point of this thing?
- Just send it down.
RJ: What Verne is
trying to say is...
I mean, it's hard to really sum
it all up in just one word.
- But...
- I'm sorry.
HAMMY: Come here.
PENNY: Come here, Verne.
RJ: That's right.
VERNE: Watch the quills.
Okay! Listen, stay in the
huddle. Here's the plan.
Now, the traps are set
here, here, here,
here, here, here and here.
Here, here, here, here.
Big one here, here,
and maybe a few over here.
STELLA: Gee, is that all?
No. There's a bunch
of red lights all over here.
Okay, Verne?
Looking a little green.
I blacked out for a second
there, but I get the idea.
There's lights, traps...
I might need to change my shell.
RJ: Okay, this is us.
- Can I be the car?
- I wanna be the car!
- I'm the car. You be the shoe.
- The shoe is lame.
Why don't you be
that snazzy-looking iron there?
Hey, it's not important!
Besides, I'm the car.
I'm always the car.
The plan works
in three simple steps.
Step one, kill the lights.
Step two, get inside. Step three,
get out with mountain of food.
But this place is
like a fortress.
Walls, so high.
Doors, impenetrable.
- How will we get in?
- The collar is the key.
Literally, the collar.
It's like a key that opens
the door and if...
And what?
You think he's just
gonna hand over his collar to you?
Not to me, my femme fatale.
To you.
- Her?
- Me?
You, Stella,
will get that cat
to give you
his collar by using...
- My stink.
- Your feminine charms.
(CACKLES)
Was that out loud?
Look, raccoon, maybe that mask
you're wearing is obstructing your view,
but if you haven't noticed,
I'm a skunk.
On the outside, maybe.
But I'm looking inside,
Stella, and I see a fox.
And all we gotta do
is get her out.
(MONITOR BEEPING)
Scissors.
STELLA: Scissors? Whoa, hey!
- Here we go.
- Hey, hey, watch the...
Charcoal.
STELLA: Charcoal?
- Air freshener.
- Tomato juice.
VERNE: Cork.
STELLA: Cork? Don't you dare.
(RAPID BEEPING)
- Get 'em!
- Score! Yeah!
One more thing.
STELLA: Ow!
Whoa. Stop. That's it.
Ladies and gentlemen,
our work here is done.
Oh, my.
- Big jeepers.
- She's all like, wow.
What?
Oh.
Meow.
- Whoa!
- Amazing!
HEATHER:
Gosh, she looks...
Wow.
All right, gang, this is it.
We're going in.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(GRUNTING)
Not again. Dang it!
Those things are so lifelike.
Curse you, plastic moldsman.
(DOGS BARKING IN DISTANCE)
Okay, Hammy.
Whoa!
Hammy!
(LASER HUMMING)
Go, go, go, go, go,
go, go, go.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
(GRUNTING)
Hammy, I told you
that cookie's junk!
But I like a cookie.
What's going on?
Is everything okay?
Mmm-hmm.
Here we go!
Come on, Hammy, come on.
Follow the pretty light.
There it is, that's it.
That's it, that's it.
There it is. Go get it.
Go get it, you little nut!
(BEEPING)
Bingo! Okay, step two.
I thought we'd be dead by step
two, so this is going great!
RJ: Okay, gorgeous, you're on.
Man, this better be
one stupid cat.
Audio, go!
(MOOING)
She's supposed
to be a cat.
Put it on cat. Maybe the cat likes a cow.
Let's hope the cat likes a cow.
Who goes there?
You're a cat!
I mean, I'm a cat.
- Uh, meow.
- Yeah, right.
Shoo. Go on,
get away from here.
My owner does not give
scraps to common strays.
Common strays?
All right, you asked for it.
- Get the collar!
- Gee, that's a nice collar you got on.
- Mind if I have a look?
- No, no, no! Come no closer!
I must not be so near
a creature of the outdoor woods.
(SNEEZES)
- Away with your filth!
- My filth?
- Jeepers, here we go.
Okay, that's it. I am sick and tired of
everybody taking one look at me
and running away
'cause they think I'm filthy.
Well, I got news for you.
I didn't get all primped and preened to
have some over-fed, pompous puffball
tell me he's too good for me.
I got makeup on my butt, dude!
And you don't even
wanna know about the cork!
Stop! No one has ever
spoken to me like that!
(ALL GASPING)
It is bold. I like it.
Well, believe me, there's more
where that came from...
- Puffball.
- All right, team, let's boogie.
You are strong.
Your essence is overpowering.
- What? What do you mean by that?
- It is your eyes.
- My eyes.
- They are luminous.
Luminous? Dang.
You know, I think this is the part
where I blacked out.
Did the little shoes and cars
actually get into the house?
(BEEPING)
- So, you got a name?
- Yes.
It is a Persian name,
for I am Persian.
I was born Prince Tigeriess
Mahmood Shabaz.
Ooh, that's a mouthful.
Can I just call you Tiger?
Whoa.
PENNY: This place is huge.
SPIKE: Wicked cool.
Animals are in the house.
ALL: Wow!
LOU: My goodness.
PENNY: This is so cool.
- Yes! Okay, stations, everybody.
- Let's boogie!
- We got it.
- Here we go.
No grip, no grip, no grip.
(STRAINING)
- Hammy! Less claw, more pad.
- Oh, okay.
That hurt.
- Uh-oh.
- (LOUD RISING NOTE)
- Just a minute, I'll be right there.
- What was that?
It... That's just the sound of
my heart. Can't you hear it?
(IMITATING RISING NOTE)
Aaah!
This way, this way!
Okay, okay, we're good.
Go back to work.
There ya go.
Here, catch!
Oh, boy.
(GASPS)
Yes, I'm gonna make it.
My father, he had
an exceptionally flat face.
He was so beautiful,
he could barely breathe.
Fascinating.
Inside, I have a multi-leveled
climby-thing with shag carpet.
- Come, I show you.
- No, no!
I haven't told you
about my life.
Good, good. Going great,
going great.
- (BEEPING)
- (WATER BUBBLING)
What is that?
That is what gets the humans
out of bed in the morning.
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Where'd she go?
Get down and stay down.
(YAWNING)
Move. Move.
Come on! We've gotta go
before she comes back.
- No! Not without those Spuddies.
- What?
Lou, Penny,
back to the TV.
Heather, keep an eye
on that human.
- I'm on it, RJ.
- No, Heather. Wait!
The tingle, the tingle.
RJ! The wagon's full,
let's get out of here.
Hang on, Vincent,
this'll only take a second.
- Vincent?
- Where?
- Who's Vincent?
- Verne, Vincent.
Simple slip of the bear.
Tongue! I...
Just bear with me
is what I meant to say.
(CHUCKLING)
There's no bear.
(GLASS CLINKING)
- Mmm?
- Oh!
Lights fading.
Limbs growing co...
(OZZIE SCREAMS)
Heather.
(RETCHES)
Heather!
There's a dead, white rat
on my staircase.
I thought you were dead.
I learned
from the best, Dad.
That's my girl.
(GRUNTS)
Come to Papa.
We better hurry.
We don't have much time.
- What's going on, RJ?
- Nothing!
Well then, let's get out of here
because we have what we need.
- No, we don't.
- What are you talking about?
- We have more than enough.
- Hey, listen.
I've got this long
to hand over
that wagon of food
to a homicidal bear,
and if these Spuddies aren't on the menu,
then I will be. Now let go of my tail.
What?
Let go!
Aah!
Hey, whoa!
(RATTLING)
- Huh?
- (GASPS)
I'm sorry, I've gotta go.
Stella, Stella,
where are you going?
Stella!
Aaah!
Look, it's not you. It won't
work, okay, because I'm a...
Skunk!
Yeah, that. Sorry
you have to see this.
Fire in the hole!
(COUGHING)
Oh my...
STELLA: This smell doesn't bother you?
No. This face was
bred for beauty.
I cannot smell a thing.
You can't smell?
To the door!
Go, go, go, go, go, go!
Run!
STELLA: This way!
Let's party.
Bunnies!
Aah! (GRUNTS)
Flee, my love.
Run, that way. Outside!
Move, kids! Come on!
(ALL GRUNT)
Buenos dias, reptile.
You've just been verminated.
(LAUGHING)
(SNIFFING)
Whoa! You stink.
That's because
you let them into my house!
- Those...
- Hey, Nancy, stop your honkin'.
These little guys will be
disposed of quickly and humanely.
No! Not humanely.
As inhumanely as possible.
It was a pleasure doing business
with you, ma'am.
(WHEELS SQUEAKING)
- What's he gonna do to us, Mama?
- I don't know, baby.
I don't wanna die, Dad.
Not for real.
There, there, there,
sweetheart. We'll be okay.
You were right
about him, Verne.
We shoulda listened.
Sorry there.
No.
I knew we couldn't trust him,
and I got us into this.
I should've known better.
VINCENT: Wow!
Vincent?
So, I was on my way
down here to kill you.
But I stopped to watch the show,
and I gotta say...
That, right there,
is a thing of beauty.
That is the most vicious,
deceitful,
self-serving thing
I've ever seen.
(CHUCKLING)
Classic RJ.
You take the food,
and they take the fall.
You keep this up,
you're gonna end up just like me.
Having everything
you ever wanted.
But I already had that.
What, them?
Who are you kidding?
You said it yourself,
you're a family of one.
Always will be.
It's how guys like
you and me survive.
So, a few saps
got hurt in the process.
Tough. That's life.
Trust me, you don't need them.
Actually, I do.
And right now,
they really need me.
So, I really need this!
RJ!
- (GASPS)
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
What the...
There goes my back again.
LOU: Are you okay?
You sorry sack of rat dung.
Whoa, Stella, this is a rescue.
I'm rescuing you.
I'm gonna gas you so hard
your grandchildren'll stink.
- (MUFFLED) Bear!
- What's that?
- Bear!
- Hair?
- Dare?
- Bear!
What?
Whoa!
- We're out of control!
- We can drive.
- It's just like Auto-Homicide 3!
- What?
(GROWLING)
Verne, let me in!
Wrong button! Wrong button!
GPS: Please
select destination.
Take us home!
Take us to the log!
Previous destination selected.
Make a legal U-turn.
We got it!
- Hammy! Let me in!
- Not listening to RJ.
(HUMMING)
Kids, lose that bear!
What weapons do we have?
- We've got a hammer.
- Cool.
(GROANING)
You little...
(GROWLING)
Thank you. Yes, yes! Hey!
- Let me in, let me in!
- No! Ring-tailed charlatan!
Ozzie!
He's just trying to help us.
Just let him in.
- After what he did to us?
- But he came back.
- (VINCENT GROWLING)
- And he brought a bear.
(ALL ARGUING)
Hey! No fighting
while we're driving.
We will turn
this van around, mister.
He started it.
I'm telling you,
he's trying to help us, really.
But, Verne, you're the one
who always says trust your tail.
But it's not tingling.
ALL: Oh!
- Why didn't you say so?
- Hey!
Thank you, thank you.
(GROWLING)
You're dead, RJ!
VERNE: Duck!
And your friends are next.
HAMMY: Look out!
(GROWLING)
GPS: Make an immediate
left turn.
Whoa!
Bonus points!
- (SCREAMING)
- Huh?
(GRUNTING)
(SCRAPING)
ALL: Yeah!
Ohh!
RJ!
- STELLA: Yeah!
- Aah!
- Look out.
- High score.
VERNE: No, no, no, no!
(TRUCK HORN HONKING)
(SCREAMING)
GPS: You have arrived.
(OBJECTS RATTLING)
(GROANING)
STELLA: Everybody all right?
(ALL GASPING)
- Come on!
- We've gotta go, we've gotta go!
The old jazz dance injury.
- LOU: Come on, come on. Quillo!
- Go, go, go.
- Did we make it?
- That was close!
- All right!
- Are we here?
Penny? The kids here?
Hammy?
Scary clown.
ALL: Aah!
(GROWLING)
(AIR HISSING)
Look out!
(SCREAMING)
- (LAUGHING)
- (ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
A weed hacker, Verne.
A weed hacker!
Hey!
PENNY: Up, up, go up.
Show your little rat faces.
Filthy creatures.
Stay in the woods
where you belong!
HEATHER: Watch out!
- (CRACKLING)
- (LAUGHING)
(GROANING)
You guys wanna party, do ya?
All right, then, let's party.
(GROWLING)
SPIKE: Mom!
LOU: Kids!
RJ: Penny, Lou, look out!
Down!
That's it!
Verne, get everybody out of here.
I'll distract him.
- Are you crazy? He'll kill you.
- Well, I'm the one he wants.
Take care
of your family, Verne.
I intend to.
The whole family.
- There's got to be something we can do.
- There's no time.
- Hammy!
- HAMMY: Ahh.
- (GROWLING)
Hey, Vincent. You were right.
With a Spuddie,
enough just isn't enough.
RJ!
(GROWLING)
Now, Hammy. Go, go, go!
Okay...
(BABBLING)
(HUMMING)
(SNIFFING)
I got the cookie.
(CHUCKLES)
(GROWLING)
(RAPID BEEPING)
- Huh?
- Ohh.
- That's the...
- The Depelter Turbo.
Prepare for a lot of stinging.
DWAYNE: Oh, no!
No, no! No, no! No!
(GLADYS SCREAMING)
GLADYS: Ow! Ow! Ouch!
My hair!
DWAYNE: That stung
like I knew it would!
- (DEPELTER WINDING DOWN)
- (CAGE RATTLING)
(CHEERING)
- Yeah!
- All right!
Good job, everybody.
That's teamwork.
Come here, Hammy, come here.
You are a genius, my boy.
Thank you.
(BURPING)
And, Verne, don't you ever
fix this shell!
Yeah. Glad
it's working for ya.
Take it off, give it back.
(GROANING)
Here we go, off to the Rockies
for you, Smoky.
Now, you do realize
that was a Depelter Turbo?
Officer, please.
It was that Verminator.
He sold it to me. This has
nothing to do with me.
Hey, hey,
it was in your yard.
Your name's on the contract,
so can tell it to the judge.
- No! It's not my fault! Let go of me!
- Ma'am...
I can't be arrested! I'm the president
of the homeowner's association!
OFFICER: Take her down!
She's getting away!
- We got a twitcher! Watch it! Ma'am!
- Get her!
- Stop that!
- Can I get help over here?
- Somebody get a hold of her legs!
- (CHEW TOY SQUEAKING)
DOG: Play?
DWAYNE: Oh, no!
- No, no! No, no!
- (CRUNCHING)
Aah!
STELLA: High five, Hammy!
- Yes!
- It worked! It worked!
- We did it!
- All right!
Yes!
TIGER: Stella!
- Stella!
- Over here, Tiger.
Stella.
So, this is the outdoor woods?
I like it.
STELLA: Come on, big boy.
You're coming with me.
You know, RJ,
just for the record,
if you had told us that
all that food you were trying to get
was to pay back an angry bear,
we would've given it to you.
- Really?
- Yeah, that's what families do.
They look out
for each other.
I've never really
had anything like that.
I know.
But believe me, this...
This is the gateway
to the good life.
Really wish you would've
told me that sooner.
Yeah, well, that's bad communication.
Also something families do.
So, what do you say?
You wanna be a part of it?
Come here, come here. I promised
I wouldn't do this. Okay.
OZZIE:
Welcome to the family!
Hey!
HEATHER: Group hug!
Okay, okay.
VERNE: What a first week
of spring.
Wait a minute! That means
there's only 267 days left till winter.
What are we gonna do for food?
Oh! Oh, oh, oh, oh!
Oh, oh, oh!
Yes, Hammy.
I filled the log.
- PENNY: Jeepers!
- What...
Look, look! I found my nuts!
(FACE SQUEAKING ON GLASS)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
RJ: That, my friends, is the object
of all human attention and devotion.
And they call it a TV.
SPIKE: Wicked cool!
RJ: Humans feel an innerneed
to connect with the world around them.
LOU: That is super-duper.
RJ: They also feel a need
to sit on their fat butts.
Watching TV fulfills
both needs at the same time.
STELLA: Wow. Interesting.
PENNY: Come on, kids.
Family time there, in front of the TV.
Got your snack food?
HAMMY:
Buy a vowel. Buy a vowel!
Buy a "Y". Please buy a "Y".
OZZIE: I can't find the remote.
LOU: Hey, Spikey, race ya!
OZZIE: Has anybody seen the remote?
HEATHER: Dad, chill.
STELLA: I could
do a little TV.
I think, today's the day
we find out if the baby is gifted,
or if Saxon is
really an alien.
HAMMY:
Like Khan in Star Trek II!
The Genesis Project was
in the hands of the Enterprise,
but Khan had his plan to steal
the invention of renewable life!
VERNE:
Well, that was specific.
HAMMY: I saw it on TNT,
a retrospective.
HEATHER: Gummi Worm, anybody?
RJ: Let me have one.
STELLA:
Bucky, pass this to Lou.
LOU: Taste this.
SPIKE: Don't you take that.
VERNE: This is the perfect food.
RJ: Fat-free cookies?
You might as well just be
eating dirt.
HAMMY: I've had dirt.
I don't like dirt. It tastes like dirt.
HEATHER: Shh!
The show is starting.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(COINS SLIDING IN SLOT)
- (BANGING)
- (WHIRRING)
RJ: Hang on a minute.
HAMMY: I can't wait.
I can't wait. I can't wait.
(ALL CHEERING)
Yes! Here we go.
- Kind of anticlimactic.
- Shoot!