Once upon a time
in a kingdom far, far away,
the king and queen were blessed
with a beautiful baby girl.
And throughout the land,
everyone was happy...
until the sun went down
and they saw that their daughter was
cursed with a frightful enchantment
that took hold each and every night.
Desperate, they sought the help
of a fairy godmother
who had them lock the young princess
away in a tower,
there to await the kiss
of the handsome Prince Charming.
It was he who would chance
the perilous journey
through blistering cold
and scorching desert
traveling for many days and nights,
risking life and limb
to reach the Dragon's keep.
For he was the bravest,
and most handsome...
in all the land.
And it was destiny that his kiss
would break the dreaded curse.
He alone would climb to the highest room
of the tallest tower
to enter the princess's chambers,
cross the room to her sleeping silhouette,
pull back the gossamer curtains
to find her...
What?
- Princess Fiona?
- No!
Oh, thank heavens.
Where is she?
- She's on her honeymoon.
- Honeymoon? With whom?
So she said
what's the problem, baby?
What's the problem?
I don't know
Well, maybe I'm in love
Think about it
every time I think 'bout it
Can't stop thinking 'bout it
How much longer
will it take to cure this?
Just to cure it,
'cause I can't ignore it
If it's love, love
Makes me wanna turn around
and face me
But I don't know nothing
'bout love
Oh, come on, come on
Turn a little faster
Come on, come on
The world will follow after
Everybody's after love
So I said
I'm a snowball running
Running down into this spring
that's coming all this love
Melting under blue skies
belting out sunlight
Shimmering love
Well, baby, I surrender
To the strawberry ice cream
Never ever end of all this love
Well, I didn't mean to do it
But there's no escaping your love
These lines of lightning
mean we're never alone
Never alone, no, no
Come on, come on
Jump a little higher
If you feel a little lighter
Come on, come on
We were once upon a time in love
We're accidentally in love
Accidentally in love
Accidentally
I'm in love, I'm in love,
I'm in love, I'm in love
Accidentally in love
I'm in love
It's so good to be home!
Just you and me and...
- Two can be as bad as one...
- Donkey?
Shrek! Fiona! Aren't you two
a sight for sore eyes!
Give us a hug, Shrek,
you old love machine.
And look at you, Mrs. Shrek.
How 'bout a side of sugar for the steed?
Donkey, what are you doing here?
Taking care of your love nest for you.
Oh, you mean like sorting the mail
and watering the plants?
- Yeah, and feeding the fish!
- I don't have any fish.
You do now. I call that one Shrek
and the other Fiona.
That Shrek is a rascally devil.
Get your...
Look at the time.
I guess you'd better be going.
Don't you want to tell me about your trip?
Or how about a game of Parcheesi?
Actually, Donkey? Shouldn't you be
getting home to Dragon?
Oh, yeah, that.
I don't know.
She's been all moody and stuff lately.
I thought I'd move in with you.
You know we're always happy
to see you, Donkey.
But Fiona and I are married now.
We need a little time, you know,
to be together.
Just with each other.
Alone.
Say no more.
You don't have to worry about a thing.
I will always be here to make sure
nobody bothers you.
- Donkey!
- Yes, roomie?
You're bothering me.
Oh, OK. All right, cool. I guess...
Me and Pinocchio was going to catch
a tournament anyway, so...
Maybe I'll see y'all Sunday
for a barbecue or something.
He'll be fine.
Now, where were we?
I think I remember.
Donkey!
I know, I know! Alone!
I'm going! I'm going.
What do you want me
to tell these other guys?
Enough, Reggie.
Dearest Princess Fiona.
You are hereby summoned
to the Kingdom of Far, Far Away
for a royal ball
in celebration of your marriage
at which time the King
will bestow his royal blessing
upon you and your...
Prince Charming.
Love, the King and Queen
of Far, Far Away.
Aka Mom and Dad.
Mom and Dad?
- Prince Charming?
- Royal ball? Can I come?
- We're not going.
- What?
I mean, don't you think
they might be a bit...
shocked to see you like this?
Well, they might be
a bit surprised.
But they're my parents, Shrek.
They love me.
And don't worry.
They'll love you too.
Yeah, right.
Somehow I don't think I'll be welcome
at the country club.
Stop it.
They're not like that.
How do you explain Sergeant Pompous
and the Fancy Pants Club Band?
Oh, come on! You could at least
give them a chance.
To do what?
Sharpen their pitchforks?
No! They just want
to give you their blessing.
Oh, great.
Now I need their blessing?
If you want to be a part
of this family, yes!
Who says I want
to be part of this family?
You did!
When you married me!
Well, there's some fine print for you!
So that's it. You won't come?
Trust me. It's a bad idea.
We are not going! And that's final!
Come on!
We don't want to hit traffic!
Don't worry!
We'll take care of everything.
Hey, wait for me.
Hit it! Move 'em on! Head 'em up!
Head 'em up, move 'em on! Head 'em up!
Rawhide! Move 'em on!
Head 'em up!
Move 'em on! Move 'em on!
Head 'em up! Rawhide!
Ride 'em up! Move 'em on!
Head 'em up! Move 'em on! Rawhide!
Knock 'em out! Pound 'em dead!
Make 'em tea! Buy 'em drinks!
Meet their mamas!
Milk 'em hard!
Rawhide! Yee-haw!
- Are we there yet?
- No.
- Not yet.
- OK, are we there yet?
- No.
- Are we there yet?
- No!
- Yes.
- Really?
- No!
- Are we there yet?
- We are not!
- No!
Are we there yet?
That's not funny.
That's really immature.
This is why nobody likes ogres.
Your loss!
- I'm gonna just stop talking.
- Finally!
This is taking forever, Shrek.
There's no in-flight movie or nothing!
The Kingdom of Far, Far Away, Donkey.
That's where we're going.
Far, far...
away!
All right, all right, I get it.
I'm just so darn bored.
Well, find a way
to entertain yourself.
For five minutes...
Could you not be yourself
for five minutes.
Are we there yet?
- Yes!
- Oh, finally!
It's going to be champagne wishes
and caviar dreams from now on.
Hey, good-looking!
We'll be back to pick you up later!
Gotta make a move
to a town that's right for me
We are definitely not
in the swamp anymore.
Halt!
Well, I talk about it, talk about it,
talk about it, talk about it
Hey, everyone, look.
Talk about, talk about movin'...
Hey, ladies! Nice day for a parade, huh?
You working that hat.
Swimming pools!
Movie stars!
Announcing the long-awaited return
of the beautiful Princess Fiona
and her new husband.
Well, this is it.
- This is it.
This is it.
Why don't you guys go ahead?
I'll park the car.
So...
you still think
this was a good idea?
Of course! Look.
Mom and Dad look happy to see us.
- Who on earth are they?
- I think that's our little girl.
That's not little!
That's a really big problem.
Wasn't she supposed to kiss
Prince Charming and break the spell?
Well, he's no Prince Charming,
but they do look...
Happy now?
We came. We saw them.
Now let's go before
they light the torches.
- They're my parents.
- Hello? They locked you in a tower.
That was for my own...
Good! Here's our chance. Let's go
back inside and pretend we're not home.
Harold, we have to be...
Quick! While they're not looking
we can make a run for it.
Shrek, stop it!
Everything's gonna be...
A disaster! There is no way...
- You can do this.
- I really...
really... don't... want...
to... be...
Here!
Mom... Dad...
I'd like you to meet my husband...
Shrek.
Well...
It's easy to see where Fiona
gets her good looks from.
Excuse me.
Better out than in,
I always say, eh, Fiona?
That's good.
I guess not.
What do you mean, not on the list?
Don't tell me you don't know who I am.
What's happening, everybody?
Thanks for waiting.
- I had the hardest time finding this place.
- No! No! Bad donkey! Bad! Down!
No, Dad! It's all right.
It's all right. He's with us.
- He helped rescue me from the dragon.
- That's me, the noble steed.
Waiter!
How 'bout a bowl for the steed?
Oh, boy.
- Shrek?
- Yeah?
Oh, sorry!
Great soup, Mrs. Q.
No, no. Darling.
So, Fiona, tell us
about where you live.
Well...
Shrek owns his own land.
- Don't you, honey?
- Oh, yes!
It's in an enchanted forest
abundant in squirrels
and cute little duckies and...
What?
I know you ain't
talking about the swamp.
An ogre from a swamp.
Oh! How original.
I suppose that would be a fine place
to raise the children.
It's a bit early to be
thinking about that, isn't it?
- Indeed. I just started eating.
- Harold!
- What's that supposed to mean?
- Dad. It's great, OK?
- For his type, yes.
- My type?
I got to go to the bathroom.
- Dinner is served!
- Never mind. I can hold it.
Bon appetit!
Oh, Mexican food!
My favorite.
Let's not sit here with our tummies
rumbling. Everybody dig in.
Don't mind if I do, Lillian.
I suppose any grandchildren
I could expect from you would be...
Ogres, yes!
Not that there's anything wrong with that.
Right, Harold?
Oh, no! No! Of course, not!
That is, assuming you don't
eat your own young!
Dad!
No, we usually prefer the ones
who've been locked away in a tower!
- Shrek, please!
- I only did that because I love her.
Day care
or dragon-guarded castle.
You wouldn't understand.
You're not her father!
It's so nice to have the family
together for dinner.
- Harold!
- Shrek!
- Fiona!
- Mom!
- Harold...
Donkey!
Your fallen tears have called to me
So, here comes my sweet remedy
I know what every princess needs
For her to live life happily...
Oh, my dear.
Oh, look at you.
You're all grown up.
- Who are you?
- Oh, sweet pea!
I'm your fairy godmother.
- I have a fairy godmother?
- Shush, shush.
Now, don't worry.
I'm here to make it all better.
With just a...
Wave of my magic wand,
your troubles will soon be gone
With a flick of the wrist and just a flash,
you'll land a prince with a ton of cash
A high-priced dress
made by mice no less
Some crystal glass pumps
and no more stress
Your worries will vanish,
your soul will cleanse
Confide in your very own
furniture friends
We'll help you set
a new fashion trend
- I'll make you fancy, I'll make you great
- The kind of girl a prince would date!
They'll write your name
on the bathroom wall...
For a happy ever after,
give Fiona a call!
A sporty carriage to ride in style,
sexy man boy chauffeur, Kyle
Banish your blemishes, tooth decay,
cellulite thighs will fade away
And, oh, what the hey!
Have a bichon frisé!
Nip and tuck, here and there
to land that prince with the perfect hair
Lipstick liners, shadows blush,
to get that prince with the sexy tush
Lucky day, hunk buffet,
you and your prince take a roll in the hay
You can spoon on the moon
with the prince to the tune
Don't be drab, you'll be fab,
your prince will have rock-hard abs
Cheese soufflé, Valentine's Day,
have some chicken fricassee!
Nip and tuck, here and there,
to land that prince with the perfect hair
Stop!
Look...
Thank you very much,
Fairy Godmother,
but I really don't need all this.
- Fine. Be that way.
- We didn't like you anyway.
Fiona? Fiona?
Oh! You got a puppy?
All I got in my room was shampoo.
Fairy Godmother, furniture...
I'd like you to meet my husband, Shrek.
Your husband? What? What did you say?
When did this happen?
Shrek is the one who rescued me.
- But that can't be right.
- Oh, great, more relatives!
She's just trying to help.
Good! She can help us pack.
Get your coat, dear. We're leaving.
- What?
- I don't want to leave.
When did you decide this?
- Shortly after arriving.
- Look, I'm sorry...
No, that's all right.
I need to go anyway.
But remember, dear.
If you should ever need me...
happiness...
is just a teardrop away.
Thanks, but we've got all
the happiness we need.
Happy, happy, happy...
So I see.
Let's go, Kyle.
- Very nice, Shrek.
- What?
I told you coming here was a bad idea.
You could've at least tried
to get along with my father.
I don't think I was going to get
Daddy's blessing,
even if I did want it.
Do you think it might be nice
if somebody asked me what I wanted?
Sure. Do you want me
to pack for you?
You're unbelievable!
You're behaving like a...
- Go on! Say it!
- Like an ogre!
Here's a news flash for you!
Whether your parents like it or not,
I am an ogre!
And guess what, Princess?
That's not about to change.
I've made changes for you, Shrek.
Think about that.
That's real smooth, Shrek.
I'm an ogre!
I knew this would happen.
You should.
You started it.
I can hardly believe that, Lillian.
He's the ogre. Not me.
I think, Harold, you're taking this
a little too personally.
This is Fiona's choice.
But she was supposed to choose
the prince we picked for her.
I mean, you expect me to give
my blessings to this thing?
Fiona does.
And she'll never forgive you if you don't.
I don't want to lose
our daughter again, Harold.
Oh, you act as if love
is totally predictable.
Don't you remember when
we were young?
We used to walk
down by the lily pond and...
- they were in bloom...
- Our first kiss.
It's not the same!
I don't think you realize that
our daughter has married a monster!
Oh, stop being such a drama king.
Fine!
Pretend there's nothing wrong!
La, di, da, di, da!
Isn't it all wonderful!
I'd like to know
how it could get any worse!
Hello, Harold.
- What happened?
- Nothing, dear!
Just the old crusade wound
playing up a bit!
I'll just stretch it
out here for a while.
You better get in.
We need to talk.
Actually, Fairy Godmother,
off to bed.
Already taken my pills,
and they tend to make me a bit drowsy.
So, how about we make this
a quick visit. What?
Oh, hello.
So, what's new?
You remember my son,
Prince Charming?
Is that you? My gosh!
It's been years.
When did you get back?
Oh, about five minutes ago actually.
After I endured blistering winds,
scorching desert...
I climbed to the highest room
in the tallest tower...
Mommy can handle this.
He endures blistering winds
and scorching desert!
He climbs to the highest bloody room
of the tallest bloody tower...
And what does he find?
Some gender-confused wolf
telling him that his princess
is already married.
It wasn't my fault.
He didn't get there in time.
Stop the car!
Harold.
You force me to do something
I really don't want to do.
Where are we?
Hi. Welcome to Friar's Fat Boy!
May I take your order?
My diet is ruined!
I hope you're happy. Okay.
Two Renaissance Wraps,
no mayo, chili rings...
- I'll have the Medieval Meal.
- One Medieval Meal and, Harold...
- Curly fries?
- No, thank you.
- Sourdough soft taco then?
- No, really, I'm fine.
Your order, Fairy Godmother.
This comes with the Medieval Meal.
There you are, dear.
We made a deal, Harold, and I assume
you don't want me to go back on my part.
Indeed not.
So, Fiona and Charming
will be together.
- Yes.
- Believe me, Harold. It's what's best.
Not only for your daughter...
but for your Kingdom.
What am I supposed to do about it?
Use your imagination.
Come on in, Your Majesty.
I like my town
With a little drop of poison
Nobody knows...
Excuse me.
Do I know you?
No, you must be mistaking me
for someone else.
Excuse me.
I'm looking for the Ugly Stepsister.
Ah! There you are. Right.
You see, I need to have
someone taken care of.
- Who's the guy?
- Well, he's not a guy, per se.
He's an ogre.
Hey, buddy, let me clue you in.
There's only one fellow who can handle
a job like that, and, frankly...
he don't like to be disturbed.
Where could I find him?
Hello?
Who dares enter my room?
Sorry! I hope I'm not interrupting, but
I'm told you're the one to talk to
about an ogre problem?
You are told correct.
But for this, I charge
a great deal of money.
Would this be enough?
You have engaged my valuable
services, Your Majesty.
Just tell me where
I can find this ogre.
Everyone says
I'm getting down too low
you've just gotta let it go
You just gotta let it go
I need some sleep
Time to put the old horse down
I'm in too deep
And the wheels keep spinning round
Everyone says
you've just gotta let it go
Dear Knight, I pray that you take
this favor as a token of my gratitude.
Dear Diary...
Sleeping Beauty is having
a slumber party tomorrow,
but Dad says I can't go.
He never lets me out after sunset.
Dad says I'm going away for a while.
Must be like some finishing school.
Mom says that when I'm old enough,
my Prince Charming will rescue me
from my tower
and bring me back to my family,
and we'll all live
happily ever after.
Mrs. Fiona Charming.
Sorry. I hope I'm not
interrupting anything.
No, no. I was just reading
a scary book.
I was hoping you'd let me apologize
for my despicable behavior earlier.
- Okay...
- I don't know what came over me.
Do you suppose we could pretend
it never happened and start over...
- Look, Your Majesty, I just...
- Please. Call me Dad.
Dad. We both acted like ogres.
Maybe we just need some time
to get to know each other.
Excellent idea! I was actually hoping
you might join me for a morning hunt.
A little father-son time?
I know it would mean
the world to Fiona.
Shall we say,
7:30 by the old oak?
Face it, Donkey!
We're lost.
We can't be lost. We followed
the King's instructions exactly.
Head to the darkest part
of the woods...
Past the sinister trees
with scary-looking branches.
- The bush shaped like Shirley Bassey!
- We passed that three times already!
You were the one who said
not to stop for directions.
Oh, great. My one chance
to fix things up with Fiona's dad
and I end up lost
in the woods with you!
Don't get huffy!
I'm only trying to help.
I know! I know.
- I'm sorry, all right?
- Hey, don't worry about it.
I just really need to make
things work with this guy.
Yeah, sure. Now let's go
bond with Daddy.
Well, well, well, Donkey.
I know it was kind of a tender
moment back there, but the purring?
What? I ain't purring.
Sure. What's next? A hug?
Hey, Shrek. Donkeys don't purr.
What do you think I am, some kind of a...
Fear me, if you dare!
Look! A little cat.
- Look out, Shrek! He got a piece!
- It's a cat, Donkey.
Come here,
little kitty, kitty.
Come on, little kitty. Come here.
Come here, little kitty.
- Hold on, Shrek! I'm coming!
- Come on! Get it off! Get it off!
Oh, God. Oh...
No!
- Look out, Shrek! Hold still!
- Get it off!
Shrek! Hold still!
- Did I miss?
- No. You got them.
Now, ye ogre, pray for mercy from...
Puss in Boots!
I'll kill that cat!
- Hairball.
- That is nasty!
What should we do with him?
Take the sword and neuter him.
Give him the Bob Barker treatment.
Oh, no! Por favor!
Please!
I implore you!
It was nothing personal, Señor.
I was doing it only for my family.
My mother, she is sick.
And my father lives off the garbage!
The King offered me much in gold
and I have a litter of brothers...
Fiona's father paid you to do this?
The rich King? Si.
Well, so much for Dad's royal blessing.
Don't feel bad. Almost everybody
that meets you wants to kill you.
Gee, thanks.
Maybe Fiona would've been better off
if I were some sort of Prince Charming.
That's what the King said.
Oh, sorry. I thought that question
was directed at me.
Shrek, Fiona knows
you'd do anything for her.
Well, it's not like
I wouldn't change if I could.
I just... I just wish
I could make her happy.
Hold the phone...
Happiness.
A tear drop away.
Donkey! Think of the saddest thing
that's ever happened to you!
Aw, man, where do I begin?
First there was the time that old farmer
tried to sell me for some magic beans.
Then this fool had a party and he have
the guests trying to pin the tail on me.
Then they got drunk and start beating me
with a stick, going piñata!!
What is a piñata, anyway?
No, Donkey! I need you to cry!
Don't go projecting on me.
I know you're feeling bad,
but you got to...
You little, hairy,
litter-licking sack of...
What? Is it on? Is it on?
This is Fairy Godmother.
I'm either away
from my desk or with a client.
But if you come by the office, we'll be
glad to make you an appointment.
Have a happy ever after.
Are you up for a little quest, Donkey?
That's more like it! Shrek and Donkey,
on another whirlwind adventure!
Ain't no stoppin' us now!
We're on the move!
- Stop, Ogre! I have misjudged you.
- Join the club. We've got jackets.
On my honor, I am obliged to accompany
you until I have saved your life
as you have spared me mine.
The position of annoying talking animal
has already been taken.
Let's go, Shrek. Shrek?
- Shrek!
- Come on, Donkey. Look at him...
in his wee little boots.
You know, how many cats can wear boots?
Honestly.
- Let's keep him!
- Say what?
Listen. He's purring!
- Oh, so now it's cute.
- Come on, Donkey. Lighten up.
Lighten up? I should lighten up?
Look who's telling who to lighten up!
Shrek!
Shrek?
They're both festive, aren't they?
What do you think, Harold?
Yes, yes. Fine. Fine.
Try to at least pretend you're interested
in your daughter's wedding ball.
Honestly, Lillian,
I don't think it matters.
How do we know there will
even be a ball?
Mom. Dad.
- Oh, hello, dear.
- What's that, Cedric? Right! Coming.
Mom, have you seen Shrek?
I haven't.
You should ask your father.
Be sure and use small words, dear.
He's a little slow this morning.
- Can I help you, Your Majesty?
- Ah, yes!
Exquisite.
What do you call this dish?
That would be the dog's breakfast,
Your Majesty.
Ah, yes. Very good then.
Carry on, Cedric.
- Dad? Dad, have you seen Shrek?
- No, I haven't, dear.
I'm sure he just went off to look for
a nice mud hole to cool down in.
You know, after your
little spat last night.
You heard that, huh?
The whole kingdom heard you.
I mean, after all,
it is in his nature to be...
well, a bit of a brute.
Him? You know, you didn't exactly
roll out the Welcome Wagon.
Well, what did you expect?
Look at what he's done to you.
Shrek loves me for who I am.
I would think you'd be happy for me.
Darling, I'm just thinking about
what's best for you.
Maybe you should do the same.
No, really?
Oh, no. That's the old Keebler's place.
Let's back away slowly.
That's the Fairy Godmother's cottage.
She's the largest producer of hexes
and potions in the whole kingdom.
Then why don't we pop in there
for a spell? Spell!
He makes me laugh.
Hi. I'm here to see the...
The Fairy Godmother.
I'm sorry. She is not in.
Jerome!
Coffee and a Monte Cristo. Now!
Yes, Fairy Godmother.
Right away.
Look, she's not seeing
any clients today, OK?
That's OK, buddy.
We're from the union.
The union?
We represent the workers in all magical
industries, both evil and benign.
Oh! Oh, right.
Are you feeling at all
degraded or oppressed?
A little.
We don't even have dental.
They don't even have dental.
Okay, we'll just have
a look around.
Oh, by the way.
I think it'd be better if the Fairy Godmother
didn't know we were here.
Know what I'm saying? Huh?
- Stop it.
- Of course. Go right in.
A drop of desire.
Naughty!
A pinch of passion.
And just a hint of...
lust!
Excuse me.
Sorry to barge in like this...
What in Grimm's name
are you doing here?
Well, it seems
that Fiona's not exactly happy.
And there's some question
as to why that is?
Well, let's explore that, shall we?
P, P, P...
Princess. Cinderella.
Here we are.
Lived happily ever after...
No ogres!
Let's see. Snow White.
A handsome prince.
Oh, no ogres.
Sleeping Beauty.
Oh, no ogres!
Hansel and Gretel? No!
Thumbelina? No.
The Golden Bird,
the Little Mermaid, Pretty Woman...
No, no, no, no, no!
You see, ogres don't
live happily ever after.
All right, look, lady!
Don't you point
those dirty green sausages at me!
Your Monte Cristo and coffee.
Oh! Sorry.
Ah, that's okay.
We were just leaving.
Very sorry to have wasted your time,
Miss Godmother.
Just go.
Come on, guys.
TGIF, eh, buddy?
Working hard or hardly working,
eh, Mac?
Get your fine Corinthian footwear
and your cat cheeks out of my face!
Man, that stinks!
You don't exactly smell like
a basket of roses.
- Well, one of these has got to help.
- I was just concocting this very plan!
Already our minds are becoming one.
If we need an expert on licking
ourselves, we'll give you a call.
Shrek, this is a bad idea.
Look. Make yourself useful
and go keep watch.
Puss, do you think you
could get to those on top?
No problema, boss.
In one of my nine lives,
I was the great cat burglar
of Santiago de Compostela.
Shrek, are you off your nut?
Donkey, keep watch.
Keep watch?
Yeah, I'll keep watch.
I'll watch that wicked witch come and
whammy a world of hurt up your backside.
I'll laugh too.
I'll be giggling to myself.
- What do you see?
- Toad Stool Softener?
I'm sure a nice BM is the perfect solution
for marital problems.
Elfa Seltzer?
- Hex Lax?
- No! Try handsome.
Sorry. No handsome.
Hey! How about Happily Ever After?
Well, what does it do?
It says Beauty Divine.
In some cultures, donkeys are revered
as the wisest of creatures.
Especially us talking ones.
Donkey!
That'll have to do.
We've got company.
Can we get on with this?
Hurry!
Nice catch, Donkey!
Finally!
A good use for your mouth.
Come on!
You spurn my natural emotions
You make me feel like dirt
and I'm hurt
And if I start a commotion
I run the risk of losing you
and that's worse
Ever fallen in love with someone,
ever fallen in love
In love with someone,
In love with someone
you shouldn't have fallen in love with
Ever fallen in love with someone,
ever fallen in love
In love with someone,
With someone
you shouldn't have fallen in love with
Fallen in love with
Ever fallen in love with someone
you shouldn't have fallen in love with
I don't care whose fault it is.
Just get this place cleaned up!
And somebody bring me something
deep fried and smothered in chocolate!
- Mother!
- Charming. Sweetheart.
This isn't a good time, pumpkin.
Mama's working.
Whoa, what happened here?
- The ogre, that's what!
- What? Where is he, Mom?
I shall rend his head
from his shoulders!
I will smite him where he stands!
He will rue the very day he stole
my kingdom from me!
Oh, put it away, Junior!
You're still going to be king.
We'll just have to come up
with something smarter.
Pardon...
Everything is accounted for,
Fairy Godmother, except for one potion.
What?
I do believe we can make
this work to our advantage.
Happily Ever After Potion.
Maximum strength.
For you and your true love.
If one of you drinks this,
you both will be fine.
Happiness, comfort
and beauty divine.
- You both will be fine?
- I guess it means it'll affect Fiona too.
Hey, man, this don't feel right.
My donkey senses are tingling all over.
Drop that jug o' voodoo
and let's get out of here.
It says, Beauty Divine.
How bad can it be?
See, you're allergic to that stuff.
You'll have a reaction.
And if you think that I'll be smearing
Vapor Rub over your chest, think again!
Boss, just in case there is something
wrong with the potion...
allow me to take the first sip.
It would be an honor to lay my life
on the line for you.
Oh, no, no. I don't think so.
If there'll be any animal testing,
I'll do it.
That's the best friend's job.
Now give me that bottle.
How do you feel?
I don't feel any different.
I look any different?
You still look like an ass to me.
Maybe it doesn't work on donkeys.
- Well, here's to us, Fiona.
- Shrek?
- You drink that, there's no going back.
- I know.
- No more wallowing in the mud?
- No more itchy butt crack?
- I know!
- But you love being an ogre!
But I love Fiona more.
Shrek, no! Wait!
Got to be... I think you grabbed
the Farty Ever After potion.
Maybe it's a dud.
Or maybe Fiona and I
were never meant to be.
What did I tell you?
I feel something coming on.
I don't want to die.
I don't want to die. I don't want to die!
Oh, sweet sister, mother of mercy.
I'm melting!
It's just the rain, Donkey.
Don't worry. Things seem bad
because it's dark and rainy
and Fiona's father hired
a sleazy hitman to whack you.
It'll be better in the morning.
You'll see...
The sun'll come out...
Tomorrow
Bet your bottom...
Bet my bottom?
I'm coming, Elizabeth!
Donkey?
Are you all right?
- Hey, boss. Let's shave him.
- Donkey?
There you are!
We missed you at dinner.
What is it, darling?
Dad...
I've been thinking
about what you said.
And I'm going to set things right.
Ah! Excellent!
That's my girl.
It was a mistake to bring Shrek here.
I'm going to go out and find him.
And then we'll go back
to the swamp where we belong.
Fiona, please!
Let's not be rash, darling.
You can't go anywhere right now.
Fiona!
Look, I told you he was here.
Look at him! Quiet. Look at him.
Good morning, sleepyhead.
Good morning!
We love your kitty!
- Oh, my head...
- Here, I fetched a pail of water.
Thanks.
A cute button nose?
Thick, wavy locks?
Taut, round buttocks?
I'm... I'm...
- Gorgeous!
- I'll say.
I'm Jill. What's your name?
- Shrek.
- Shrek? Are you from Europe?
- You're tense.
- I want to rub his shoulders.
- I got it covered.
- I don't have anything to rub.
Get in line.
- Have you seen my donkey?
- Who are you calling donkey?
- Donkey? You're a...
- A stallion, baby!
I can whinny.
I can count.
Look at me, Shrek!
I'm trotting!
That's some quality potion.
What's in that stuff?
Oh, don't take the potion,
Mr. Boss, it's very bad.
Warning. Side effects may include
burning, itching, oozing, weeping.
Not intended for heart patients
or those with nervous disorders.
I'm trotting, I'm trotting in place!
Yeah!
What?
Señor? To make the effects
of this potion permanent,
the drinker must obtain his
true love's kiss by midnight.
Midnight?
Why is it always midnight?
- Pick me! I'll be your true love!
- I'll be your true love.
I'll be true enough.
Look, ladies,
I already have a true love.
And take it from me, Boss.
You are going to have
one satisfied Princess.
And let's face it.
You are a lot easier on the eyes.
Inside you're the same
old mean, salty...
- Easy.
- cantankerous, foul,
angry ogre you always been.
And you're still the same
annoying donkey.
Yeah.
Well...
Look out, Princess.
Here comes the new me.
First things first.
We need to get you out of those clothes.
- Ready?
- Ready!
Driver, stop!
Oh, God! Help me, please!
My racing days are over!
I'm blind! Tell the truth.
Will I ever play the violin again?
You poor creature!
Is there anything
I can do for you?
Well, I guess there is one thing.
Take off the powdered wig
and step away from your drawers.
- Not bad.
- Not bad at all.
Father?
Is everything all right, Father?
Thank you, gentlemen!
Someday, I will repay you.
Unless, of course,
I can't find you or if I forget.
Oh, yeah
Turn and face the strange
Changes
Don't wanna be a richer one
Turn and face the strange
Changes
Just gonna have to be
a different man
Time may change me
But I can't trace time
Halt!
Tell Princess Fiona her husband,
Sir Shrek, is here to see her.
Still don't know what
I was looking for
And my time was running wild,
a million dead-end streets
Every time I thought
I'd got it made
It seemed the taste
was not so sweet
Changes
Turn and face the strange
- Shrek?
- Changes
Don't wanna be a richer one
Time may change me
But I can't trace time
Fiona?
Hello, handsome.
Shrek!
- Princess!
- Donkey?
Wow! That potion
worked on you too?
What potion?
Shrek and I took some magic potion.
And well...
Now, we're sexy!
Shrek?
For you, baby, I could be.
- Yeah, you wish.
- Donkey, where is Shrek?
He went inside looking for you.
Shrek?
Fiona! Fiona!
You want to dance, pretty boy?
Are you going so soon?
Don't you want to see your wife?
Fiona?
Shrek?
Aye, Fiona. It is me.
What happened to your voice?
The potion changed
a lot of things, Fiona.
But not the way I feel about you.
Fiona?
- Charming?
- Do you think so?
Dad. I was so hoping
you'd approve.
- Who are you?
- Mom, it's me, Shrek.
I know you never get a second chance
at a first impression,
but, well, what do you think?
Fiona! Fiona!
Fiona!
- Fiona!
- Fiona, Fiona!
Oh, shoot! I don't think they
can hear us, pigeon.
Don't you think you've already
messed her life up enough?
I just wanted her to be happy.
And now she can be.
Oh, sweetheart.
She's finally found
the prince of her dreams.
But look at me.
Look what I've done for her.
It's time you stop living
in a fairy tale, Shrek.
She's a princess,
and you're an ogre.
That's something no amount
of potion will ever change.
But...
I love her.
If you really love her...
you'll let her go.
Shrek?
Señor.
What's going on?
Where are you going?
You wouldn't have had anything to do
with this, would you, Harold?
People just ain't no good
I think that's well understood
There you go, boys.
Just leave the bottle, Doris.
Hey. Why the long face?
It was all just a stupid mistake.
I never should have rescued her
from that tower in the first place.
I hate Mondays.
I can't believe you'd walk away from
the best thing that happened to you.
What choice do I have?
She loves that pretty boy,
Prince Charming.
Come on. Is he really
that good-looking?
Are you kidding?
He's gorgeous!
He has a face that looks like
it was carved by angels.
- Oh, he sounds dreamy.
- You know...
shockingly, this isn't
making me feel any better.
Look, guys.
It's for the best.
Mom and Dad approve,
and Fiona gets the man
she's always dreamed of.
Everybody wins.
Except for you.
I don't get it, Shrek.
You love Fiona.
And that's why
I have to let her go.
Excuse me, is she here?
She's in the back.
Oh, hello again.
Fairy Godmother. Charming.
You'd better have a good reason
for dragging us down here, Harold.
Well, I'm afraid Fiona isn't really
warming up to Prince Charming.
- FYI, not my fault.
- No, of course it's not, dear.
I mean,
how charming can I be
when I have to pretend
I'm that dreadful ogre?
No, no, it's nobody's fault.
Perhaps it's best if we just
call the whole thing off, okay?
- What?
- You can't force someone to fall in love!
I beg to differ.
I do it all the time!
Have Fiona drink this and she'll fall
in love with the first man she kisses,
which will be Charming.
- No.
- What did you say?
I can't. I won't do it.
Oh, yes, you will.
If you remember, I helped you
with your happily ever after.
And I can take it away
just as easily.
Is that what you want? Is it?
- No.
- Good boy.
Now, we have to go.
I need to do Charming's hair
before the ball.
He's hopeless.
He's all high in the front.
He can never get to the back.
You need someone to do the back.
Thank you, Mother.
Mother?
Mary! A talking horse!
The ogre!
Stop them! Thieves! Bandits!
Stop them!
The abs are fab
and it's gluteus to the maximus
here at tonight's Far, Far Away
Royal Ball blowout!
The coaches are lined up
as the cream of the crop pours out of them
like Miss Muffet's curds and whey.
Everyone who's anyone
has turned out
to honor Princess Fiona
and Prince Shrek.
And, oh my,
the outfits look gorgeous!
Look! Hansel and Gretel!
What the heck are the crumbs for?
And right behind them,
Tom Thumb and Thumbelina!
Oh, aren't they adorable!
Here comes Sleeping Beauty!
Tired old thing.
Who's this? Who's this?
Who is this?
It's the one, it's the only...
It's the Fairy Godmother!
Hello, Far, Far Away!
Can I get a whoop whoop?
May all your endings be happy
and...
Well, you know the rest!
We'll be right back with the Royal
Far, Far Away Ball
after these messages.
I hate these ball shows.
They bore me to tears.
Flip over to Wheel of Torture!
I'm not flipping anywhere, sir,
until I see Shrek and Fiona.
Whizzes on you guys.
Hey, mice, pass me a buffalo wing!
No, to your left. Your left!
- Tonight on Knights...
- Now here's a good show!
We got a white bronco heading east
into the forest. Requesting backup.
It's time to teach these madcap mammals
their devil may mare attitudes
just won't fly.
Why you grabbing me?
Police brutality!
I have to talk to Princess Fiona!
We warned you!
Did someone let the cat
out of the bag?
You capitalist pig dogs!
- Catnip!
- That's not mine.
Find Princess Fiona!
I'm a donkey!
Tell her Shrek...
I'm her husband, Shrek!
Quick! Rewind it!
Darling?
I thought I might
find you here.
How about a nice hot cup
of tea before the ball?
I'm not going.
The whole Kingdom's turned out
to celebrate your marriage.
There's just one problem.
That's not my husband.
I mean, look at him.
Yes, he is a bit different,
but people change
for the ones they love.
You'd be surprised how much
I changed for your mother.
Change?
He's completely lost his mind!
Why not come down to the ball
and give him another chance?
You might find you like
this new Shrek.
But it's the old one
I fell in love with, Dad.
I'd give anything to have him back.
Darling. That's mine. Decaf.
Otherwise I'm up all night.
Thanks.
I got to get out of here!
You can't lock us up like this!
Let me go!
What about my Miranda rights?
You're supposed to say
I have the right to remain silent.
Nobody said I have the right
to remain silent!
You have the right to remain silent.
What you lack is the capacity.
I must hold on before I, too,
go totally mad.
Shrek? Donkey?
Too late.
Gingy! Pinocchio!
Get us out of here!
Fire in ze hole!
Look out below!
Quick! Tell a lie!
- What should I say?
- Anything, but quick!
Say something crazy like
I'm wearing ladies' underwear!
I am wearing ladies' underwear.
- Are you?
- I most certainly am not!
It looks like you
most certainly am are!
- I am not!
- What kind?
- It's a thong!
- They're briefs!
- Are not.
- Are too!
- Are not!
Here we go. Hang tight.
Wait, wait, wait!
Hey, hey, hey!
- Excuse me?
- What? Puss!
Pardon me, would you
mind letting me go?
- Sorry, boss.
- Quit messing around!
We've got to stop that kiss!
I thought you was going
to let her go.
I was, but I can't let them
do this to Fiona.
Boom! That's what I like to hear.
Look who's coming around!
It's impossible!
We'll never get in.
The castle's guarded.
There's a moat and everything!
Folks, it looks like we're up chocolate
creek without a Popsicle stick.
- What?
- Do you still know the Muffin Man?
Well, sure!
He's down on Drury Lane. Why?
Because we're gonna need flour.
Lots and lots of flour.
Gingy!
Fire up the ovens, Muffin Man!
We've got a big order to fill!
It's alive!
Run, run, run,
as fast you can!
Go, baby, go!
There it is, Mongo!
To the castle!
No, you great stupid pastry!
Come on!
Mongo! Down here!
Look at the pony!
That's right!
Follow the pretty pony!
Pretty pony wants to play
at the castle!
Pretty pony.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Presenting Princess Fiona
and her new husband, Prince Shrek.
Shrek, what are you doing?
I'm just playing the part, Fiona.
Is that glitter on your lips?
Cherry flavored.
Want to taste?
- What is with you?
- But, Muffin Cake...
C Minor, put it in C Minor.
Ladies and gentlemen.
I'd like to dedicate this song to...
Princess Fiona and Prince Shrek.
Fiona, my Princess.
Will you honor me with a dance?
Where have all the good men gone
And where are all the gods?
Dance!
Where's the streetwise Hercules
To fight the rising odds?
Since when do you dance?
Fiona, my dearest,
if there's one thing I know,
it's that love is full of surprises.
Late at night I toss and I turn
And I dream of what I need
Hit it!
I need a hero
All right, big fella!
Let's crash this party!
Man the catapults!
Aim! Fire!
- Brace yourselves!
- Ooh! Purty!
Not the gumdrop button!
Incoming!
All right!
Somewhere after midnight
in my wildest fantasy
Go, Mongo! Go!
Man the cauldrons!
After you, Mongo.
- That's it! Heave-ho!
- Watch out!
Shrek!
More heat, less foam!
Up where the mountains
meet the heavens above
Out where the lightning
splits the sea
I could swear there is someone
somewhere watching me
Heave! Ho!
No...!
Come on!
Look out!
Be good.
He needs me!
Let me go!
Donkey!
Puss!
Go! Go! Your lady needs you! Go!
Today, I repay my debt.
On guard!
He's gotta be strong
and he's gotta be fast
And he's gotta be fresh
from the fight
- I need a hero
- Stop!
- Hey, you! Back away from my wife.
- Shrek?
You couldn't just go back to your swamp
and leave well enough alone.
- Now!
- Pigs und blanket!
Pinocchio! Get the wand!
I see London! I see France!
I'm a real boy!
Catch!
Donkey!
I'm a real boy.
That's mine!
Pray for mercy, from Puss...
And Donkey!
She's taken the potion!
Kiss her now!
No!
- Fiona.
- Shrek.
Harold! You were supposed
to give her the potion!
Well, I guess I gave her
the wrong tea.
- Mommy!
- Mommy?
I told you.
Ogres don't live happily ever after.
Oh, Dad!
- Is he...?
- Yup.
He croaked.
Harold?
Dad?
I'd hoped you'd never
see me like this.
- And he gave you a hard time!
- Donkey!
No, no, he's right.
I'm sorry.
To both of you.
I only wanted what
was best for Fiona.
But I can see now...
she already has it.
Shrek, Fiona...
Will you accept
an old frog's apologies...
and my blessing?
Harold?
I'm sorry, Lillian.
I just wish I could be
the man you deserve.
You're more that man today
than you ever were...
warts and all.
Boss! The Happily Ever After Potion!
Midnight!
Fiona. Is this what you want?
To be this way forever?
- What?
- Because if you kiss me now...
we can stay like this.
You'd do that?
- For me?
- Yes.
I want what any princess wants.
To live happily ever after...
with the ogre I married.
Whatever happens,
I must not cry!
You cannot make me cry!
No. No, no.
Oh, no.
Hey. You still look like
a noble steed to me.
Now, where were we?
Oh, I remember.
Hey! Isn't we supposed
to be having a fiesta?
Uno, dos, quatro, hit it!
Puss and Donkey, y'all...
She's into superstitions
Black cats and voodoo dolls
- Sing it, Puss!
- I feel a premonition
That girl's gonna make me fall
Here we go!
She's into new sensations
New kicks in the candlelight
She's got a new addiction
For every day and night
She'll make you take your clothes off
And go dancing in the rain
She'll make you live her crazy life
But she'll take away your pain
Like a bullet to your brain
Upside inside out
Living la vida loca
Hey gorgeous!
Her lips are devil red
And her skin's the color of mocha
She will wear you out
- Living la vida loca
- She livin' it loca!
Living la vida loca
- Say it one more time now!
- Living the vida loca
Hey, Donkey, that's Spanish!
She'll push and pull you down
Living la vida loca
She will wear you out
She'll push and pull you down
Living the vida loca
Her lips are devil red
And her skin's the color of mocha
She will wear you out
Living la vida loca
All by myself
Don't wanna be
All by myself anymore...
Amigo, we are off
to the Kit-Kat Club.
Come on, join us.
Thanks, compadre.
I'm... I'm not in the mood.
We will cheer you up!
Find you a nice burro!
Hey, baby!
Hey, that's my girl!
Yeah! All right!
Baby, where you been?
I'm sorry too.
I should've stayed.
But Shrek had this thing he had to do.
What? Say it one more time.
What you talking about?
Are you serious?
Papa!
Look at our little mutant babies!
I got to get a job.