(McQUEEN EXHALES)
McQUEEN: Okay, here we go.
Focus. Speed. I am speed.
(ENGINES ROARING)
One winner, 42 losers.
I eat losers for breakfast.
Did I used to say that?
- MATER: Yes, sir, you did.
- (McQUEEN GASPS)
- You used to say that all the time.
- Mater, what are you doing in here?
Well, I didn't want you to be lonely.
(STUTTERS) Thank you.
But I'm kind of preparing for a race.
I need a little quiet.
Oh, right. You got it, buddy.
Hey, everybody, listen up.
My best friend, Lightning McQueen,
needs quiet. (SHOUTING) Perfect quiet!
(CHUCKLES)
Okay. Where was I?
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
Racing. Real racing.
(SCOFFS)
That ain't racing.
That wasn't even a Sunday drive.
That was one lap.
Racing is 500 of those.
Everybody fighting to move up.
Lap after lap. Inside, outside,
inches apart. Never touching.
Now that's racing.
(CHUCKLES) Well, I can't argue
with The Doc Hudson.
(CHUCKLES) How true, how true.
(LAUGHS)
(BANGS ON DOOR)
(CHUCKLES)
MACK: Hey, Lightning, you ready?
Oh, yeah. Lightning's ready.
(ENGINE REVVING)
This one's for you, Doc.
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
Whoo-hoo! Come on, Stickers.
Pardon me. Excuse me.
Best friend coming through.
Go, McQueen! Whoo-hoo!
- CAR: Pass him now, 24!
- Lightning McQueen!
(CROWD CHEERING)
Go, 95! (HORN HONKS)
Whoo-hoo!
Hey, Cal, your blinker's on.
What? No, it's not.
Hey! Your blinker's on.
Good comeback, Cal.
♪ Because I want to run that race
♪ I want to run that race
♪ I do it at my pace
♪ Long as I get to run that race ♪
CUTLASS: Into the pit goes
Lightning McQueen,
Bobby Swift and Cal Weathers.
These three are fun to watch,
aren't they, Darrell?
You know, Bob, I can't tell
if they have more fun on or off the track.
(WHIRRING)
Finito! (SPEAKS ITALIAN) Mmm.
You getting a car wash too, Cal?
No, you're getting a car wash, McQueen.
Good comeback, Cal.
♪ We gotta run that race
♪ We do it at our pace
♪ Long as we get to run that race
Hey, hey, hey, hey ♪
Lightning, how do you keep your focus
racing against Bobby and Cal?
I think the key is we respect each other.
These guys are real class acts...
(LAUGHTER)
BOBBY: Congratulations, cupcake.
Oh, they are gonna pay.
- (CHEERING)
- CAR: Go, Dinoco!
Great win today, Cal.
Thank you, Shannon.
It was a great boost and I was...
- Hey! Hey! Guido!
- (LAUGHTER)
Pit stop.
Ha, ha. Laugh it up. Real funny.
- (ALL LAUGHING)
- (TIRE HISSING)
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
Keep it going, buddy!
McQUEEN: Whoo!
(CHUCKLES) Hey!
Are my sponsors happy today?
Stop winning
for crying out loud.
We're running out
of bumper cream to sell.
- (ALL LAUGHING)
- Lightning McQueen!
Hey, Big Tex.
How's my favorite competitor?
Just say the word and...
I'll boot Cal off the Dinoco team
and replace him with you.
You know I can hear you, right?
I'm right here.
Bye, Cal. See you next week. Or not.
Oh, come on now. I'm joking.
Go, little buddy! Whoo-hoo!
And big buddy too!
(ENGINES ROARING)
CUTLASS: Another great finish
in the making.
McQueen and Swift nose to nose.
How's the view back there, Bobby?
(SCOFFS) Well, you better not blink.
I'll blow right past you.
CUTLASS: The flag is out.
It's the final stretch.
McQueen in the lead.
- Okay, let's see what you got.
- Whoo-whee!
(CAR ACCELERATING)
DARRELL: Holy cow!
CUTLASS: Whoa!
It's Jackson Storm for the win.
A huge upset!
DARRELL: Neither Lightning nor
Bobby ever saw him coming.
ANNOUNCER ON PA:
It's one thing to start fast,
but we haven't seen
anyone cross the line...
with that kind of speed
and power since a young...
Lightning McQueen
first arrived on the scene.
- McQUEEN: Hey, Bobby? Who is that?
- That's, um, Jackson Storm.
Yeah. He's one of the rookies.
(CAMERAS SNAPPING)
Huh.
- (REPORTERS CLAMORING)
- Thank you, guys. Thank you.
No, I appreciate it.
Thank you very much.
Hey. Jackson Storm, right?
Great race today.
Wow! Thank you, Mr. McQueen.
You have no idea what a pleasure it is
for me to finally beat you.
Oh, thanks. Wait. (CHUCKLES)
Hang on. Did you say "meet" or "beat"?
- I think you heard me.
- Uh, what?
REPORTER: Storm,
can we get some pictures?
Yeah, yeah. Come on.
Let's get a picture. You know what?
Get a ton of pictures
because champ here
has been a role model of mine...
for years now.
And I mean a lot of years.
Right? I love this guy.
REPORTER: Storm, give us a quote.
What's your top speed?
I think I touched a nerve.
(TECHNO MUSIC PLAYING)
Welcome back to Chick's Picks
with Chick Hicks.
I'm your host, former and forever,
Piston Cup champion, Chick Hicks.
Doo-doo-doo-doo. This just in...
Rookie Jackson Storm
slams the proverbial door
on Lightning McQueen.
(LAUGHS) Oh.
I couldn't have enjoyed it more
if I'd beaten McQueen myself.
Oh, wait, I have. (CHUCKLES)
But enough about me.
Here to tell you how it happened
is professional number cruncher,
Miss Natalie Certain.
It's a pleasure to be here, Chick.
And actually,
I prefer the term "Statistical Analyst".
Right. So, who is this
mysterious newcomer, Jackson Storm?
And why is he so darn fast?
It's no mystery if you study
the data, Mr. Hicks.
Jackson Storm is part
of the next generation
of high-tech racers.
Unlike the veterans of yesterday...
(STAMMERS) What?
Old-timers like this guy? (LAUGHS)
Um... Right. Storm achieves his top speeds
by exploiting the numbers.
I refer, of course, to racing data.
Tire pressure, downforce,
weight distribution, aerodynamics, and...
next-gens like Storm
are taking advantage.
The racing world is changing.
And for the better if it means my old pal,
Lightning, is down for the count.
Am I right, Certain?
Well, if I'm certain of anything, Chick...
it's that this season is about
to get even more interesting.
CUTLASS: I'll tell you what, Darrell,
Jackson Storm has
certainly made an impact.
We've got six more
next-generation rookies in the field.
DARRELL: With six veterans
fired to clear the way.
Morning, champ.
How's our living legend today?
Uh... Still very much alive, thank you.
- And I would appreciate...
- You know, I can't believe I get to race
- the Lightning McQueen.
- (SIGHS)
In his farewell season.
What are you talking about?
JACKSON STORM: Oh, green flag.
Good luck out there, champ.
You're gonna need it.
(ENGINE REVVING)
NATALIE CERTAIN: One reason Storm
and the next-gens are more efficient:
Their ability to hold
the optimum racing line
every single lap.
CUTLASS: Win number three
for the rookie sensation.
NATALIE CERTAIN:
Storm's in a class of his own.
And a big reason for that: Training on
the newest cutting-edge simulators.
These machines create a...
virtual racing experience so real
racers never even have to go outside.
CUTLASS: Storm's ability
to hold that line
is like nothing we've ever seen.
DARRELL: Four in a row?
Are you kidding me?
NATALIE CERTAIN:
2% lower drag coefficient.
CUTLASS: Oh, what a finish!
NATALIE CERTAIN:
5% increase downforce.
- DARRELL: Lucky number seven.
- 1 .2% higher top speed.
CUTLASS: Amazing! Nine!
Piston Cup winner, Chick Hicks here
with the racer taking the circuit...
by storm. Jackson Storm.
Another easy win over old "Ka-chow".
Or should I say, "Caboose"?
Because he's always in the back.
Am I right?
No, no, no, Chick.
McQueen is a crafty veteran champ.
He's the elder statesman of the sport.
You know?
Takes everything I got to beat him.
(SIGHS) You got to be kidding me.
(REPORTERS CLAMORING)
REPORTER 1: What changes
are you gonna make
to get McQueen back on top?
REPORTER 2: Will McQueen try
new training methods?
REPORTER 3: Is he prepared to retire?
Come on, guys. Let's not overreact.
It's just a slump.
We'll get 'em next week.
Okay, that's enough. No comment.
Not even about Weathers retiring?
Wait. What?
Cal Weathers.
He's hanging up his Lightyears.
No. No comment on that either.
REPORTER 3: Wait a minute.
Please, come on.
You got to give us something.
Hey, Cal! Hey.
Retirement? What's going on?
(SIGHS)
You know, I asked my uncle once
how I'd know when it was time to stop.
You know what he said?
The youngsters will tell you.
We had some good times together.
I'm gonna miss that the most I think.
Yeah.
NATALIE CERTAIN:
More changes ahead, Chick.
Every week we've seen
veteran racers either retire...
like Cal Weathers tonight,
or fired to make room
for these younger...
faster racers.
And, it's not over yet.
ANNOUNCER: Hello racing fans.
Welcome to the Los Angeles 500.
The final race of the Piston Cup season.
It's been a year of surprises...
BRICK: They can't do this.
I've raced for you guys almost 10 years.
Sorry, Brick. My mind's made up.
I'm giving your number to someone new.
Hey, I had two wins last year!
SPONSOR: The whole sport's changing.
I'm just doing what I got to do.
Hey, do you know what's
happening with Brick... Oh!
Wait, you're not Bobby.
(ENGINE REVS)
The name's Danny, bro.
Hey, champ,
where'd all your friends go?
CUTLASS: A final check of his tires
as Storm settles into the pole position.
DARRELL: Boogity, boogity, boogity.
Let's end this season with a great race.
(ENGINES REVVING)
That's it, buddy!
NATALIE CERTAIN: Forty laps to go
and race leader, Jackson Storm...
is making his way onto pit road
with McQueen on his tail.
A good stop here could mean the
difference between victory and defeat.
Come on, come on. Come on!
Faster, Guido, come on.
I got to get back out there
before he does.
- Guido, hurry up!
- (WHIRRING)
- (GUIDO SPEAKING ITALIAN)
- (TIRES SQUEALING)
DARRELL: What a pit stop
by McQueen!
Man, he just got the lead!
CUTLASS: But can he hold on to it?
- (PANTING)
- Hey, McQueen, are you all right?
Listen, don't you worry, pal.
You had a good run.
Enjoy your retirement!
CUTLASS: Storm takes back the lead!
DARRELL: Unbelievable!
McQueen is fading!
McQueen is fading! Fading fast!
No. No! No! No!
No!
(McQUEEN PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(GASPS)
(CLATTERING)
(CROWD GASPING)
(SIRENS WAILING)
MAN ON RADIO:
(SING-SONG) W-H-I-Z
RADIO HOST: Welcome back
to Piston Cup Talk.
Around the clock where we do nothing
but talk racing. Let's get to it.
Starting of course
- with Lightning McQueen.
- (SNORING)
With the season just two weeks away,
there's still no official announcement.
But with number 95 coming off
his worst year on record...
Don't shoot the messenger here, folks.
I think it's safe to assume...
that Lightning McQueen's
racing days are over.
Meanwhile, Jackson Storm
is looking even faster...
(TURNS OFF RADIO)
(SIGHS HEAVILY)
(WHIRRING)
COMMENTATOR:
For the checkered flag.
As they enter the final lap,
the number 6 and number 12 cars...
are still fighting it out for the lead.
But wait! Here he comes!
It's the Fabulous Hudson Hornet
knocking at their door.
What's he got up his sleeve today?
And there it is!
With one move, he's past them.
The Hornet takes a decisive lead.
He's left the pack behind.
His crew chief, Smokey, is loving it!
It's unbelievable!
Oh, no! He's in trouble!
- The Hudson Hornet has lost control!
- (HUDSON CRASHING)
(CARS GASPING)
What should have been
a scene of jubilation
- has turned tragic, folks.
- (SIRENS WAILING)
As we await news
on the Hudson Hornet's condition.
After such a devastating crash...
we can only hope that
this race today wasn't his last.
(PROJECTOR CLICKS)
HUDSON: When I finally
got put together,
I went back expecting a big welcome.
You know what they said?
You're history.
Moved right on to the next rookie
standing in line.
There was a lot left in me
I never got a chance to show.
(DOOR CREAKING)
Hey, Stickers.
Hey, Sal.
How you feeling?
Yeah, great. (SIGHS)
Really, really great.
Been thinking about Doc again?
(SIGHS)
Yeah. You know they told him
when he was done.
He didn't decide.
I don't want what happened to Doc
to happen to me.
But that hasn't happened.
No, but I can't go out on the track
and do the same old thing. It won't work.
Then change it up! Try something new.
- I don't know, Sally. I...
- Don't fear failure.
Be afraid of not having the chance.
You have the chance. Doc didn't.
And you can either take it or you can
do what you been doing. Sitting.
In here. For months.
And by the way,
I love what you've done with the place.
I mean the monster movie lighting
and the musky air freshener.
Don't let anyone tell you
you're not working that primer because...
Wow, I have never found you
more attractive.
And now that I've been in here
for a couple minutes, the stench...
- I'm getting kind of used to it.
- Okay, Sal. I get it. I get it.
I miss you, Lightning.
We all do.
(SIGHS)
Try something new, huh?
Hey, did it work, Miss Sally?
Did you set him straight
with your lawyerly powers
of persuasion?
Is he ready to start training?
Well, Stinky... Stickers?
(CHUCKLES)
Yes, Mater, I am.
Whoo-hoo!
I decide when I'm done.
I was hoping you'd say that.
Okay, but I got an idea.
And I'm gonna need to talk
to Rusty and Dusty, all right?
Oh, I'll get them on the horn.
(CHUCKLES) Get it? On the horn?
(HONKS AND LAUGHS)
Oops. Hold on. Got to sneeze.
(GASPING)
Dadgum, I lost it.
Hey, I'll see you at Flo's.
(SNEEZES LOUDLY)
I found it.
Hey, watch your step.
RUSTY ON SPEAKERS:
What about the car from Everett?
Remember him?
He was stuck in reverse!
I said, you need a house
with a circular driveway!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
You need to get your
rusty tails down here.
I created a drink in your honor.
Yeah! The Rust-eze Medicated
Bumper Bomb.
It goes down faster
than an elevator full of Winnebagos.
- McQUEEN: Rusty and Dusty!
- Well, look who's here.
Hey, there he is!
Good to see you, Lightning!
Thanks, guys. Wow. You're all here.
Sorry, buddy,
did you want this call to be private?
No, Mater. This is perfect. Listen,
thanks, everyone, for sticking by me.
It took me a while to figure it out,
but I know now that it's time...
for me to make some changes.
Changes? What kind of changes?
It's futile to resist change, man.
- You're right, Fillmore.
- Really?
Which is why I have
an announcement to make.
I've thought long and hard about it.
Done a lot of soul-searching
and considered all of the options.
And I've finally decided...
You do want to keep racing?
Are you kidding?
Of course I want to keep racing!
- Thank goodness!
- Glad to hear it. All right.
(SIGHS) Man, for a second I...
Wait a minute.
I knew that the whole time.
Guys! I'm talking about making
this my best season yet!
We were hoping you'd say that.
The thing is, if I'm gonna be
faster than Storm,
I need to train like him.
BOTH: We're way ahead of you, buddy!
Lightning, we want you on the road
first thing in the morning...
so you can come out
and see the brand-new...
BOTH: Rust-eze Racing Center!
- It's wicked awesome.
- What? Rust-eze Racing Center?
It's got all the fancy bells and whistles
that kids are training on these days.
We'll send Macky boy all the directions.
Now get moving, all right?
Okay! Yes!
- Fancy new training center?
- That sounds nice!
Guido, come! We have to pack the tires!
Hey, McQueen!
You can't race in primer, man.
Come on! Let's go.
(WHIRRING)
(CHUCKLES) Ramone,
you have done it again.
It's like the Sistine Chapel on wheels.
- (ENGINE REVVING)
- I'm coming for you, Storm.
SARGE: Morning, McQueen!
Hey, look at you.
CAR 1: Oh!
CAR 2: He looks so good!
Welcome back. You look different.
- (CHUCKLES) Obviously.
- You look ready.
Guido, come! Scusi, scusi.
Tires coming through.
Go kick those rookies in the trunk.
- (SALLY CHUCKLES)
- All right, bye.
- Catch you on the flipside.
- I'll see you guys in Florida.
- See you, McQueen.
- Don't forget to call me.
- LIZZIE: Good luck in college.
- (CHUCKLES)
Hey, Sal. Thanks.
Anytime.
- Love you!
- Love you more.
Rust-eze Racing Center, here we come!
- Good times ahead.
- (HORN BLOWING)
(SOBBING)
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
♪ When the time gets right
♪ I'm gonna pick you up
♪ And take you far away from
♪ From trouble, my love
♪ Under a big old sky
♪ Out in a field of green
♪ There's got to be something
♪ Left for us to believe
♪ Oh, I await the day
♪ Good fortune comes our way
♪ And we'll ride down
the King's Highway
♪ Yeah, yeah
Yeah ♪
(REPORTERS CLAMORING)
REPORTER 1: McQueen, over here!
REPORTER 2:
McQueen, how you feeling?
Have you seen the latest
records Storm's been setting?
Have you given any thought
to retirement?
Okay, that's enough. No questions!
Scusi. Out of the way!
Coming through! Okay, back up.
Back up! No pictures. No, no, no.
(CAMERAS CLICKING)
Okay, thank you. Bye-bye.
(SIGHS) Guido, can you believe them?
Paparazzi. (SPITS)
(CHUCKLES EXCITEDLY)
Wow!
DUSTY: Looks good, doesn't it?
- Hey, guys.
- What do you think?
What do I think? It's unbelievable.
DUSTY: Yeah, you know,
it's kind of a cozy,
humble, little place.
Guys, how did you ever do this?
- You want to tell him or should I?
- No, you start. Go ahead.
(CLEARS THROAT)
We sold Rust-eze. Huh?
What?
What? You think a couple of jabronis
like us could do this on our own?
- Wait. You sold Rust-eze?
- It's all good news.
We just realized that you needed
something that we couldn't give you.
It felt like the time
was right for us too.
I mean, we're not as young
and handsome as we look.
- (BOTH CHUCKLE)
- Oh, that's true.
DUSTY: Besides, this Sterling fellow?
He's got every high-tech thing
you'll ever need.
Everything we wanted to give you,
but couldn't.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Sterling? Who's Sterling?
STERLING: Lightning McQueen!
You made some serious time, partner.
Your new sponsor.
He's the Mudflap King
of the Eastern seaboard.
Welcome to the
Rust-eze Racing Center!
You have no idea how much
I've been looking forward to this.
- Thanks, uh, Mr...
- Please. No "mister". Just Sterling.
I have been a fan of yours forever.
And to be your sponsor?
How great is that?
I can't thank
Rusty and Dusty here enough.
Tough negotiators by the way.
- Oh, you flatter us, but don't stop!
- (ALL LAUGHING)
Anyway, just wanted to say
a quick hello.
Take as much time as you need.
Door's always open, guys.
See?
(SIGHS) I sure am gonna miss
racing for you guys.
You know, you gave us
a lot of great memories, Lightning.
Memories we'll remember.
Wow. That's good.
- Hey, Lightning, whatever you do...
- Don't drive like my brother!
Don't drive like my brother.
RUSTY: Please no pictures.
DUSTY: Okay, maybe one.
Get my good side though, will you?
(CHUCKLES)
Whoa.
STERLING: So? You like it?
Oh, hey, Mr. Sterling. Wow.
My career on a wall.
Nice that you included Doc.
Of course. He was your mentor.
Losing him left a giant hole in the sport.
Yeah.
Jars of dirt?
STERLING: Sacred dirt.
Each of those jars contains dirt
from all the old tracks that Doc raced on.
Florida International, Thunder Hollow,
just down the road and...
our very own Fireball Beach,
right outside.
McQUEEN: Huh.
- Hey, is that...
- A bit of asphalt from Glen Ellen.
My first win!
You really are a fan.
I am. And a fan of your future.
You ready for it?
Definitely.
First, let's get you into a more...
contemporary look.
Wow.
STERLING ON SPEAKER:
It's an electronic suit.
With it we'll be able to track your speed
- and your vital signs.
- (BEEPING)
Does it have a phone?
(LAUGHS) Don't be crazy.
Racecars don't have phones.
Wow.
- Not bad, huh?
- This is really impressive.
STERLING: This center has
quickly become
the most coveted destination...
for young racers training
to make our team someday.
And it's where you'll train
until you leave for Florida.
Treadmills, wind tunnels, virtual reality.
(THUDS)
Still working on that.
And the best fitness regimen
anyone could possibly imagine.
Wait. Wait. Whoa. Is that the simulator?
STERLING: Oh, yes.
Lightning, I'd like to introduce
you to the multi-million dollar...
flagship of interactive race simulation.
The XDL 24-GTS Mark Z.
The XDL... etcetera.
Jackson Storm wishes
he had this model.
(WHIRRING)
(PANTING)
CAR 1: That was amazing.
CAR 2: Awesome. Yeah!
It's just like being on a real track,
so put your hours in.
Okay, let's hit the treadmills.
Come on. Show me what you got!
Wow. Pretty fast. Who's the racer?
No. She's not a racer. She's a trainer.
Cruz Ramirez.
The best trainer in the business.
ALL: Ready to meet it,
greet it and defeat it?
All right. Now bring up those RPMs!
(CHUCKLES) Like the attitude.
Yeah, we call her
our maestro of motivation.
You're driving
a little tense again, Ronald.
- No, no. I'm cool. I'm cool.
- Do your exercise.
I am a fluffy cloud! I am a fluffy cloud!
I am a fluffy cloud. (SIGHS)
CRUZ: There you go!
- You're a cloud. (LAUGHS)
- Shut up, Kurt!
- Here come the bugs, Kurt. You ready?
- (INHALES SHARPLY)
(INSECTS BUZZING)
Hey, I kept my eyes open this time!
Got to see that track.
Oh, no. Homesick again, Gabriel?
Si.
(SPANISH MUSIC PLAYING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
- Win for them!
- McQUEEN: Wow.
STERLING: She trains young racers
to push through their own obstacles.
Tailor-made for each one.
Now, she's gonna work with you.
Let's go! Let's go!
You guys got to work through this stuff...
so when your big chance comes along
you can take it.
Hey, Cruz.
Oh, hey, Mr. Sterling!
I'd like to introduce you
to Lightning McQueen.
I hear you're the maestro.
Mr. Sterling, did you say
Lightning McQueen was here because...
(SNORTS) I don't see him anywhere.
Uh, but he's right here.
Do you not see him?
Nope, still don't see him.
He's right in front of you!
It's Lightning McQueen!
He's obviously an imposter. He looks old
and broken down with flabby tires.
- Hey! I do not!
- Use that!
Whoa! Oh.
Yeah, I see.
I can use that energy
for motivation, right? (GROWLS)
It's all about motivation, Mr. McQueen.
You can use anything negative as fuel
to push through to the positive.
I've been pretty positive
ever since I was a rookie.
I am so excited that I get to train you.
I grew up watching you on TV.
Huh? Is that right?
These young guys are great and all,
but I like a challenge.
(CHUCKLES)
I'm not that much older, but...
In fact, I call you my senior project.
(UP-TEMPO MUSIC PLAYING)
We need to loosen those ancient joints.
First the wheels.
And forward, and rest,
and forward, and rest.
Join me! Rest. (HUFFING) And rest.
Is all this resting necessary?
We're working you in slowly.
And reach for your lunch.
Reach for your lunch.
Now reach, to the front.
What is there? It's your lunch.
Now backwards. Is lunch there?
McQUEEN: When do we go
on the simulator?
CRUZ: Good morning,
Mr. McQueen. Looking good.
(YELPS AND GRUNTS)
Why?
This'll get oil to places
it hasn't been in a long time.
- Is that a drip pan?
- Just in case.
How old do you think I am?
Visualize yourself driving fast
down a steep hill.
I'll be back in a few.
Visualize... Wait. Cruz! A few what?
I just want to go on the simulator.
KURT: How's it hanging, Drip Pan?
(ENGINES ROARING)
- 'Sup?
- Okay, day three...
Treadmill. I've set a maximum
speed to conserve your energy.
What I want you to do is
visualize beating this guy.
(McQUEEN GRUNTS)
- Storm!
- Uh-huh, that's right.
Get him! Get him, Mr. McQueen!
Get him? This thing's only
going like 5 miles an hour!
We'll work up to the higher speeds
right after you take your nap.
- Nap? I don't need a nap!
- (RACERS LAUGHING)
KURT: Hit him with the bugs! (LAUGHS)
I am not taking a nap!
ANNOUNCER: All cars in
the test bay simulator...
(YAWNING)
How was your nap, Mr. McQueen?
It was kind of refreshing actually.
Oh! Okay, what are you... Hey!
You've been driving on tires a long time.
Have you ever stopped
to get to know them?
I'm sorry, what?
Tires are individuals.
You should give each a name.
Name them? (SCOFFS)
I won't be doing that.
Mine are named Maria, Juanita,
Ronaldo, and Debbie Richardson.
- What?
- Long story.
May I have my tires back so I can go
on the simulator please?
Name them!
Uh, Lefty, Righty, Backy,
Backy Junior. Okay?
- Does this make you mad?
- Yes, it does!
Use that! And merge, and yield,
- and merge, and yield.
- (DANCE MUSIC PLAYING)
Beep, beep, beep, beep.
Now you got some tire damage.
Speed bump, speed bump.
Now clean up your messy garage.
- Bug in your windshield.
- Thank you, Cruz, I'm done.
Mr. McQueen, where are you going?
McQUEEN: To the future.
Okay. Here we go. How do I do this?
- Come on, baby.
- Mr. McQueen...
Cruz, thank you for the old-man
training, as crazy as it was,
but I'm... warmed up enough
and now I need you to launch this thing.
Wait until you can handle it. Please?
- There are no shortcuts.
- (CLICKING)
Okay. We'll just see about that.
STERLING: All right.
My star racer is on the simulator!
Why, yes, I am!
Well, let's see you
take it out for a spin.
Right away, Mr. Sterling,
owner of the company.
Okay. Have fun.
(CLICKS SWITCH)
This is what I'm talking about.
Whoa. Didn't know about those.
(GASPS)
SIMULATOR: Prepare to race.
The green flag is out.
I don't see the flag. What do I do?
- Go.
- Go?
(REVVING)
Whoa.
That's sensitive. (YELPING)
SIMULATOR: You have hit a wall.
- It shouldn't be this hard, should it? Ah!
- You have hit a wall.
You're fighting the simulator.
Just race like you always do.
- You have hit a wall.
- Whoa.
There can't be this many walls
on a regular track!
You have been passed by
Jackson Storm.
- Wait, Storm's in here?
- For motivation.
Storm races at 207.
Pick it up, Mr. McQueen!
I'm trying!
(GRUNTING)
- Ahhh!
- You have hit a wall.
Mr. McQueen, come down from there
and we'll work you up to this.
I am fine, Cruz. I can do it, okay?
- Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
- (CRASHING)
- Ahh!
- You have jumped a barrier.
- Oh!
(BABBLING)
(GASPS) Sorry!
You have maimed two vehicles.
You have destroyed a drinking fountain.
(SCREAMING)
You have disabled an ambulance.
You are on fire. Danger. Danger.
You are going the wrong way.
Look out! Turn it off!
Get these things off of me!
- (SCREAMING)
- (CRASHING)
SIMULATOR: You have crashed.
You have crashed.
- Are you all right?
- You have crashed.
I have crashed.
(ELECTRICITY BUZZING)
(POWER SHUTS DOWN)
CRUZ: It's not easy for him.
STERLING: Cruz, just relax.
- Give him another chance.
- STERLING: I will talk to him.
CRUZ: I can still work with him.
STERLING: I know he's your project.
- CRUZ: Are you sure?
- Cruz.
- CRUZ: Well, can't you just...
CRUZ: It's not easy for him.
STERLING: Look, I'm trying to help you.
McQUEEN: Whoa.
You're all warshed up, McQueen.
(STUTTERS) I'm sorry. What?
I said, the floor's
all washed up and clean.
Oh, right. (CHUCKLES)
- STERLING: Thank you very much.
- Uh...
Good luck.
STERLING: Hey, Lightning.
Come on in.
Got something to show you. You ready?
Uh, for what?
Wow.
You are about to become
the biggest brand in racing.
We are talking saturation on all
continents for every demographic.
Movie deals, infomercials,
product endorsements.
- McQUEEN: Mudflaps?
- Of course.
We'll be rich beyond belief.
You think you're famous now?
- (LAUGHS)
- (CHUCKLES SHEEPISHLY)
I thought you'd be mad
about the simulator.
I mean, this is all great, Mr. Sterling,
I guess, but I don't know.
I've never really thought
of myself as a brand.
Oh, nor do I. I'm a fan.
Maybe your most avid.
I think of this as your legacy!
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
It sounds like something that
happens after you're done racing.
Mr. Sterling, what is this about?
Look, Lightning. I'm not gonna race you.
What? What do you mean not race me?
- Hold on. Hold on.
- I'm not going to Florida?
You have no idea how excited I was
to get you here because...
I knew you'd be back.
It was gonna be the
comeback story of the year!
But your speed and performance
just aren't where they need to be.
I'm sorry.
We're talking about speed
on a simulator.
- Listen to how crazy that sounds.
- Look, I'm trying to help you.
As your sponsor, yes,
but also as your friend.
Your racing days are coming to an end.
Every time you lose,
you damage yourself.
Damage the brand, you mean?
Oh, Lightning, come on.
You've done the work.
Now move on to the next phase
and reap the reward.
The racing is the reward. Not the stuff.
I don't want to cash in.
I want to feel the rush
of moving 200 miles an hour...
inches from the other guys,
pushing myself faster
than I thought I could go!
That's the reward, Mr. Sterling!
Oh, Lightning, come on.
Look, I can do this. I can, I promise!
I'll train like I did with Doc.
I'll get my tires dirty
on every dirt track from here to Florida.
I can start on Fireball Beach
where all the old greats used to race.
Get your tires dirty.
That's how you're gonna
get faster than Storm?
Yes! Exactly! I mean, sacred dirt, right?
Mr. Sterling, if you care about
my legacy, the one that Doc started,
you'll let me do this.
I promise you, I will win.
(SIGHS) I don't know.
What you're asking, it's too risky.
Come on. You like it, I can tell.
It's got that little "comeback story
of the year" feel to it, doesn't it?
(SIGHS)
One race?
If you don't win at Florida,
you'll retire?
Look, if I don't win
I'll sell all the mudflaps you got.
But if I do win,
I decide when I'm done. Deal?
Deal.
Thank you, Mr. Sterling.
You won't be sorry.
Just one thing and this is only because
I don't like taking chances.
You're taking someone with you.
(CRUZ PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
You talked him into it!
Way to go, Mr. McQueen!
(SIGHS) Cruz.
You could talk a snowmobile
into an air conditioner.
You're going with me? With that thing?
Yeah. You still need my help.
You're brittle like a fossil.
(WHIRRING)
- We got the cable. (MUMBLING)
- I don't need a trainer out here, Cruz.
You're old!
What if you fall on this beach
and can't get up?
Well, life's a beach and then you drive.
(LAUGHS)
- Oh, McQueen.
- Thank you.
This is beautiful.
I can see why Mr. Sterling
said you wanted to train here.
As soon as this thing's booted up,
we'll get you on the treadmill...
and I'll track your speed.
What? No!
The whole idea is getting
my tires dirty. Real racing.
I'm not driving on that thing
when I've got the sand
and the whole earth.
(MACHINE CHIMING)
- Oh, okay.
- Luigi, let's do this.
LUIGI: Welcome, racers,
to Fireball Beach!
Historic home for today's
great test of speed.
Our finish line will be
the abandoned pier in the distance.
All right. Quicker than quick,
faster than fast, I am speed...
That is great self-motivation.
Did you come up with that?
Yeah, I did.
On your mark. Get set. Go!
(WHOOPING)
There you go! Felt good!
Hey, what was my speed?
I don't know.
I can only track you on the treadmill.
No treadmills!
Oh! What about Hamilton?
ELECTRONIC MALE VOICE:
Hamilton here.
Who's Hamilton?
My electronic personal assistant.
You know, like on your phone.
You do have a phone, don't you?
Racecars don't have phones, Cruz.
Hamilton, track Mr. McQueen's
speed and report it.
- Tracking.
- I'll stay as close as I can.
Your suit will transmit
your speeds to Hamilton.
Fine. Whatever. Let's do this.
Quicker than quick, faster than fast,
I am speed. Come on, Luigi.
On your mark, get set, and go!
HAMILTON: 46 miles per hour.
63 miles. Out of range.
Huh.
That's odd. I didn't go!
(REVVING)
On sand you got to ease into your start
so your tires can grab, okay?
- Okay.
- You do work with racecars, don't you?
Yeah, but never outside.
All right. Let's go again.
Go!
HAMILTON: 54 miles per hour.
75 miles per hour. Out of range.
- Huh?
- (HAMILTON REPEATING)
Sorry! Got stuck!
- Go again!
- And go!
- Ah! Sorry!
- LUIGI: Go!
Whoa!
- Go!
- (ENGINE REVVING)
The beach ate me.
McQUEEN: All right, Cruz,
pick a line on the compacted sand.
You got to have traction
or you're gonna spin out.
Let's do this thing!
On your mark, get set, go!
HAMILTON: 122 miles per hour.
134 miles... Out of range.
- Now what?
- I didn't want to hit a crab!
- You got to be kidding me.
- What? It was cute!
(McQUEEN GROANS)
McQUEEN: All right, one last chance
to try this before it gets dark.
Now, you're going to take off slow
to let your tires grab.
And pick a straight line on hard sand
- so you don't spin out.
- Uh-huh.
And all of the crabbies
have gone night-night.
Mr. McQueen.
All right. Let's go again.
And go!
150 miles per hour. 175 miles per hour.
196 miles per hour.
(WHOOPING)
All right! Finally! You made it!
Congratulations! How'd I do?
- You topped out at 198.
- 198? That's it?
Still slower than Storm.
Wasted my whole day.
I wouldn't say that.
It did feel great to be
out here doing real racing.
This isn't real racing. We're on a beach!
All you do is go straight.
How am I gonna get faster if I don't...
Thunder Hollow.
Thunder Hollow!
There's a dirt track there!
That's what I need!
To race against actual racers.
No! Too public! If the press find you,
they will be like many bugs on you.
- Paparazzi! (SPITS)
- Guys, I really need this!
Ah, just leave it to me, boss.
I am a master of disguise.
(COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING)
- (CAMERAS CLICKING)
- (CARS HONKING)
FEMALE CAR: All right! Next!
(WHISTLING TUNE)
(COUGHS AND SPITS)
You, sir, are officially incognito.
Nobody's bothering you.
The great Lightning McQueen.
I can feel it, guys.
Tonight is the night I find my speed!
ANNOUNCER: Racers, get on over
to the startin' line. Pronto!
(ALL CHATTERING)
All right! No more straight lines.
Just a good old-fashioned oval.
Hey, now! You that out-of-towner?
Uh, yes. That's me!
Chester Whipplefilter.
And I'm Frances Beltline.
- Cruz, what are you doing?
- I'm your trainer.
I'm gonna track your speed
from the infield, Whipplefilter.
Fine. Just stay out of the way.
Excuse me, sir?
Where are the other racers?
Oh, they'll be along.
We always let our guests
start right up front.
- (DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
- (CROWD CHEERING)
ANNOUNCER: Welcome, y'all,
to Thunder Hollow Speedway...
for tonight's edition of Crazy Eight!
Did he say Crazy Eight?
Whoa.
ANNOUNCER: Race fans!
It's time to meet tonight's challengers!
- (SIREN CHIRPS)
- (IMITATING SIREN SOUNDS)
- Have a nice trip!
- (EVIL LAUGHTER)
Protect and swerve!
(ALL LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
(WHOOPING)
(WHISTLING TUNE)
Cruz! This isn't what I thought it was.
Come on, follow me and we'll slip out.
Rule number one:
The gate closes, you race.
CRUZ: (GASPS) Wait!
No, no, no. I'm not a racer.
Rule number two: Last car standing wins.
And rule number three:
No cursing! It's Family Night.
- Excuse me, sir?
- Wait. No, I'm just a trainer!
- Whoo!
- (BOTH YELPING)
ANNOUNCER: And make way for
the undefeated Crazy Eight champion...
the Diva of Demolition, Miss Fritter!
(SCREAMING)
Boo! (LAUGHS)
Lookie here, boys.
We got us a couple of rookies.
I'm gonna call you Muddy Britches
and you Lemonade.
Hey, neither one of them
has a single dent.
Oh, I'm gonna fix that!
All right, everybody! Let's go racing!
(CROWD CHEERING)
(MISS FRITTER LAUGHS)
I'm about to commit a moving violation.
- McQUEEN: Ow.
- (GRUNTS)
- Boo!
- (CROWD CHEERING)
(GASPING)
Cruz!
RACER: Ha-ha! Watch out.
What are you doing?
Got to keep moving!
I shouldn't be out here! (SHRIEKS)
- Move, Cruz! Move!
- (SCREAMS)
What do I do? I can't steer!
Turn right to go left!
That doesn't make any sense!
(RACER WHOOPING)
(MANIACAL LAUGHTER)
- Whoa.
- (RACER CAR WHIMPERING)
- Hey, Patty.
- Oh, hey, Bill!
Ahhh! (YELPS)
(GRUNTS)
(CREAKING)
(WHOOPING)
Look, Ma, I can drive... Oh, man!
Nice day for a drive, huh?
Hey, buddy!
Get the (HONKS) out of my way!
- Whoo-hoo!
- (CROWD CHEERING)
Hey! I'm driving...
- (IMITATING SIREN)
- (LAUGHS)
(GRUNTS)
(WHIMPERS)
(GASPS)
- Oh, look at my new hat!
- (McQUEEN SCREAMING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
SUPERFLY: I'm flying!
No! I'm not flying!
- (CROWD EXCLAIMING)
- CAR: Get it. Get it.
- I got it!
- (CHEERING)
- Cruz!
- (SCREAMING)
(IMITATING SIREN SOUND)
Oh!
CABBIE TAXI: Hey, buddy! Move it!
Turn right to go left.
Whoa, whoa. Whoa!
- Here I come, boy!
- TACO: No, no, no!
(GROANING)
Oh, no.
Buckle up, everybody!
It's Fritter time!
(CROWD CHEERING)
CROWD: (CHANTING) Fritter! Fritter!
Fritter! Fritter! Fritter!
We love you, Miss Fritter.
Oh, yeah! Your license plate's gonna
look real nice in my collection.
- Oh, boy.
- Run!
Oh, no.
Remember, obey all
appropriate street signs.
- Cruz!
- (LAUGHS)
- (MUD SQUELCHING)
- (GRUNTING)
Whoa! Hey...
Whoa, whoa, whoa. (GRUNTS)
- Oh, my gracious! Miss Fritter's down!
- (ALL GASPING)
(GRUNTING)
(REVVING)
(CLATTERING)
MISS FRITTER: Nobody touches him.
He is mine! (GRUNTS)
You gonna get it now, Whipplefilter!
(GRUNTING)
Come on, McQueen. You can do it.
Come on, Lightning, keep going.
ANNOUNCER: Miss Fritter is
looking to get upright, folks.
And she is not pleased.
CAR: Get up. Get up!
CROWD: Fritter! Fritter!
You about to feel the wrath of the...
Lower Belleville County
Unified School District!
Oh! What the... Wait...
(SCREAMING)
No, no, no! No! No!
(GASPS)
ANNOUNCER: Ladies and gentlemen,
we have a winner!
Frances Beltline!
Is that me? That's me! I won! I won!
- Cruz! Cruz! No!
- Ahhh! Watch out!
Whoa, whoa. (WHIMPERS)
(WATER GUSHING)
- (CROWD GASPS)
- (SPITS)
MALE CAR: Whipplefilter?
- It's Lightning McQueen!
- (ALL SCREAMING)
(GASPS)
- CAR: McQueen!
- (CAMERAS FLASHING)
(HORN BLARING)
Fans here at Thunder Hollow
still buzzing over tonight's...
unexpected appearance
of Lightning McQueen.
He has always been my favorite!
My garage is covered from
head to toe with 95 posters.
REPORTER: Tell our listeners at home
you weren't really trying
- to wreck him, were you?
-So trophy's kind of nice.
Don't you think?
I mean, I know you got like
a billion of them, so you would know.
I still can't believe I won. (CHUCKLES)
It's pretty shiny.
I have never seen one up close.
Looks like they spent
a lot of money on it.
I mean, I think it's real metal.
Stop. Just stop, okay, Cruz?
You don't even know.
- You don't even have one clue...
- Hey! I was just trying...
Do you know what happens
if I lose this race?
Every mile of this trip was to get me
faster than Jackson Storm. Faster!
I started off getting nowhere
for a week on a simulator!
I lose a whole day with you
on Fireball Beach.
And then I waste tonight
in the cross-hairs of Miss Fritter!
I'm stuck in the same speed
I was a month ago!
I can't get any faster because
I'm too busy taking care of my trainer!
This is my last chance, Cruz.
Last! Final! Finito!
If I lose, I never get to do this again.
If you were a racer...
you'd know what I'm talking about
but you're not! So you don't.
(CRUZ GASPS)
Mack! Pull over!
What? Now?
Now!
Ahh! Okay! Pulling over!
Ask me if I dreamed of being a trainer,
Mr. McQueen. Go ahead.
Ask me if I got up in the dark
to run laps before school every day.
Ask me if I saved every penny
to buy a ticket
to the races when they came to town.
Ask me if I did that so I could be
a trainer someday. Ask me.
- Did you?
- No!
I've wanted to become a racer forever!
Because of you!
I used to watch you on TV,
flying through the air.
You seemed so... fearless.
"Dream small, Cruz,"
that's what my family used to say.
"Dream small or not at all."
They were just trying to protect me.
But I was the fastest kid in town
and I was gonna prove them wrong.
What happened?
When I got to my first race,
I figured it out.
What?
That I didn't belong.
The other racers looked nothing like me.
They were bigger and stronger
and so... confident.
And when they started their engines,
that was it...
I knew I'd never be a racer.
I just left.
It was my one shot and I didn't take it.
Yeah, so, uh, I'm gonna head back
to the training center.
I think we both know it's for the best.
But can I ask you something?
What was it like for you?
When you showed up to your first race?
How did you know you could do it?
I don't know.
I just never thought I couldn't.
I wish I knew what that felt like.
Good luck, Mr. McQueen.
Cruz. Cruz, wait.
(SIGHS)
FEMALE CAR ON TV:
And earn your physics degree
from the comfort of your own home...
MALE CAR: You'd get
that and a $200 gift,
- for $29.95.
- (MACK SNORING)
MALE CAR 2: Now look here, Warden...
FEMALE CAR 2: Oh, no!
He's got a jack!
NARRATOR: Autos over 100,000 miles
also reported trouble sleeping.
You could have 12 worn-out wrenches
or you could have one atomic wrench.
MALE CAR: Throw the old ones out.
This covers...
HICKS: "Champion for the Ages"
Chick Hicks here.
Coming to you live from...
Chick Hicks Studios,
where I'm joined once again by...
next-gen racing expert, Natalie Certain.
Thanks, Chick. Piston Cup champion
Jackson Storm set a new record today...
when he pulled off
the fastest lap ever recorded.
An unprecedented 213 miles an hour.
HICKS: Wow!
So what do you think, Certain?
Stormy boy gonna start
the season with another win?
Highly likely, Chick.
Based on his recent run times
and forecasted...
track temperatures on race day,
Storm's chances of winning...
are 95.2%.
That low, huh?
Oh, and in case you missed it,
talk of the track tonight
is Lightning McQueen...
finding yet another way
to embarrass himself
at a demolition derby. Whoa.
Almost makes me feel sorry for the guy.
Not really. (CHUCKLES)
Here's what his new sponsor had to say.
Everyone, relax. The 95's gonna race.
Lightning's just taking a somewhat
unconventional approach to this race.
It's one of the things
his fans love about him.
HICKS: Yeah, right!
Talk about humiliating.
If I were old Ka-chow...
I wouldn't even bother
to show up in Florida.
That could be for the best, Chick.
Even if he does race...
McQueen's probability
of winning is 1.2%.
HICKS: Wow!
Numbers never lie.
I'm willing to predict tonight
that Lightning McQueen's racing...
career will be over within the week.
It might even be over now.
I mean, I knew his career
was stuck in the mud...
(SIGHS)
♪ First you find a can from a rusty van
♪ Bump-bump
♪ Quicker than a dart, make it into art
♪ That's the way it's done,
it's a lot of fun
♪ Bump-bump
♪ Liftin' my funk,
makin' sculpture outta junk ♪
- (CHUCKLES)
- (DEVICE BEEPING)
What's that? (SCOFFS) There we go!
Somebody's interrupting genius!
- (GASPS) Well, hey, there, buddy!
- (CHUCKLES) Mater!
You know, I was just thinking of you
and here you are lookin' right at me!
You see me okay? Hang on a second
there. Hold on. Let me see here.
- That better?
-(CHUCKLES)
Looking you straight
in the eye there, pal.
Hey, sorry about calling so late.
Shoot, not for me it's not.
I'm always burning that midnight oil.
So get me caught up on everything.
Well, actually kind of hoping
I might hear what's going on back home.
Not much. If you don't
count Sarge and Fillmore
tryin' to run the tire shop.
But tell Luigi not to worry,
Sarge is gonna track down...
every last tire
that Fillmore done gived away.
Other than that, everything's good.
- How's Sally?
- Oh, she's fine.
Keeping busy at the Cone.
She misses you.
Well, shoot! We all do
when you're on the road.
Yeah. You know, I've been
kind of thinking about that.
You know, what we should do
when I'm not on the road anymore.
What do you mean not on the road?
Well, you know.
Mater, I can't do this forever.
Huh?
I'm just not getting anywhere
with the training.
If anything,
I've gotten slower not faster.
Shoot, buddy, it'll work out.
Just tell me what the problem is...
and I'll stay right here
with you until we fix it.
That's just it, Mater. I don't know.
And I feel like I'm all out of ideas.
Hmm.
All right, let me think.
Oh! You know what I'd do?
What?
I don't know. I got nothin'.
I guess I ain't Doc when it comes to that.
I would give anything
to talk to him right now.
Yep, there was nobody
smarter than old Doc.
Well, except for maybe
whoever taught him.
Yeah. Wait. What?
Everybody was taught
by somebody, right?
Take my cousin Doyle.
He taught me how to sing
and whistle at the same time.
He was very musical that way.
Smokey. Mater, you're brilliant.
Ah, well... It's all about
the shape of your teeth.
I got to go to Thomasville.
MATER: Oh, well, good.
You know me, buddy,
I'm always happy to help.
Think I am better at that than most folks.
You know, talkin' and stuff.
(MACK HONKING)
Hey, Cruz.
You won't talk me out of this,
Mr. McQueen.
I'm going back. I resign as your trainer.
All right. I accept your resignation. Bye.
Oh... Okay.
But since you cleared your calendar,
why don't you come with us?
I'm looking for someone named Smokey.
Hoping he can help me.
Maybe he can help you too.
Nah.
Come on. I fixed it.
No. Thanks anyway. But I'm done.
Okay. But maybe this will
change your mind. Hit it.
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
First I'm going to loosen up
these ancient joints...
No, please don't.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry that I yelled.
It wasn't your fault
that I almost got killed.
But now you're leaving
and you won't get on the ramp.
- CRUZ: All right, I'll go.
- You won't get on the ramp.
All right, I'll go! Just stop!
CRUZ: How do you know
Smokey's going to be here?
McQUEEN: I don't.
CRUZ: Oh. Do you know
if he's even alive?
McQUEEN: Nope.
CRUZ: Okay.
So tell me this: How do you know
if it's Smokey? Is there such...
McQUEEN: Wait. Mack, pull over!
Back it up! Back it up.
McQUEEN: Good to see you, Doc.
Hey, isn't that your old crew chief?
Hey, Cruz? You want to
check out the home track
of the greatest racer ever?
Aren't we supposed to be
looking for Smokey?
Oh, that's right, he's dead.
McQUEEN: We don't know that.
Are you sure you have time for this?
For this, I do.
Wow!
If this track could talk.
Cruz, what do you say? Let's take a lap.
- (ENGINE REVVING)
- Oh, yeah!
Oh, whoa!
(CRUZ AND McQUEEN LAUGH)
Yes! You nailed it!
Way easier without
the school bus of death
trying to kill us! (LAUGHS)
Yeah, no kidding!
(CHUCKLES AND GASPS)
(YELLS)
(GRUNTING)
Was starting to think
I might never meet you.
Smokey?
(CRUZ GASPS)
He is alive.
I know why you're here. You're thirsty.
(COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING FAINTLY)
SMOKEY: I'll tell you what,
these folks are gonna get a kick
out of meeting Hud's boy.
Who's Hud? Oh, Doc Hudson! Right.
(COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING)
- Hey!
- (MUSIC STOPS)
Act civilized. We got company.
Hey, Les.
How's that back axle treating you?
- Hey, sugar, welcome to Thomasville.
- (MUSIC CONTINUES)
(McQUEEN CHUCKLES)
- Would you look at that?
- CRUZ: What?
McQUEEN: Three of the biggest
racing legends ever!
Junior "Midnight" Moon.
River Scott. Louise...
Louise "Barnstormer" Nash?
She had 38 wins!
Well, as I live and breathe.
If it ain't Lightning McQueen.
Ms. Nash, it's a pleasure to meet you...
You've had a tough year, haven't you?
Oh, uh...
Shouldn't you be running practice laps
in Florida by now?
- Yeah, sure, but...
- They're here to steal our secrets.
Looking for your lost mojo?
Wow. You don't mince words
around here, do you?
(SCOFFS) Truth is always quicker, kid.
(COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING)
♪ But all he kept talking about was
♪ Glory days
♪ They'll pass you by Glory days
♪ In the wink of a young girl's eye
♪ Glory days
♪ Glory days ♪
Guido, she's an angel.
(ALL CHUCKLING)
RIVER: Lou won't admit this,
but she used to have
serious eyes for Hud.
(CHUCKLES) Oh, really?
Even if I did, it wouldn't have mattered.
Hud didn't like fast women.
And that left me out.
(LAUGHTER)
Old Lou wasn't just fast,
she was fearless.
The second I saw my first race,
I just knew I had to get in there.
Of course, the fellas in charge
didn't like a lady racer showin' them up.
So they wouldn't let me have a number.
(GASPS) What did you do?
I stole one!
- What?
- Wow.
Life's too short to take no
for an answer. Right, River?
If we had waited for an invitation,
we might've never raced.
And once we got on the track,
we didn't want to leave.
I think that's how Doc felt too.
You should've seen him
when he first came to town.
Shiny blue paint.
Not just the Hudson Hornet.
He was already calling himself...
ALL: ...the Fabulous Hudson Hornet.
- Whoo-hoo!
- (ALL LAUGHING)
Did we ever ride him on that.
Not for long.
Hud was the fastest racer
this side of the Mississippi.
Until he wasn't.
What?
Everything changed
when the rookie showed up.
(ALL CHEERING)
SMOKEY: Took Hud all of no time
to work his way
through the best racers...
in both Carolinas.
Past River. Past Lou. Even Junior.
But there was still
the rookie to deal with.
Tried slamming him into the wall.
But Hud never touched any wall,
unless he wanted to.
(CROWD CHEERING)
That rookie never saw
anything like that before.
- Doc did that?
- Whoa! Are you kidding?
Couldn't wipe the smile off his face
for a week after that.
- (ALL LAUGH)
- (McQUEEN SIGHS)
I wish I could've seen him like that.
- Like what?
- So happy.
SMOKEY: You didn't come all this way
for a quart of oil, did you?
I need your help, Smokey.
Yeah? What kind of help?
That's just it, I'm not sure.
All I know is if I lose in Florida...
it's over for me.
What happened to Doc
will happen to me.
What did happen to him?
You know,
racing was the best part of his life.
And when it ended, he...
Well, we both know he was
never the same after that.
Is that what you think?
Come on. I want to show you something.
SMOKEY: You got the first part right.
The crash broke Hud's body
and the "no more racing"
broke his heart.
He cut himself off.
Disappeared to Radiator Springs.
Son of a gun didn't talk to me
for 50 years.
But then one day,
the letters started coming in.
And every last one of them
was about you.
Yeah, Hud loved racing.
But coaching you?
(SIGHS) I had never seen
the old grump so happy.
Racing wasn't the best part of Hud's life.
You were.
You ready to blow out
a little carbon there, boy?
Yes, I am!
(SCREAMS)
You give it too much throttle,
you're in the tulips.
(CHUCKLES)
Hey, Lightning. You might want
to take notes on this one.
(LAUGHS)
(CHUCKLES)
HUDSON: You got a lot of stuff, kid.
Hud saw something in you
that you don't even see in yourself.
Are you ready to go find it?
Yes, sir.
All right, all right. Bring it back.
(McQUEEN PANTING)
Lesson one: You're old. Accept it.
- I told him that.
- He's probably losing his hearing.
(SHOUTING)
He said you're old and losing...
I heard him.
You'll never be as fast as Storm,
but you can be smarter than him.
Okay, what do I do?
They said you were
in a demolition derby.
Yeah, it was terrible and I almost...
Are you sure?
Because there's not a scratch on you.
Funny what a racer can do
when he's not over-thinking things.
SHANNON: Shannon Spokes
here at Florida International,
where Jackson Storm...
clocked 214 miles per hour today.
SMOKEY: You want to beat Storm,
you need someone to stand in for him.
Like a sparring partner.
I'm not so sure. Not a racer.
(CHUCKLES) Just a trainer!
Go ahead and gun it.
(ENGINE REVVING)
- Oh, yeah!
- (SMOKEY CHUCKLES)
With no muffler
you even sound like Storm.
Oh, you're going down, McQueen!
Get that arthritis-riddled keister
onto the track
so I can put you into...
the old folks' home against your will!
How was that?
- That'll work.
- Worked for me.
- I'm good.
- Yep. That'll do.
Did you hear what she said?
SMOKEY: You didn't show up
in Florida for qualifying
so you'll be starting last.
I'll give you three laps to catch her.
Go through the entire field in three laps?
You want to beat Storm or not?
- Yes! Of course I do.
- Well, then, go!
(CRUZ SQUEALS)
Come on, kid.
All right. Looks like
we got some work to do.
Look alive. The reflexes
are the first thing to go.
(EXCLAIMING)
- Ah!
- (MOOING)
McQUEEN: Why are we in a field?
Sneak through that window!
- What does that mean?
- I don't know.
- Go!
- (HONKS)
(BOTH SCREAM)
McQUEEN: Whoa!
CRUZ: Not cool, man. Not cool!
Let's run it back.
Do you even want to be out here?
Only two days left, kid.
- You got to work harder.
- (GRUNTING)
Wait, wait, who was that?
I put McQueen in there.
Give you some real competition.
(BOTH LAUGH)
SMOKEY: Hud was a master
of letting the other cars
do the work for him.
RIVER: He used to say
cling to 'em like you was
two June bugs...
on a summer night.
- He stole that from me.
- (CHUCKLES)
Drafting? I've never had to do that.
Yeah, that's when you were fast.
Now you're slow.
- RIVER: And old.
- And rickety.
- And dilapidated.
- Okay! Okay, I get it.
The new you has to
look for opportunities...
you never knew were there.
(MOOING)
- Sneak through the window!
- (BOTH EXCLAIM)
Sneak through the window.
What?
When a window opens, take it!
(McQUEEN WHOOPS)
Whoa!
Yes.
- Whoa! I made it!
- All right!
(BOTH EXCLAIM)
Let's go! Let's move!
- (GUIDO GRUNTING)
- SMOKEY: Reflexes!
All right, Guido, turn up the heat.
GUIDO: Okay.
Whoa! Whoa!
(GASPS)
All right, look who finally showed up.
SMOKEY: This is where
we cut our racing teeth.
In the woods?
Let's just say the moon
was always shining on us.
Huh?
If the moon didn't shine,
we didn't have to...
Oh, never mind.
JUNIOR MOON:
We ran moonshine, dummy!
Oh!
By the way, no lights. Instinct only.
(ALL WHOOPING)
CRUZ: Yeah!
(CRUZ EXCLAIMING)
RIVER: Yeah!
(GASPING)
Oh!
(GRUNTS)
Whoa!
(CHUCKLES) Yeah!
(WHOOPING)
Whoo-hoo!
(CRUZ WHOOPS AND LAUGHS)
McQUEEN: All right!
(McQUEEN WHOOPING)
McQueen's still not here?
Didn't he pull this
when he was a rookie?
At least that's what
my grandfather told me.
SMOKEY: All right, we got
time for one last race.
Hurry this along, boss,
we got to get you to Florida.
Go!
Maybe it's best that he doesn't show up,
after how last season ended.
Let me put it this way.
I'm not losing any sleep
wondering where Lightning McQueen is.
Come on, boy. Come on!
SMOKEY: All right, McQueen.
There you go, boy!
There you go.
DARRELL: McQueen is fading.
McQueen is fading. Fading fast.
(PANTING)
CRUZ: Whoo-hoo! Yes!
Ah! (CACKLES)
Whoo! Did you see that? That was...
Uh...
Sorry. I didn't mean to...
Hey, uh, boss, it's time to hit the road.
Yeah.
(STAMMERING)
I want to thank everyone for the training.
We better get going to Florida.
CUTLASS: Welcome to
racing's greatest day!
We're beach-side
at the Florida International Speedway...
to kick off a new season
of Piston Cup racing.
It's the Florida 500.
DARRELL: Forty-three cars
and a quarter million fans
await today's intense contest of..
Strategy, skill, but most of all, speed.
This crowd is in for
one great day of racing.
CUTLASS: I'm Bob Cutlass,
joined as always
by my broadcasting partner...
Darrell Cartrip and stat
sensation Natalie Certain.
I've never seen
the numbers line up for Storm
like they do today, Bob.
Storm should be 96.8% unstoppable.
DARRELL: Well, don't
overlook Lightning McQueen.
Whipplefilter! Yeah-hoo!
(ALL CHEERING)
CUTLASS: We've heard stories
of the unusual way
McQueen trained to get here.
Now the question is did it work?
Speed. I am... speed?
(BANGING ON DOOR)
MACK: Hey, boss, they're, uh...
calling the racers to the track.
(EXHALES)
REPORTER: Jeff Gorvette,
how does today's talent stack up?
Oh, I think we're in for a treat today.
These racers are...
Oh... Hey, McQueen,
win one for us old guys.
Hah! Will do, Jeff.
- MATER: Hey, there, buddy!
- Hey, guys.
- Stickers.
- Hey, Sal.
- You okay?
- Yeah. Absolutely.
Listen, you're gonna do great today.
And no matter what happens...
I'm going to move onto the next rookie
and forget I ever knew you.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
I'm glad you're here.
(CHUCKLING) Oh, wow! Nice costume.
Come here, let's get a picture.
It's so great to meet my number-one fan.
(SIGHS) What a jerk.
- She's not a fan, Storm.
- Oh, hey there, champ.
I heard you're selling
mudflaps after today.
Is that true?
Hey, you put me down
for the first case, okay?
(ALL CHEERING)
Lightning! Lightning McQueen!
STERLING: Hey, Lightning!
Hey, Mr. Sterling.
To the future, eh, champ?
Yeah. To the future.
Hey, just focus on
what you're here to do, kid.
Thanks, Smokey.
SMOKEY: Now, go make Hud proud.
You got it.
DARRELL: Boogity, boogity,
boogity, let's go racing!
CUTLASS: McQueen
is making steady progress
in the early parts of this race.
NATALIE CERTAIN: Well,
it won't be enough to catch Storm.
DARRELL: Considering
he started dead last...
I don't think
he's doing half-bad out there.
SMOKEY: Not too shabby!
You keep this up,
you'll finish in the top 10!
Top 10's not gonna cut it, Smokey.
I got to go all the way.
So dig in! Remember your training.
Find Storm and chase him down!
Oh, tell him he has
three laps to catch me!
Cruz says you've got
three laps to catch her.
Yeah, okay! Tell her, thanks.
- Cruz, what are you doing here?
- Oh, Mr. Sterling, I was just...
I'd like you to head back
to the training center right away.
Oh. But why?
I need you to get Kurt up to speed
for the race next weekend.
Um... Wait, not Kurt.
He's the bug guy, right?
The other one... Ronald. Yes!
But I want to stay and watch.
That's not gonna happen, Cruz.
Now go.
(STUTTERS) But Mr. McQueen
still has a chance...
Just go do your job!
Yes, sir.
And take off that spoiler
and those racing tires.
You look ridiculous!
You are a trainer, remember?
Not a racer! (ECHOING)
McQUEEN: If you were a racer,
you'd know what
I'm talking about but you're not!
So you don't!
STERLING: No. (LAUGHS)
She's not a racer. She's a trainer.
(CRUZ WHOOPING)
CRUZ: I've wanted to become
a racer forever!
Because of you!
It was my one shot and I didn't take it.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
SMOKEY: Wreck in two.
Wreck in turn two.
Go low. Go low.
(McQUEEN GRUNTS)
Kid, you okay?
Smokey, I need Cruz!
Never mind that now.
No! I need her back here.
Now!
MIKE: The yellow flag still out, folks.
Wrecked cars everywhere.
We're still trying to figure...
HAMILTON: Hamilton here.
Call from Chester Whipplefilter.
Chester... Mr. McQueen?
The green light's on, pit road is open,
and everybody's coming in.
Get ready, guys.
Luigi, Guido, tires! Fillmore, fuel!
Okay, I'm here. What's going on?
No! Not me! Her.
- ALL: Huh?
- What?
- What is she doing back here?
- Come on, guys! Get her set up!
- Okay! Hot tires!
- Wait! What's happening?
Hey, Ramone! You got your paints?
- You know I do!
- CRUZ: Guys! What are you doing?
Man, I don't understand it!
McQueen's just sitting there.
Something's got to be wrong.
Mr. McQueen?
Today's the day, Cruz.
You're getting your shot.
What?
I started this race
and you're gonna finish it.
What? She'll damage the brand!
She's just a trainer!
No, she's a racer.
Just took me awhile to see it.
That can't be legal!
The rules only say
the number has to be out there.
Doesn't say who has to wear it.
- No! You can't do that...
- Did I tell you I love your mudflaps?
Out of my way, bumpkin!
Got my fishing flaps,
got my church flaps,
my going out and eating flaps.
McQUEEN: Come on, guys!
We got to get her out there! Let's go!
- Tires, check!
- Fuel, check!
Ramone?
- Best I could do in the time frame, boss.
- (ENGINE REVVING)
Yeah. (CHUCKLES) That'll work.
Why are you doing this?
You said it yourself,
this might be your last chance.
Which makes it my last chance
to give you your first chance, Cruz.
And this time I want you to take it.
She's got to beat that pace car out.
- No! You can't do that!
- Now or never.
What do you say?
Whoa! Hey! 35-mile-per-hour pit speed!
CRUZ: I knew that!
McQueen's team has entered
a different car sporting the 95.
I don't believe what I'm seeing!
You're watching this, right?
What, the girl in the costume?
You're kidding me.
He put her in the race?
(CROWD CHEERING)
CUTLASS: The green flag is out
and we're back to racing.
(EXCLAIMS)
SMOKEY: Cruz? What are you doing?
Come on. Pick it up!
You got to go faster.
Call her Frances Beltline
and tell her the school bus
of death is after her.
- What? No.
- Trust me.
Uh, Frances Beltline,
the school bus of death is after you.
What? Oh, uh... (STUTTERS) Right.
Okay, that was different.
SMOKEY: Cruz, you're
looking too tight now.
Come on. Loosen up.
- Tell her she's a fluffy cloud.
- What? No.
Smokey, tell her.
Uh, Cruz, you are a fluffy cloud.
Oh, right. Uh, too tight.
I'm a fluffy cloud. I'm a fluffy cloud.
- (BRAKES SQUEALING)
- Uh...
SMOKEY: Anticipate your turns.
Cruz! Get your head in the race.
(STUTTERING)
Tell her she's on a beach
and all the little crabbies
have gone night-night.
No! I ain't saying that. You tell her.
McQUEEN: All right, Cruz. The beach.
I need you to think of the beach.
- Mr. McQueen?
- Yeah. It's me. Remember the beach.
Oh, pick a line, stick to it. Got it.
All right. Not too bad.
This is nothing like the simulator.
You got every tool you need.
Now remember Thomasville.
- Thomasville?
-Yeah.
Sneak through the window.
Now that I understand.
(MOOING)
(GRUNTING)
CUTLASS: We're just learning
that the racer
replacing McQueen is Cruz Ramirez.
This is her very first race!
Actually, Darrell, it says here
she does have one win under her belt.
At a place called Thunder Hollow?
Thunder Hollow!
She said Thunder Hollow!
Try moving half a lane. Half a lane.
- Got it.
- All right, watch that lap car.
He's gonna go high.
Go low! Go low! Nice job.
You are smoking these guys.
Now watch the tire marbles along
turn three. Keep your tires clean.
- Okay.
- Bump coming up on the inside.
Careful you don't go airborne.
- Now?
- Yes. Now!
Watch out by the wall, it's a little
slick there. Watch it, watch it, watch it.
(CRUZ SQUEALING)
You have hit a wall. You have hit a wall.
Ha-ha. Just being aggressive.
Okay, I want you to pit.
Watch your RPM.
Get out of the gas.
On the brake. On the brake.
Too fast!
Uh, we're back here.
Sorry.
All right.
Pick 'em off one at a time. Go, go, go!
That's it. Nice and straight.
Whoo-hoo!
Go, go, go, go! Smokey, you watching?
(LAUGHING)
Just wanted to let you know
Ramirez is moving up toward you.
(SCOFFS) Why should I care?
Because now she's in the top 10!
Okay. Now you're coming up
on the leaders.
- CREW CHIEF: Ramirez up to fourth.
- In fourth? Huh.
(WHOOPING) Get 'er done!
CREW CHIEF: Ramirez is in third.
What are you doing, Storm?
Hey! Costume Girl.
You know, at first I thought
you were out here...
because your GPS was broken.
Don't listen to him, Cruz!
JACKSON STORM: You look good!
It's important to look the part.
You can't have everyone thinking
that you don't deserve to be here.
He's trying to get in your head!
They don't need to know
what you and I already do.
That you can play dress-up all you want,
but you'll never be one of us.
Cruz, did you see what happened there?
Yeah. (STUTTERS) He's in my head.
No! Listen to me.
You got into his head.
Don't you understand?
He would never have done that
if you didn't scare him.
What?
He sees something in you
that you don't even see in yourself
You made me believe it,
now you got to believe it too.
You are a racer.
Use that.
And how far back is she now?
- CREW CHIEF: Look behind you.
- What?
- Good evening, Storm!
- Wait, how did you...
Just back here drafting on your butt.
Nothing to be concerned about.
Like two June bugs on a summer night.
(SMOKEY LAUGHS)
(CHUCKLING) Hey, Hamilton.
- HAMILTON: Hamilton here.
- Call out our speed.
208 miles per hour, 207 miles...
Would you stop that?
You're taking me off my line!
- Last lap!
- Come on, Cruz!
CRUZ: Oh-oh!
My GPS is saying
I have slow traffic in my way.
- No, you are not winning this!
- Ah, you're angry.
I am not angry!
You know, you can use that
anger to push through.
I said I'm not angry!
Oh, I don't think so! No!
(CRUZ GRUNTS AND GASPS)
Cruz, get out of there!
You don't belong on this track!
Yes, I do!
CUTLASS: I don't believe it.
It's Cruz Ramirez for the win!
DARRELL: I am speechless!
(ALL CHEERING)
- (WHOOPING)
- MATER: Nice finish, Cruz! You done it!
Cruz Ramirez!
- Yeah, there you go!
- Way to go, Cruz!
Oh, yes!
Whoo-hoo!
Man, heck of a win!
Yeah. Heck of a win.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Hey, Cruz! You were flying!
Thanks.
You really had it rolling today.
- That was cool.
- Thank you!
Hey, Cruz, your blinker's on.
It is? Oh! You got me!
Very funny! (LAUGHS)
CROWD: (CHANTING)
Cruz! Cruz! Cruz!
MALE FAN 1: Ramirez!
Whoo!
MALE FAN 2: Way to go, Cruz!
Go ahead. Give them some smoke.
(CROWD CONTINUES CHANTING)
Cruz! Cruz! Cruz!
(LAUGHING)
(LAUGHS AND COUGHS)
(CHUCKLES) You'll get used to that.
STERLING: Out of my way!
Come on! Move it! Move!
Cruz! I knew you had something.
And now look at you... a winner.
I could use you as a racer
on our team. We could make...
Sorry, Mr. Sterling.
I would never race for you.
I quit.
(HORN HONKING MELODIOUSLY)
Well, then race for me!
Tex!
Miss Cruz, I would be tickled pink
to have you race for team Dinoco.
As you know, we have a long
history of great racers,
except for Cal.
Uh, guys, I'm still right here.
Team Dinoco, Cruz!
Hire her. I don't care.
Lightning, now that you're retired...
I need you first thing Monday
morning for a photo shoot.
Yeah, all right, Mr. Sterling.
Whoa! Hang on now.
(CROWD CHEERING)
McQUEEN: What?
Why is my name up there?
You started the race.
That's how it works.
Wait, wait, now... Wait a minute. No!
Lightning wins, he decides
when he's done racing.
That was the deal.
Hi, I'm his lawyer.
You are not a nice guy.
Although, I got to say,
you do make a quality mudflap
at an affordable price.
(CLEARS THROAT) Hey, Sterling.
Why don't you and I
take a drive and talk?
Billionaire to billionaire.
- (REPORTERS CLAMORING)
- Cruz, over here.
Just one picture. How does it
feel to beat Jackson Storm?
- (LAUGHS)
- Take us through it,
- lap by lap.
- (CAMERAS FLASHING)
It was great! Uh, didn't expect this.
(LAUGHS)
Kid's got a lot of stuff, eh, Doc?
Well, she had a great teacher.
And now you get to decide
when you're done racing.
So what's it gonna be, Stinky?
Uh, Stickers.
(CHUCKLES)
Oh, I'm gonna keep racing.
But before that,
I got something I want to do.
Welcome all to historic Willy's Butte
for today's great exhibition of speed!
(ENGINES REVVING)
(WHOOPS) There she is! Cruz!
Oh, I love it. I love it. I love it.
(LAUGHS) Thanks, guys!
Nice paint, kiddo.
Pardon me. Big hat, coming through.
Get 'er done, 51! Whoo-hoo!
Great number. Was McQueen's idea.
He felt Hud would've
wanted you to have it.
I love it.
Oh, it's perfect. It's very old-school.
McQUEEN: Did someone
just say old-school?
NASH: Whoo-hoo! Yeah!
FAN: Oh, yeah! I like that.
It's bright, but I like it.
(ALL CHEERING)
FLO: Looking fabulous.
LUIGI: Favoloso.
- (LAUGHS)
- Trying something new. I like it.
Wow. Subtle.
Figured if I'm gonna be your crew chief,
I better do it in style.
What's Mr. Sterling gonna say?
I'm actually more worried
about what Tex is gonna say,
considering he, uh...
bought Rust-eze. Thanks, Tex!
(HORN HONKING MELODIOUSLY)
I made that Sterling fella
a Texas-sized offer!
So, you ready to start training?
I don't know. You ready to lose again?
Oh! Hope you've got your fluffy cloud.
I hope you got your drip pan.
Got my drip pan and I've taken my nap.
Bring it on, old man.
- Luigi.
- Go! Whoo-hoo!
(ROCK SONG PLAYING)
♪ I live my life out on the edge
♪ Yeah, I don't stop just 'cause it's red
♪ Let's push this thing
see what we get ♪
- (ALL CHEERING)
- TEX: Let's go, Team Dinoco!
♪ This black pavement
these yellow lines
♪ I pull exhaust into the night
♪ I feel my temperature rise
♪ Ride, ride
Ooh, ooh, ooh
♪ Ride, ride, yeah we gonna ride
♪ I used to sit inside my room
♪ Dreaming of things that I could do
♪ Too scared to put my
hands up on the wheel
♪ Now I'm with you and I can't look back
♪ It's such a rush but we're movin' fast
♪ I can't deny the way you make me feel
♪ Whoa, whoa, whoa
♪ I live my life out on the edge
♪ Yeah, I don't stop just 'cause it's red
♪ Let's push this thing see what we get
♪ This black pavement
these yellow lines
♪ I pull exhaust into the night
♪ I feel my temperature rise
♪ Ride, ride, ooh, ooh, ooh
Ride, ride, ooh, ooh, ooh
♪ Ride, ride, yeah we gonna ride
♪ Ride, ride, ride
Head on the floor
♪ Rock that ride
What you waiting for?
♪ Ride, ride, ride
Ride, ride, ride
♪ Head on the floor
♪ Rock that ride
♪ What you waiting for?
♪ Ride, ride
Ride, ride
♪ Ride, ride, yeah we gonna ride
♪ I live my life out on the edge
♪ Yeah, I don't stop just 'cause it's red
♪ Let's push this thing see what we get
♪ Ride, ride, ooh, ooh, ooh
Ride, ride, ooh, ooh, ooh
Ride, ride, yeah, we gonna
♪ Ride, ride, ride
We gonna ride
♪ Ride, ride
♪ Yeah, we gonna ride, ride, ride
♪ We gonna ride
Ride, ride
♪ Yeah, we gonna ride ♪
(MATER SINGING)
♪ My cup holder's happy
My tank is full
♪ My engine's running
like a Brahma bull
♪ My bumpers are polished
and talk about luck
♪ I just got a date
with an ice cream truck ♪
(DEVICE RINGS)
(LAUGHS) Huh? Ahh!
Shoot.
Hey, McQueen, you still there?
McQueen?
Ugh. Technology.