♪ Fun, fun, fun ♪
♪ And fancy-free ♪
♪ Full of fun and fancy-free ♪
♪ That's the way I wanna be ♪
♪ I don't let my troubles trouble me ♪
♪ Fancy-free
Full of the, full of fun ♪
♪ Got no time to worry none ♪
♪ Too busy singin' in the sun
Sweet sun ♪
♪ If you should have a chronic ache ♪
♪ Pills won't make you strong ♪
♪ The only tonic you should take ♪
♪ Is a teaspoonful of song ♪
♪ So if you'd really like to be ♪
♪ Happy-go-lucky, just like me ♪
♪ Drown your frowns, my
friend and you will see ♪
♪ You'll see
That you'll be full of fun ♪
♪ And fancy-free ♪
♪ Come along,
Lend an ear ♪
♪ See it for yourself ♪
♪ Meet a guy who's got a song ♪
♪ Troubles are on the shelf ♪
♪ He's so happy all the livelong day ♪
♪ Livin' life the simple way ♪
♪ Knowin' it's the only way to be ♪
♪ Just full of fun
Full of fun and fancy-free ♪
♪ Everyone keeps askin' me ♪
♪ My recipe for livin' ♪
♪ It's simple as the ABC's ♪
♪ And hardly seems worth givin' ♪
♪ I've tried it out in every way ♪
♪ It always sees me through ♪
♪ It's made me what I am today ♪
♪ That's why I'm tellin' you ♪
♪ I'm a happy-go-lucky fellow ♪
♪ Full of fun and fancy-free ♪
♪ You can make the whole
world seem mellow ♪
♪ If you take it in your stride like me ♪
♪ Don't cross a bridge
or peek 'round the corner ♪
♪ Until you're there ♪
♪ Just learn to smile and in a while ♪
♪ You'll find trouble's
a bubble of air ♪
♪ Get a happy-go-lucky feelin' ♪
♪ Keep it and I guarantee ♪
♪ That you'll find you'll wind
up livin' in the sun ♪
- ♪ So right ♪
-♪ Full of fun and fancy-free ♪
♪ Full of fun and fancy-free ♪
♪ That's the way I wanna be ♪
♪ I don't let my troubles trouble me ♪
♪ Now some folks like the heavy stuff ♪
♪ With titles five feet wide ♪
♪ Not me, I'm always out for fun ♪
- ♪ I like the lighter side, yes, sir ♪
- ♪ Hooray ♪
♪ Don't let my troubles trouble me ♪
♪ Don't cross a bridge or
peek 'round the corner ♪
♪ Until you're there ♪
♪ Just learn to smile and in a while ♪
♪ You'll find trouble's
a bubble of air ♪
♪ Get a happy-go-lucky feelin' ♪
You know, you worry too much.
In fact, everybody
worries too much.
Here. Just look at
the morning paper.
Turn to any page.
You'll find the whole
world worryin'...
about some future age.
But why get so excited?
What's gonna be is gonna be.
The end of the world's
been comin' since 1903.
That's, uh, B.C., of course.
♪ Don't cross a bridge or
peek 'round the corner ♪
♪ Until you're there ♪
♪ Just learn to smile and in a while ♪
♪ You'll find trouble ♪
You bet, you'll find trouble!
Take it easy, son.
Why, you're just a
bundle of nerves.
You see? Jumpy as a cat!
Comes from always
rushin' into things.
Now what have I done?
I guess I don't know
my own strength.
Sorry to upset you, miss.
Have you on your feet in a jiffy.
- Upsy-daisy.
- Mama!
Your mama isn't here, honey.
But if I can be of service,
the name is Cricket.
J. Cricket.
You can call me Jiminy.
Sorry!
Howdy, chum.
Why so glum?
Say, what's the matter?
You worried about somethin' too?
Never saw such a dismal pair.
A deadpan doll...
and a droopy bear.
You ought to try my recipe.
Be full of fun and fancy-free.
Life is a song... happy, gay.
So let's have some music.
Come on! What d'you say?
"Bongo"? Now, what in
the world is Bongo?
Oh! "A Musical Story
Sung by Dinah Shore."
Well, what are we waitin' for?
A ringer!
It's a gift.
Take it away, Dinah!
This is the story...
- of three bears.
- Yeah, I know.
The mama bear, the papa bear,
and the itsy-bitsy baby bear.
But it's not the story you expect.
This is a love story.
It's about a little girl bear...
and a big, burly,
brawny brown bear...
who wanted very much
to be her boyfriend.
But mostly, this is
a story about Bongo.
He was a circus bear.
He was born in the circus,
grew up in the circus.
In fact, Bongo was
the star of the circus.
Why, he could juggle and dance
while on a trapeze,
walk a tightrope with
the greatest of ease.
In jujitsu,
he was beyond compare.
Once threw a bull
at the county fair.
Super at wrestling
and lifting weights.
Outboxed the champs
of 17 states.
They all packed in
from near and far...
to see this death-defying star.
With mouths wide open,
they watched his ascent...
as he daringly climbed
to the top of the tent!
Then, for a grand climax,
he would gracefully
plunge 300 feet...
into a wet sponge!
Poor Bongo.
Naturally, you'd think
he'd be handled with kid gloves,
treated like a king...
and pampered like a baby.
But, no! He was tossed
around like an old shoe.
Bongo, the bear in the gilded cage.
His thoughts would wander
to an imaginary life...
far removed from the circus.
♪ Bongo, Bongo, Bongo ♪
Some half-forgotten
instinct kept calling him.
For you see, Bongo was a dreamer.
Hey, Bongo! Get going! You're on!
The call of the wild kept
ringing in his ears.
Psst! Hey. Bongo!
He couldn't ignore it any longer.
♪ Bongo, Bongo, Bongo ♪
He had to answer the call
of the great open spaces.
Come on out, Bongo.
♪ Bongo, Bongo ♪
Come on out, Bongo!
Bongo, Bongo.
He was crackin' up!
Bongo, Bongo!
- He was losin' his grip!
- Bongo, Bongo, Bongo!
He had to escape, to get away!
Just gotta get away!
- Bongo, Bongo!
- Gotta get away! Gotta get away.
- Bongo, Bongo, Bongo!
- Gotta, gotta, gotta!
Bongo! Bongo!
Bongo! Bongo! Bongo!
At last he was free.
Free.
Free?
But this was even better
than he'd expected!
"Oh, boy, "thought Bongo,
"this is livin'!"
He felt so good, he just had
to run around... and jump.
Why, he even tried to growl.
"Oh, boy! A tree. That's for me!"
Just right for climbin' too.
"Oh, well. What if I can't
climb a big old tree?
This is still the place
for a fellow like me."
Just lazy and loafin'...
and fancy-free.
♪ I love to hang around ♪
♪ The lazy countryside ♪
♪ Where things are nice and breezy ♪
♪ With nature's gang around ♪
♪ The lazy countryside ♪
♪ Where life is twice as easy ♪
♪ Where the crickets ♪
♪ You don't hear in the city ♪
♪ Keep a-hummin' in your ear
Oh, so pretty ♪
♪ And it's just too much for words ♪
♪ Listenin' to the
chorus of the birds ♪
♪ I like to stay around ♪
♪ The lazy countryside ♪
♪ And while away the hours ♪
♪ Just kind of play around ♪
♪ The lazy countryside ♪
♪ As free as bees and flowers ♪
♪ There's more fun in
takin' the sun in ♪
♪ And to roam the spaces wide ♪
♪ It's the place for me
Gee, but it's great to be ♪
♪ 'Round the lazy countryside ♪
♪ There's more fun in
takin' the sun in ♪
♪ And to roam the spaces wide ♪
♪ It's the place for me ♪
♪ Gee, but it's great to be ♪
♪ 'Round the lazy ♪
♪ Countryside ♪
"Oh, boy," thought Bongo,
"this is the stuff."
"To stretch out under
a canopy of stars...
"studding the velvet
softness of the night.
To sleep in the peace and
quiet of the woods."
The stillness of the night
descends like a sheltering veil.
Hush. All nature sleeps.
Then came the dawn.
Ohh. Bongo felt as
stiff as a board...
and as cranky as an old bear.
Bongo was discouraged.
A fine kind of bear
he'd turned out to be!
He didn't even know
how to act like a bear.
This rough, rugged
stuff wasn't for him.
Especially on an empty stomach.
Bongo thought, "This is
just too good to be true!
"I... I'm either hungry
or I'm still dreamin'.
"Ow! I'm awake!
It must be true.
Oh, this is much
better than dreamin'!"
"This must be heaven.
I-it can't be real!
"It's just too good to be true.
But let me go right on dreamin',
as long as I'm with you."
♪ This is too good ♪
♪ To be true ♪
♪ I can't believe it's real ♪
♪ Can it be you ♪
♪ I really see ♪
♪ I never knew ♪
♪ I'd find an angel ♪
♪ And out of the blue ♪
♪ You came to me ♪
♪ You're all the heavenly things ♪
♪ That I've been dreaming of ♪
♪ Don't spread your wings ♪
♪ And fly away ♪
♪ But if you're only ♪
♪ Passing through ♪
♪ Then take me to heaven with you ♪
♪ Or is this a dream ♪
♪ Too good to be ♪
♪ True ♪
♪ This is too good to be true ♪
♪ I can't believe it's real ♪
♪ Can it be you ♪
♪ I really see ♪
♪ I never knew I'd find an angel ♪
♪ Out of the blue you came to me ♪
♪ You're all the heavenly things ♪
♪ That I've been dreaming of ♪
♪ Don't spread your wings ♪
♪ Don't fly away ♪
♪ But if you're only ♪
♪ Passing through ♪
♪ Then take me to heaven with you ♪
♪ Or is this a dream ♪
♪ Too good to be ♪
♪ True ♪
The air grew still with a sudden chill.
No talk, no laughs, no chatter.
With the trees shaking, the ground
quaking, the crowd began to scatter.
Out of his lair came the third
bear, with murder in his eye.
He took in the scene of love
serene with jealousy and surprise.
He was the roughest,
toughest, meanest bear.
Lump jaw by name,
a villain for fair.
Well... what's this?
It's no dream.
It's a nightmare!
"He-He-Hello,"
was all Bongo could say.
"Kind of unfriendly.
Probably doesn't know
who I am."
"Just a moment.
This is my affair."
"He-He-Hello, Lulubelle, dear."
Gosh, Bongo was surprised.
Why should Lulubelle
turn against him?
That was no way
for a lady to act.
Lulubelle's feelings were hurt.
All right.
She'd give Mr. Bongo
just one more chance.
"What have I done?"
Poor Bongo.
♪ It was too good ♪
♪ To be true ♪
Gone were his dreams.
His world was shattered.
Why hadn't someone
ever told him about
all of these things that...
really mattered?
And now,
well, now it was just too late.
He'd never find out that
when bears are in love,
they always say it with a slap.
♪ When a bird loves a
bird he can twitter ♪
♪ When a puppy falls
in love he can yap ♪
♪ Every pigeon likes to coo
when he says I love you ♪
♪ But a bear likes to
say it with a slap ♪
♪ When a whippoorwill's
in love he can whipper ♪
♪ All the horses neck and
all the turtles snap ♪
♪ Every deer and every dove
has a way of makin' love ♪
♪ But a bear likes to
say it with a slap ♪
♪ You can ask any bear, Oh
There's nothin' to compare ♪
♪ With a love tap
Strong or weak ♪
♪ So if you're ready for romance
and you ever get the chance ♪
- ♪ Grab your girl
- Give her your cheek ♪
♪ So when love comes along ♪
♪ Don't be silly ♪
♪ Never ever waste your time ♪
♪ Like a sap ♪
♪ Let the others hug and kiss ♪
♪ But the bare facts are this ♪
♪ That a bear likes to
say it with a slap ♪
- ♪ Slap, slap ♪
♪ - Give me a love tap ♪
♪ Grab your bears ♪
♪ And swing 'em wide ♪
♪ Shake their fur and
scratch their hide ♪
♪ Give her a slap ♪
♪ Give her a cuff ♪
♪ Go 'round that floor ♪
♪ And strut your stuff ♪
♪ He slapped her once ♪
♪ And he missed her jaw ♪
♪ And he wound up smackin' ♪
♪ his mother-in-law ♪
♪ Now here comes Grandpa
gettin' in line ♪
♪ And here comes baby bear behind ♪
♪ When a bird loves a
bird he can twitter ♪
♪ When a puppy falls
in love he can yap ♪
♪ Every pigeon likes to coo ♪
♪ When he says I love you ♪
♪ But a bear likes to
say it with a slap ♪
♪ When a whippoorwill's
in love he can whipper ♪
♪ All of the horses neck
and all the turtles snap ♪
♪ Every deer and every dove
has a way of makin' love ♪
♪ But a bear likes to
say it with a slap ♪
♪ You can ask any bear ♪
♪ Oh, there's nothing to compare
with a love tap strong or weak ♪
♪ If you're ready for romance ♪
♪ And you ever get the chance
Grab your girl give her your cheek ♪
♪ So when love comes
along don't be silly ♪
♪ Never ever waste
your time like a sap ♪
♪ Let the others hug and kiss
but the bare facts are this ♪
♪ That a bear likes to
say it with a slap ♪
♪ Slap, slap ♪
♪ So when love comes
along don't be silly ♪
♪ Never ever waste
your time like a sap ♪
♪ Let the others hug and kiss
But the bare facts are this ♪
♪ That a bear likes to
say it with a slap ♪
"I love you, Lulubelle."
"I love you too, Bongo."
♪ You're all the heavenly things ♪
♪ That I've been dreaming of ♪
♪ Ohh don't spread your wings ♪
♪ And fly away ♪
♪ But if you're only ♪
♪ Passing through ♪
♪ Then take me to heaven with you ♪
♪ Or is this a dream ♪
♪ Too good to be ♪
- ♪ True ♪
♪ - Is it only a dream ♪
♪ Too good to be true ♪
Excuse me. There.
Now who says dreams
don't come true? Well!
Three is a crowd, they say.
So I'll drop back another day.
"Miss Luana Patten."
Well...
Of course, it's not cricket
to read other folks' mail, but...
"A party!
Tonight!"
"The house across the way.
"Charlie McCarthy.
Mortimer Snerd!
Edgar Bergen?"
Never heard of him.
"Please come!"
Why, I'd be delighted!
♪ Join the party
Come along ♪
♪ It's a cinch
Can't go wrong ♪
♪ Now's the time to see
what you can see ♪
♪ The house is just across the way ♪
♪ Better hurry
Don't delay ♪
♪ You'll be full of
fun and fancy-free ♪
Oh, dear. Nanny goats
and petticoats.
- I'm a caution.
- Yes, you certainly are.
Tell me, what is the secret
of your lovely complexion?
- Well, I... I use saddle soap.
- I see.
Yes. If I'm not being too
personal, Ophelia...
- Yeah?
- Uh, how old are you?
- Oh, I'm, uh, a girl my age.
- A girl your age?
- Yes.
- And how old is that?
- Uh, 28.
- Twenty-eight.
I thought you were a little
bit older than that.
Well, I knocked off a few years
for good behavior.
I don't care for that.
It's kid stuff.
Well, we're awfully glad
you came to our party.
- Well.
- Did you have fun?
Oh, yes, indeedy.
I thought Charlie made a pig of himself
with that chocolate cake.
- Oh, you're quite right.
- Yes, I am. Yes.
Yes, I agree with you.
- Well, good night, Luana.
- Good night, Ophelia.
- Bonne nuit, Mortimer.
- Uh... ma'am?
- Bonne nuit.
- Oh, yes, ma'am. Yeah, yeah. Bunny...
Uh, bunny, bunny wee,
bunny wee. Bun...
I don't know no bunny wee.
- Good night, Charlie.
- Uh, good night.
- You know, Ophelia, you look so sweet.
- Ah, what'd you say?
- I say, I think you look so sweet.
- Yes?
- I'm going to kiss you good night.
- Oh, help, help, help!
Help, he...
Isn't that a wonderful trick?
Yes, it is. Yes.
I wish I could enjoy
my first childhood...
as much as he does
his second.
Now, Luana, how would you like
another piece of cake
or some ice cream?
- No, thank you. I'm full up.
- Some candy?
- Care for a cigar?
- Me?
How about you, Mortimer?
Mortimer?
I don't smoke.
I don't mean that.
Well, what shall we do now?
Any suggestions?
How would you like
to go down to the city dump
and watch me slug rats?
- Certainly not.
- No?
How would you like to
hear me tell a story?
Oh, I'd love it.
Wouldn't you, Charlie?
Well, I, uh...
Y-y-yeah... no.
This is a story that
everyone should know.
Yes, but not everyone
should tell it.
And you know who.
Well, I'm going to
tell it anyway.
Now, many, many years ago...
I think I'll run out
and wind a sundial.
- You'll stay right here.
- Yes, sir.
Once upon a time, long, long ago...
Funny, nothing ever
happens nowadays.
There was a place
called Happy Valley.
Now, it was called Happy Valley...
because everyone
who lived there...
was happy.
No! Well, there's
a hunk of logic for you.
Are you listening, Mortimer?
- Happy Valley?
- That's right, yes.
Now just try and imagine it.
Can't you just close your eyes
and see it?
Well, I can't see very good
with my eyes closed.
My eyelids get in the way.
You create a picture
in your mind's eye.
That's not easy for him.
His mind gets in the way.
- Now try and paint a mental picture.
- Yeah.
I... I painted a barn once, I did.
- Well, that's very interesting.
- Yeah.
It was... It was a red barn.
It was. Yeah.
Well, forget the barn.
- Yeah.
- And try and picture Happy Valley.
- Well, I'll... I'll work on it.
- That's the spirit.
Yeah. Yeah.
I'll work on it.
Let's see...
Let's see, now.
It's... Oh, let's say
it's about...
Uh, what was the question?
- Happy Valley.
- Oh, yeah! Yeah. That's right. Yeah.
- Let's see, uh...
- Think hard!
Yeah.
Let's see, uh...
Oh, I'm tired.
All that work for nothin'.
- Can I try?
- Certainly.
Yes. I think
I can see it, Mr. Bergen.
It's beautiful.
Yes, it was one of
nature's garden spots,
nestled among
the green, rolling hills.
Can't you see the lovely brook
as it flows through the valley?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
The winding roads,
lined with stately trees.
Trees. Yeah.
Lush fields and prosperous
farms dot the landscape.
L-Landscape. Yeah.
And high on a hilltop
overlooking the valley,
- shining like a jewel, stands...
- My red barn.
No, no. It was
something much nicer.
- It was a majestic castle!
- Oh, that's pretty.
And something very precious is
kept within these castle walls.
- ♪ My ♪
- What is it?
It's a magic, singing harp. Listen.
♪ What a happy day ♪
♪ What a sunny sky, kind of
makes you sigh in a happy way ♪
♪ What a very merry day ♪
♪ All the world is gay ♪
♪ When your cares are light
and your heart takes flight ♪
♪ And you're swept away ♪
♪ The air is sweet with clover ♪
♪ The clouds are turning over ♪
♪ Oh, yes
They're turning over ♪
♪ Just to show their silver lining ♪
♪ My, what a happy day ♪
♪ Never knew such bliss
Never read of this ♪
♪ In a book or play ♪
♪ What a lovely day ♪
♪ What a great big gorgeous,
sumptuous thumping, bumptious ♪
♪ Hum-galumptious simply scrumptious ♪
♪ My, what a happy day ♪
♪ M-M-My, what a happy day ♪
♪ Never knew such bliss
Never read of this in a book or play ♪
♪ What a lovely day ♪
♪ What a great big gorgeous,
sumptuous thumping, bumptious ♪
♪ Hum-galumptious simply scrumptious ♪
♪ Oh, my, oh, my ♪
♪ What a happy ♪
♪ Day ♪
Yes, the voice of
this golden harp...
cast a magic spell of joy and
prosperity over the valley.
- But it was too good to last...
- I knew there was a catch in it.
- for one day...
- They built a schoolhouse.
No, no.
One day a mysterious shadow
crept over the valley.
And then something
dreadful happened!
What happened?
When the shadow lifted,
the golden harp was gone.
No longer was the valley happy,
for without the magic of the harp,
all was misery, misery, misery.
Just like the eighth grade.
Desolation spread over the land.
Everything was drying up.
- Dry rot.
- Yes, isn't it?
- Charlie.
- Yes, sir.
The fields of golden
corn turned to dust.
Kerplop.
The laughing brook flowed no more.
To think that this was
once Happy Valley!
Now it's Gruesome Gulch.
Days pass, weeks pass.
I pass. New deal.
What happened to all the people?
Well, suppose we look in
on these humble peasants.
- Is that a peasant?
- That's a cow, stupid.
Well, at least they had milk.
Well, she used to be a
good milker. But now...
She's an udder failure.
She was the bosom friend
of a once-proud family.
Well, they're certainly out
of the high rent district.
And there they are,
three poor farmers, gripped
by the pangs of starvation.
Still alive, still breathing,
sharing a pitiful
crust between them.
Share and share alike.
Sharing and staring.
Staring and sharing.
Uh, just tell it, don't ham it.
But are their spirits broken?
Have they lost hope?
Yes. Men facing famine,
naught left but beans.
Ahem. Bean, you mean.
If it were one man
and three beans...
But, no. One bean and three men.
Well, at least there
are no bones in it.
Just look at that
miserable creature,
doggedly struggling
to maintain life,
a gaunt, lean bag of
bones and feathers.
Truly a picture of despair.
But Donald doesn't whimper.
- Donald doesn't give up.
- Shut up!
I can't stand it!
Easy, Donald. Easy!
There. There, now.
There. Easy, Donald.
I... I'll be all right.
Yeah. I'll be all right.
I'll be all right.
He says he's all
right, but I wonder.
He's suffered too much.
What diabolical thought is being
hatched in the fevered brain...
of this poor, demented duck?
Donald! No! No!
Nice bossy, bossy.
- Nice old cowsy wowsy.
- Donald!
Donald! No, Donald!
Give it here! Let me...
I just gotta eat.
I'm so... hungry.
The little fellow was
completely out of his head.
- Cut it out, will ya? I get the idea!
- He was a pitiful sight.
- Weeks without food. Poor Donald.
- Yeah, poor me!
It was all they could do to restrain him.
You see, he had just about reached...
- the end of his rope.
- Yeah.
Oh, it was a sorry
predicament indeed.
What to do? What to do?
Well, Donald may be nuts, but he's
got the right idea. Kill the cow.
Oh, no, Charlie! The cow
was their best friend.
Well, a friend in need
is a friend indeed.
- So what?
- So, they need some steak.
No! If you're gonna kill the cow,
I don't wanna hear
the rest of the story.
Well, she wouldn't have to know.
They could sneak up on her
and surprise her.
Yeah, that's what we'll do.
- We'll kill the cow.
- Oh, no, Charlie. You mustn't.
We'll get a stranglehold
on her while she's asleep.
- a-a-and then push her off the cliff.
- Oh, no!
I ain't a-gonna listen
to the story.
Well, it'll be your fault
if they starve to death.
- Why don't they sell the cow?
- That's just what they did.
Well, why didn't you say so
in the first place,
and save a lot of time?
I could save a lot of time
by not telling the story at all!
Your idea is not without merit.
Well, back to the
scene of desolation.
Things are beginning to
look much brighter now,
because as Mickey goes
to the village to sell the cow,
the thought of prosperity...
brings new hope
to the famished farmers.
Even Donald has fully recovered,
for soon their long-empty plates...
will overflow with food.
Hey, look! ♪ Turkey,
lobster sweet potato pie ♪
♪ Pancakes piled up
'til they reach the sky ♪
♪ I wanna eat and eat
and eat and eat ♪
♪ And eat until I die ♪
♪ Turkey, lobster sweet potato pie ♪
♪ Pancakes piled up
'til they reach the sky ♪
♪ Lots of starches
Lots of greens ♪
♪ Fancy chocolate-covered... ♪
Beans!
- What d'you mean, beans?
- Yeah, fellows.
I sold the cow for
some magic beans!
Beans!
But Donald!
These are not ordinary beans!
They're magic beans!
If you plant these beans in the light of
a full moon, do you know what'll happen?
Yes! We get more beans!
- No, no, Donald!
- Magic beans! Phooey!
Poor Mickey,
cheated into trading his cow
for a handful of beans.
Tsk, tsk, tsk. What a mean trick!
Swindling an innocent farmer
out of all he owned...
and lying to him, telling him
that the beans were magic.
Planted in the light
of a full moon!
What a shame to deceive a
simple little peasant.
Magic beans, indeed!
- Light of a full moon.
- Bergen? Oh, Bergen!
- What?
- There's something moving.
Why, yes. Well, maybe there
is some magic in them!
All right, now let's all keep
quiet and see what happens.
Mmm.
And all through the night, it grew,
onward and upward.
That thing is a menace to aviation.
And so, with the coming of dawn,
we find the bewildered farmers
staring at a mammoth castle,
miles above the earth.
Their curiosity was aroused,
nothing could hold them back.
Who lives there? Man or monster?
Friend or foe?
A princess or a dragon?
Well, search me.
What drew them toward
this place of mystery?
Hunger? Desperation?
Or perhaps it was
love of adventure.
What a fantastic experience,
perhaps mortal man...
has never before set foot
on this strange land.
- Well, somebody did.
- Oh, gosh! Who made them?
Well, it wasn't Cinderella.
Soon they reached the moat
surrounding the castle.
But this didn't stop them.
On they went, as if drawn
by some irresistible force.
And then, suddenly, without
warning, out of the sky above...
Ooh, dragonflies!
Yeah. A-flyin' front
and draggin' behind.
- Gee, what whoppers!
- Yeah. Bombers!
Come back and fight!
Finally, they reached the castle.
The hard way.
This was the biggest
adventure of their lives.
Forgotten was their hunger,
forgotten was their fear.
It took courage to scale
these massive steps,
to make this journey
into the unknown.
But these stouthearted
lads never faltered.
Three minds with but
a single thought.:
What mystery lurked within
those cold, forbidding walls?
What strange spell hovered
over this gloomy place?
Will no one answer?
Are they walking into a trap?
Do they go in?
You know, you could stand
some rehearsal on this story.
Inside, the tremendous hall
was as silent as a tomb.
Not a sign of life anywhere.
Caught with his pants...
- Charlie!
- Caught with his pants...
- Well, his slip was showing.
They gazed in speechless wonder,
almost afraid to breathe.
Suddenly they looked up.
What was it?
Food! Yum, yum, yum, yum!
Let me at it!
Oh! Who's there? Who is it?
- That's the harp!
- Boy, oh, boy!
How'd you get here?
I was kidnapped by
that wicked giant!
- Oh. A... A giant!
- A giant!
- A giant?
- Bigger than 40 men.
- Oh, no!
An ogre who had the power to turn
himself into anything, man or beast.
That calls for a drink.
It was this heartless monster that
swooped down under cover of darkness,
carried off the golden harp and...
- brought ruin to Happy Valley.
- No!
- I'm a giant.
- You are not.
- You're nothing of the kind.
- Well, I'm a small giant.
- No, you're not.
- I'm, uh... I'm tougher than 40 men.
- You're not.
- Well... uh, 20 men.
- No.
- No? Ten men?
Aren't you ashamed of yourself,
Charlie? Why do you act like that?
I don't know. I guess it's just
a stage I'm goin' through.
- Well, take off that moustache.
- Yeow!
Now go over there and
behave yourself.
Yes, sir. Everything I do is wrong.
But why did the giant
want to steal the harp?
Because he was cruel and selfish. He
didn't care what happened to the valley.
He just wanted someone
to sing him to sleep.
Well, why didn't he
turn on the radio?
Well, they didn't have
radios in those days.
Yeah. That's why they
called it Happy Valley.
- What did the giant look like?
- Well, he was...
Oh... I'll try and show you.
He looked something like this.
Ha. Looks like my pig Smedley.
Never mind the
self-portraits. Ha-ha.
Well, no, that isn't right.
He... He looked more like...
more like this.
There he is now. And the giant
came home for dinner, roaring...
- Drunk.
- I was not!
- I mean, he was not.
- No.
Down the castle hall
he came, roaring...
Fe, fi, fo, fum!
♪ Fe, fi, fo, fum ♪
♪ He, hi, ho, hum ♪
♪ I'm a most amazing guy
A most amazing guy am I ♪
♪ Fe, fi, fo, fum ♪
♪ He, hi, ho, hum ♪
♪ I'm the stuff, I'm tellin'
you for here's what I can do ♪
♪ I can change myself into an elf ♪
♪ Fly up high like the birdies ♪
♪ I can disappear into atmosphere ♪
Peekaboo. ♪ 'Cause I
know the magic wordies ♪
♪ Fi, fo, fe, foy
Fe, fe, fe, fe ♪
Fifi? I don't know no Fifi.
Those are his magic
words, you know.
Fe, fi, fo, fum.
- I smell...
- You're telling us!
Wait. He may be smarter
than he looks.
Oh, I hope he doesn't find them.
Hey, Giant, you're getting warm.
Well, don't tell him!
- Behind the jar, stupid.
- Charlie!
Pot roast! Chocolate pot roast!
With stispacio...
With dismashmee...
With dismash...
With green gravy.
Feedy, fidey,
fodey,
fum!
Gesundheit.
Oh, no, you don't!
You can't get away
from Willie.
I gotcha!
I think I gotcha.
Yeah, I gotcha.
Willie.
What?
He'll have to talk fast
to get out of this one.
Well, you leave it
to Mickey. Just watch.
Ten, twenty, thirty, forty.
Boy, what a life line!
But what's this here?
What is it? What is it!
Uh-oh! I can't believe it!
- Is it bad?
- Why, i-it says here...
that you can change
yourself into anything!
Sure, sure! You wanna see me?
I can change myself
into the darndest things!
Go on, gimme somethin'.
- Anything!
- Anything?
Anything.
See? Mickey never misses a trick.
- He's got a good idea.
- Well, uh...
Can you change into a fly?
A cute, teeny-weeny,
itsy-bitsy housefly?
That's it. A housefly.
Aw, you don't want a fly.
How about a bunny
with long, pink ears?
Ha. Well, of course,
if you can't do a fly, why, uh...
All right. A fly.
- Why?
- Well, they're, uh...
- Because.
- Okay.
A teeny-weeny fly.
With pink wings.
Now for the magic wordies.
♪ Fe, fi, fo, fum
He, hi, ho, hum ♪
♪ I'm a most amazing guy
Te, ti, te, ti, te, ti ♪
You sure you don't
want a pink bunny?
Hey, what is this?
You think you fool Willie.
Yeah, a couple more good ideas
like that and they're finished.
Well, I'll admit the little
fellows are in a bad fix.
But Mickey isn't one to
give up without a struggle.
And with a little luck,
they may still pull through.
This isn't the first time
Mickey's been in a tight spot.
Anybody wanna buy
a tall, thin mouse?
No, thank you.
Uh, I mean no.
Yes, things look pretty
dark for the prisoners.
Looks like their goose is cooked.
Oh, Fate may yet deal
them a winning hand.
Don't forget,
there's still the magic harp.
She knows the giant's weakness.
She could be my weakness.
There might still be
a chance of escape...
if she could only use
her magic voice
to put the giant to sleep.
If she can't,
I know who can.
Let's all be quiet now,
and see.
♪ In my favorite dream ♪
♪ Everyone is so delightful ♪
♪ No one's mean or spiteful ♪
♪ In my favorite dream ♪
♪ Yes, and in my favorite dream ♪
♪ There my heart
can go romancing ♪
♪ Dancing to a heavenly theme ♪
♪ But there's something else
I look forward to ♪
♪ It's a secret ♪
♪ But here's a clue ♪
♪ He's my favorite ♪
♪ You know who ♪
♪ You're the hero of ♪
♪ My most favorite ♪
♪ Dream ♪
Oh, mercy. Forgive us.
♪ In his right vest pocket ♪
♪ You'll find the key ♪
♪ The right vest pocket
Go carefully ♪
I'll smash... Ah... I'll smash...
Where is he?
Hello?
Nightmare.
Oh, boy.
- He made it!
- He did?
- Here he comes with the key!
- Let me have it, Mickey!
Well, it looks like
success at last.
Free from the clutches
of that terrible monster.
And now to find
the beanstalk,
climb down and
return home in triumph,
with a big surprise
for Happy Valley.
But wait... Mickey's going
to make doubly sure.
He's taking no chances.
Just in case the giant
might wake up.
Should have left
well enough alone.
Come back here!
And there goes the giant!
He's helpless now, tumbling
over and over and over,
down, down, down, down.
And so with the passing
of the wicked giant,
Happy Valley echoed once again
with song and laughter.
For with the return
of the magic harp,
peace and prosperity reigned
throughout the land.
- And the people of the valley...
- We know.
Lived happily ever after.
You're a wonderful storyteller,
Mr. Bergen. Isn't he, Charlie?
Simply thrilling.
You're even better than the
old-fashioned sleeping pill.
What's the matter, Mortimer?
Oh, the poor giant got
killed, that he did.
- I don't like them sad endings.
- Oh, now, you don't understand.
W-Willie was a nice giant, he was.
He just got too big
for his britches.
- But you don't understand.
- No, don't touch me.
I'll be all right.
Oh, excuse me.
What I'm trying
to explain, Mortimer,
is that Willie the Giant
didn't actually exist.
- No?
- No.
He's a metaphysical phenomenon
of your subconscious mind,
a phantasmagoria of
your mental faculties.
- Yeah?
- In other words,
just a figment of
your imagination.
- No!
- Yes.
So there's nothing
to be upset about.
Hey! Has anybody seen anything...
of a teensy-weensy little mouse?
No. I-I-I, uh...
Oh, Mr. Bergen!
Bergen, speak to me.
Speak to me.
What's the matter with him?
Somethin' he ate?
Uh, no. It's, uh...
It's a fig, uh, fig...
fig-a-mentation of his imagination.
- No!
- Yeah.
Well, uh, good night, Willie.
Uh, don't slam the roof.
You might wake Mr. Bergen.
♪ Now some folks don't
believe in giants ♪
♪ Castles up above ♪
♪ And others say that
bears don't talk ♪
♪ And never fall in love ♪
♪ If you really wanna find ♪
♪ Happiness
Peace of mind ♪
♪ Believe in all your dreams ♪
♪ And you will see ♪
♪ You'll be full of fun and fancy ♪
♪ Free and full of fun ♪
♪ And fancy-free ♪