Read the charges.
Dr. Jumba Jookiba,
lead scientist of Galaxy
Defense Industries,
you stand before this council
accused of illegal
genetic experimentation.
How do you plead?
Not guilty!
My experiments are only theoretical,
completely within legal boundaries.
We believe you actually
created something.
Created something? Ha!
But that would be
irresponsible and unethical.
I would never, ever...
make more than one.
What is that monstrosity?
Monstrosity?
What you see before you is
the first of a new species.
I call it experiment 6-2-6.
He is bulletproof, fireproof
and can think faster
than supercomputer.
He can see in the dark and move
objects 3,000 times his size.
His only instinct, to destroy
everything he touches!
So, it is a monster.
Hey, just a little one.
It is an affront to nature.
It must be destroyed!
Calm yourself, Captain Gantu.
Perhaps it can be reasoned with.
Experiment 6-2-6, give us some
sign you understand any of this.
Show us that there is something
inside you that is good.
Meega, nala kweesta!
So naughty!
I didn't teach it that.
Place that idiot
scientist under arrest!
I prefer to be called
evil genius!
And as for that abomination...
it is the flawed product
of a deranged mind.
It has no place among us.
Captain Gantu, take him away.
With pleasure.
Uncomfortable?
Oh, good!
The council has banished you
to exile on a desert asteroid.
So, relax, enjoy the trip,
and don't get any ideas.
These guns are locked onto
your genetic signature.
They won't shoot anyone but you.
Ow! Why, you...
May I remind the Captain
that he is on duty.
Secure the cell!
Aye, Captain.
Captain on deck.
All ahead full.
Does this look infected
to you?
Quiet, you.
- Gunfire in the cell bay!
- Open a channel.
He's loose on Deck C!
Red alert. Seal off the deck!
Security, converge on Door 7!
Deadly force authorized.
Fire on sight! Fire on sight!
There he is!
Security to bridge.
It's in the ventilation system.
He's headed for the power...
grid.
What was that?
I don't think he's
on the ship anymore.
Confirmed. He's taken
a police cruiser.
Yeah. He took the red one.
That's it!
We got it. We got it!
Hyperdrive activated.
System charging.
He's engaged his H-drive!
Warning, guidance is not
functional.
Pursuit Commander, that crazy
trog is about to make a jump!
Break formation!
Get clear of that ship!
Navigation failure.
Do not engage hyper...
Get me Galactic Control.
Where is he?
He's still in hyperspace.
Where will he exit?
Calculating now.
Quadrant 17, section
0-0-5, area 51.
A planet called Ee-arth.
I want an expert on this
planet in here now!
What is that?
Water. Most of the
planet is covered in it.
He won't survive in water. His
molecular density is too great.
No...
Of course.
How much time do we have?
We have projected his landing
at three hours, 42 minutes.
Oh, we have to gas the planet.
Hold it! Hold everything!
Earth is a protected
wildlife reserve.
Yeah. We've been using it to
rebuild the mosquito population
which, need I remind you,
is an endangered species!
Am I to assume you
are the expert?
Oh, I don't know about expert.
Agent Pleakley at your service.
Can we not simply
destroy the island?
No! Crazyhead!
The mosquito's food of choice,
primitive humanoid life forms,
have colonies all
over that planet.
Are they intelligent?
No, but they're very delicate.
In fact, every time an
asteroid strikes their planet,
they have to begin life
all over.
It's fascinating, isn't it? With
this, I've been able to study...
What if our military
forces just landed there?
Well, that'd be a bad idea!
These are extremely
simple creatures, miss.
Landing there would create mass
mayhem and planet-wide panic!
A quiet capture would require
an understanding of 6-2-6
that we do not possess!
Who, then, Mr. Pleakley, would
you send for his extraction?
Does he have a brother?
Close grandmother, perhaps?
Friendly cousin?
Neighbor with a beard?
He got away?
I'm sure this comes as
no surprise to you.
I designed this creature
for to be unstoppable.
Which is precisely why you
must now bring him back.
What? Me?
And to reward you,
we are willing to trade your
freedom for his capture.
6-2-6 will not come easily.
Maybe direct hit from plasma cannon
might stun him long enough to...
Plasma cannon granted. Do we
have a bargain, Dr. Jumba?
But it's a delicate planet!
Who's going to control him?
You will.
Very good, Your Highness.
I didn't quite...
You're not joking!
So, tell me, my
little one-eyed one,
on what poor, pitiful,
defenseless planet
has my monstrosity
been unleashed?
One, two, three, four...
Stop. Stop.
Lilo, why are you all wet?
It's sandwich day.
Every Thursday, I take Pudge the
fish a peanut butter sandwich.
Pudge is a fish?
And today we were out
of peanut butter!
So I asked my sister what to give
him and she said a tuna sandwich.
I can't give Pudge tuna!
Do you know what tuna is?
- Fish?
- It's fish!
If I gave Pudge tuna,
I'd be an abomination!
I'm late because I had
to go to the store
and get peanut butter 'cause
all we have is stinkin' tuna!
Lilo, Lilo, why is this
so important?
Pudge controls the weather.
You're crazy.
Please! Please!
Everybody calm down!
Girls...
- Lilo...
- I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
I won't do it again!
Maybe we should call
your sister.
No! I'll be good!
I want to dance.
I practiced.
I just want to dance.
Ooh, she bit me.
I called your sister.
She said to wait for her
here on the porch.
We'll try again on Sunday.
Does this look infected to you?
Yeah.
You better not have rabies.
If you have rabies, the dogcatcher
is going to have to cut...
Are you going to play dolls?
You don't have a doll.
This is Scrump.
I made her, but her
head is too big.
So I pretend a bug laid eggs
in her ears, and she's upset
because she only has a
few more days to...
Lilo!
Lilo?
Oh, no.
You better be home.
Hey! Watch where you're going!
Stupidhead!
Oh, Lilo!
Lilo! Open the door, Lilo!
Go away.
Lilo? We don't have
time for this.
Leave me alone to die.
Come on, Lilo that social worker's
going to be here any minute!
You are so finished
when I get in there!
Oh, I'm going to stuff you in
the blender, push puree,
then bake you into a pie and
feed it to the social worker!
And when he says, mmm, this is great.
What's your secret? I'm going to say...
Love and nurturing.
Hi...
You must be the...
The stupidhead.
Oh, you know, I'm
really sorry about that
and if I'd known who you were,
of course I never would've...
I can pay for that.
It's a rental.
Are you the guardian
in question?
Yes. I'm Nani.
Nice to meet you, Mister...
Bubbles.
Mr. Bubbles. That's a strange...
Yes, I know.
Are you going to
invite me in, Nani?
I thought we could sit
out here and talk.
I don't think so.
Right...
This way.
Wait here.
Hey!
So, lemonade?
Do you often leave your
sister home alone?
No. Never.
Well, except for just now.
I had to run to the store
to get some...
You left the stove on
while you were out?
Low heat! Just a simmer.
It's coming along great.
I found that this morning.
Lilo! There you are.
Honeyface, this is Mr. Bubbles.
Nice to meet you.
Your knuckles say Cobra.
Cobra Bubbles.
You don't look like
a social worker.
I'm a special classification.
Did you ever kill anyone?
We're getting off the subject.
Let's talk about you.
Are you happy?
I'm adjusted. I eat
four food groups
and look both ways before
crossing the street
and take long naps
and get disciplined.
Disciplined?
Yeah. She disciplines me real good.
Sometimes five times a day.
- With bricks.
- No...
Bricks?
In a pillowcase.
Okay! That's enough
sugar for you.
Why don't you run along,
you little cutie.
The other social workers just
thought she was a scream.
Thirsty?
Let me illuminate to you
the precarious situation
in which you have found
yourself.
I am the one they call
when things go wrong,
and things have
indeed gone wrong.
My friends need to be punished.
Call me next time
you're left here alone.
Yep.
In case you're wondering,
this did not go well.
You have three days
to change my mind.
Lilo!
Why didn't you wait
at the school?
You were supposed to wait there!
Lilo!
Do you not understand?
Do you want to be taken away?
Answer me!
- No!
- No, you don't understand?
- No, what?
No!
You're such a pain!
So why don't you sell me
and buy a rabbit instead?
At least a rabbit would
behave better than you!
Go ahead! Then you'll be happy because
it'll be smarter than me too!
And quieter!
You'll like it, 'cause
it's stinky, like you!
Go to your room!
I'm already in my room!
Hey.
I brought you some pizza,
in case you were hungry.
We're a broken family,
aren't we?
No.
Maybe, a little.
Maybe a lot.
I shouldn't have yelled at you.
We're sisters. It's our job.
Yeah, well, from now on...
I like you better as
a sister than a mom.
Yeah?
And you like me better as a
sister than a rabbit, right?
Yes.
Yes, I do.
I hit Mertle Edmonds today.
You hit her?
Before I bit her.
You bit her.
Lilo, you shouldn't...
People treat me different.
They just don't know
what to say.
I'll tell you what.
If you promise not
to fight anymore
I promise not to yell at you,
except on special occasions.
Tuesdays and bank
holidays would be good.
Yeah? Would that be good?
Oh! My camera's full again.
Aren't they beautiful?
A falling star!
I call it! Get out! Get out!
I have to make a wish!
Can't you go any faster?
Oh, no! Gravity is
increasing on me.
No, it's not!
It is too, Lilo. The same
thing happened yesterday.
You rotten sister! Your
butt is crushing me!
Why do you act so weird?
It's me again.
I need someone to be my friend.
Someone who won't run away.
Maybe send me an angel.
The nicest angel you have.
What we when hit?
There it is. It stay
jammed under the fender.
We better call somebody.
We're looking for something
that can defend itself...
Something that won't die.
Something sturdy, you know?
Like a lobster.
Lilo, you lolo. Do we
have a lobster door?
No. We have a dog door.
We are getting a dog.
So nice to see your pretty
face again!
Jumba?
We need your name and address
at the bottom of the form...
The kennel's back this way.
Go. Pick someone out.
Hello?
Are there any aminals in here?
Hello!
Hi.
Oh, yes. All of our dogs
are adoptable.
Except that one!
What is that thing?
A dog, I think. But it
was dead this morning.
It was dead this morning?
Well, we thought it was dead.
It was hit by a truck.
I like him!
Come here, boy.
Wouldn't you like a
different dog?
We have better dogs, dear.
Not better than him.
He can talk! Say hello.
Dogs can't talk, dear.
He did.
Does it have to be this dog?
Yes, he's good. I can tell.
You'll have to think of
a name for him.
His name is Stitch.
Now, that's not a real name...
in Iceland, but here,
it's a good name.
Stitch it is.
And there's a two
dollar license fee.
I want to buy him!
Can I borrow two dollars?
He's all yours.
You're all mine.
Well, what's he doing?
Keep quiet.
He's listening for us.
How good is his hearing?
I mean, can he...
Why don't you run?
Coming! I'm coming!
Stop!
I have just determined this
situation to be far too hazardous!
Don't worry, I won't hit her.
No! That girl is a part of
the mosquito food chain.
Here! Educate yourself.
Using a little girl for a shield.
This is low, even for you!
Tear him apart with all
both my bare hands!
Have you lost your mind?
What is it, Stitch?
We cannot be seen!
Bad dog, barking at nothing!
You can't shoot, and
you can't be seen.
Look at you!
You look like a monster.
We have to blend in.
Okay, I got to get to work.
Stick around town and stay
out of the roads, okay?
I'll meet you at 1:00.
Okay, I guess we should be going.
What about Stitch?
My friends!
What do you want?
I'm sorry I bit you and pulled your
hair and punched you in the face.
Apology not accepted.
Now get out of my way
before I run you over.
I got a new dog.
His name is Stitch.
That is the ugliest thing
I have ever saw.
- Yeah.
Eww! Get it away from me!
I'm gonna get a disease!
Somebody do something!
Oh, great! He's loose.
His destructive programming
is taking effect.
He will be irresistibly
drawn to large cities
where he will back up sewers,
reverse street signs and
steal everyone's left shoe.
It's nice to live on an island
with no large cities.
Are you okay?
Hey, over here, little buddy.
When you're ready to give
up just let us know, heh?
Yeah!
This is you.
This is your badness level.
It's unusually high for
someone your size.
We have to fix that.
Ay-yi-yi, Lilo!
Your dog cannot sit
at the table.
Stitch is troubled.
He needs desserts.
Oh, you didn't even eat
your sweet potato.
I thought you liked them.
Desserts!
David!
I got a new dog.
You sure it's a dog?
He used to be a collie
before he got ran over.
Hey...
Howzit, Nani?
Did you catch fire again?
Nah, just the stage.
Listen, I was wondering if you're
not doing anything this...
David, I told you, I can't.
I...
I got a lot to deal with
right now.
I know. I just figured you
might need some time...
You smell like a lawn mower.
Look, I got to go.
The kid at Table 3's
throwing poi again.
Maybe some other time, okay?
Don't worry.
She likes your butt
and fancy hair.
I know. I read her diary.
She thinks it's fancy?
Aha! Look what I find!
Get restraints!
- Right.
- Take that! Hurry!
Hold still just a...
Hey, Nani!
Is that your dog?
All is well.
Please, go about your business.
I'm okay.
Oh, your head looks swollen.
Actually, she's just ugly.
Darling. He's joking.
Ugly, look at me...
This is not working out.
But...
Yeah?
Well, who wants to
work at this stupid...
fakey luau anyway.
Come on, Lilo.
Did you lose your job
because of Stitch and me?
Nah. The manager's
a vampire
and he wanted me to join
his legion of the undead.
I knew it.
This is a great home.
You'll like it a lot.
See?
Lilo...
Comfy.
- Hey!
What is the matter with you?
Be careful of the little angel!
It's not an angel, Lilo.
I don't even think it's a dog.
We just have to take
him back.
He's just cranky because
it's his bedtime.
He's creepy, Lilo.
I won't sleep while he's
loose in the house.
You're loose in the house all
the time and I sleep just fine!
Hey, what are you doing?
Stop that, Stitch!
Hey!
Look at him, Lilo.
He's obviously mutated
from something else.
We have to take him back.
He was an orphan and
we adopted him!
What about ohana?
He hasn't been here that long.
Neither have I.
Dad said ohana means family.
Ohana means family.
Family means...
Nobody gets left behind.
Or?
Or forgotten.
I know. I know. I hate it when
you use ohana against me.
Don't worry,
you can sleep right next to me.
Look how curious the puppy is.
This is my room, and
this is your bed.
This is your dolly and bottle.
See? Doesn't spill.
I filled it with coffee.
Good puppy. Now get into bed.
Hey! That's mine!
Down!
Be careful of that! You don't
touch this! Don't ever touch it!
No! Don't pull on her head!
She's recovering from surgery.
No! That's from my blue period.
There.
You know, you wreck
everything you touch.
Why not try and make
something for a change?
Wow. San Francisco.
Save me!
No more caffeine for you.
This little girl is wasting
her time.
6-2-6 cannot be taught to ignore
its destructive programming.
Push that over.
- What are you doing?
- Nothing!
- Say, I want to try it on.
- No!
Share! Let me try it!
Hey! Ow! You're just
jealous 'cause I'm pretty!
Don't move. A mosquito has
chosen me as her perch.
She's so beautiful.
Look, another one.
And another one!
Why, it's a whole flock.
And they like me!
They're nuzzling my
flesh with their noses.
Now, they're, they're...
I think it might be a koala.
An evil koala.
I can't even pet it.
It keeps staring at me,
like it's going to eat me.
Hello?
Nani?
Are you there?
- Now, this is interesting.
- What?
6-2-6 was designed
to be a monster
but now he has
nothing to destroy.
You see, I never gave
him a greater purpose.
What must it be like
to have nothing...
Not even memories to visit
in the middle of the night?
That's the Ugly Duckling.
See? He's sad because he's all
alone and nobody wants him
but on this page, his
family hears him crying
and they find him.
Then the Ugly Duckling
is happy
because he knows
where he belongs.
Want to listen to the King?
You look like an Elvis fan.
Nani.
Nani!
Yeah?
Look.
We can't go on together
With suspicious minds...
Cious minds...
Can build our dreams...
On suspicious minds...
Heard you lost your job.
Well, actually, I just quit
that job because, you know,
the hours are just not conducive to
the challenges of raising a child...
Hey!
I am so sorry about that.
What is that thing?
That's my puppy.
Really?
Thus far, you have been adrift in the
sheltered harbor of my patience,
but I cannot ignore
you being jobless.
Do I make myself clear?
Perfectly.
And next time I see this dog, I expect
it to be a model citizen. Capisce?
Yes?
New job.
Model citizen.
Good day.
Mrs. Hasagawa?
I'm here to answer
your newspaper ad.
Elvis Presley was a model
citizen.
I've compiled a list of his
traits for you to practice.
Number one is dancing.
I can't talk now, dear.
I'm waiting for someone
to answer my ad.
That's why I'm here.
Hands on your hips.
Now follow my lead.
Ah! That's my want ad.
I know!
Why is everything so dark?
I am all about coffee.
Let's move on to step two.
Elvis played guitar. Here.
Hold it like this, and
put your fingers here.
See? Now you try.
And I make great cappuccinos
and lattes with...
I wish I could, Nani,
but I just hired Teddy
and with tourist season
ending...
Concierge-er-ing is my life.
I just love to answer phones...
This is the face of romance.
She looks like she could
use some lovin'.
Oh, we might have something.
Good. Now kiss her.
I'm sure Elvis had
his bad days too.
I'm all about saving people?
Actually, I do think
we have an opening.
- Really?
- Okay, this is it.
Time to bring it all together.
Oh, that'd be so great!
You have no idea how
badly I need this job.
It's all you!
Knock 'em dead!
Don't crowd him!
Hey, knock it off!
Hey, Lilo!
Howzit, Nani?
We've been having
a bad day.
Hey, I might not be a doctor
but I know that there's no
better cure for a sour face
than a couple of boards
and some choice waves.
What you think?
I think that's a great idea.
Oh, can't complain, Mom.
I'm camping out with
a convicted criminal
and, oh, I had my head
chewed on by a monster!
Wait...
Something is not right.
6-2-6 is returning
willingly to water.
Oh, hold on, Mom,
another call.
Mr. Pleakley, you are overdue.
I want a status report.
Oh, things are going well.
He cannot swim!
Things are going well.
Jumba, aren't they going well?
Why will he risk drowning?
Jumba?
Jumba, help me out here.
I would have expected you back
by now, with 6-2-6 in hand.
Just a few things left to
pack and we'll be...
Hang up.
We are going swimming.
Yeah!
Lilo!
What happened?
Oh, some lolo must have
stuffed us in the barrel.
Where's Stitch?
Get off of her!
What happened?
Stitch dragged her down.
We lost Stitch!
Lilo? Lilo, look at me. Look
at me, baby. Are you hurt?
No.
He's unconscious, but
I think he's alive.
David, take Lilo.
This isn't what it looks like.
We were... It's just that...
I know you're trying, Nani,
but you need to think about
what's best for Lilo...
Even if it removes you
from the picture.
I'll be back tomorrow
morning for Lilo.
I'm sorry.
Nani? Is there
something I can do?
No, David.
I need to take Lilo home now.
We have a lot to talk
about, you know.
Thanks.
You know, I really believed
they had a chance.
Then you came along.
Lilo, honey...
We have to...
Don't worry. You're nice, and
someone will give you a job.
I would.
Come here.
One fond embrace
Until we meet again
That's us before...
It was rainy, and they
went for a drive.
What happened to yours?
I hear you cry at night.
Do you dream about them?
I know that's why you
wreck things and push me.
Our family's little now and
we don't have many toys,
but if you want, you
could be part of it.
You could be our baby and
we'd raise you to be good.
Ohana means family.
Family means nobody
gets left behind
but if you want to
leave, you can.
I'll remember you though.
I remember everyone
that leaves.
Lost.
I'm lost.
Help!
I don't like the ocean!
Oh, look, a friendly
little dolphin.
They helped sailors
in the war...
It's a shark! It's a shark,
and it ain't friendly!
It looks like a dolphin.
Tricky fish! Tricky fish!
Oh, octopus, come and help me?
An octo... octopus is
worse than a shark!
I hate this planet!
Little monster!
Agent Pleakley here.
I have lost patience
with you both.
Have you captured 6-2-6 or not?
Consider yourselves
fired and prisonbound.
Your incompetence is nothing
short of unspeakable!
But...
We're fired!
Now we do it my way!
Your way?
Oh, wait!
It seems I have overestimated
Jumber and Blinkley.
Jumba and Pleakley.
Whatever. The mission
is in jeopardy.
This could be your chance to
redeem yourself, Captain Gantu.
How soon will you be
prepared to leave?
Immediately.
Don't run.
Don't make me shoot you.
You were expensive.
Yes. Yes, that's it.
Come quietly.
Waiting.
For what?
Family.
You don't have one.
I made you.
Maybe I could...
You're built to destroy.
You can never belong.
Now come quietly and we
will take you apart.
No, no, no, no, don't, don't run!
Don't run!
Lilo.
I didn't hear you get up.
Baby, what's wrong?
Stitch left.
Really?
It's good he's gone.
He didn't want to
be here anyway.
We don't need him.
Lilo...
Sometimes you try your hardest
but things don't work out
the way you want them to.
Sometimes things have
to change
and maybe sometimes
they're for the better...
even if...
Nani!
- David!
- I think I found you a job.
You what?
Old man Kukhkini's store,
but we got to hurry.
Oh, okay. Lilo? Baby,
this is really important.
I need you to stay here
for a few minutes.
I'm going to be right back.
Lock the door and don't
answer it for anyone, okay?
Things are finally
turning around.
David, I owe you one.
That's okay.
You can just date me,
and we'll call it even.
Come back here,
you little...
Stitch?
What is it?
Oh, hiding behind your little
friend won't work anymore.
Didn't I tell you?
We got fired this morning.
New rules.
What are we going to do?
Ooh! I love this song!
Pliers.
Screwdriver.
Check.
Come out, my friend from
whomever you're hiding behind.
What the...
Come on! What's the big deal?
I'll put you back together again.
I'll make you taller
and not so fluffy!
I like fluffy!
No... No...
No!
Oh, leave my mother
out of this!
You could do with
a makeover.
I tried to give you my good looks, but
let's face it, something went wrong.
No!
Quick! Follow me!
If we make it to...
- You're alive!
- They're all over the place!
Running away? Here...
Let me stop you.
You always get in the way!
Where's the girl? What
have you done to the girl?
Hello? Cobra Bubbles?
Aliens are attacking
my house.
No, no, no! No aliens!
Blue punch buggy!
No punch back.
They want my dog!
There's no need to
alert the authorities.
Everything's under control.
Lilo, who was that?
Oh, good, my dog
found the chainsaw.
Lilo! Don't hang...
You shouldn't play with guns.
- Oh, okay.
- Thank you.
Oh, I just remembered.
It's your birthday!
Happy birthday!
- Merry Christmas!
- It's not Christmas.
Happy Hanukkah!
We're leaving Stitch?
Trust me. This is not
going to end well.
- One potato.
- Two potato.
- Three potato.
- Four.
- Five potato.
- Six potato.
Seven potato, more.
My... Mother... Told... Me...
You... Are... It.
Oh, I win!
Thanks. Mahalo plenty. You
won't be disappointed.
I'll show up early to help
with the morning deliver...
Oh, don't turn left.
No.
One of them had a giant eye
in the middle of his face.
Oh, Lilo!
Please don't do this.
You know I have no choice.
No! You're not taking her!
I'm the only one who
understands her!
You take that away, she
won't stand a chance!
You're making this harder
than it needs to be.
You don't know what you're
doing! She needs me!
Is this what she needs?
It seems clear to me that you need
her a lot more than she needs you.
Lilo! Lilo!
Lilo!
You ruined everything.
You're one of them?
Get out of here, Stitch.
Surprise!
And here I thought you'd
be difficult to catch.
Silly me.
Lilo?
Lilo!
There you go, all buckled
up for the trip.
And, look, I even caught
you a little snack.
No! Stop!
Lilo.
Okay, talk.
I know you had something
to do with this.
Now where is Lilo?
Talk! I know you can.
Okay, okay.
Where's Lilo?
Lilo...
Now all your washing is up!
You're under arrest!
Read him his rights.
Listen carefully.
Hello? Galactic command?
Experiment 6-2-6 is in custody.
We'll wait right here.
Don't interact with her.
Where's Lilo?
Who? What?
Lilo. My sister.
Sorry, we do not know
anyone by this...
Lilo! She's a little
girl, this big!
She has black hair and brown eyes and
she hangs around with that thing!
We know her.
Bring her back.
Oh, we can't do that.
That would be a misuse
of Galactic resources.
See, problem is...
We're just here for him.
So she's gone?
Look at the bright side.
You won't have to yell
at anyone anymore.
Come.
Ohana.
Hey! Get away from her.
No! What did you say?
Ohana means family.
Family means...
Nobody gets left behind.
Or forgotten.
Yeah.
Hey...
What?
After all you put me through you
expect me to help you just like that?
Just like that?
Fine.
Fine?
You're doing what he says?
He's very persuasive.
Persuasive? What
exactly are we doing?
- Rescue.
- We're going to get Lilo?
Oh, good! I was hoping to
add theft, endangerment
and insanity to my list
of things I did today.
You too?
Oh! Yeah, yeah, yeah!
What? Did you think
we walked here?
This is Gantu, requesting
hyperspace clearance.
Stand by for clearance.
Clearance is granted
on vector C-12.
Connect me to the
Grand Councilwoman.
Gantu, what's going on?
I thought you'd like to know that
the little abomination is...
Yes, Captain?
I'll call you back.
How did you get out of there?
So what exactly are we doing?
Don't worry, is
all part of plan.
We are professionals.
Hey!
Get that out of your mouth!
Hold on!
Okay, is show time!
This is it!
Go! Go! Go!
Little savage!
Get off my ship!
Stitch!
Computer, locate
experiment 6-2-6.
6-2-6 located.
We finish this now.
Stitch is unconscious.
- What do we do now?
- We stay close. Hope for a miracle.
That's all we can do.
No!
Don't leave me, okay?
Okay.
Target 6-2-6 is in motion.
Speed is 84.
Impossible!
Stitch!
Abomination.
Stupidhead.
Aloha!
You're vile! You're foul!
You're flawed!
Also cute and fluffy!
You came back.
Nobody gets left behind.
Lilo!
Good dog.
David!
Hey, Lilo.
Can you give us a ride
to shore?
Sure!
But I have to make
two trips.
So you're from outer space, huh?
I heard the surfing's choice.
We have 6-2-6.
Take him to my ship.
- Leave him alone.
- Hold on.
Grand Councilwoman,
let me explain.
Silence!
I am retiring you,
Captain Gantu.
Actually, credit for
the capture goes to...
Goes to me.
You'll be lucky if you end
up on a Fluff Trog farm
after we sort this thing out.
I think I should...
You! You're the
cause of all this!
If it wasn't for your Experiment
6-2-6, none of this...
- Stitch.
- What?
My name Stitch.
Stitch then.
If it wasn't for Stitch...
Does Stitch have
to go in the ship?
Yes.
Can Stitch say good-bye?
Thank you.
Who are you?
This is my family.
I found it all on my own.
It's little and broken.
But still good.
Yeah. Still good.
Does he really have to go?
You know as well as I that
our laws are absolute.
I cannot change what the
council has decided.
Lilo, didn't you buy that
thing at the shelter?
Hey!
Three days ago, I bought
Stitch at the shelter.
I paid two dollars for him.
See this stamp? I own him.
If you take him,
you're stealing.
Aliens are all about rules.
You look familiar.
CIA. Roswell. 1973.
Ah, yes. You had hair then.
Take note of this.
This creature has been
sentenced to life in exile,
a sentence that shall be
henceforth served out here...
on Earth...
And as caretaker of the
alien life-form, Stitch,
this family is now under
the official protection
of the United Galactic Federation.
We'll be checking
in now and then.
I was afraid you were
going to say that.
This won't be easy to explain
back at headquarters.
I know what you mean.
Don't let those two
get on my ship.
CIA?
Former.
Saved the planet once.
Convinced an alien race
that mosquitoes were
an endangered species.
Now, about your house...
Wait.