(INDIAN MUSIC PLAYING)
RANJAN: Hooray! Mowgli!
SHANTI: (SHUSHING)
Ranjan, hush. It's starting.
FATHER: (LAUGHING)
Come, children. Come watch.
(RANJAN GIGGLING)
Mowgli, tell us your story.
MOWGLI: I never knew
where I came from,
but I always knew where I belonged.
This is me and Bagheera, the panther
who found me in the jungle.
He's a good friend of mine.
But my best friend of all was good old Papa Bear.
Man, we had some crazy times together.
And when the monkeys grabbed me, things got really crazy.
RANJAN: Monkey!
(ANIMALS SCREECHING)
RANJAN: Go, Papa Bear!
MOWGLI: Then, I came face to face
with the meanest, scariest tiger in the whole jungle.
Shere Khan.
(RANJAN MIMICKING ROARING)
You stay away from Mowgli, you mean, old tiger.
Or I'll tie some fire to your tail and burn your butt!
(EXCLAIMING FIERCELY)
(RIPS)
SHANTI: Ranjan!
RANJAN: Whoa!
(MUFFLED ROARING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
MOTHER: (LAUGHING)
Oh, Ranjan.
(CONTINUES ROARING)
I got him, Mowgli!
Did you see? I got him.
You sure did, Ranjan, but it's gonna be
kind of hard to finish the story now.
But we all know how it ends.
Shanti blinks her big, beautiful brown eyes at you,
and you followed her into our village.
I did not.
Did so.
- Something was in my eye.
- Both of them?
Well, you were so ugly you made my eyes water.
- Well, you...
- (LAUGHS) Now, now.
We give thanks for Shanti's beautiful brown eyes.
Without them, Mowgli would never
have found his way into our lives.
Come to think of it, you used the same trick on me.
And you still fall for it.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Thank you for a wonderful story, Mowgli.
Good night, Mowgli.
Night, Shanti.
Watch out for Shere Khan on your way home.
You and your stories.
Everyone knows tigers don't come into the village.
(RANJAN GROWLING)
Tigers go wherever they want!
(SCREAMS)
Ooh!
(CHUCKLES)
Good night, boys.
(BOYS LAUGHING)
Tomorrow's gonna be so great.
MOTHER: What happens tomorrow?
- Um... Nothing.
- Nothing.
A-ha.
Well, then, you will need plenty of rest
for doing nothing tomorrow.
Off to bed.
(YAWNING)
We never get to stay up late.
(LAUGHS)
Even wild beasts need their sleep.
- (MIMICKING TIGER ROAR)
- Oh, help! Ferocious tiger!
(PARENTS LAUGHING)
Ah, good night, my little wild thing.
(KISSING)
Good night, Mowgli.
Happy dreams.
Um, good night...
Sir.
RANJAN: Why do you
always call him "Sir"?
His name's "Pa."
(MOWGLI SNORING)
(MIMICS ROARING)
(GRUNTS)
(SNORING CONTINUES)
Hmm.
(SNORING)
(CHUCKLES)
(STRETCHING)
(ROARS)
(GASPS)
Whoa!
Come on, Mowgli!
Wake up, it's morning!
- You said we would go to...
- Ranjan! Ranjan!
Do you wanna wake up the whole village?
When does the tiger roar?
(MUFFLED)
I don't know.
After he catches his prey.
His prey.
Let's go get our prey.
(MOTHER HUMMING)
- Boys.
- BOTH: Huh?
Where are you going so early?
- To do our chores?
- Yeah!
Not without breakfast, you aren't.
(SHANTI HUMMING)
(BOTH GASP)
- That's okay. We're not hungry.
- Gotta go!
Ooh!
- Boys, where are you going?
- To do our chores!
Bye, Papa! See you later!
Remember, don't cross the river!
(SIGHS)
You can take the boy out of the jungle...
But you can't take the jungle out of the boy.
Yes.
That's what worries me.
(GASPS)
(WATER FLOWING)
- Hey, Shanti.
- (EXCLAIMS)
- What are you doing here?
- Getting water.
What are you doing here?
Oh, uh, I'm on the lookout for danger.
Danger? Please.
There's no danger around here.
Uh...
(WHISPERING)
Well, uh,
keep this just between us?
Yesterday, I saw tiger tracks.
Tiger tracks? Right.
It's Shere Khan.
I hear he's looking for me,
seeking his bloodthirsty revenge.
So keep your ears open and always watch your back,
or the last thing you'll ever hear is...
- (ROARS)
- (SHANTI GASPS)
(SCREAMS)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
When does the tiger roar?
(BOTH ROARING)
Oh! You're horrible!
Horrible, stinky boys!
Come on, Ranjan. He's a bad influence.
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
Now, don't move.
That wasn't very nice, you know.
(ROARS)
Stop that. You're not a jungle boy.
Why are you so scared of the jungle?
Because it's dangerous.
Dangerous? But Mowgli says...
You shouldn't listen to everything Mowgli says.
But I thought you liked Mowgli.
Well, I do. I like Mowgli.
But I... Oh. Ooh.
Uh, you left this at the river.
(SIGHS)
Thank you.
She's in a bad mood.
Hey, Ranjan, you want to see
a little trick I learned in the jungle?
Mmm.
That's a pretty good trick.
Well, here's a little trick I learned right here at home.
Wow. That's a neater trick.
- Like I said, Ranjan, don't listen to him.
- Blah, blah, blah, blah.
She's right, Ranjan, don't listen to me.
(DRUMS BEATING)
Listen to the jungle.
Can you hear it?
Yeah.
The jungle.
(MUSIC GROWING LOUDER)
Yeah, man!
And when you hear that rhythm,
you get a crazy feeling inside.
(SINGING) That morning sun peeks over the mountains
And all the rhinos rub their eyes When they hear
Hear what?
Hear the jungle rhythm
Those birds are
Tap-tap-tapping the tree trunks
The busy bee hums as he flies
Loud and clear
To the jungle rhythm
Now, you can hightail it out of the jungle
But it never leaves your heart
First you feel that beat start bubbling under
Then you hear the tom toms loud as thunder
It's moving me!
Sounds a lot like being free
When you feel
Feel the jungle rhythm
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
BOY: Yeah, guys.
Feel the jungle rhythm
Come on, Shanti!
Can't do without rhythm
And when it fills the air
Animals everywhere join in the dance
Hey, give me that!
You'll dance along with 'em
(LAUGHING)
Feelin' it steal your soul
We'll stomp our paws
Flap our wings
Maybe do one or two crazy things
(CHILDREN CHEERING)
Caw! Caw!
MOWGLI: Yeah, that's it!
Ooh-ooh-ah-ah!
A-whoo!
(TRUMPETS BLOWING)
Eep! Eep! Eep!
Caw! Caw!
Chika chika boom!
Eep! Eep! Eep!
A-whoo!
(RHYTHMIC ANIMAL CHANTS)
(BLOWING)
Shanti! Try this.
Not quite.
There we go. Oh... No.
Take a look. Perfect.
Boom-a-chaka
Boom-a-chaka, boom
Check out those
chat-chat-chattering monkeys
Swinging through the banyan trees
- Two by two
To the jungle rhythm
Sounds like a wolf pack way in the distance
Singing pretty harmonies
Woo, woo, woo Woo, woo, woo
To the jungle rhythm
Yeah! Whoo-hoo!
Yeah, that's it!
Now, you can hightail it out of the jungle
But it never leaves your heart
First you feel that beat start bubbling under
Then you hear the tom toms loud as thunder
It's moving me!
Sounds a lot like being free
- When I feel
Feel the jungle rhythm
Boom shaka-laka
boom sh-bop sh-bop
Whoa, wait, wait, stop.
You're crossing the river.
Mowgli, you can't go in the jungle!
It's too dangerous! Mowgli!
Stop!
(MUSIC STOPS)
(ALL GASPING)
Shanti, what is it?
Children, come inside this instant, all of you!
Mowgli!
That includes you!
I am very disappointed in you.
You put everyone in danger.
You know that you're not allowed to cross the river,
and yet you deliberately disobeyed me.
- But I...
- No, Mowgli.
The jungle is a dangerous place.
I should know.
(GASPS)
(SIGHS)
You are confined to your room without dinner.
That should give you plenty of time
to think about what you've done.
Mowgli, I was only trying to...
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(SINGING) Oh, you can hightail it out of the jungle
But it never leaves your heart
Oh, Baloo.
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(SINGING) Look for the bare necessities
The simple bare necessities
Forget about your worries and your strife
Yeah, I mean the
bum-bada-dada-dee-dada
The rum-pum-pa-ta
ree-ta-ta
That bring the bare necessities of life
Now, that's more like it!
(LAUGHING)
Look at you!
Aw, growing like a proverbial weed.
Let's see if you still got it.
Take it away, Little Britches.
Poor fellow.
I said, take it away!
(SLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
Oh.
This ain't gonna work.
You just ain't Mowgli.
Ah, I guess I gotta get used to singing solo.
He's just not getting over that...
(GASPS)
Oh, no, not again!
Baloo!
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(GROWLING)
Mowgli...
Huh? Hmm...
(TWITTERING)
(CONTINUES TWITTERING)
Get out of here! Shoo! Shoo!
(TWITTERING)
Now... Now, don't worry.
I'll take care of it.
Baloo?
Oh, man.
(CHUCKLING) Bagheera.
How's it wagging?
(GRUNTS)
This has to stop.
You can't keep trying to
take Mowgli from the man-village.
The boy's future lies with his own kind.
BALOO: Aw, his future can wait.
I miss my bear cub.
(SIGHS)
It's not safe for him in the jungle.
You know Shere Khan is looking for Mowgli.
Just let Shere Khan try something.
We handled old Stripes once.
We'll do it again.
Baloo, don't push your luck.
- Out of the way, Baghee.
- You're not going near the village!
(SCREECHING)
Oh!
(COUGHING)
Later, Baghee.
That's it! Hathi! Plan B!
(ELEPHANTS TRUMPETING)
ELEPHANTS: Hup, two, three, four!
Keep it up, two, three, four!
Now, remember, men, our objective
is full and complete containment.
Prepare for Operation... Uh, Oper...
Um, Stop that Bear?
Very good, son! Yes.
Prepare for Operation Stop that Bear!
(GULPS)
ELEPHANTS: (SINGING)
By the ranks or single file
(SCREAMING)
Over every jungle mile
Run, Baghee!
You're in the parade ground.
(GASPS)
Oh! No, please, stop!
HATHI: Company, halt!
(SCREECHING)
Huh?
I told you, Baloo, there's no way
we're letting you near the man-village.
You ain't gonna stop me now, Baghee.
Look out below!
Search the water!
- Follow me.
- This way.
ELEPHANT: Nothing here, sir.
(GASPS)
Baloo!
HATHI: Check over there!
(MUTTERING)
(INHALES)
(BUBBLING)
I've got him, Colonel!
(ELEPHANTS LAUGHING)
Confound it, soldier!
- That's a fish!
- Oopsy.
Disgrace to the uniform.
(HEAVY FOOTSTEPS)
(GASPS)
Colonel!
This log can't possibly support your weight!
(LAUGHING)
Balderdash!
- Why, my dear boy, back in '88...
- (LOG CREAKING)
...in service to the Crown,
I found myself straddling a...
Oh, no, not again.
- (TRUMPETTING)
- Whoa!
Oh, no, no. (ROARS)
(GASPING)
Well, they don't make trees like they used to.
Got him! Got him right here.
- (COUGHING)
- Ah-ha!
Disguised as a panther, Baloo.
It's me, Hathi! Put me down!
Sorry. (CHUCKLES)
Whoa!
HATHI: Keep searching, men.
Couldn't have gone far!
(SPITS)
ELEPHANT: Who are we
looking for, anyway?
Oh, Confound it, man!
(LAUGHING)
(CHUCKLES)
Don't turn me in, little guy.
I just want to see my bear cub.
I won't. I miss Mowgli, too.
This way, quick!
Hey, thanks, kid. You're all right.
(GROWLS)
- Say, fellas, look who's coming.
- That's Shere Khan.
- What we gonna do?
- Don't start that again.
Lucky. Hey, Lucky.
Yeah?
That's the one we told you about, Shere Khan.
Mmm. Shere Khan. You don't say.
Hey, watch this, watch this.
I got one for you. Check this out.
Hey, hey! Look at me! Look at me!
- Hey!
- Whoa!
I'm Shere Khan, and me tiger tush has been torched.
(VULTURES LAUGHING)
Ask me if I could whoop that tiger.
Go on, go on, ask me.
Can you whoop that tiger?
I Shere Khan.
(VULTURES LAUGHING)
Did you get it? Did you get it?
Save me! Save me!
I've been outwitted by
40 pounds of scrawny man-cub.
- (VULTURES LAUGHING)
- (GROWLING)
LUCKY: I'm cracking myself up here.
I don't know how I do it.
(LAUGHTER CONTINUES)
(GROWLING)
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
(SNORING LIGHTLY)
(GROWLS)
(TWIGS CRACKLE)
(GASPS)
- (RUSTLING)
- (GASPS)
(CHIMING SOFTLY)
(GRUNTS)
(CLATTERING)
(GASPS)
(SIGHS)
(TWIG CRACKLES)
(FOOTSTEPS SPEEDING)
(CLATTERING)
- Hiya, kid!
- (EXCLAIMS)
Mind if I drop in?
Baloo?
(EXCITEDLY)
Oh, Bal...
- (MUFFLED TALKING)
- (SHUSHING)
(MUFFLED TALKING)
- Ah.
- Papa Bear!
Boy, am I glad to see you!
What are you doing here?
(LAUGHING)
What am I doing here?
Feeling right for the first time in a while, that's what.
(LAUGHING)
Hey, kid, show me you can still fight like a bear.
- Come on.
- Aah!
Oh, Little Britches, you lost your touch.
Mowgli.
I've got something for you.
SHANTI: Mowgli, it's me.
Don't be mad.
I get grounded all the time.
Ah. (LAUGHING EVILLY)
Mowgli, I'm sorry you got in trouble.
Come on, man-cub, show yourself.
(SIGHS)
BALOO: Come on! Come on!
- Whoa!
- Mowgli?
(MOWGLI GRUNTING)
MOWGLI: Wait. No! No!
(BALOO LAUGHING)
MOWGLI: Oh!
Come on, stick and move.
- Whoa!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(SCREAMS)
Help! Wild animal!
Wild animal? Where?
Come on, let's get outta here.
Help!
MAN: What? What is it?
What's that bear doing here?
There's a wild animal in the village.
FATHER: What is the matter?
- There he is!
- There's a tiger!
Where are you going?
No, come back! Come back!
You're going the wrong way.
Wow, a tiger!
- (SHERE KHAN ROARING)
- (MIMICKING ROAR)
MAN: Don't let him get away!
(ROARING)
(GASPS)
(MEN SHOUTING)
No! Uh, please...
We gotta get out of here.
Shanti, get indoors!
No, no, no, he's over... No!
Shanti!
Shanti, wait for me!
(ROARING)
(MEN GRUNTING)
Come on, come on.
Follow me! Follow me!
(PANTING)
- (MOWGLI SCREAMING)
- Mowgli!
(GASPS)
Hold on, Mowgli!
(EXCLAIMS)
MOTHER: Shanti?
Shanti?
Hmm.
(GRUNTING)
Mowgli?
- MOTHER: Shanti!
- (GROWLING)
FATHER: Where are you?
- Mowgli!
- They must be in the jungle.
Ah.
(LAUGHING WICKEDLY)
The jungle.
What a weird scene.
Is that place always like that?
You don't know the half of it.
That village was terrible.
All you ever hear is rules, rules, rules
and work, work, work.
Whoa, kid. Watch your language.
That's all they do! Washing, dressing...
Oh, man, I'm tired just listening to it.
Sounds like they're kinda screwy over there.
I don't want to talk about it.
Especially Shanti.
- Who's Shanti?
- Ah, she's just a girl from the village.
Now, hold on.
Not the one that lured you
into that village in the first place.
Yep, that's the one.
I knew it, I knew it.
I knew she was trouble.
I even tried bringing her to the jungle,
and she got me in trouble.
Say again?
I just wanted her to see how much fun we have.
And she got you into trouble for that?
- Yep.
- Ooh, man.
She thinks the jungle is a scary place.
- Where'd she get that crazy idea?
- You got me.
Mmm.
Do my snake eyes deceive me?
Ooh. It's the succulent man-cub. Mmm.
BALOO: Well, you're with me now, kid.
Forget that girl.
You're better off without her.
You got everything you need right here.
And me, I've got my old singin' partner back.
Then hit it, Papa Bear.
BOTH: (SINGING)
Look for the bare necessities
The simple bare necessities
Forget about your worries and your strife
I mean the bare necessities
Old Mother Nature's recipes
That bring the bare necessities of life
Wherever I wander
BALOO: Where you goin'?
Wherever I roam
BALOO: Oh, yeah.
I couldn't be fonder of my big home
The bees are buzzing in the tree
To make some honey just for me
When you look under the rocks and plants
Take a glance at the fancy ants
And maybe try a few
Thanks, Baloo.
(INHALES)
The bare necessities of life will come to you
They'll come to you
Oh, Baloo.
I don't ever want to see that girl or that village again.
Well, of course you don't.
It's just us bears from here on in.
Yeah, man.
Hey, you remember everything I learned ya?
You bet I do, Papa Bear.
- Nuh-uh-uh.
- Huh?
Now, when you pick a pawpaw
Or a prickly pear
And you pick a raw paw
Well, next time beware
Don't pick the prickly pear by the paw
When you pick a pear try to use the claw
But you don't need to use the claw
When you pick a pair of the big pawpaw
Have I given you a clue?
The bare necessities of life will come to you
They'll come to you
MOWGLI: They'll come to me?
I so despise
these song-and-dance routines.
(GROANS)
Mowgli!
Mowgli?
Is that you?
- (HOOTING)
- (GASPS)
He's gotta be here somewhere.
(SKIRT RIPS)
(EXCLAIMS)
(SQUAWKING)
(YELLS)
- (SHRIEKING)
- (GASPS)
(SCREAMING)
(GROANS)
Oh, oh, oh.
I swear...
I shall never again associate...
(SOBBING)
...with man-cubs. Oh!
(PANTING)
Oh. Oh, where could he be?
(SIZZLING)
(SNIFFING)
Mmm.
(SOBBING)
(BLOWING)
Why, the little... (GASPS)
(SLURPS)
(HISSES)
Snack.
(EXCLAIMS)
(HISSES)
(GASPS)
Who is it?
- Who's there?
- (CHUCKLING)
(GASPS)
(SMACKS LIPS)
Excuse me.
Might I be of some assistance?
(CHUCKLING)
Hmm?
Are you lost, little one?
Are you hungry?
I'm starved.
(LAUGHING)
(SMACKS LIPS)
(INHALES)
Bad snake! Bad snake!
Ranjan? What are you doing here?
You leave Shanti alone!
- (GULPS)
- (THUD)
(WHIMPERING)
Okay, Ranjan. I...
I think he's had enough.
(GROANING)
- (EXCLAIMS)
- Oh!
Oh!
(COCONUTS THUD)
You're not getting away that easy.
Oh, Ranjan, what are you doing?
You're not supposed to be here.
We have to get you home right now.
No! Mowgli's in trouble,
and we're going to find him.
(SNIFFING)
I can smell him.
He's this way.
Oh, okay, but stay close.
We don't want to run into any more scary animals.
- (RANJAN ROARS)
- Oh, stop that.
(MUFFLED GROANING)
Oh, mercy.
(SHERE KHAN LAUGHING)
(STUTTERING)
Shere Khan?
(MOANING)
Anyone I know?
I wish.
Aw, stupid man-cub.
(GRUNTS)
- Man-cub?
- Uh...
Did... Did I say man-cub?
Well, well, I... I... You know...
I'd love to stay and shoot the breeze and all, but...
What's your hurry?
(GULPS)
Uh, no reason. I... I...
Oh!
Where is he?
Who he?
The man-cub Mowgli.
I know you know.
(STUTTERING)
Well, but I... I don't.
Oh, please don't insult my intelligence.
It makes me irritable.
Oh, he's not in the village.
- (SQUEAKS)
- I know where he isn't.
(GULPS)
Now, tell me where he is.
Well, he's... He's... He's...
The swamp! He's at the swamp, yes.
Hmm. The swamp, eh?
Yes. Trust in me.
- (THUD)
- Hmm.
He'd better be, for your sake.
He is, he is!
(WHEEZES) I'd...
I'd take you there myself,
but I'm afraid I'd slow you down, indigestion and all.
- (BIRDS CHIRPING)
- FATHER: Mowgli!
MOTHER: Ranjan!
(BIRDS FLUTTERING AWAY)
- (BIRDS CHIRPING)
- Huh? What?
(EXCLAIMS)
Huh?
(MICE SQUEAKING)
What is... What on earth?
- (GROUND RUMBLING)
- HATHI: Retreat!
- (TRUMPETING)
- (SCREAMS)
(GRUNTING)
(YELLING)
- Colonel Hathi!
- Take cover!
Oh, no! Not again.
- (ELEPHANTS GRUNTING)
- (RUMBLING)
(HONKS)
Whoa!
(ALL GROANING)
Excuse me.
Pardon.
Colonel Hathi, what...
What is the meaning of this?
Man is in the jungle!
What... What does he want?
MAN 1: Think they'll come out?
MAN 2: I think they're over here.
Mowgli!
Oh.
Perhaps I was too harsh with the boy.
Don't worry. We'll find them.
MAN: Children, can you hear me?
- Mowgli!
- Ranjan!
Baloo.
(GRUNTS)
Almost got it, Baloo.
- Alley-oop!
- Whoa!
(LAUGHS)
Whoa!
Ah, them primo mangos, always the hardest to get.
Got 'em.
(LAUGHING)
(SIGHS)
Ah, this is the life.
Heads up.
(GULPS)
Ah. Delicious.
Hey, check this out.
Hmm.
(MOWGLI CHUCKLING)
(LAUGHING) Hey, not bad.
Where'd you learn to do that?
Shanti showed me.
- Shanti?
- (SPLAT)
I... No, I... I said wanti.
I wanti another mango.
(NERVOUS CHUCKLE)
No, no, no, that's not what you said.
You said Shanti.
No, I didn't.
- Yes, you did.
- No, I didn't.
- Did.
- Didn't.
- Did. Uh-huh.
- Didn't. Uh-uh.
- Yep. I heard it.
- Uh-uh.
You know what?
Who cares about Shanti?
Because it's just a stupid trick, right?
(LAUGHS)
Yeah, right.
You don't need her, kid.
You're with old Baloo now.
(LAUGHS)
What are you laughing at?
(GASPS)
- What are you doin' out here, Baghee?
- (GASPS)
Haven't you heard?
Man is in the jungle.
(STUTTERING)
What do they want?
They're searching for Mowgli.
BALOO: Mowgli?
I thought that perhaps maybe you have seen the boy.
Me? Uh, no. Ha.
Well, you know his future is in that village.
Yes.
I just wish I knew where he was.
Yeah. Whew, sorry. Huh!
Man, wish I could help you out, Baghee.
Oh! Enough games, Baloo.
Now give me the boy.
Baghee, Baghee, Baghee, Baghee.
I can explain.
I can explain. I...
Can explain, but I don't have to,
'cause you can plainly see Mowgli is not here.
I'm all alone.
(SIGHS) I know he's around here
somewhere, and he can't hide forever.
Well, he won't get past you, Baghee.
Hmm.
Whew! Kid?
Kid, where'd you go?
- (SCREAMING)
- (GASPS)
(GRUNTING)
Oh! What are you tryin' to do?
Scare the tick out of my ticker?
- (LAUGHS)
- Oh!
Wow, the whole village looking for me?
We can't let nobody see you.
I thought they were mad.
We gotta lay low, hunker down...
Hibernate, like...
They must really miss me.
I wonder if Shanti's with them.
Shanti?
You definitely don't want her to find you.
Do ya?
No.
We can't let anyone find us, especially that girl.
Come on, Baloo. We gotta get moving.
Lay low, hunker down, hibernate, like.
Now, Mowgli,
what if that girl tracks us down?
What are you gonna do?
Then... Then you're gonna
have to scare her.
(MUFFLED) Scare her?
Has the milk run out of your coconut?
No, she's terrified of wild animals.
In case you haven't noticed, kid, I'm no wild animal.
(LAUGHING)
Except at parties.
I suppose I'm more of a... honey bear.
You can do it, Baloo.
You're the one that taught me, remember?
You scrunch up your eyes like this,
and show your teeth like this,
and roar like this...
(ROARING)
Roar?
No, no, no, no. Like you mean it.
Do you want that girl to take me back to the village?
(ROARING FIERCELY)
(COUGHING)
Yeah, man! That was great.
Well, I don't know.
Trust me. That'll do it.
Well, in that case, Mowgli, consider that girl scarified.
Thanks, Papa Bear.
Anything for my Little Britches.
Okay, let's skedaddle.
Now, don't you worry.
I got a place downriver.
It's the perfect hideout.
Real quiet, huh?
Quiet? Heh.
You want quiet,
go back to that man-village.
This place is happenin'.
SHANTI: Okay, here's the village.
We crossed the river...
(YELLING)
Ranjan, be careful.
(CHUCKLES)
Okay, we went right.
No, no, no, no. Left, left, I mean.
Right. No, left, then right, and...
Oh!
This jungle all looks the same!
(LAUGHING)
Ranjan, what's that?
Mowgli? He must've been here.
Or some animal with really sharp claws.
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
That snake lied to me.
Now, don't take it out on the water just
because you don't like the reflection.
(LAUGHING) I mean, not everyone
can be born with such great looks.
You let that tiger get his claws on you,
and you won't be so good-looking.
What, that pussycat?
He's harmless. Watch this.
- Oh.
- (GASPS)
What's the matter, Stripes?
Man-cub got your tongue?
(CHUCKLES)
Uh, Lucky, let's find something to do somewhere else.
No, no, no, no. Hang on, fellas.
I got another one.
How many men does it take to whoop a tiger?
(LAUGHS)
Surprise me.
None.
A little kid could do it all by himself.
(LAUGHING HILARIOUSLY)
(GROWLS)
- Come on, Lucky, let's go.
In fact, we heard that kid is right here in the jungle.
- (ALL GASP)
- Right under your whiskers.
- (LAUGHING)
- Interesting.
I heard he's headed back to the village.
(MIMICKING BUZZER)
Wrong again, kitty.
No, Lucky, keep your gob shut.
No, they say he's headed downriver with a bear.
Downriver, you say? Ah.
Oh, don't listen to him.
Ooh, yeah, he's new around here.
He don't know anything.
On the contrary, he seems to know quite a lot.
Hey, hold on, hot pants!
Where's the fire? (LAUGHING)
(GULPS)
Isn't it ironic that your name is Lucky?
- (ROARING)
- (SCREAMING)
Come on, lads! This way! Let's get out!
MOWGLI: This is the perfect hideout?
This is King Louie's place.
Was, kid, was. He's splitsville.
Now, me and the monkeys have turned
it into the greatest secret hideout ever.
Excuse me.
Comin' through. Hey, Baloo!
Oh, good to see you back again, man.
Heh. Everybody knows about it.
But if everybody knows about it, how can it be a secret?
I mean, everybody who's anybody.
Nobody who's nobody don't know nothin' about no place
that everybody who's anybody knows about, you dig?
(GROANS)
My head hurts.
Hey, turn the thinker off for a minute and just dive in.
Step aside, and I'll show you
what a real rug-cutter can do.
- (MONKEYS CHATTERING)
- Ladies and gentlemen,
please welcome the boss of bop, the jack of jive,
the jungle cat who's really gonna keep it alive.
Get ready to stir it up and serve it up.
I'm talkin' about,
Baloo is in the house!
Hey, cats, all right!
(UP-BEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(SINGING) When we start to move
Hey, honey, it ain't no joke
(LAUGHS)
We got a savage groove
We didn't learn from human folk
No human folk
'Scuse our incivility
We're W-l-l-l-L-D
When the music plays all the people stomp their feet
Go, Baloo.
But a stompin' paw can lay down a better beat
- Tell me we ain't naturally
- ALL: W-l-l-l-L-D
It's a snap to bring out the beast in you
You're free like ze bird It's true
Or a frog or a hog
Baby, we were born free
From the baddest cat to the sweetest little deer
(GIGGLES)
Tonight's the night we're gonna get our tails in gear
Show me your ferocity
Go W-l-l-l-L-D
We snort, we squeak
Up high or deep underground
We snarl, we shriek
We fly round and round and round
(SCATTING)
Oh, you sweet thing, that's inhuman, baby!
The old mongoose gets good and loose
The ocelot gives it all he's got
The parakeet goes tweedle-deet
The red macaque shouts "Hang on, Jack"
- The tiny worm
- The pachyderm
- The spotted cat
- The water rat
- The great cuckoo
- The bear Baloo
Are W-l-L-D
Here's the thing
If we're broke, we never squawk
We don't need to check no clock
To know what time it is
It's time to rock
When you dance like that hey, honey, it sure is hip
I can't stand it!
I want to tip my hat but I got no hat to tip
I don't need no hat
Ask me why and I won't lie
I'm W-l-l-l-L-D
We grunt, we growl
Up high or deep underground
We hoot, we howl
We fly round and round and round
My, oh, me, it's plain to see
We're W-l-l-l-L-D
He, she, me, you-nique-ally
W-l-l-l-L-D
Every beastie running free
Huh? Ooh!
(SCREAMING)
Whoa!
- (ALL CHEERING)
- (BOTH LAUGHING)
Whoo-hoo! That's my boy.
They don't swing out like that in your
man-village, now do they, kid, hmm?
Well, uh, no.
(LAUGHING) Big fat no.
Say, what's that village like, anyway?
Hey, whoa, don't bother the kid.
He told me all about that scene.
Let me lay it out for you.
Those people are crazy.
Everybody works and nobody plays.
Oh, man!
BALOO: They got nothin' but
rules, rules, rules.
Oh, and there's even this girl
who thinks the jungle is a scary place.
(ANIMALS LAUGHING)
But, you know, it doesn't matter,
'cause Mowgli's never gonna see
that village or that crazy girl again.
(LAUGHING)
Ain't that so, kid?
Mowgli? Mowgli?
Mowgli?
BALOO: (DISTANTLY)
Mowgli!
(SINGING SOFTLY)
That morning sun peeks over the mountains
And all the rhinos rub their eyes
When they hear
Hear the jungle rhythm
(RANJAN YAWNS)
Did we find Mowgli yet?
Oh, are you tired?
A little.
I'm sure we'll find him soon.
Come on, hop up.
You okay up there?
Uh-huh.
(SINGING) How could it be
Half as good as being free?
Part of me
Like the jungle rhythm
(GASPS)
- Did you hear that?
- Hear what?
It sounded like Mowgli.
- Mowgli!
- Ranjan, wait!
Ranjan!
Mowgli!
Shanti? Whoa!
Are you okay?
Oh, I feel vine. (LAUGHS)
What are you doing up there?
Hold on, I'll be right... Whoa!
- I can't believe I finally found you!
- I thought I would never see you again!
You out here, kid?
Hey, Little Britches?
(ECHOES)
Mowgli!
MOWGLI: Ow! Ow!
Hmm.
- Ow, you're not really helping.
- Ranjan, stop pulling.
It's her.
MOWGLI: So, what are you
doing out here, anyway?
SHANTI: I came to save you.
MOWGLI: Save me? From what?
That wild bear that carried you off.
What wild...
- (BALOO ROARING)
- (GASPS)
(ROARING FIERCELY)
(SCREAMING)
Baloo, don't! No, no, no! Stop! Wait!
(GRUNTING)
- Ow! Oh!
- (SCREAMS)
Roar. (GRUNTS)
Oh. My poor sneezer. That hurt.
You come anywhere near Ranjan,
and I'll really show you hurt.
- Wait! Whoa!
- Don't make me do it!
Wait, wait, wait! Calm down! It's okay.
- But he's attacking us!
- BALOO: Attacking?
I'm the one that got socked in the schnozzle.
Well, that's because you scared her.
But you... You told me to scarify her!
- (GASPS) What?
- No, no, no, no. I... (GRUNTS)
Mowgli, you planned this?
Well, I, um...
(SCOFFS)
Come on, Ranjan.
- No, Shanti, I can explain!
- Don't even bother.
Shanti, wait!
Oh, man, you weren't kiddin' about her.
She's bad news.
No, she's not!
She was just trying to help, and you scared her!
Man alive.
First, you tell me to scare her,
then you tell me not to scare her.
Kid, I only got so much room
up in this noggin, and it's fillin' up fast!
You just don't understand.
All right.
How's about layin' it out for me?
(SIGHS)
Read you loud and clear, kid.
You wanted that girl to find you.
(EXCLAIMS)
(SIGHS)
Shanti!
Where are you?
(GRUNTING)
Come on!
There you are.
I'm so sorry.
Will you let me explain?
Uh... Come on, at least talk to me.
- (GASPS)
- (GROWLS)
You seem surprised to see me,
man-cub.
(CHUCKLES)
I can't imagine why.
I wasn't going to let you get away
with what you did to me.
You see, you humiliated me, man-cub.
Surely you do realise I simply can't let you live.
(GASPS)
Run!
(GROWLS)
Oh, you're going to try and outrun me.
How droll.
(PANTING)
Come on, this way!
(GROWLING)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
All right, stay here.
Mowgli, no!
(ROARING)
Ranjan, wait here.
I gotta go help Mowgli.
- But I want to help Mowgli, too!
- No, no.
I... I'll be right back, I promise.
Don't move.
(STRETCHING)
(GRUNTING)
Whoa!
(GASPS)
Whoa, whoa, hold still. Calm down, kid.
- Now, where's Mowgli?
- Shere Khan!
Shere Khan? Hold on!
Whoa! Whoa!
- Whoa!
- (LAVA HISSING)
(SHERE KHAN ROARING)
(GRUNTS)
(STRAINS)
(GROWLS)
(ROARING)
(CHUCKLES)
(PANTING)
SHERE KHAN: No matter how fast
you run, no matter where you hide,
I will catch you.
(PANTING)
Come out, come out, wherever you are.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
RANJAN: Hurry! Hurry! Faster! Faster!
(GASPS)
Not another man-cub.
Can't you go any faster?
(GASPS)
Baloo!
- What... What is the meaning of this?
- Mowgli's in trouble!
Shanti, too!
Who's Shanti?
(PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
Oh.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Take the kid, Baghee. I'll help Mowgli.
Baloo!
Be careful.
(PANTING)
(ROCK CRUMBLES)
Hmm? Mowgli?
(WHISPERING)
Mowgli, is that you?
- (ROCK CLATTERS)
- (GASPS) Mowgli?
- (THUD)
- (GRUNTS)
(BOTH GASP)
- You!
- You stay away from me!
- What are you doing here?
- Hey, I'm here because when...
- I'm really not in the mood.
...a member of my den has a problem...
- I spent a night in the jungle.
I was attacked by a snake, but I really don't care!
- That's why I am here to help Mowgli!
- 'Cause I am here to help Mowgli!
- You what?
- You are?
I guess we're on the same side.
I guess so.
- Okay.
All right, you go that way. I'll cover you.
(GROWLS)
(GASPS)
(KNUCKLES CRACKING)
(BANGING GONG)
(GASPS)
(GROWLS)
(ROARS)
(GONGS RINGING)
- (ROARING)
- (CHAIN RATTLING)
(GASPS)
(BOTH GASP)
Oh, no.
(GROWLING)
Well, isn't this a delightful turn of events?
(CHUCKLES)
So, what's it going to be, man-cub?
You or your adorable little girlfriend?
(GRUNTING)
I'm waiting.
One...
- Two...
- No, don't!
Three...
(LAUGHING)
No more games, man-cub.
- (ROARING)
- (GASPS)
(GRUNTING)
Mowgli?
Come on!
(GRUNTING)
(ROARING)
Mowgli, look out!
- Oh, no!
- We can do it!
- Jump!
- (SCREAMING)
(ROARING)
Come on!
Mowgli.
(CRUMBLING)
(SHANTI SCREAMING)
- (ROARING)
- (SHANTI SCREAMING)
(BALOO GRUNTS)
(ROARING)
Hello, Stripes!
You're looking a bit down in the mouth today.
(LAUGHS)
Oh, no.
Hey, hey, what's the matter?
Cat got your tongue?
(CONTINUES LAUGHING)
Oh, I always said you had a good head
on your shoulders, Khannie, me boy.
Oh, this is fantastic, playing to a captive audience.
I just love it.
(ALL LAUGHING)
- Bagheera.
- Hey, Mowgli.
(LAUGHING)
It's awfully good to see you, man-cub.
Come on, come on, follow me.
Bagheera, this is Shanti,
my best friend from the village.
FATHER: Ranjan!
MOTHER: Mowgli!
- (GASPS) There they are!
- Papa! Whoo-hoo!
Come on, Mowgli.
(SOFTLY)
Um...
FATHER: Mowgli!
- Shanti!
- MOTHER: Shanti!
Mowgli, I have to go.
MOTHER: Shanti!
Well, come on, Mowgli.
Uh...
Come on, Ranjan.
(SIGHS)
Uh...
Aw, Baloo.
It's okay, kid.
That girl isn't so bad after all, now, is she?
Go on, Mowgli.
Really?
Really. Don't let her get away.
Come with me.
Now, you know I can't do that.
I'm going to miss you, Papa Bear.
Me, too, Little Britches.
Me, too.
(SIGHS)
All right. (CLEARING THROAT)
There. Come on, now.
You better hurry up.
(SIGHS)
(SNIFFLES)
MOWGLI: Hey. Wait up!
(GASPS)
Mowgli!
(LAUGHS)
What took you so long?
(ALL LAUGHING)
Race you back.
Come on, Ranjan.
RANJAN: Whoo-hoo!
SHANTI: Wait. Wait!
- We're over here!
- (GASPS)
- Shanti!
- We've found the children!
- Ranjan!
- Mommy!
You gave us quite a scare.
Shanti, I was so worried about you.
I'm okay. Mom, I'm so sorry.
I was just trying to help Mowgli...
I'm sorry, sir. It's just...
No, Mowgli. I'm sorry.
I should've understood
that the jungle is a part of who you are.
I'm just glad you're safe.
- RANJAN: Papa!
- Ranjan.
You won't believe it.
There was a big, old snake, and I beat him up.
(LAUGHING)
Of course you did.
I'm proud of you, Baloo.
That was a very brave thing...
Uh, Baghee?
Don't go getting any ideas about running after him
and trying to talk him into staying here with us.
He belongs in that village, and you know it.
Oh, really?
Yes, really.
He's got his whole future there.
I'm sorry, Baloo. You're absolutely right.
(SIGHS)
- I'm really going to miss that kid.
- Me, too.
(SIGHS)
Wait a minute.
I'm having myself an idea.
Baloo...
(LAUGHS)
Come on, Mowgli, we'll be late.
Okay. (GRUNTING)
I'm right behind you.
- Ooh!
- Oops.
Just getting some water.
- (LAUGHS) All right, but be careful, son.
- Oh, I will. See you, Pop.
(CHUCKLES)
Let's see if he remembers to actually
bring back some water this time.
Hey, Shanti, let's remember to actually
(LAUGHS)
(GRUNTING)
(HIGH TAPPING)
(LOW TAPPING)
Yeah, man!
Man, that beat is chillin' me.
- Hiya, Papa Bear.
- Hey, there, Little Britches.
Shanti. (LAUGHING)
Ranjan?
- Oh! Ow!
- (LAUGHS)
(GRUNTING)
(SINGING) Look for the bare necessities
The simple bare necessities
Forget about your worries and your strife
MOWGLI: Yeah, man!
I mean the bare necessities
That's why us bears can rest at ease
With just the bare necessities of life
MOWGLI: Oh, yeah!
BALOO: One more time!
With just the bare necessities of life
Yeah, man
(ALL LAUGHING)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
MOWGLI: Can you hear it?
Yeah, man.
(RECORD SCRATCHING)
MAN: (SINGING)
Now, I'm the king of the swingers
Oh, the jungle VIP
I've reached the top and had to stop
And that's what's botherin' me
I wanna be a man, man-cub
And stroll right into town
And be just like the other men
I'm tired of monkeyin' around
Oh, oobee doo I wanna be like you
I wanna walk like you
Talk like you, too
You'll see it's true
An ape like me
Can learn to be human, too
BALOO: Whoo. Baby!
(LAUGHING)
Yes! Take it away!
(GUITAR SOLO PLAYING)
Crazy, man. Crazy!
Heads up.
Here we go!
Come on!
Vout-o-roonie!
(BALOO LAUGHING)
Ah! Yeah! Whoo!
- (RECORD SCRATCHING)
- MOWGLI: Check this out.
BALOO: This place is happenin'.
MOWGLI: Can you hear it?
BALOO: Oh, yeah.
(RECORD SCRATCHING)
BALOO: Step, step, step, step aside,
and I'll show you
what a real rug-cutter can do.
Anything for my Little Britches.
MOWGLI: Hit it, Papa Bear.
MAN: (SINGING)
Yeah, you
I wanna be like you
I wanna walk like you
Talk like you, too
You'll see it's true
Someone like me
Can learn to be
I can learn to be
Someone like you
Someone like me
MOWGLI: Yeah, man.
BALOO: (LAUGHING)
Hey, not bad.
(ORCHESTRAL MUSIC PLAYING)
WOMAN: (SINGING)
Sometimes when night has come
The river sings a song
In my dreams it seems to lead me