Which pet's address
is the finest in Paris?
Which pets possess
the longest pedigree?
Which pets get
to sleep on velvet mats?
Naturellement
The Aristocats
Which pets are blessed with
the fairest forms and faces?
Which pets know best
all the gentle social graces?
Which pets live
on cream and loving pats?
Naturellement
The Aristocats
They show aristocatic bearing
When they're seen upon an airing
And aristocatic flair in what they do
And what they say
Aristocats are never found in alleyways
Or hanging 'round the garbage cans
Where common kitties play
Oh, no
Which pets are known
To never show their claws?
Which pets are prone
to hardly any flaws?
To which pets do the others
tip their hats?
Naturellement
The Aristocats
Do mi so do
Do so mi do
Every truly cultured
Music student knows
You must learn your scales
and your arpeggios
Bring the music ringing from your chest
And not your nose
While you sing your scales
and your arpeggios
If you're faithful
to your daily practicing
You will find your progress
is encouraging
Do mi so mi
Fa la so it goes
When you do your scales
and your arpeggios
Do mi so do...
Do mi so do
Do so mi do
Though at first it seems
as though it doesn't show
Like a tree, ability
will bloom and grow
If you're smart
you'll learn by heart
What every artist knows
You must sing your scales
And your arpeggios
I like a chee-chee-chee-rony
like they make at home
Or a healthy fish with a big backbone
I'm Abraham de Lacy
Giuseppe Casey
Thomas O'Malley
O'Malley the alley cat
I've got that wanderlust
Gotta walk the scene
Gotta kick up highway dust
Feel the grass that's green
Gotta strut them city streets
Showin' off my éclat, yeah
Tellin' my friends of the social elite
Or some cute cat I happen to meet
That I'm
Abraham de Lacy
Giuseppe Casey
Thomas O'Malley
O'Malley the alley cat
I'm king of the highway
Prince of the boulevard
Duke of the avant-garde
The world is my backyard
So if you're goin' my way
That's the road you wanna seek
Calcutta to Rome
Or home sweet home in Paris
Magnifique, you all
I only got myself
And this big old world
But I sip that cup of life
With my fingers curled
I don't worry what road to take
I don't have to think of that
Whatever I take is the road I make
It's the road of life
Make no mistake
For me
Yeah, Abraham de Lacy
Giuseppe Casey
Thomas O'Malley
O'Malley the alley cat
Everybody wants to be a cat
Because a cat's the only cat
Who knows where it's at
Tell me, everybody's pickin'
up on that feline beat
'Cause everything else is obsolete
Strictly high-button shoes
A square with a horn
makes you wish you weren't born
Every time he plays
But with a square in the act
You can set music back
To the caveman days
I've heard some corny birds
who tried to sing
But, still, a cat's the only cat
who knows how to swing
Who wants to dig a long-haired gig
or stuff like that
When everybody wants to be a cat
A square with a horn makes
you Wish you weren't born
- Every time he plays
- Oh, a rinky tinky tinky
With a square in the act
you can set music back
To the caveman days
Oh, a rinky tinky tinky
Yes, everybody wants to be a cat
Because a cat's the only cat
who knows where it's at
When playin' jazz
you always has a welcome mat
'Cause everybody digs a swingin' cat
Shanghai, Hong Kong, egg foo yong
Fortune cookie always wrong
If you want to turn me on
Play your horn
Don't spare the tone
And blow a little soul into the tune
Let's take it to another key
Modulate and wait for me
I'll take a few ad-libs
and pretty soon
The other cats will all commence
Congregatin' on the fence
Beneath the alley's only light
Where every note is
Out of sight
Everybody, everybody
Everybody wants to be a cat
Hallelujah
Everybody, everybody
Everybody wants to be a cat
I'm tellin' you, everybody
Everybody
Everybody wants to be a cat
Yeah, everybody
Everybody
Everybody wants to be a cat
Everybody, everybody
- Hallelujah
- Everybody
Everybody
Everybody wants to be a cat...
Everybody wants to be a cat
Because a cat's the only cat
Who knows where it's at
Oh, yeah
Everybody, everybody
Everybody wants to be a cat
Everybody
Everybody, everybody
Everybody wants to be
A cat
Oh, yeah