GOOD EVENING, SIR.
I'M PROFESSOR IVARSSON.
YES, SIR. SIR ANTHONY'S
BEEN EXPECTING YOU.
IT'S IN YOUR HANDS, MARLOW.
STAND FAST WITH THOSE
STEEL FELLOWS.
THEY'LL COME TO TERMS. IF
ANY OTHER PROBLEMS COME UP,
CONSULT WITH THE BOARD.
THEY KNOW MY THINKING.
AH! PROFESSOR IVARSSON.
I CANNOT TELL YOU
HOW GRATEFUL I AM...
THAT YOU'VE AGREED
TO JOIN ME.
I HAVEN'T AGREED TO ANYTHING.
ALL I KNOW IS THAT SOMEBODY
WOKE ME UP AT 6:00 YESTERDAY
MORNING SAYING HE WAS...
THE BRITISH AMBASSADOR.
IT WAS THE
BRITISH AMBASSADOR.
HE'D ARRANGED MY PASSAGE
ON A MAIL BOAT FROM NORWAY
TO ENGLAND.
THEN A LARGE MAN
APPEARED AT MY DOOR.
HE HELPED ME PACK MY BAGS...
AND DROVE ME TO THE DOCK.
YOUR TRAIN LEAVES
IN TEN MINUTES, SIR.
GOOD. COME ALONG, IVARSSON.
BUT, UH, SIR ANTHONY...
AN EXPEDITION
TO THE ARCTIC?
I'M... I'M HARDLY A
PROFESSIONAL EXPLORER...
AH, LET ME FINISH.
I'VE HAD YOU
LOOKED INTO.
OH?
YOU'RE AN AMERICAN FROM
THE UNIVERSITY OF MINNESOTA,
CURRENTLY A GUEST LECTURER AT
THE UNIVERSITY OF CHRISTIANIA.
YOUR SPECIALITY
IS THE ARCHAEOLOGY
OF THE NORTH.
IN THE PAST, YOU'VE LED
SEVERAL SUCCESSFUL EXPEDITIONS.
YOU'VE DONE SOME VERY
INTERESTING WORK IN GREENLAND.
OH, NO, NO.
YOU'RE THE RIGHT MAN
FOR THE JOB, ALL RIGHT.
THE RIGHT MAN FOR WHAT JOB?
AND WHAT'S SO URGENT?
WHAT IS IT YOU HOPE TO FIND?
MY... SON.
YOU SEE, MY WIFE DIED
WHEN DONALD WAS A CHILD.
AS HE GREW OLDER,
I BEGAN TO GROOM HIM...
TO TAKE MY PLACE
IN THE BUSINESS.
I PUSHED HIM TOO HARD.
I... ANYWAY, WE HAD WORDS.
THEN SUDDENLY DONALD DROPPED
EVERYTHING AND WENT OFF
ON A WHALING SHIP...
AS AN ORDINARY SEAMAN.
THREE MONTHS LATER,
I GOT WORD THAT HE'D LEFT
THE SHIP IN BAFFIN LAND.
WHY?
I HAD NO IDEA...
UNTIL I RECEIVED THIS
FROM A TRADING POST
AT FORT CONGER
ON ELLESMERE ISLAND.
APPARENTLY, DONALD HAD
LEFT IT WITH THE FACTOR
FOR SAFEKEEPING...
WHEN HE'D GONE OFF ON
SOME SORT OF EXPEDITION.
WHEN HE DIDN'T COME BACK,
THE FACTOR SENT IT ON TO ME.
HMM. IT'S AN OLD PAGE
FROM A HUDSON'S BAY COMPANY
JOURNAL.
LOOK AT THE ENTRY
FOR JANUARY 15, 1856.
"TO THIS POST THIS DAY
CAME JOHN MURCHISON
WITH HIS ESKIMOS,
"WHO HUNT THE WHITE BEAR
FAR BEYOND THE LAND'S END.
"HE TOLD OF SEEING
A LONE CLOUD AS IF
LYING ON THE ICE,
"AND HIDDEN BENEATH IT,
AN ISLAND.
"THIS ISLAND
HE SOUGHT TO EXAMINE,
"BUT HIS ESKIMOS
REFUSED HIM, SAYING...
"IT'S GUARDED
BY EVIL SPIRITS,
FOR IT'S THE PLACE WHERE
THE WHALES GO TO DIE."
WE'RE COMING
INTO DOVER NOW, SIR.
THANK YOU.
SIR ANTHONY,
THE GRAVEYARD OF WHALES...
IS JUST A FANTASY,
A WHALER'S EL DORADO,
WHERE HE THINKS HE'S
GOING TO FIND A HUGE FORTUNE
IN WHALE BONE AND AMBERGRIS.
THE FACT IS,
IT SIMPLY DOESN'T EXIST.
GRAVEYARD OF WHALES
IS A LEGEND, NOTHING MORE.
A LEGEND OR NOT,
THE GRAVEYARD IS WHAT
MY SON WENT AFTER.
IT'S MY SON
I'M LOOKING FOR.
PORTER, SIR?
YES, TAKE OUR LUGGAGE
TO THE ADMIRALTY PIER.
VERY GOOD, SIR.
SIR ANTHONY,
I'M AFRAID THIS HAS TO BE
THE END OF THE LINE FOR ME.
I'D HELP IF I COULD.
I KNOW HOW MUCH
THIS MEANS TO YOU.
BUT YOU'RE TRYING
THE IMPOSSIBLE:
TO TRY TO FIND ONE MAN...
WITH NOTHING MORE
TO GO ON THAN A PAGE
FROM AN OLD JOURNAL...
THERE IS SOMETHING MORE.
DONALD ALSO LEFT THIS
WITH THE FACTOR.
I WAS HOPING YOU
MIGHT KNOW WHAT IT WAS.
IT'S CARVED BONE.
IT'S ESKIMO WORK.
IT'S QUITE COMMON
IN THE ARCTIC.
THIS ONE'S A KIND OF A MAP.
MAP?
IF I HAD THE RIGHT CHART,
I COULD SHOW YOU HOW
THIS THING WORKS.
MY YACHT IS AT THE PIER.
YOU CAN HAVE ALL THE CHARTS
YOU NEED.
THIS PATTERN HOPEFULLY
WILL CORRESPOND...
TO SOME PART OF THE SHORELINE
HERE ON THE CHART.
LOOK. SEE HOW
THIS MATCHES?
IT'S NOT EXACTLY
TO SCALE, OF COURSE.
THEN THIS RED MARK COULD BE
THE ISLAND WE'RE LOOKING FOR.
IF THERE WERE SUCH AN ISLAND.
AND WHY SHOULDN'T
THERE BE?
'CAUSE THERE'S NO LAND HERE.
IT'S JUST A GIGANTIC FROZEN SEA.
ALL THE EXPLORERS AGREE TO THAT.
PEARY, NANSEN, ALL OF THEM.
AND WHAT IS
IVARSSON'S OPINION?
OF COURSE, THERE'S
A LOT THEY HAVEN'T COVERED.
BUT IF THERE WERE
SUCH AN ISLAND,
IF THE GRAVEYARD OF WHALES
REALLY DID EXIST...
THE WORLD WILL NEVER KNOW,
WILL IT?
UNLESS YOU DISCOVER IT.
OR UNLESS SOMEONE ELSE
BEATS YOU TO IT.
SIR ANTHONY,
YOU'RE A DEVIOUS MAN.
YES, I AM, AREN'T I?
I'VE GOT YOUR
CONTRACT HERE,
YOUR LEAVE FROM
THE UNIVERSITY,
POWER OF ATTORNEY.
MY SOLICITORS WILL
HANDLE YOUR AFFAIRS
IN YOUR ABSENCE.
WE'RE UNDERWAY.
AND HAVE BEEN
FOR SOME TIME.
WE'LL BE IN FRANCE
IN THE MORNING.
WHY FRANCE? THAT'S HARDLY
THE MOST DIRECT ROUTE
TO FORT CONGER.
ON THE CONTRARY.
I THINK YOU'LL FIND
THAT IT IS.
CAN'T YOU SLOW HIM DOWN?
YOU'D THINK WE WERE
LEAVING TOMORROW MORNING.
WE ARE.
WHAT?
I SAID WE ARE.
FIRST THING
IN THE MORNING.
IMPOSSIBLE!
IT'S WINTER. NO SHIP
CAN GET THROUGH THE ICE
BEFORE SPRING.
I'VE MADE
OTHER ARRANGEMENTS.
WHAT ARRANGEMENTS?
IF I TOLD YOU,
YOU'D THINK I WAS MAD.
SIR ANTHONY,
YOU ARE MAD.
NOW YOU'RE GOING TO MEET
ANOTHER MADMAN.
CAPTAIN BRIEUX!
AH! MONSIEUR ROSS!
WHAT A PLEASURE!
HE WAS BUILDING THIS FOR
A SYNDICATE OF AMERICANS,
BUT HE RAN THROUGH
ALL THEIR MONEY.
I HEARD OF THE PROJECT
AND TOOK IT OVER. AH!
CAPTAIN BRIEUX!
GOOD EVENING,
SIR ANTHONY.
PROFESSOR IVARSSON.
I'M HONORED,
PROFESSOR.
IT'S MY PLEASURE, CAPTAIN.
DO YOU MIND IF I TAKE
A CLOSER LOOK?
NO, NO, NO.
PLEASE. I'M PROUD
WE SHALL HAVE YOU WITH US
FOR THE CEREMONY TOMORROW.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WHAT CEREMONY?
WHY, THE FIRST FLIGHT
OF MY CREATION.
TOMORROW, THE WHOLE WORLD
WILL KNOW OF ME
AND MY HYPERION.
FRANCE WILL RULE THE AIR!
WHATEVER YOU'VE PLANNED,
CANCEL IT.
TOMORROW, WE LEAVE
FOR THE ARCTIC.
THE ARCTIC?
THE ARCTIC! SIR ANTHONY,
THAT'S RIDICULOUS!
IT CAN'T BE DONE!
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE!
WE WOULD NEED FOOD,
SUPPLIES, FUEL FOR
THE MOTORS!
THE FUEL I LEAVE TO YOU,
CAPTAIN.
ALL OTHER NECESSITIES
HAVE BEEN AMPLY PROVIDED
BY MY STAFF.
MONSIEUR, I THINK
IT IS BEST THAT YOU AND I
HAVE AN UNDERSTANDING.
WE HAVE AN UNDERSTANDING.
I BOUGHT AND PAID FOR
YOUR AIRSHIP.
IT'S MINE.
I INTEND TO USE IT...
TO FIND MY SON WHO IS
LOST IN THE ARCTIC.
BUT I CANNOT DO IT
WITHOUT YOUR HELP.
I CAN OFFER YOU NOTHING
EXCEPT HARDSHIP AND DANGER,
EXCEPT YOUR PLACE
IN HISTORY.
HISTORY?
THINK OF IT,
CAPTAIN.
YOU HAVE AN OPPORTUNITY
WHICH COMES BUT ONCE
IN A GENERATION.
THE WORLD WILL KNOW YOU,
NOT ONLY AS THE FIRST MAN
TO FLY OVER THE ARCTIC,
BUT THE FIRST MAN,
PERHAPS, TO BRAVE
THE NORTH POLE ITSELF!
TODAY WE MAKE HISTORY.
THERE SHOULD BE FLAGS,
MUSIC, A SPEECH
FROM THE PRESIDENT.
BUT WHAT DO WE HAVE?
TWO SMALL CHILDREN
AND A HERD OF GOATS.
DON'T WORRY, CAPTAIN.
WHEN YOU BRING HER
BACK TO FRANCE,
THE CELEBRATION'S
GONNA BREAK ALL RECORDS.
PAREZ, MON CAPITAINE.
TRES BIEN, MARCEL.
MES COMPLIMENTS.
NOW WE ARE READY TO DEPART.
VERY GOOD, CAPTAIN.
CARRY ON.
SILENCE!
THERE WILL BE
NO SPEAKING.
MARCEL, LANCEZ
LE MOTEUR A BABORD.
BIEN, MON CAPITAINE.
LANCEZ LE MOTEUR A BABORD!
CONTACT!
LANCEZ LE MOTEUR
A TRIBORD.
LIBEREZ LES CORDAGES.
WELL, WE'RE
ON OUR WAY.
A GLORIOUS DAY, MESSIEURS.
WE RISE WITH THE SUN.
CONGRATULATIONS, CAPTAIN.
THIS'LL BE A MORNING
TO REMEMBER.
SOMETHING IN THE FOOD HAMPER
JUST BIT ME.
THAT IS NOT THE FOOD HAMPER.
THAT IS, UH,
THE SMALL BOUDOIR OF JOSEPHINE.
IT'S SOME KIND OF A DOG!
BUT OF COURSE.
THE BEST KIND. FRENCH.
I AM NOT INTERESTED
IN ITS NATIONALITY.
WHO BROUGHT IT ABOARD?
NO ONE BROUGHT HER ABOARD.
SHE LIVES HERE.
THIS IS HER HOME, SINCE
THE AIRSHIP WAS BEGUN.
I'M NOT RUNNING
SOME KIND OF FLYING KENNEL.
GET RID OF IT.
IF YOU WISH, MONSIEUR.
BUT OF COURSE,
IT WILL TAKE TIME.
THE SUN HAS WARMED THE GAS.
WE MUST WAIT UNTIL NIGHT
TO RETURN TO THE HANGAR,
THEN BRING BACK
THE GROUND CREW...
WAIT UNTIL NIGHT?
BUT THAT WILL MEAN 12 HOURS.
I CAN'T LOSE THE TIME.
YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT,
SIR ANTHONY.
CONGRATULATIONS, JOSEPHINE.
WE'VE JUST SIGNED ON
OUR SHIP'S MASCOT.
VERY WELL.
BUT I DON'T LIKE
SMALL DOGS, AND
I NEVER DID.
BRITANNIA MAY RULE
THE WAVES, SIR ANTHONY,
BUT THE FRENCH AIRSHIP
RULES THE SKY.
ALREADY WE ARE
SPEEDING IN TRIUMPH ACROSS
THE SHORES OF YOUR HOMELAND.
RAINING AS USUAL, I SEE.
HOW FAR HAVE WE COME?
ABOUT 150 MILES.
150?
IN SIX HOURS?
THAT WHAT YOU CALL
"SPEEDING IN TRIUMPH"?
IN A DAY OR TWO,
WE'LL TRAVEL FASTER, BUT NOW
MY MOTORS ARE AT HALF SPEED.
WHAT ON EARTH FOR?
THEY ARE NEW.
THEY MUST RUN
THEMSELVES IN.
POPPYCOCK!
I WANT FULL SPEED.
THERE ARE THE CONTROLS,
MONSIEUR. IF YOU WANT
FULL SPEED,
IT'S YOUR RESPONSIBILITY,
NOT MINE!
WHAT DO YOU SAY NOW,
SIR ANTHONY?
I SAY I WANT FULL SPEED.
AND I MEAN TO HAVE IT.
YOU HAVE YOUR WISH,
MONSIEUR.
IT'S ON YOUR HEAD.
[ Shouting in French ]
- SOMETHING ABOUT THE PROPELLER.
I FOLLOWED YOUR ORDERS,
MONSIEUR, AND YOU SEE
THE RESULT.
NOW WE MUST GO BACK
TO FRANCE FOR REPAIRS.
WE WILL NOT!
WE WILL PROCEED
ON ONE PROPELLER.
IN ARCTIC WINDS?
THAT WOULD BE INSANITY.
WITHOUT FULL POWER, MY
AIRSHIP COULD NOT SURVIVE.
I REFUSE TO GO FORWARD!
AND I REFUSE TO GO BACK.
WELL, GENTLEMEN,
WE HAVE TO GO SOMEWHERE.
CAPTAIN, YOU CARRY
A SPARE PROPELLER,
DON'T YOU?
NATURALLY.
WELL, WHY DON'T WE
PUT IT ON NOW?
IN MIDAIR?
MM-HMM.
- IMPOSSIBLE!
- NOTHING'S IMPOSSIBLE.
SPLENDID IDEA, IVARSSON.
COME ALONG. GIVE ME A HAND.
GENTLEMEN!
MAY I REMIND YOU THAT
I AM IN COMMAND HERE.
ONLY AN IDIOT
WOULD ATTEMPT
SUCH A THING.
I WILL DO IT MYSELF.
DO BE CAREFUL. AND DON'T
TAKE ANY UNNECESSARY RISKS.
TAKE GOOD CARE.
THE WIND'S COMING UP.
LET'S HAUL HIM UP.
WELL DONE, CAPTAIN.
MY CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU, SIR ANTHONY.
I AM DEEPLY HONORED.
[ Josephine Barking ]
WHAT'S HE UP TO NOW?
MARCEL, MAKE CONTACT.
CONTACT, MON CAPITAINE.
[ Josephine Barking ]
VIVE LA FRANCE!
STOUT FELLOW,
BRIEUX.
THE MAN'S INCREDIBLE.
BRAVE BUT
MAD AS A HATTER.
MUSK OX.
OH, REALLY?
WHAT ARE THEY DOING?
THEY'RE FORMING
A DEFENSIVE RING.
THEY THINK
WE'RE ATTACKING THEM.
CAPTAIN, IS IT REALLY
NECESSARY TO FLY SO LOW?
IT'S EASIER
TO CONTROL THE AIRSHIP
AT THIS ALTITUDE.
NO NEED TO BE ALARMED,
SIR ANTHONY. LOOK.
I'M IN FULL COMMAND.
YOU'VE MADE YOUR POINT,
CAPTAIN.
THERE'S NO NEED
TO OVERDO IT.
NON! ATTENDEZ!
TAKE HOLD OF THE LINES.
WHAT I DON'T UNDERSTAND
IS WHY DONALD TOOK
ONLY ONE ESKIMO WITH HIM.
BECAUSE ONLY ONE
COULD BE PERSUADED
TO GO.
YOU SEE, THEY ALL KNEW
WHAT HE WAS LOOKING FOR.
THE MYTHICAL ISLAND
WHERE THE WHALES GO TO DIE.
ONE MAN'S MYTH IS ANOTHER MAN'S
GOSPEL, MR. IVARSSON.
ANYWAY, THE ESKIMOS
BELIEVE THE ISLAND EXISTS.
THEY'RE FRIGHTENED
TO DEATH OF IT. SAY IT'S
GUARDED BY EVIL SPIRITS.
WHAT ABOUT THE ESKIMO
WHO WENT WITH HIM?
AYE. OOMIAK'S
HIS NAME.
THEY CALL HIM
THE FEARLESS ONE,
THOUGH HE WAS
FAR FROM FEARLESS
WHEN HE COME BACK.
HE CAME BACK?
OH, AYE.
AS A MATTER OF FACT,
THAT'S HIM OUT THERE,
SHOWIN' THE CAPTAIN
HOW TO FLY HIS AIRSHIP.
HA! FETCH THE FELLOW.
CALL HIM IN.
I'M AFRAID YOU WON'T GET
ANYTHING OUT OF HIM, SIR.
CALL HIM IN AT ONCE.
DON'T ARGUE.
VERY WELL, SIR.
ANY MAN WHO GOES OFF
WITH MY SON AND THEN
COMES BACK ALONE...
I'LL SEE THAT
HE TALKS, ALL RIGHT.
I THINK YOU'D BETTER
LET ME HANDLE HIM.
YOU'VE NEVER DEALT
WITH ESKIMOS.
THEY HAVE A SORT OF
DIPLOMACY ALL THEIR OWN.
BLAST IT, IVARSSON.
ANYONE WOULD THINK
I HAD NO TACT.
COME ALONG, OOMIAK.
AH, SO THERE YOU ARE.
NOW, WHAT I WANT FROM YOU
IS AN EXACT ACCOUNT...
OF EVERYTHING THAT HAPPENED...
SIR ANTHONY,
THIS IS THE GREAT OOMIAK.
- YOUR FAME HAS TRAVELLED FAR.
WHAT FAME?
NOT EVEN MY DOGS
KNOW ME.
YOU WERE MY SON'S GUIDE.
WHAT HAPPENED TO HIM?
- THIS IS THE FATHER
OF DONALD ROSS.
WE WANT TO KNOW
ABOUT YOUR...
TELL US WHAT HAPPENED
WHEN YOU LEFT HERE
TO FIND THE ISLAND.
- ISLAND.
- DON'T TRY TO PLAY
THAT GAME WITH ME.
OOMIAK, I THINK
YOU'VE SEEN THIS BEFORE.
THIS IS THE PLACE WHERE
THE WHALES GO TO DIE.
IT'S THE ISLAND...
DONALD WAS LOOKING FOR.
WELL?
- SPEAK UP, MAN.
- MY MIND FORGETS.
IS THE FEARLESS ONE
AFRAID TO HELP US?
WE TRAVELED MANY DAYS.
EVIL SPIRITS WATCH US.
WHEN WE FIND ISLAND,
THEY MAKE BIG BLIZZARD.
PSSSSS!
THEN THEY ATTACK US.
I FIGHT LIKE BEAR. AHHH!
FIGHT LIKE BEAR,
BUT EVIL SPIRITS TOO STRONG.
SO YOU RAN AWAY
AND LEFT MY SON.
NO! WE BOTH RUN
BLIND IN SNOW.
WHEN BLIZZARD STOP,
I SEARCH FOR MANY HOURS.
NO DONALD.
I TELL TRUTH.
YOU DONALD FATHER.
I DONALD FRIEND.
HIS WHOLE STORY
IS A PACK OF LIES.
MAYBE.
BUT IT'S THE ONLY
CHANCE WE HAVE.
AT LEAST HE COULD SHOW US
WHERE HE LOST DONALD.
WE COULD START OUR SEARCH
FROM THERE. I DON'T SUPPOSE
THERE'S ANY CHANCE...
HE'D GO WITH US.
OH, NO, SIR. NONE AT ALL.
NOTHING ON EARTH
WOULD MAKE HIM GO BACK.
NOTHING ON EARTH?
CAPTAIN! WHY DON'T YOU LET
JUST ONE OF THEM GO ON BOARD?
THEN HE CAN TELL THE OTHERS...
ALL ABOUT IT.
NO, NO, NO, MONSIEUR...
WHAT ABOUT THIS FELLOW?
HE'S BEEN A GREAT HELP TO US.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO SEE
THE INSIDE OF THE AIRSHIP?
ME? YES, I LIKE.
GOOD MAN.
GIVE HIM A HAND, CAPTAIN.
WHY DON'T YOU SHOW HIM AROUND?
PERHAPS WE CAN,
AH, WIN HIM OVER.
WELL, WE CAN TRY.
CAPTAIN, A WORD WITH YOU.
CAPTAIN?
MM-HMM.
NO, NO, NO, MONSIEUR.
QUITE IMPOSSIBLE.
THERE IS NO ROOM,
AND WE ARE OVERLOADED NOW.
WE COULD LEAVE THE MECHANIC
BEHIND, PICK HIM UP
ON THE WAY BACK.
YOU ASK ME TO FLY THE SHIP
WITHOUT A MECHANIC?
BUT YOU HAVE ME.
JUST TELL ME WHAT TO DO.
I COULD TELL YOU
WHAT TO DO, MONSIEUR,
BUT YOU WOULDN'T DO IT.
LOOKS LIKE WE'RE
GETTING READY TO LEAVE.
I BETTER TAKE YOU DOWN.
OOMIAK!
LET GO THE LINES THERE.
WAIT A MINUTE.
OOMIAK'S STILL ON BOARD.
HANG IT ALL, HE'S
THE ONLY ONE WHO KNOWS
WHERE DONALD WENT TO.
WE'LL BRING HIM BACK.
AFTER HE'S HELPED US
TO FIND HIM.
SIR ANTHONY, SINCE I
NO LONGER HAVE A MECHANIC,
MAY I SUGGEST THAT YOU
FIRST MAKE FAST THE DOOR,
THEN GO ALOFT AND TAKE IN
THE LANDING LINES.
AYE, AYE, CAPTAIN.
WE'RE HERE. WE CAN ONLY GUESS
HOW FAR THE ISLAND IS.
THIS ESKIMO MAP'S
A LITTLE VAGUE.
IT'S A LOT TO GAMBLE
ON A PIECE OF BONE.
HE'S NOT MUCH HELP
TO US EITHER.
DID YOU EXPECT HIM TO BE?
SIR ANTHONY!
HUH?
COME UP, PLEASE!
IT'S VERY IMPORTANT.
WHAT IS IT?
LOOK OVER THERE.
WHALES.
WHITE WHALES. BELUGA.
INDIGENOUS TO THE ARCTIC.
NOW LOOK OVER THERE.
I SAY, THAT ONE'S
QUITE DIFFERENT.
THE CALIFORNIA GREY.
IT'S SUPPOSED TO BE FOUND
ONLY IN THE PACIFIC.
A NARWHAL,
THE UNICORN OF THE SEA.
THAT'S A RARE SIGHT,
SIR ANTHONY.
BY JOVE, THERE ARE
WHALES EVERYWHERE!
ALL KINDS OF WHALES.
AND ALL MOVING
IN THE SAME DIRECTION.
EXACTLY.
SO THERE IS A PLACE
WHERE WHALES GO TO DIE.
CAPTAIN! THAT BIG LEAD
OF OPEN WATER.
FOLLOW IT!
IF WE REALLY ARE
ON THE RIGHT TRACK, WE'D
HAVE SEEN SOMETHING BY NOW.
LOOK. YOU REMEMBER
THE JOURNAL.
"A LONE CLOUD,
AS IF LYING ON THE ICE."
OOMIAK!
IS THAT WHERE
THE ISLAND IS?
WRONG WAY!
ISLAND NOT THAT WAY!
ISLAND BACK THIS WAY!
HE JUST TOLD US
WHAT WE WANTED TO KNOW.
YES.
STEADY AS YOU GO,
CAPTAIN.
LOOK!
"AND HIDDEN BENEATH THE CLOUD,
AN ISLAND."
CAPTAIN! WHAT HAPPENED?
CAPTAIN!
CAPTAIN?
WHY ARE WE STOPPING?
IN SUCH A CLOUD,
IT'S NOT SAFE TO PROCEED.
NOT SAFE?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
I COULD NOT SEE
TO NAVIGATE.
AND THERE WILL BE
STRONG WINDS.
MY AIRSHIP COULD BE DASHED
AGAINST HIDDEN CLIFFS
AND TORN APART.
WE CAN'T TURN BACK NOW.
WE DON'T HAVE TO.
WE CAN GO IN ON FOOT.
OH.
CAPITAL IDEA!
TAKE THE SHIP DOWN
TO THE ICE, CAPTAIN.
- I'LL GET EVERYTHING READY.
- NO, NO. YOU CANNOT LEAVE
THE SHIP.
PROFESSOR! YOU KNOW
THE DANGERS THAT LIE BELOW.
EVEN IF YOU SURVIVE THE COLD,
THERE ARE STILL THE CLIFFS.
YOU COULD NOT CLIMB THE CLIFFS.
WE MUST TRY,
CAPTAIN.
I KNOW.
IT'S A GAMBLE, CAPTAIN.
BUT WITH MY SON'S LIFE AT STAKE,
I HAVE NO CHOICE.
NO, SIR ANTHONY.
IT IS I WHO HAVE NO CHOICE.
I'M NOT A MAN OF STONE.
THERE ARE TIMES
WHEN THE HEART
MUST RULE THE HEAD.
WE WILL ATTACK THE CLOUD.
CAN WE GO
ABOVE THEM?
IMPOSSIBLE!
OUR LOAD IS TOO HEAVY.
I'LL SOON LIGHTEN IT.
HURRY UP!
WE ARE LOSING HEIGHT!
YOU ALL RIGHT?
YES, QUITE.
I CAN'T HELP THINKING
OF THE CAPTAIN, THOUGH.
POOR FELLA.
HOW LONG MUST WE
KEEP THIS UP FOR?
WE CAN'T SURVIVE
IN THE OPEN. WE'VE
GOT TO KEEP MOVING...
'TIL WE FIND SHELTER.
THERE SHOULD BE CAVES
IN THOSE MOUNTAINS.
OOMIAK.
IS THIS ANYTHING LIKE
THE PLACE THAT YOU
AND DONALD CAME TO?
I TELL YOU, DONALD FATHER.
WE SEE NOTHING
IN BLIZZARD.
THEN SPIRITS COME, AND...
AND YOU FOUGHT
LIKE A BEAR.
YES, YOU MENTIONED THAT.
- SOMEBODY WATCHES.
I DON'T SEE.
I FEEL.
TOMMYROT!
SOMETHING MOVED!
DID YOU SEE ANYTHING?
I DON'T THINK SO.
NEITHER DID I.
ALL THE SAME,
I THINK WE SHOULD HEAD
IN THAT DIRECTION.
OH, VERY WELL.
IF YOU DON'T KNOW
WHERE YOU'RE GOING,
I SUPPOSE ONE WAY
IS AS GOOD AS ANOTHER.
IT'S INCREDIBLE.
I DON'T BELIEVE IT.
GREEN AND FERTILE
IN ALL THIS...
ICE AND SNOW.
LOOK.
THERE'S THE EXPLANATION.
THE ISLAND MUST BE
VOLCANIC.
HEAT RISING THROUGH
FISSURES IN THE GROUND.
IT'S PROBABLY THERMAL
SPRINGS, EXACTLY LIKE
PARTS OF ICELAND.
THERE ARE BUILDINGS
DOWN THERE.
LOOKS LIKE
SOME SORT OF SETTLEMENT.
- THERE ARE PEOPLE THERE.
THAT MEANS THAT DONALD
COULD BE THERE.
[ Speaking Norse Dialect ]
THE SPIRIT! SPIRIT!
WAIT A MINUTE.
NO, WAIT!
WE'RE FRIENDS.
[ Speaking Norse Dialect ]
DO YOU UNDERSTAND
THEIR LANGUAGE?
IT'S NORSE.
THE OLD NORSE
OF THE SAGAS.
THEIR WEAPONS,
THEIR CLOTHES,
THEIR WHOLE APPEARANCE.
THEY'RE VIKINGS.
VIKINGS?
THEY THINK WE'RE INVADERS.
WE'VE COME TO TAKE OVER
THEIR LAND.
WHAT, THE THREE OF US?
NO, THEY THINK
WE'RE THE FIRST...
AND THAT THOUSANDS MORE
ARE GONNA FOLLOW US.
WHY, IT'S RIDICULOUS.
TALK TO THEM.
EXPLAIN WHY WE'RE HERE.
WELL, I'LL TRY, BUT
I'VE NEVER SPOKEN OLD NORSE.
I'VE ONLY READ IT.
VENER!
FRED VENER.
VI VIL INGEN NOKA ILT.
VI ER KOMME
FOR A LIETE...
ETTER EIN DEI
KALLER DONALD ROSS.
DONALD?
THAT'S IT!
DONALD ROSS.
WHERE IS HE?
TELL THEM
I'M HIS FATHER.
DETTE ER FAR AT DONALD.
VENER.
WHAT IS IT?
WHAT'S GOING ON?
I KNOW HE UNDERSTOOD ME.
BUT NOW HE'S GONE OFF
TO SOUND AN ALARM, STIR UP
THE WHOLE COUNTRYSIDE.
WE'RE TO BE KEPT
UNDER CLOSE GUARD
AND FOLLOW ALONG.
THAT'S NOT GOOD.
IF THEY THINK WE'RE INVADERS,
THEN DONALD COULD HAVE BEEN
A PRISONER ALL THESE MONTHS.
MAKE THEM TELL US WHERE HE IS.
OOMIAK! NO!
IDIOT. HE MIGHT HAVE
GOT US ALL KILLED.
BUT HE DOES FIGHT
LIKE A BEAR.
HE SAYS YOU SAVED HIS LIFE.
I'M GLAD HE
APPRECIATES IT.
BUT TELL HIM
I DON'T WANT ANYTHING
TO HAPPEN TO OOMIAK.
SPARA OOMIAK.
JA.
THANK YOU.
HE SAYS YOUR SON
IS HERE AND WELL.
HE'S LIVING ON A FARM
WITH THE FAMILY OF THE MAN
WHO FOUND HIM...
AFTER THE GREAT BLIZZARD.
I-I KNEW IT.
I-I KNEW HE WAS SAFE.
I VEG.
STOGG.
HER KVILLER VI OG ET.
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
WE'RE STOPPING TO EAT.
I JUST HAD A TALK
WITH OUR FRIEND.
I FOUND OUT WHY THEY'RE
SO PANICKY ABOUT INVADERS.
OH
THESE PEOPLE
HAVE BEEN HERE
FOR CENTURIES.
THEY'RE DESCENDANTS
OF SOME EARLY
VIKING EXPEDITION.
WE'VE ACTUALLY DISCOVERED
A LOST COLONY.
THAT'S QUITE REMARKABLE.
THEY'VE BEEN SO
ISOLATED UP HERE...
THAT THEY'VE COME
TO BELIEVE THAT ALL
THE REST OF THE WORLD...
IS A FROZEN WILDERNESS
OF ICE AND SNOW.
HOW VERY ODD.
AH. TAKK.
TAKK.
YOU MEAN NONE OF THEM
HAVE EVER LEFT THE ISLAND?
THEY HAVE NO REASON TO.
THEY CALL THIS ISLAND
ASTRAGARD...
AND BELIEVE IT TO BE
THE GARDEN OF THE GODS...
AND PERFECT AND UNIQUE
IN A DESOLATE WORLD...
AND SET ASIDE
FOR THEM ALONE,
FOREVER.
WHY DO THEY FEAR INVADERS?
BECAUSE THEY HAVE
A PROPHECY.
THERE'LL BE A DAY WHEN
THE BARBARIANS FROM
THE ICE AND SNOW...
WILL TRY TO CONQUER
THEIR PARADISE.
SO THAT EXPLAINS IT.
THEY THINK THAT WE'RE
THE SAVAGES...
WHO'VE COME
TO DESTROY THEM.
COULD BE
A BIT TRICKY.
ANYWAY,
AS SOON AS I GET
TO THEIR HEAD MAN, I'LL,
UH, STRAIGHTEN THINGS OUT.
REINDEER. PROBABLY
SERVE THEM AS CATTLE.
THAT'S THE HOUSE
WHERE DONALD'S LIVING.
DONALD IS THERE?
WELL, COME ON!
HALT!
MY SON. I HAVEN'T
SEEN HIM FOR TWO YEARS.
TELL THEM, IVARSSON.
I'LL GO WITH THEM, BUT
NOT UNTIL I'VE SEEN MY SON.
HAN VIL BERRE SJA
SON SIN FYRST.
THANK YOU, MY BOY.
VERY DECENT OF YOU.
TAKK.
THEY DON'T LOOK
VERY HAPPY TO SEE US.
THAT HUNTER MUST HAVE
STIRRED THEM UP.
I DON'T SEE DONALD.
THANK YOU, SIR.
UH, DONALD.
DONALD ROSS.
WHERE IS HE?
CAN YOU TELL US?
ASK HIM
ABOUT DONALD.
IS IT TRUE THAT YOU
ARE DONALD'S FATHER?
GOOD HEAVENS.
YOU SPEAK ENGLISH.
DONALD TAUGHT ME.
HE LIVES WITH US SINCE
HE CAME TO OUR LAND.
THIS IS MY FATHER.
I'M GRATEFUL TO YOU, SIR,
FOR LOOKING AFTER MY SON.
UH, WHERE IS HE NOW?
HE WANTS US
TO GO INTO THE HOUSE.
WE CANNOT TALK OUT HERE.
OH, VERY WELL.
THANK YOU.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN
THEY TOOK DONALD AWAY?
WHO TOOK HIM?
THE GODI'S MEN.
THEY CAME WITH WEAPONS.
THE GODI'S
THEIR HIGH PRIEST.
IT WAS BECAUSE OF THE HUNTER.
HE RODE DOWN FROM THE MOUNTAIN
SHOUTING OF INVADERS.
IT WAS THAT FELLOW
ON THE HORSE.
YES.
WHEN THE GODI HEARD,
HE SOUNDED THE LONG HORN.
THE LONG HORN...
IS THEIR CALL TO BATTLE.
BATTLE
WHAT HAS THIS TO DO
WITH DONALD?
WHEN IT WAS TOLD THAT
ONE OF THE INVADERS
WAS DONALD'S FATHER,
THE GODI SAID THAT
DONALD WAS A SPY...
WHO CAME HERE TO
BETRAY US TO THE ENEMY.
WELL, SURELY YOU
DON'T BELIEVE THAT.
WE DON'T... BECAUSE
WE KNOW DONALD.
THERE WERE MANY
THAT DID BELIEVE...
BECAUSE THERE WAS
AN OMEN IN THE SKY.
OMEN?
A MONSTER LIKE A WHALE,
BUT BIGGER MANY TIMES.
OH, MY DEAR GIRL,
THAT'S EASILY EXPLAINED.
WHAT THE PEOPLE SAW
WAS MY AIRSHIP.
YOU SEE, IT'S LIKE...
IT... IT...
IT'S LIKE ONE
OF YOUR BOATS, ONLY
IT SAILS IN THE AIR.
NOW, LOOK, IF I COULD
JUST TALK TO THIS GODI,
I COULD EXPLAIN EVERYTHING.
WE'RE TO BE TAKEN
BEFORE THE COUNCIL
AT THE TEMPLE.
ERIK'S A MEMBER.
YOU'LL GET YOUR CHANCE
TO BE HEARD.
THAT GIRL. SHE SPEAKS
BETTER ENGLISH THAN OOMIAK.
SHE'S PRETTIER TOO.
IF SHE LEARNED IT ALL
FROM DONALD,
HE MUST HAVE SPENT
QUITE A LOT OF TIME
IN HER COMPANY.
CAN YOU BLAME HIM?
I CAN'T SAY
I DO, NO.
THIS IS LIKE
AN ARCHAEOLOGIST'S DREAM.
TO GO BACK IN HISTORY
AND WALK THE EARTH
AS IT WAS...
TEN CENTURIES AGO.
I SUGGEST
YOU FORGET THE PAST...
AND START THINKING
ABOUT THE FUTURE,
WHICH, FROM THE LOOK OF THINGS,
I'D SAY IS NOT VERY PROMISING.
THE CLOTHES THEY WEAR,
THE WEAPONS THEY CARRY.
EACH ONE OF THEM
COULD BE A MUSEUM PIECE.
THAT'S WHAT I DON'T LIKE.
THOSE MUSEUM PIECES.
LOOK AT THAT!
A VIKING LONG SHIP,
EXACTLY THE WAY THEY WERE
BUILT A THOUSAND YEARS AGO.
HERE, NONE OF THAT.
NOW STOP IT.
POOR FELLA.
AND IT'S ALL MY FAULT.
KOMM HER.
THE TEMPLE. THAT'S WHERE
WE'RE GONNA MEET THE COUNCIL.
AH, GOOD. GO STRAIGHT
TO THE TOP, I ALWAYS SAY.
ODIN, THOR AND FREY...
THE GREATEST
OF ALL THE VIKING GODS.
I HOPE THEY'RE
ON OUR SIDE.
WE MAY NEED
ALL THE HELP
WE CAN GET.
A VIKING COUNCIL,
STRAIGHT OUT
OF A HISTORY BOOK.
THAT'S THE GIRL'S FATHER.
HE SEEMS A SENSIBLE
OLD FELLOW.
THEY PROBABLY STILL CALL
THE ONE WITH THE STAFF...
THE LAWSPEAKER.
THEY ALL LOOK
REASONABLE ENOUGH.
THEY MIGHT BE
MY BOARD OF DIRECTORS...
IF IT WEREN'T FOR
THEIR OUTLANDISH COSTUMES.
HE SAID, "BRING OUT
THE OTHER PRISONER."
- DONALD!
- FATHER!
THAT'S MY SON!
I'VE BEEN LOOKING FOR YOU.
I THOUGHT YOU MIGHT.
HE'S MY SON.
JOHN IVARSSON.
DONALD.
HOW DO YOU DO?
HE'S, UH,
KEEN ON THE PAST.
ARCHAEOLOGY.
OH.
SORRY ABOUT ALL THIS.
IT'S A BIT STICKY, I'M AFRAID.
DONALD ROSS...
HE SAYS THAT WHEN
I CAME TO THIS LAND,
I GAVE MY OATH
THAT I CAME ALONE
AND IN PEACE.
BUT NOW COME OTHERS,
AND WITH THEM, AN EVIL
OMEN IN THE SKY...
THAT CANNOT BE
IGNORED.
THAT'S MY CONFOUNDED AIRSHIP.
LET THE PRISONERS SPEAK
BEFORE THEY'RE JUDGED.
THAT IS PRECISELY
WHAT I WANTED TO DO.
FATHER...
I'LL HANDLE THIS.
YOU JUST TRANSLATE FOR ME.
WHAT DO THEY CALL
THIS ISLAND?
ASTRAGARD.
BUT, FATHER, IT'S...
TSK, TSK, TSK.
HONORED COUNCIL OF ASTRAGARD,
I COME TO YOUR BEAUTIFUL
COUNTRY AS A FRIEND,
IN PEACE, [ Speaking Norse ]
SEEKING ONLY MY SON,
WHO WAS LOST TO ME.
[ Donald Speaking Norse ]
- THE GODI.
HE'S TELLING THEM
NOT TO LISTEN
TO OUR LIES.
IT'S OBVIOUS THAT WE'RE
BARBARIANS WHO COVET
THEIR SACRED LANDS.
AND WE MUST
BE CONDEMNED AT ONCE,
AND WITHOUT A HEARING.
NOW, LOOK HERE,
I THOUGHT I EXPLAINED...
IT IS NO LONGER A MATTER
FOR THE COUNCIL,
FOR THE GODS HAVE SPOKEN.
IF THESE MEN ARE SPARED,
MORE WILL COME...
IN ARMED HORDES...
TO PILLAGE AND PROFANE
OUR SACRED LAND.
DODEN! DODEN! DODEN!
THERE CAN BE BUT ONE PENALTY
FOR THE INVADERS: DEATH.
DODEN! DODEN! DODEN!
DODEN.
DODEN! DODEN!
QUITE A SEND-OFF.
FULL VIKING HONORS.
ALL VERY AUTHENTIC.
VERY FINAL.
I'M SORRY, FATHER.
- NONSENSE, MY BOY.
- DONALD!
FREYJA!
WE'RE IN YOUR DEBT,
YOUNG LADY.
HERE THEY COME!
AND PULL!
THE SHORE!
IT'S OUR ONLY CHANCE!
YOU STAY HERE.
I WILL DRAW THEM AWAY.
NO, YOU WON'T!
IT'S TOO DANGEROUS.
HE'S RIGHT, MY DEAR.
IT'S YOU THEY'RE AFTER,
NOT ME.
THERE IS A HUNTERS'
CAVE UP THERE...
WITH FOOD AND CLOTHING.
I'LL BE BACK
WHEN IT'S SAFE.
FREYJA!
HERE THEY COME.
I THINK SHE'S DONE IT.
GOOD GIRL.
I SHOULD NEVER
HAVE LET HER GO.
IF THEY CATCH HER...
OH, DON'T WORRY, MY BOY.
SHE KNOWS WHAT SHE'S DOING.
LET'S FIND THAT CAVE.
HELLO.
OOMIAK,
MY DEAR OLD FRIEND!
I'M SO GLAD TO SEE YOU!
WE ALL ARE.
- WE THOUGHT WE'D LOST YA.
- CAN'T KILL OOMIAK.
I HIDE IN WATER,
SWIM FAR LIKE WHITE BEAR.
GOOD! GOOD!
BUT LET'S GO.
I WATCH NOW.
THERE'S STILL NOTHING.
OH, IVARSSON'S UP ABOVE
SCOUTING AROUND, RIGHT?
GOOD MORNING, FATHER.
HMM?
GOOD MORNING.
DID YOU SLEEP WELL?
WRETCHEDLY. YOU MUST BE
A BIT DONE-IN YOURSELF.
OH, I'M WORRIED ABOUT FREYJA.
SO AM I, MY BOY.
SO AM I.
WELL, I'VE MADE
A MESS OF IT,
HAVEN'T I?
OF WHAT, FATHER?
THE WHOLE MISERABLE THING.
ALL THIS NIGHTMARE
WE'RE LIVING IN, IT...
IT'S ALL MY FAULT.
EVERY BIT OF IT.
YOUR FAULT
IF ANYONE'S TO BLAME,
I'M THE ONE THAT RAN OFF
CHASING RAINBOWS.
AND YOU'RE NOT
RESPONSIBLE FOR THAT.
I AM. RIGHT FROM
THE BEGINNING.
I WAS ALWAYS
TRYING TO SHAPE YOU...
INTO MY MOLD.
BULLYING, BADGERING,
NEVER LETTING UP.
IF I HADN'T DRIVEN YOU
AWAY FROM HOME, NONE OF THIS
WOULD HAVE HAPPENED.
FATHER, YOU DIDN'T DRIVE ME.
DONALD,
I RODE AN AIRSHIP
ACROSS THE TOP OF THE WORLD
TO TELL YOU THIS.
IF WE GET OUT OF THIS,
YOU CAN DO ANYTHING
YOU WANT TO DO.
YOU'LL BE FREE OF ME,
I PROMISE YOU.
BUT I DON'T WANT
TO BE FREE OF YOU.
I NEVER DID.
I CAME HERE
LOOKING FOR ADVENTURE,
AND I CERTAINLY FOUND THAT.
BUT... I DON'T BELONG HERE.
NOW, WHEN WE GET
OUT OF THIS...
AND WE WILL...
THEN I'M COMING HOME WITH YOU.
I WANT TO SHARE IN YOUR WORK
AND YOUR RESPONSIBILITIES...
IF YOU'LL LET ME.
IF I'LL LET YOU?
WH...
YOU WON'T REGRET IT.
I'LL SEE TO THAT.
DONALD?
FREYJA!
- HE WAS QUITE WORRIED
ABOUT YOU, MY DEAR.
I WENT BACK
TO THE FARM.
IT WILL BE JUST AS WE HAD
ARRANGED IT. FATHER WILL
GIVE US DOGS AND A SLED.
WHAT HAD YOU ARRANGED?
YOU SEE,
FOR SOME TIME NOW,
FREYJA AND I
HAVE BEEN PLANNING
TO LEAVE THE ISLAND.
IF WE MANAGED TO ESCAPE,
WE HOPED TO REACH
FORT CONGER.
THE TWO OF YOU TOGETHER?
DO YOU THINK
I'D LEAVE HER BEHIND?
NOT IF YOU'RE
YOUR FATHER'S SON, NO.
HELLO! BOATS!
THEY COME!
WHAT DO WE DO NOW?
THERE'S NOT MUCH COVER,
BUT I THINK WE CAN
GET TO THE TOP
WITHOUT BEING SEEN.
THAT SETTLES IT.
WE CAN'T STAY HERE.
THOSE HOUNDS WOULD
FIND US IN NO TIME.
LOOK. THE GODI'S
JOINED US.
BLOODTHIRSTY BOUNDER.
COME ON, EVERYBODY.
UP WE GO.
THEY GO! THEY GO!
WE'VE DONE IT!
THEY'VE FINALLY GIVEN UP!
- THANK HEAVENS FOR THAT.
- LOOK OUT, FATHER!
CLUMSY OF ME.
NOW THE WOLVES
ARE AFTER US AGAIN.
I'M AFRAID SO,
FATHER.
IT'S INCREDIBLE!
IT'S ABSOLUTELY
INCREDIBLE!
NASTY SORT OF PLACE.
- OOMIAK, GO WATCH BELOW.
WE'RE GOING TO NEED
SOMEWHERE TO HIDE.
BUT WHERE?
THEY MUST KNOW
EVERY FOOT OF THIS ISLAND.
THE BAY OF WHALES!
DONALD!
IT'S SOMEWHERE
OVER THERE,
TO THE SOUTH.
IT'S SACRED. TABOO.
THE VIKINGS WON'T
GO NEAR IT.
THAT'S IT, THEN.
LET'S GO!
NO, DONALD, PLEASE!
THE SPIRITS!
FREYJA, BELIEVE ME...
WHAT IS IT?
THE SPIRITS
ARE GOOD SPIRITS.
DIDN'T THEY PROTECT
YOUR PEOPLE WHEN
THEY FIRST CAME HERE?
SURELY THEY'LL
PROTECT US.
THEY COME!
THEY COME! WE GO!
FREYJA, TRUST ME.
COME ON UP!
ODDLY ENOUGH,
THEY SAY THIS SULFUR'S
GOOD FOR THE LUNGS.
AHH.
SIR ANTHONY, THIS IS
HARDLY THE TIME TO REST.
I ONLY HOPE WE SOON FIND
THAT BLASTED BAY OF WHALES.
COME ON!
MY FATHER!
FATHER!
BURNING ONE MINUTE,
FREEZING THE NEXT.
A MAN COULD
CATCH HIS DEATH.
WELL, THAT'S
WHAT'S SO INTERESTING
ABOUT THE ARCTIC:
ITS, UH,
CONTRADICTIONS.
YOU KNOW, ON MY FIRST
EXPEDITION TO BAFFIN LAND...
IVARSSON, PLEASE. STOP!
WHAT WE NEED
IS A CONFERENCE.
CONFERENCE?
ABOUT WHAT, FATHER?
WELL, IF WE FIND
THE BAY OF WHALES,
AND IF IT'S TRUE
THAT THE GODI
WON'T FOLLOW US THERE,
WHAT DO WE DO THEN?
WE LIE LOW FOR A BIT,
TRY AND MAKE OUR WAY ACROSS
THE MOUNTAINS TO FREYJA'S FARM.
WE CAN'T GO BACK
THROUGH THAT INFERNO.
NO, NO, NO, NO.
WE FIND ICE BOAT, FLOAT.
FFFF, VERY GOOD.
BOAT?
WHAT ON EARTH'S
HE TALKING ABOUT?
I THINK HE WANTS TO FIND...
A PIECE OF PACK ICE
DOWN THERE AND FLOAT
AROUND THE MOUNTAIN.
PREPOSTEROUS.
WHERE THE WHALES
GO TO DIE.
ALL THOSE GREAT CREATURES
FROM EVERY SEA LYING THERE
FROM THE BEGINNING OF TIME.
JUST LOOK AT
ALL THAT WHALEBONE!
WORTH MILLIONS OF POUNDS!
AND HEAVEN KNOWS WHAT PRICE
THE AMBERGRIS WOULD FETCH!
ALL THAT DOESN'T MATTER NOW,
DOES IT, FATHER?
FREYJA. DON'T BE AFRAID.
THINK OF THE SAGA.
DOESN'T IT TELL HOW,
LONG AGO, IT WAS THE WHALES...
THAT LED YOUR PEOPLE HERE,
WHERE THEY FOUND PEACE
AND HAPPINESS?
SO THERE'S NOTHING
TO FEAR, BELIEVE ME.
WE NEED ICE BOAT.
HOW WE GET DOWN THERE?
YES, HOW? NOT DOWN
THESE CLIFFS, OBVIOUSLY.
THERE MUST BE A WAY.
THE VIKINGS FOUND ONE.
FREYJA, IS IT IN THE SAGA?
DOES IT TELL HOW THEY CAME
UP FROM THE SEA?
WITH THE HELP
OF THE GODS.
IT IS TOLD
THAT THEY CAME THROUGH
THE... MOUTH OF HELL.
THAT'S NOT VERY EXPLICIT,
I'M AFRAID.
WAIT A MINUTE.
THAT VOLCANO IN ICELAND,
MOUNT HEKLA.
THE EARLY CHRISTIANS
BELIEVED THAT WAS
THE ENTRANCE TO HELL.
- ENTRANCE.
IT'S A WILD THOUGHT.
COME ON!
THE CRATER OF
A DEAD VOLCANO!
QUIET!
YOU HEAR THAT?
DOWN THERE SOMEWHERE
THERE'S AN UNDERGROUND RIVER.
THE RIVER MUST
FLOW DOWN TO THE SEA,
WHICH MEANS THERE HAS TO BE
A PASSAGE FROM THE BOTTOM
OF THE CRATER TO THE BAY!
HELLO!
COME ON!
LOOK! THE WATER'S
RUNNING OUT! COME ON!
WHERE TO?
WHEREVER THE WATER WENT.
LOOK!
DO NOT WORRY.
I HUNT SEAL THIS WAY
MANY TIMES.
IT'S NOT THIS
I'M WORRIED ABOUT.
IT'S THEM.
WILL THEY NEVER GIVE UP?
I CAN'T UNDERSTAND WHY
THE BOWMEN HAVEN'T
BEEN SHOOTING AT US.
THEY DO NOT
HAVE TO.
THEY ONLY WAIT
TO SEE US DIE.
FREYJA!
IT'S TOLD IN THE SAGAS
THAT THE BAY IS GUARDED
BY SEA BEASTS.
WE CANNOT ESCAPE.
KILLER WHALES!
WHAT DO WE DO NOW?
ANYTHING WE CAN!
HERE COMES THE OTHER ONE!
HOLD ON, EVERYBODY!
- HELLO, HELLO!
THE HYPERION!
AND HEAVEN BE PRAISED,
OUR OLD FRIEND
THE CAPTAIN!
MY COMPLIMENTS,
CAPTAIN.
YOU KEEP AN
EXCELLENT TABLE.
AND YOU'RE AN EXCELLENT SHOT.
YOU SAVED OUR LIVES.
THANK YOU.
AN UNEXPECTED PLEASURE.
SINCE I LANDED TWO DAYS AGO,
I'VE BEEN TRYING TO SAVE MY OWN.
BUT GETTING
OUT OF HERE...
THAT'S GOING TO BE
QUITE A PROBLEM,
ISN'T IT, CAPTAIN?
I HAVE THE SOLUTION.
MY SHIP MAY BE
BATTERED AND TORN,
BUT THE MIND
THAT CONCEIVED IT...
THAT STILL FUNCTIONS.
AS YOU SEE, THE SHIP
HAS LOST MUCH GAS,
BUT IT RETAINS
SOME, UH... BUOYANCY?
SO IF WE REDUCE
SUFFICIENTLY THE WEIGHT,
THEN IT WILL RISE.
HOW WOULD YOU
REDUCE THE WEIGHT?
ABANDON THE MOTORS.
THE PROPELLERS
ARE BROKEN ANYWAY.
THE GONDOLA TOO.
STRIP THE SHIP
OF EVERYTHING
THAT WEIGHTS IT DOWN.
WHAT HAVE WE THEN?
A FREE BALLOON.
BY JOVE!
AT LEAST IT WOULD
CARRY US ACROSS THE BAY.
YES, AND IF WE CAN
JUST REACH THE PACK ICE.
WE SHALL GO FARTHER THAN THAT.
THE PREVAILING WIND
IS TO THE SOUTH.
IF IT HOLDS,
WE SHOULD BE ABLE
TO DRIFT TO GREENLAND.
WHEN WE REACH THE COAST,
WE DESCEND...
AND PROCEED ON FOOT
TO THE NEAREST HABITATION.
CAPTAIN BRIEUX, YOU ARE
A VERY REMARKABLE MAN.
I'VE ALWAYS FELT SO.
SIR ANTHONY!
I'D SAY THIS IS
A BIT MUCH, ISN'T IT?
HARDLY THE TIME
FOR CEREMONIES.
LET'S BE OFF.
PLEASE, SIR ANTHONY.
THIS IS A MOMENT TO BE SAVORED.
ONCE MORE WE STAND
ON THE THRESHOLD OF
A GREAT ADVENTURE.
TO MY HYPERION!
MAY SHE RISE...
LIKE A PHOENIX
FROM THE ASHES OF DESPAIR...
AND SOAR
LIKE MAN'S IMAGINATION...
TO GREENLAND AND BEYOND.
THE HYPERION.
NOW LET'S GET GOING,
SHALL WE?
BUT OF COURSE,
MONSIEUR.
I WILL SHOW YOU NOW
THE INGENIOUS ARRANGEMENTS...
I'VE MADE
FOR OUR DEPARTURE.
PERHAPS YOU HAVE OBSERVED THAT
I'VE CUT LOOSE THE GONDOLA,
AND THE SHIP IS NOW
ATTACHED TO IT
ONLY BY A SINGLE CABLE.
SO ARE THE MOTORS
AND THE TAIL.
THIS SECTION, TOO,
LINKED TO THE SHIP
ONLY BY A CABLE.
WHEN I SLIP THESE CABLES,
THE GONDOLA, THE MOTORS,
AND THE TAIL DETACH
THEMSELVES, AND WE RISE.
ARE YOU SURE?
YOU WILL SEE.
NOW, GENTLEMEN,
IF YOU WILL ASSIST ME.
THE GONDOLA.
THE MOTORS AND THE TAIL.
WHEN I SAY "THREE," YOU WILL
PULL WITH ALL YOUR FORCE.
RIGHT.
- PERMISSION TO PROCEED,
MONSIEUR?
OOH, YES, YES, YES.
PROCEED.
VERY WELL.
ONE.
TWO.
THREE!
WELL, SIR ANTHONY?
IT WORKED PERFECTLY.
ONCE AGAIN, CAPTAIN,
I UNDERESTIMATED YOU.
WELL, I THINK I'LL TURN IN.
I HAVEN'T HAD A GOOD NIGHT'S
SLEEP SINCE I LEFT ENGLAND.
SIR ANTHONY?
HMM?
TAKE A LOOK.
CAMPFIRES.
SO THEY'RE STILL
WAITING FOR US.
IT'S A PITY WE'LL
HAVE TO DISAPPOINT THEM.
WHAT IS IT?
YOU'RE NOT
FRIGHTENED ANYMORE?
A LITTLE.
OH, NO, YOU MUSTN'T BE.
IT'S ALL OVER.
WE'RE SAFE NOW.
I KNOW. IT IS NOT THAT.
WHAT, THEN?
IT IS THE WORLD
BEYOND OUR MOUNTAINS...
YOUR WORLD.
MY WORLD ISN'T
REALLY SO DIFFERENT.
IT'S BIGGER AND
EVERYTHING MOVES FASTER.
WE LIVE BY CLOCKS
AND MACHINES...
INSTEAD OF TIDES
AND SEASONS.
YOU'LL GET USED TO IT...
AND BE HAPPY,
BECAUSE YOU'LL BE SURROUNDED
BY PEOPLE YOU LOVE
AND WHO LOVE YOU.
I WISH MY FATHER
COULD BE WITH US.
I KNOW.
BUT HIS HOME
IS ASTRAGARD.
HIS HEART
WILL ALWAYS BE HERE.
MINE IS WITH YOU.
IVARSSON!
HM... HMM?
WHEN DOES THE FIRST SHIP
LEAVE GREENLAND
IN THE SPRING?
USUALLY THE BEGINNING
OF APRIL.
SO WITH ANY LUCK,
WE SHOULD BE
BACK IN ENGLAND...
IN ABOUT SIX WEEKS.
I SHOULD NOT
COUNT ON IT,
MONSIEUR.
THE WIND HAS CHANGED.
WE ARE DRIFTING
BACK TO THE LAND.
HANG IT ALL.
CAN'T SOMETHING
BE DONE?
I CANNOT COMMAND
THE WIND, MONSIEUR.
WE'RE RISING.
THE UPDRAFT. THE WIND
AGAINST THE CLIFFS.
WHAT HAPPENS WHEN
WE GET TO THE TOP?
EVERYBODY, OUT. QUICK!
IT'S TRUE THAT
THE GODS WERE ANGRY,
BUT IT WAS THE GODI
WHO DID WRONG...
BY LEADING
THE PEOPLE TO HATRED
AND TO VIOLENCE.
I'M GLAD
THEY RECOGNIZE THAT.
THE PRISONERS
MAY GO IN PEACE
ON THIS CONDITION:
THAT THEY SWEAR
A SACRED OATH...
NEVER TO REVEAL
THE EXISTENCE OF THIS,
THE SACRED ISLAND.
THAT'S FAIR ENOUGH.
BU... TO ENSURE THAT
THE OATH BE HONORED
FOR ALL TIME,
WE MUST DEMAND
ONE THING.
WELL, GO ON. WHAT IS IT?
THAT YOU LEAVE
A HOSTAGE HERE.
YOUR SON.
I REFUSE TO DISCUSS IT
ANY FURTHER.
HOW COULD THEY
POSSIBLY IMAGINE I WOULD
LEAVE YOU BEHIND?
BUT THOSE ARE THEIR TERMS!
I WILL NOT PERMIT IT.
FATHER, WITHOUT A HOSTAGE,
NONE OF US WILL LEAVE HERE!
BLAST IT!
THEN I'LL BE THE HOSTAGE!
I DON'T THINK SO, SIR ANTHONY.
AS A MATTER OF FACT,
EVERYTHING'S ALREADY
BEEN ARRANGED.
AND VERY SATISFACTORILY
FOR EVERYBODY, I THINK.
ARE YOU SURE
IT'S WHAT YOU WANT?
ARE YOU REALLY SURE
YOU WANT TO BE LEFT BEHIND?
YES, I'M SURE.
THIS IS A CHANCE
NO ARCHAEOLOGIST
COULD TURN DOWN.
NOT ONLY TO STUDY THE PAST,
BUT TO RELIVE IT?
I MEAN, HERE IT ALL IS,
HIDDEN BEHIND THIS MIST
FOR A THOUSAND YEARS,
AND I HAVEN'T EVEN
SCRATCHED THE SURFACE.
BESIDES, WHO SAYS
I'M BEING LEFT BEHIND?
WE ARCHAEOLOGISTS
TAKE A LONGER VIEW.
WHOLE CIVILIZATIONS
HAVE VANISHED BEFORE,
YOU KNOW.
THE DAY MAY COME
WHEN THIS MIGHT BE
MAN'S LAST REFUGE.
GOOD LUCK.
RIGHT, THEN!
GET!
GOOD-BYE,
MY FRIENDS!