[thundering]
[creaking]
[foghorn]
[p.a. system.:
foreign language]
[p.a. continues]
Attention, please,
the economic and social council...
will convene
in five minutes.
[p.a. system.:
foreign language]
[p.a. continues]
- Bonjour, Bernard.
- Good day, sir.
- Good day, Mr. ambassador.
- [ Russian ]
- How do you do, Ma'am ?
- [ German ]
- [ gavel pounding ]
- Order, order.
This emergency meeting...
of the international
rescue aid society is now in session.
Delegates, you have been summoned
from all corners of the globe...
... because we have reason to believe
that someone is in distress.
As you know,
our society...
has never failed
to answer a call for help.
- Hear, hear.
[cheering]
We will face the portrait of the
beloved founder of our society,
Euripides mouse.
Delegates,
hands over hearts!
Mouse scouts,
bring in the bottle.
[creaking]
[indistinct chatter]
Mr. Bernard,
if you please.
Uh, coming through,
pardon me.
Have a care there.
- [laughing]
- I'm, I'm--
I'm sorry.
Excuse me, sir.
- Whoops!
- Egad!
[laughing]
Delegates,
this is no time for levity.
Serious business,
you know, serious business.
[sighing]
Now what?
Sir, there... uh...
are 13 steps on this ladder.
Oh, superstitious nonsense.
[grunting]
What next?
Oh, uh, sorry, sir.
I'll have it out
in a jiffy, sir.
[applause]
Ahem. Ahem.
Hmm, most difficult
to decipher.
I can't make it out.
Terrible trouble.
Oh, dear,
it's all watered out.
Penny?
Morningside orphanage?
Dash it all, it's not
much to go on, is it?
Oh, that poor little girl.
Oh, Mr chairman, please,
please, may I have...
... this assignment?
You? Miss Bianca?
[chuckling]
Dear lady, it's absolutely
without precedent.
I mean, it's not like the old
days when it was a man's world.
However, I suppose
there has to be a first time.
Mr chairman, sir,
I don't think
Miss Bianca should go.
It could be dangerous.
I mean, anything...
... could happen to her.
You see, dear lady, before
our janitor interrupted,
ahem...
I was about to suggest...
... that you should have
a co-agent go with you.
Gentlemen,
who will volunteer?
Why, gentlemen,
this is indeed a most
difficult decision to make.
I choose...
Mr Bernard...
to be my co-agent.
M-me ? Oh, that's
really very, uh--
see, I'm a--
I'm only a-- a janitor.
Oh, come on. We'll be
a great team together.
Oh, come on.
Bravo! Bravo!
[cheering]
A janitor and a lady?
Ho, ho, good heavens,
bless my soul.
Tsk-tsk-tsk.
Morningside
orphanage?
Here, here it is.
Three blocks down and,
uh... four blocks over.
Why don't we take
the short-cut through the zoo?
Gee, Miss Bianca,
I, uh--
I don't know. I mean...
it's... you know--
- It could be risky.
- Oh, come on.
Remember our pledge?
Never fail to do
what's right.
All right... duty calls.
[Indistinct sounds]
Mr Bernard, maybe
we better go back.
It's so dark in there.
Dark?
Who's afraid of the dark?
Look, you stay here.
I'll check it out.
[Indistinct sounds]
[growling]
Aaah!
Wait for me!
[panting]
How--
How about trying
the three blocks down
and four blocks over?
What did you do
to make him so mad?
Nothing, he's just
a grumpy old lion.
But after all, waking him up
in the middle of the night--
wouldn't you
be grumpy too?
I didn't wake him up
in the middle of the night.
I was walking through,
banging into something.
I'll, uh--
I'll take a look around.
see what I can find.
Psst!
Psst! Miss Bianca, over here,
I found something.
These are
Penny's belongings.
Good work.
now we're getting some where.
[Bianca]
Oh, look, the little girl's treasures.
[Bernard]
Boy, the things kids collect.
[Bianca]
Do you think she could be
still here in the orphanage?
[Bianca]
Maybe she's been adopted?
[Bernard]
No, because she would have
taken these things with her.
- Mice!
- Cat!
Now look here,
you two.
If folks find out
that mice moved in here,
I'll get kicked out,
lose my job.
Oh, don't worry,
Mr. cat.
- We won't be here long.
[yawning]
I'm a bit too old
to be chasing mice.
Sir, could you tell us what happened
to a girl named Penny ?
Well, I sure can.
You ain't gonna
find her around here.
The poor little thing
ran away.
When was the last time
you saw Penny?
Was there anything unusual?
Try to remember.
Let's see now.
the last time I saw her...
She was sitting over there
on her bed.
All alone.
She looked awful sad.
so I asked her,
- What's wrong, Penny honey ?
- Nothing.
Oh, come on now.
come on, no secrets.
You tell old Rufus, huh?
Well, it was adoption day
at the orphanage.
- What happened?
- A man and a lady came...
She was prettier than me.
Oh, she couldn't be.
You listen to me, darlin'.
- You're something extra special.
- No, I'm not.
Why, someday a mama
and a papa'll come
to the orphanage...
... lookin' for a pretty girl
just like you.
- Honest ?
- l'll bet my whiskers on it.
but... you got to believe it.
Keep the faith, sweetheart.
See that bluebird ?
Yes, I do.
Well, faith is a bluebird
you see from afar.
It's for real and assure
as the first evening star.
You can't touch it
or buy it or wrap it up tight,
But it's there
just the same,
Making things
turn out right.
Can't touch it or buy it
or wrap it up tight,
But it's there
just the same,
Making things
turn out right.
But who ever 'dopts me
has to 'dopt teddy too.
Oh, they'll love him.
He doesn't eat much, does he ?
Oh, here.
I brought you something.
Land of goshen!
Catnip snaps.
No! They're
ginger-snaps!
Well, an old codger
like me...
could use
a little ginger.
We're not supposed
to do that.
You can trust me.
I won't
tattletale on you.
I love you, Rufus.
[purring]
Gee, we better hurry.
We'll be late for supper.
[Rufus]
She seemed happy enough,
but the next thing I heard,
Penny was gone.
Well, aren't the police
still looking for her?
No, no,
they gave up weeks ago.
Oh, this is terrible.
that poor little girl.
I just can't believe
that Penny would run away.
Mr. Rufus, please think.
there must be something.
Well, come to think of it...
...there was.
No, no, it's nothing.
Penny wouldn't get in with her.
Get in what?
With who?
A weird lady tried
to give Penny a ride,
She wouldn 't have anything
to do with trashy people.
Trashy people?
Who?
She and her partner run a sleazy
pawnshop down the street.
Miss Bianca, we must
go down there and investigate.
Suit yourself, but you'd be
wastin' your time goin' down there.
She could be in trouble.
we gotta find and help her.
Yeah, but
two little mice?
What--
What can you do?
[ticking]
[whispering]
Bernard, a child's book.
- It's Penny's.
- then she's got to be here.
Cuckoo! Cuckoo!
[laughing]
What's so funny?
Your tail.
[chuckling]
Here, let me
help you fix it.
[ringing]
Who could be ringing
at this time of the night?
Madame Medusa's
pawnshop boutique.
- Hello, boss?
- Snoops!
Don't tell me.
Let me guess.
You found it. Ha-ha-ha!
You've found the diamond!
[snoops indistinct]
- Give you time?
You bungler!
You have been down there
for three months.
[snoops indistinct]
- Bottles?
What bottles?
You caught Penny...
Sending messages
in bottles!
You blundering fool!
Can't you control...
A little girl?
Shut up!
I am taking the next flight
down to devil's bayou.
This is terrible.
We've got to go with her.
Yeah, come on,
in the suitcase.
[sighing]
Bumbling boob!
He fouls up everything.
Leave him for a few weeks
and hah--
Oh, why won't this
stupid thing close?
[grunting]
[engine reeving]
[honking]
Out of my way, you road hog!
[screeching]
[p.a. system]
Please report for flight 614.
Hurry, Miss Bianca.
Medusa could be at
the devil's bayou by now.
[panting]
I'm sorry,
But a lady does have
to pack a few things, you know?
[p.a. system]
Will Mr. Jenkins report
to the ticket counter, please?
All passengers,
please report...
for flight 614
now departing.
Flight leaves 6:45.
[Bernard]
Oh no, we missed the flight!
Miss Bianca,
if you hadn't--
You worry too much.
Flights are always late.
[radio]
Albatross flight 13 to tower.
- Albatross 13.
- What did i tell you?
We are lucky, Mr Bernard.
Luck? Flight 13?
Maybe we'd better
take the train.
[radio]
Wake up!
Dad-dratit!
Somebody answer down there.
Get off the dime!
Hello ! Hello!
Is anybody
down there?
Uh, hello?
- Where you been,
you lazy knucklehead?
- We just got here, sir.
- See, my co-agent insisted
on packing her, uh--
[helicopter]
Look, bud, am clear to land?
Traffic is thicker--
[helicopter]
Wow! Dad-blast!
You dirty road hog!
crazy--
Look, what is--
[louder]
Stupid lug-headed--
- What is he saying?
- I wouldn't dare repeat it.
Then give him
the permission to land.
Captain, you have
our permission to land.
It's about time, bud!
Look! Look!
There he is.
[Bianca]
Doesn't he fly beautifully?
And you wanted to take
the train, you 'fraidy cat.
'fraidy cat?
It was just that, uh--
I like trains.
l mean they
serve Roquefort  .
[gasping]
Pull up! Pull up!
[skidding]
[screeching]
Are you hurt, sir?
Oh, great.
come on,
We're gonna
take the train.
[whispering]
Play it safe.
- Train? Safe?
Listen here, buster.
I'm as fit as a fiddle.
And you look
simply wonderful, captain.
Shucks, just call me
Orville, little lady.
All right, all right.
It's most important
we get to devil's bayou.
You just keep
your shirt on.
Flight 13 hits the wild
blue yonder in 5 minutes.
Eight, nine,
ten, eleven,
...twelve,
Oh no.
There are 13 steps
on this ramp.
Well, why don't
you jump the last one?
This is your captain speaking.
Welcome aboard, folks.
Fasten your seat belts.
No smoking.
[chuckling]
Miss Bianca, be sure
it's fastened good and tight.
I can't.
It'll wrinkle my dress.
Say, bud,
read the checklist to me.
- Oh, oh, yeah. goggles down.
- Check.
- Wing flaps down.
- Tail feathers.
- Double-check.
Try, try again.
And here we go!
[panting]
Sure wish we would have
taken the train!
[panting]
Ooh, I just love takeoffs.
[Bianca]
Captain, you fly beautifully.
lt's just like being
on a roller-scooter.
[tires screeching]
He just went
through a red light.
Oh, I do that
all the time, darling.
Now come on,
stop worrying.
Listen to this.
"Planned with care and--''
Good night,
Bianca.
[Birds squawking]
[Medusa]
Penny! Penny?
Penny, answer me!
Penny!
Snoops!
Snoops, get down here!
What's happening, Medusa?
What's going on?
That little brat
has escaped again!
Nero, Brutus,
bring her back, boys!
[engine revving]
Oh, why won't
it start?
Snoops!
What's wrong?
What's--
I don't know!
- lt was working
good yesterday.
- oh, shut up.
Send up flares!
Light up the swamp...
so i can find her.
[chuckling]
Well, folks, we'll be landing
at devil's bayou in a minute.
Your crew thanks you
for flying albatross air--
[whistling]
- what in the--
[exploding]
Sufferin' sassafras!
My rudder's on fire!
Bail out!
Help!
- Bernard!
[exploding]
Mayday!
[exploding, popping]
Bufferin' catfish!
What on earth?
Luke! Luke!
Wake up!
Luke!
Get down here!
- It's Orville!
- Oh, that Orville.
No, Luke, no!
He's in trouble!
- You get down here right now!
- I'm a-comin'!
[skidding]
[chuckling]
Wow-wee!
This new batch
really packs a wallop.
Ahhh!
[Bernard]
Look out below!
Ohh!
Oh, tsk, tsk,
what a shame.
Here, honey,
let me help you.
Cousin, you look like you
could use a swig of this.
It's good for
what ails ya.
There, where
you folks from, anyway?
We're--
[clearing throat]
[whispering]
We're from new York.
[Orville]
Now stand back, folks.
I ain't gonna hang around
this creepy place long.
Clear the runway!
[coughing]
Great balls fireproof!
[panting]
Ooo-ooo!
Aah-aah!
Ooo!
[squawk]
[squawking]
Holy smoke! Why don't you
watch where you're going?
[coughing]
Bernard, it's that
terrible Medusa!
I'd like to give her a few whacks
with my rolling pin.
We swamp folks would like
to run her out of our bayou.
[indistinct noise]
- Hold it! hold it!
Somebody's comin'
this way!
Why'd you have to go
and spoil everything?
Nero, don't you dare
get my teddy bear wet.
Oh, it's that
poor little young'un.
She's tried
to run away again.
It's Penny!
Oh, how terrible.
Hurry! We've got to find out
where they're taking her!
You need a boat.
Evinrude's got
the fastest boat here!
Evinrude!
Wake up!
- Start your engine, boy!
[buzzing]
Send Evinrude back
as soon as you need help.
I'll round up
the neighbors!
Faster!
Evinrude, faster!
[coughing]
You stop that, Brutus!
This fog is awful.
You can't see a thing.
Slow down,
Evinrude.
[panting]
They got to be
around here somewhere.
[panting]
Oh, dear,
we've lost them.
Jehoshaphat!
Hang on!
Hard aport, Evinrude!
Help!
We're gonna--
Bernard !
Bianca!
Come on, Evinrude!
Give it all you got!
[Bianca]
Keep trying, Evinrude!
[panting, gasping]
Poor Evinrude,
your carburettor
is all pooped out.
Bring her right on in, boys.
[chuckling]
Come on.
So you tried to run away.
didn't work, did it ?
Put me down,
Brutus!
Creepy old dragon.
Nice work, good boys.
Steady, boys!
D-d-down, boys! Heel, heel!
There, there, teddy.
I won't let them do
that to you again.
Don't cry.
Now, teddy, teddy.
Poor teddy.
All she ever thinks about
is that simple bear.
You behave or I'll let
Nero and Brutus have
your old teddy bear.
You will not. besides,
I'm not scared of them...
Like you are,
Mr. Snoops!
Don't you sass me!
Boys, take this naughty
girl to her room.
I can go by myself.
Thank you!
[popping sounds]
Stick around, Evinrude.
We'll signal if we need ya.
Look out!
Here she comes!
Where is she?
Oh, I sent her up to her room.
Why did you let her escape?
What is your alibi this time, nitwit?
Nitwit?
Don't blame me.
Those leather-headed lizards of yours,
they're supposed to patrol the island.
They let her get away.
Ha!
My precious pets!
We know who caught
that ungrateful brat,
Don't we, hmm?
[snoops]
lt was your idea to use
a little girl for this caper.
lf you'd
left it to me--
[Medusa]
Snoops! You're not thinking.
[snoops]
l know, she's the only one small
enough to squeeze down the hole.
[Medusa]
Yes, but why can't
she find my big diamond?
[snoops]
l don't know, but just look at
these beauties she brought up.
They'll sell for
a lot of cold cash.
[snoops]
Owww! l wish you
wouldn 't do that!
She's insane, utterly mad.
I want that diamond.
You didn't leave the girl
down in the cave long enough.
She won't take orders.
You are too soft.
The water was rising
and the tide was coming in.
All she did down there was fuss
about her teddy getting wet.
Snoops,
you don't have a way...
with children.
You must gain
their confidence,
make them like you.
Yeah?
How do you do that?
You force them
to like you, idiot !
At the next low tide
I'm going to put her down there,
myself,
and keep her there...
until she finds it.
It is as simple as that.
Oh, simple as that,
is it?
Well, you're the boss, boss.
Yes.
Now, come along,
petsy-poos.
We gotta get penny
out of here tonight.
- uh-oh, Bianca!
they smell your perfume.
- Oh, dear.
Aaah!
- Oh no!
- Bianca!
- Aaah !
- Let go, you big-bullies.
[panting]
[Medusa]
Brutus! Nero!
Stop that infernal racket!
I mean, now!
[screaming]
Snoops! Snoops!
A mouse!
Oh, kill it! Kill it!
[Medusa]
Run, Snoops, kill it!
There's another one!
Oh, what is wrong
with this thing?
[clicking]
Snoops!
What's wrong?
- I don't--
[gunshot]
Evinrude, over here!
Are you all right, dear?
She tried to kill us,
that... that terrible woman!
Oh, if I was only
a ten-foot mouse, I'd show her!
It's-- it's no use, Bianca.
Maybe Rufus the cat
was right.
What can two little mice do?
But, Bernard,
the society's counting on us.
We can't quit now.
Oh, and that little girl,
we've just
got to rescue her!
Penny, dear?
Auntie Medusa
wants to talk to you.
High tide or not,
that little brat is going
to find me that diamond...
tomorrow... or else!
- [knocking]
- Come in. Come in.
Did you wanna see me,
ma'am?
Yes, my dear.
Don't be so shy.
Now, l am going to let
by-gones be by-gones.
Do you know what would make
Auntie Medusa very happy?
Yes. you want me
to find that diamond.
That's right, dear.
But I tried as hard
as I could... honest !
Of course you have,
But we must try harder,
mustn't we?
Then please, will you take me
back to the orphanage...
- Like you promised?
- Penny, don't you like it here?
A big, beautiful boat
all to yourself!
But if I don't get back
to the orphanage...
I'll never get 'dopted.
Adopted?
What makes you think
anyone would want...
A homely little girl
like you?
Good night, teddy.
Sleep tight.
Oh, we almost forgot
to say our prayers.
Please bless...
Rufus and teddy...
and all the kids
at the orphanage:
Jennifer, Bobby,
Mary, Julie.
And please let some one
find my bottle.
There's a message in it.
Because running away
isn't working. Amen.
Don't worry, teddy.
We'll be...
[sniffing]
All right.
Penny? Penny?
Yes?
Penny, dear, now don't cry.
We are here to help you.
Wait. Hi!
Where'd you come from?
We found the bottle
with your message and
we've come to rescue you.
Did you hear that, teddy?
Our bottle worked!
Didn't you bring
somebody big with you?
- Like the police?
- No, there's just the two of us.
But if the three of us
worked together, and
we have a little faith--
That's what Rufus said!
Faith makes things
turn out right.
I know it's late but we have
to escape tonight... right now.
But I just got caught
by Brutus and Nero.
Look what they did
to my pants!
Yeah, and they're still down there
guarding the gangplank.
Oh, those vicious monsters!
They ought to be
locked up in a cage.
I know!
C'mon, I'll show ya.
See there?
The elevator.
[Bianca]
lt's a perfect cage, Penny.
Great idea.
Now, what can we use
for bait?
They'll eat anything.
Yeah, I know.
I've got it...
My perfume!
Remember?
They'll follow the scent
right into the elevator!
And I'll slam the door.
And will that make
Medusa mad!
Brutus, Nero!
Did you let that
little brat escape again?
You're too soft !
Wap! Wap!
Ha-ha-ha-ha.
Penny, that's not bad.
That's exactly like Medusa.
Track her down, boys!
Bring her back!
We'll be so far ahead,
They'll never catch us.
Wait a minute.
She might catch us...
I've always wanted
to drive it.
Vroom-vroom!
What if Medusa wakes up
while we're starting it ?
We're in trouble.
We've gotta stall 'em
somehow.
How about Mr Snoops'
fireworks?
We'll shoot 'em off
in her bedroom.
That'll keep her busy.
Oh, Bernard,
It's so exciting.
Perfume, crocs,
swamp-mobile!
It's just got to work!
It's our only chance.
But we're
gonna need help.
[Medusa]
Snoops, get down here!
What's up, Medusa?
What's going on?
[Medusa]
Oh, shut up!
- High tide or not--
- I bet those two
are up to something.
I don't wanna go down
in that awful black hole again.
Don't worry about that.
You must hurry and get dressed.
C'mon.
We haven't got much time.
Evinrude, up here.
We need help.
Go get Ellie-Mae!
And hurry!
[cheering]
Are you ready to help rescue
that little young'un?
- Sure enough !
- Hallelujah!
- Luke!
[snoring]
On your feet,
you lazy critter !
Ooo-shh!
Shucks, Ellie-Mae,
Dag-nabit!
Let's cut out the jawin'
and get a-goin'!
Hee-hee. when ol' gramps
gets head-up,
his nose gets
plumb out of joint.
Take it easy, gramps.
We gotta stay here 'til
Evinrude brings us word
from them mice.
If'n that bug
don't get here soon,
they'll put that poor little girl
down the black hole again.
All right,
you little brat.
You are gonna go down
in that hole...
And you're gonna dig
till you find me the diamond.
and no sassing me!
[Medusa]
Uh-uh-uh, Snoops!
That is no way to speak
to our little Miss Penny.
Oh, okay, boss.
Okay.
Now, my dear,
you're going to find
the big, shiny diamond...
for your auntie Medusa,
aren't you, hmm ?
[penny]
Teddy doesn 't like it down there.
He's afraid,
aren't you, teddy?
Ahh, tsk-tsk.
Poor teddy.
I'll just keep him up here
with me where he'll be safe.
Give me back my teddy bear!
He's mine! He's mine!
You get down there and
find the big diamond...
or you will never
see teddy again!
All right.
I'll go.
[snoops]
Boss, you really got
a way with kids.
Don't worry, teddy,
I won't be gone long.
l'll find her ol' diamond!
[water dripping]
Oh, what a dreadful,
frightening place!
Yeah, it used to be
a pirate's cave.
How do you know that,
Penny ?
- Him!
- Ah! Oh dear!
C'mon, girls.
Let's look for that diamond
so we can get out of here.
I looked there already.
Medusa doesn't want
those little ones.
[rumbling sounds]
Wha-- What's--
What's that?
[water sloshing]
[penny]
That's where
the water comes in.
Ooo! I'm afraid
to go over there.
Well, if I was a pirate,
that's just where
I'd hide the devil's eye.
I'll, uh, go over
and check it out.
[loud rumbling
and sloshing]
Come--
Come to think of it,
if I was a pirate,
I wouldn't--
I wouldn't hide
anything back there.
Bernard, look!
I can see something.
- C'mon, let's see what it is.
- No, Bianca.
You stay here.
I'll see if i can find
a safe way over.
[rumbling and sloshing]
Aaah!
- Bianca!
- Hang on!
Help!
I'm coming.
[Medusa]
What are you doing down there?
I'm looking!
Well, look faster!
Wow!
[tingling sounds]
Penny, hold
your lantern up again.
- Holy mackerel! That's it.
- The devil's eye!
Penny, we found it!
We found it!
Medusa, I found it!
Let me look.
Let me look, Medusa.
Back!
Ah, good girl!
Good girl!
Let's get it up here.
[rumbling]
[Bernard]
Look, it won't go through.
We can't get it out.
[Medusa]
What's taking so long?
It's stuck tight.
Stuck tight!
You get that diamond...
or you'll never see
daylight again!
[Bernard]
No, back, Penny!
[Bianca]
Penny, you'll fall!
[screaming]
[coughing]
Forget the diamond.
Let's get out of here
before we drown !
The water's coming in!
Please pull me up.
Not until you
get the diamond!
Penny, the pirate's sword.
Use the sword!
[grunting]
[Bianca]
Penny! Penny, help!
I've got it!
Hurry!
Pull me up!
Faster!
- I'm pulling as fast as I can.
- Ahh-ha-ha-ha!
At last!
The devil's eye!
Heh-heh-heh-heh.
It's worth millions!
Ha-ha-ha-ha!
Mmm!
Just look at it.
Filled with power...
for its owner.
Let me look at it.
I got-- hey, that wasn't
a very good look.
[screaming]
- But know
there's enough there...
to cut it into
two equal shares.
- You idiot!
Cut up a perfect gem!
And it's mine.
It's all mine!
All yours! Half of it is mine,
you double-crossing crook!
- Put me down, Brutus.
- lt's mine. lt's all mine.
- [snoops]: Double-crosser!
- [Medusa] Cheap pickpocket.
- Chi seller!
- Cheap crook!
[gasping]
Land sakes,
it's Evinrude.
Ol' ev sure is a mess.
- Where in tar-nation
you been, boy?
- What's happening?
- Do they want us now?
- Where are they?
- They're on the boat?
- Speak up, boy.
Buck up! We mustn't be
quitting now, must we?
[sighing]
Stand back!
Give poor Evinrude
some air.
He's plumb tuckered out.
Here, son.
This'll make
a new bug outta ya.
Gulp! Gulp!
- Ya-hoo!
- Yoo-hoo!
[cheering]
We're gonna have us
a rip-snortin' fight.
Yip...pee!
Charge!
Where'd everybody go?
I don't need any help
from anybody!
- Charge!
- Ya-hoo!
[indistinct yelling]
[snoops]
Welsher! Swindler! Chiseler!
Shut up, Snoops,
and don't move.
lf either of you
try to follow me,
you'll get blasted!
You give me my teddy bear.
You promised.
Teddy goes with me,
my dear.
l've become
quite attached to him.
Heh-heh-heh-heh!
- Yeow!
[gunshot]
Ah! My diamond!
My diamond!
- Charge!
[screaming]
[whistling]
Now!
Now! Now!
[engine sputtering]
[Bernard]
Look out!
Oh, please start.
Advance the spark!
Not the horn!
The spark lever!
Digger, hold this.
It's the doohickey
on the steering wheel.
[Medusa]
You! You and your
infernal fireworks!
You--
[screaming]
You dunderhead!
- We're not getting any gas.
- Fill her up, Luke.
Hurry... all of it.
[screaming]
Look out!
The riverboat!
Ha-ha-ha-ha!
- We did it, Bianca!
- Hooray!
Bernard,
you're wonderful!
- We did it!
- We sure showed
that Medusa woman!
There goes...
...my diamond!
[sobbing]
... and because of a courageous
little girl named Penny,
the world's largest diamond,
the devil's eye,
is now in the
Smithsonian institute.
But what's even
more important, folks,
this little orphan's dream
has come true.
Today she's being adopted.
And here she is with
her new mother and father.
Bernard, I am so happy
for Penny.
Yes, uh, you might say
that Penny, uh...
... brought us together.
You are a darling.
Penny, you were
a brave little girl,
to do what you did
all by yourself.
I didn't do it
all by myself.
Two little mice from the
rescue aid society helped me.
Mice?
Rescue aid society?
Yes, they rescued me.
Could i say hello to them?
Hello, Bianca!
Hi, Bernard!
- You can talk to
these little mice?
- All the time.
Mice can talk like anybody.
didn't you know that?
[announcer]
Well, l didn 't.
But l do now, Penny.
[applause]
Evinrude,
what are you doing here?
[gasping]
It's another call for help.
Here. Uh, you're gonna
need some volunteers.
Bu-- but, Bianca--
Oh, Bernard, adventure,
Thrills, intrigue,
travel, exotic places.
Oh, come on, darling,
let's go.
Sure wish we had
taken the train!
Yah-ho-ho-ho-hee!
[gasping]