FATHER'S CURSE.
DEAD or ALIVE.
THE FLYING DUTCHMAN.
- Father.
- Henry. What've you done?
- I said I'd find you.
- Look at me, son.
I don't care.
There's no place for
you on the Dutchman.
They know you're here...
Get home to your mother.
No.
- Leave now, before it's too late.
- I won't.
I'll never stop... And
if you throw me over,
I'll come straight back.
Don't you see, I'm
cursed to this ship?
That's why I'm here.
I think I know a way
to break your curse.
To free you from the Dutchman.
- Henry, no.
- I've read about a treasure.
A treasure that holds all
the power of the sea,
The Trident of Poseidon
can break your curse.
Henry.
The Trident can never be found.
I found you.
- It's just a tale.
- Like the tales of you.
And Captain Jack Sparrow?
He will help me find the Trident.
You stay away from Jack.
Leave the sea forever. You
have to stop acting like a...
A pirate. I won't stop.
I want you to come home.
Henry.
I'm sorry.
My curse will never be broken.
This is my fate.
You must let me go.
I love you son.
Captain Jack Sparrow.
Nine years later.
Faster, you pathetic bilge
rats, you'll pump the bilge,
and fill the scuppers.
We're chasing down pirates.
Henry get back here. You don't
wanna get kicked off another ship.
It's a Dutch barque. Probably
stolen by the Pirate Bonet.
My God.
I warned you of leaving
your post, boy.
I need to speak with the captain.
- What did you say?
- Move.
Turner.
She's going in, sir.
Chase her down.
No, don't do it.
Don't do it.
You will not address
a Captain, boy.
Sir, look at your charts. I
believe you're sailing us,
in to the Devil's Triangle.
Do you hear this man?
This landsman, believes
an old sailor's myth.
Sir.
With all due respect I have
spent my life studying,
the myths of the sea. I know
every legend and every curse.
And I know, ships that
sail into the triangle
do not necessarily sail out.
Don't worry sir.
- This one is clearly disturbed.
- Sir, trust in what I say.
Change your course.
You dare to give me orders, boy?
Arrest him.
Turner.
I'll not let you kill us all.
Come on.
This is treason.
Lock him up.
- No.
- We're going in.
This was your last chance, Turner.
If it were up to me, I'd
string you from the yard arm.
On deck.
Jack Sparrow.
He's dead.
Buried in an unmarked grave
on the isle of St. Martin.
Sir, there's something
in the water.
Ship to starboard.
That's no ship, sir.
It's a shipwreck.
No.
She's sailing straight towards us.
Open fire.
What are you?
Death.
WANTED. JACK SPARROW.
Do you know this pirate?
- Only by name.
- You're looking for him?
- Is that a yes?
- Yes.
For too many years the
Triangle has cursed us.
Condemned us to
this Hell on Earth.
The key to our escape.
Is Jack Sparrow and the
compass, which he holds.
No, no. No need to fear me boy.
I always leave one man alive
to tell the tale.
Find Sparrow for me
and relay a message.
From Capitan Salazar.
Salazar.
Tell him I'll behold
the daylight again.
And on that day.
Death.
Death... will come
straight for him.
Would you say that to him? Please?
Yes.
I wish I could do
it myself, but...
Dead men tell no tales.
Carina Smyth.
You're an orphan,
born of the devil.
Accused of practising witchcraft.
Before you die.
Do you have anything to confess?
I confess that I am not a witch.
That I am a woman of science.
I confess that I have survived on
my own, with nothing but a diary
from a father I never knew.
And a quest for the
truth of who I am.
I confess that I will die
before I give up the search.
And I confess.
That while we've been
talking. I picked this lock.
Today we dedicate The
Royal Bank of St. Martin.
The most secure banking
institution in the Caribbean.
Our new vault.
Is 5 inches thick.
And weighs an imperial tonne.
I've got her.
Get her.
Don't let her get away.
Stop that witch.
With this bank, the
town of St. Martin,
enters the modern world.
- I'm so sorry, sir.
- The witch escaped her chains.
Find that wicked lass.
Or you swing in her place.
- Sir.
No man. Nor army.
Can ever rob the gold
from St. Martin.
Open the vault.
Pirate.
Pirate?
Pirates.
This may seem a peculiar question.
Could someone explain to me.
To why I'm here?
How long?
No, no no, wait,
it's coming to me.
Need just a moment
to clear my head.
Make ready.
Hold your fire. There's a
woman with him in the vault.
Never mind about that trollop.
Sir, I believe...
that's your wife.
Francis?
Oh, I've got it.
I've got it. I'm robbing the bank.
Shoot him.
That was not part of the plan.
After him. Don't let him get away.
NO DOGS, NO WOMEN.
No woman's ever
handled my Herschel.
Clear a path.
No, no, no, no.
Stop, stop... stop.
Hard to starboard.
Sir, your celestial fix was off.
I've adjusted two
degrees north. Your
map will no longer be imprecise.
Although you will have
to start again with it.
You're a witch.
No, I'm not. Am I a witch
for having catalogued.
- Over 200 stars?
- Witch.
There is a blood moon coming.
I simply need to purchase...
A chronometer.
I'll pay you double for
selling to a woman.
Help.
Help. Help. There's
a witch in my shop.
And a pirate.
There is a witch and
a pirate in my shop.
Well this is your lucky day.
Have either of the four
of you seen my bank?
Found it.
- Were you part of the plan?
- I'm not looking for trouble.
What a horrible way to live.
- Stop that witch. Get her.
- We're trapped.
What do we do?
You need to scream.
Over there. Secure that woman.
- You filthy pirate.
- No need for name calling.
Jack.
Bridge?
It's empty.
Where is the dash?
Do you think that
robbing a bank is easy?
You gaggle of gutless.
You's are the ones.
Guilty of putting me in this
dreadful pickle in
the first place.
Now line up. And
offer me a tribute.
Do you want us to pay you?
Am I not the captain of this ship?
You call this a ship?
- Where's the treasure?
- All of us are starving.
We'll no longer follow a
captain without a ship.
I have a ship.
Black Pearl has
never left me side.
The pirate Barbossa
rules these seas now.
Has 10 ships. Guns full.
Not to mention his canon balls.
18 pounds each they say.
One legged man with
18 pound balls?
That's why he walks funny.
Oh come, come mates?
Did we not find the treasure
of Macedonia together?
It was a troll of rotten wood.
- Gold of King Midas.
- A pile of donkey dung.
Face it Jack. Bad luck dogs you,
day & night.
Now that is a blatant fabrication.
- You've lost your luck.
- You've lost your ship.
Now... you've lost your crew.
Jack Sparrow is no
longer our captain.
I'm sorry Jack. But we've
reached the end of the horizon.
Right then.
You're all dismissed.
All of ya. Dismissed.
Never sail with Captain
Jack Sparrow again.
Tell you that.
The whole town speaks of you.
The only survivor of the
Monarch. A boy who paddled
all the way to St.
Martin, against the tide
on a piece of driftwood.
Now jabbering about pirates.
And Tridents.
Please sir, let me
go of these chains.
My job is to protect this
island and these waters.
And your sleeves have been
ripped. The mark of treason.
We were attacked by the dead.
You're a coward who
ran from battle.
And that is how you die.
- I don't believe you're a coward.
- Please leave me sister.
I've risked my life to come here.
To see if the rumours are true.
- You speak of the Trident?
- Who are you?
Tell me why you seek the Trident?
The Trident can break,
any curse at sea.
My father is trapped
by such a curse.
You're aware that curses are
not supported by science.
- Neither are ghosts.
- So you have gone mad?
- I should never have come here.
- Then why did you come here?
Because I need to get
off this island.
To solve the map.
"No man can read".
Left by Poseidon himself.
You've read the ancient text?
In each language
they were written.
But this map has never
been seen or read,
by any man.
Luckily I'm a woman.
This is the diary
of Galileo Galilei.
He's spent his life
searching for the Trident,
It's why he invented the spyglass.
Why astronomers have spent their
lives staring in to the sky.
So you're saying the
map no man can read,
Is hidden in the stars?
It was left to me by my father.
He believed I could find.
What no man has ever found.
I will not let him down.
Soon, there will be a blood moon.
Only then can the map be read.
- And the Trident found.
- Who are you?
- Carina Smyth.
- If you wish to save your father,
you'll have to save
me. Find us a ship.
And the Trident will be ours.
Come to me witch.
Oh.
He's gone.
He's gone sir.
Find that coward.
He'll hang with the witch.
Think Captain Jack's washed up?
I have not had a wash in years.
Check the alley down there.
You two, check the church.
The rest of you, with me.
Bugger.
JACK SPARROW
THE NOTORIOUS PIRATE
DEAD OR ALIVE
GOD SAVE THE KING
May I please have a drink, please?
Show me your silver.
Silver?
How about a trade?
Give me the bottle.
Capitan.
What's happening?
Jack Sparrow, Jack Sparrow
has given away the compass.
Daylight. Daylight.
We're free.
Now, now, it's time,
to hunt a pirate.
Pirate's life.
Come to daddy.
Just the man we've
been looking for.
Why? Why am I looked for?
Let it be known that the
pirate Jack Sparrow.
Will be executed at dawn.
Executed?
I will never set foot in this town
again, sir. You mark my words.
I do mean it, you know. I shall
never be back here again.
To release the power of the sea.
One must divide.
It's an island. The stars
lead to an island.
Goodbye there sir.
Very good. Make the
rest of the sails.
I'm looking for a
pirate, Jack Sparrow.
Bugger off.
I need to speak with you.
- Hand me your sword.
- I don't have a sword.
What kind of soldier
has no weapon?
I'm currently wanted for treason.
So, not the very good kind, then.
I'm looking for a pirate,
Captain Jack Sparrow?
Well, today is your lucky day.
Because I just happen to be.
Captain Jack Sparrow.
No, it can't be.
I've spent years
searching for. This?
The great Jack Sparrow is
not some drunk in a cell.
Do you even have a ship? A crew?
Pants.
A great pirate does not
require such intricacies.
Do you know how long I've
been waiting for this moment?
The risks I've taken to be here?
Are you sure you're
the Jack Sparrow?
The real question is.
- Who are you?
- My name is Henry Turner.
Son of Will Turner
and Elisabeth Swann.
You're the evil spawn of them two?
Does mummy ever ask about me?
No.
Go on. She call my
name in her sleep?
She never spoke of you.
Are you sure we're talking
about the same people?
He's a cursed eunuch.
She's golden haired, stubborn,
pouty lips. Neck like a giraffe.
And two of the those wonderful...
Yes Yes, it's her.
I need you to listen Jack.
Because at the moment
you're all I've got.
I found a way to save
my father. There
is one thing that can
break his curse,
and free him from the Dutchmen.
The Trident of Poseidon.
The treasure to be found with...
the map that no man can read.
Never heard of it.
There is a girl inside
this prison, Jack,
who holds that map.
The moon has turned to blood,
the Trident will be found.
And you could be the
one who holds the sea.
And with it become all
that you once were.
The great.
Jack.
Oh, I'm so sorry. Were
you still talking?
I believe I nodded off a bit.
One more thing.
A message from someone you
know, named Captain Salazar.
I once knew a Spaniard named...
Something in Spanish.
El Matador Del Mar. The
butcher of the sea.
Him? No, no, no. Quite
happily he's dead.
Very, very dead. Ship went down.
Inside the triangle.
He's coming for you
Jack, to seek revenge.
As the dead man's tale is told.
I don't believe you.
What did he say?
He said your compass was the key,
to his escape. An army of dead,
are coming straight for you, Jack.
The Trident of Poseidon
is your only hope.
Do we have an accord?
I'm not going in
there to tell him.
It was your idea.
No, it was my idea
for you to tell him.
He likes you more than me.
He doesn't like anybody.
Sorry sir. We know you
said never to disturb you.
Or to come in without good cause.
Or to speak without first...
asking ourselves whether our,
thoughts were
absolutely necessary.
Like the time the
ship was on fire.
That being an example
of necessary thought.
So again, we do apologise
for starting that fire.
Speak.
It's the ships, sir. They're
being attacked by an enemy.
- That takes no riches.
- Kills without provocation.
The ships? Not possible.
Three have already been sunk, sir.
They've been sunk by a
captain called Salamander.
Sandoval.
Salazar.
That's it, your sireness. He
leaves one man from each vessel.
To tell the tale. The
entire fleet is being sunk.
And we'll soon be dead.
And quite possibly
out of business.
I'll be needing some
time with your witch.
I've been expecting you Captain.
Perhaps you'd like some tea.
I shall pass, thank you kindly.
The price of crossing my
door is blood, Captain.
That explains why
you're not so busy.
Everyone pays, eventually.
Shansa, you and I
made a bond long ago.
I saved you from the gallows.
Remember?
And I cursed your enemies.
But now you come to me in fear.
As the dead have taken
command over the sea.
And what would the dead
be wanting with me?
Not you, Captain.
- They're searching for a Sparrow.
- Jack?
Jack will sail for the Trident.
With a girl and a Pearl.
The Trident can never be found.
The Trident is Jack's only hope.
The dead are conquering the sea,
unable to step on dry land.
Maybe you should retire
to the countryside.
Do you mean grass?
On a farm?
Milking a cow, making cheese.
- While they sink me treasure?
- Ask yourself this, Captain.
Is this treasure worth dying for?
I'm a pirate.
Always will be. So how do I save,
- what be mine.
- Jack held a compass.
Which points you to the
thing you desire most.
But betray the compass...
And it releases
your greatest fear.
And a pirate's greatest fear
will be Salazar, is it?
- How did you get this?
- I have my ways.
Lead them to Jack before
he finds the Trident.
And all your treasure
will come back to you.
Time to make a deal with the dead.
Come on, pirate.
Hold on, stop.
Dad?
- Uncle Jack.
- Jackie boy, how's it going?
Can't complain really. You?
I've been waiting all morning
in here, for a beating.
- But the service is terrible.
- Shameful.
Jack.
The oceans have turned to blood.
Best to stay on dry
land, where it's safe.
I'm about to be
executed on dry land.
Good point.
Did I ever told you the
one about the skeleton?
Yes you have, many times.
Skeleton goes into a
bar, orders a beer.
And a mop.
Funny as ever.
Come on let's go.
If they disembowel you, ask for
Viktor. He's got
the softest hands.
Thank you.
And mention my name, they
won't cut your feet off.
Come on. You're first.
And how would you
like to die pirate?
Hanging, firing squad
or a new invention.
- The guillotine.
- Guillotine?
Sounds French. I love the French.
Did you know that they
invented mayonnaise?
How bad could it be?
It's French, right?
Oh, my bad. I changed me mind.
No, please have mercy upon
me. I'm a bet wetter.
Oh, come on.
I mean I have to walk
upstairs as well for this?
- Bring the basket.
- Basket... why?
Strap him down.
Here's an idea.
Why don't we try a
good old fashioned
stoning? I'd kill to
be stoned right now.
Gets the crowd
involved, doesn't it?
I should like to speak to
Victor in disembowelment.
I should like to speak to Vic.
I'm not one to complain normally,
but this basket's full of heads.
Final words of
Carina Smyth. Quiet.
The final words of Carina Smyth.
Good sirs. I'm not a witch.
But I forgive your common dim
wittedness and feeble brains.
In short, most of you
have the mind of a goat.
Pardon me sir. Is it
not common practise...
for those about to be executed
to be granted a last, I don't
know, something or another...?
I believe I was making a point.
If you could just be patient.
No.
My head's about to be lopped
off. Hence the urgency.
And my neck is to be broken.
Did you know that on occasion,
the neck doesn't actually break.
- It just hurts.
- What?
Oh yes.
I've seen men swing for hours.
Eyes bulging, tongues swelling.
- Revolting gurgling sound.
- May I finish?
No. You're lucky.
Wish I was hung.
Kill the filthy pirate, I'll wait.
The witch is first.
I'm not a witch. Did
you not listen?
Quite hard to listen when you
have the mind of a goat.
Enough. Kill them both.
Yes.
There's another noose. Did you
think you could defeat us boy?
No sir, I'm just a diversion.
Fire.
I'd still rather be stoned.
Reload.
Thank you.
Come here. You pirate scum.
Hey.
What're you doing? No, no, no, no.
Careful.
Horses?
- Thank you.
- You're welcome milady.
Got you.
Knew you'd come
crawling back, traitor.
The Turner boy gave us.
10 silver pieces
to save your neck.
From this moment on
we are to be allies.
Considering where
your left hand is,
- I'd say we're more than that.
- We find the Trident together.
Do I have your word?
You're holding
everything but my word.
Then I bestow upon you
the honour of saving me.
For a small donation.
You expect us to pay
you to save you?
Yes.
For a mere 10 pieces.
Madness.
- We won't pay more than 5.
- Well, then.
8 it is.
Perhaps we could
discuss this later,
as I'm having trouble
hoisting your porch.
You're far from port.
That is my stern.
Are you sure?
- Positive.
- Well, look at this.
If I kill the coward,
the witch hangs.
- Two for the price of one.
- Please don't let go of me.
It might be difficult
once he kills me.
Gentlemen, these two
prisoners will lead us,
to the Trident.
Captain. Do you really think
we can find the Trident?
Master Gibbs, you old worrywart.
There's nothing to be
concerned about at all.
What could possibly
go wrong, right?
So this was your plan?
To be tortured and
killed by pirates?
You said you needed a ship.
- You call this a ship?
- Cut the shard.
Prepare to drown.
My dear beloved crew. Finally...
Today is.
DYING GULL.
Something's gone wrong.
She floats.
Ship dead ahead.
Sir.
We would never question
your reason as a captain.
But, however.
Is there a reason as
captain, you've chosen.
To sail in this
unreasonable direction?
Tell the men to prepare
to be boarded.
To stand their ground.
And show no fear.
Capitan. A ship sails towards us.
Captain Salazar. I hear you've
been looking for Jack Sparrow.
Hold point.
And await orders.
My name is Captain Barbossa.
And I stand before you,
- with cordial intent.
- Ay, ay heh, cordial intent.
Do you hear that? This
pirate wishes to be cordial.
So let me show you what
my cordiality is, hombre.
Every time I tap my sword.
One of your men will die, So
I suggest you speak quickly.
Might want to go a
bit faster capitan.
- Where's Jack Sparrow?
- Jack be sailing for the Trident.
- No. The sea belongs to the dead.
- The Trident controls the seas.
No, no. There's no treasure.
There's no treasure...
that can save him. He
will die with you.
I be the only one that
can lead you to him.
I declare you shall have Jack's
life by sunrise on the morrow.
Or you can take me own then.
Do we have an accord?
Take me to him, and you
will live to tell the tale.
You have my word.
I thank you on behalf of me crew.
Ole. You can take what's left of
them. The living come aboard.
Carina, we haven't got much time,
the dead are sailing
straight for us.
- Is that so?
- Yes, I've spoken to them.
You spoken to them?
Have you spoken to krakens
and mermaids as well?
Krakens don't speak,
everyone knows that.
Of course, I never
should have saved you.
Last night there was a blood
moon, just as you described.
Tell me what it revealed.
And why should I trust you?
You trusted me to hold
your porch, remember?
It was my stern.
Clearly you need to
spend more time at sea.
Tell me what you found and
I promise to help you.
I don't need any help.
Then why did come to me Carina?
Why are we tied together
in the middle of the sea.
Chasing the same treasure?
The moon revealed a clue.
To release the power of the sea.
- One must divide.
- Divide?
- What does it mean?
- I'm not sure yet.
Then we'll find out.
- There is no map in this map.
- Give me my diary.
Give me the map no man can read.
If you could read it,
then it wouldn't be called
the map no man can read.
I beg you please,
don't argue with her.
Most of the men on
this ship can't read.
Which makes all maps
the maps that no man can read.
Well if you can't read it, then
you have no use for it, or me.
Let me start again.
Show me the map.
I can't. It doesn't yet exist.
- She's a witch.
- I'm an astronomer.
- She breeds donkeys.
- What? No.
An astronomer
contemplates the sky.
Yay, on a donkey.
- No, there's no donkey.
- Well then how do you breed then?
Allows me to simplify this
equation. Give me the map.
Or I will kill...
him. I'll kill him.
Go on then. You're bluffing.
And you're blushing.
Throw him over.
We call this keel hauling.
Young Henry will be tossed over.
And he will be dragged
under the ship.
Alright.
- What're you waiting for?
- He doesn't appear to be bluff...
No. Not bluffing, me. He's
trying to say something.
No, no, we don't have
any food aboard. Sorry.
If he's lucky, he'll drown,
before the barnacles
shred him to ribbons.
- Barnacles.
- Like a thousands knives,
across your back. And of course,
the blood attracts sharks.
Sharks?
- Shark of the bow.
- Where?
I would say that swimming is
no longer his primary concern.
The map is there.
- Where?
- On the tip of your finger?
No. In the heavens.
That diary will lead me to a map,
hidden in the stars.
Let him up, I'll find it tonight.
Sorry, can't bring him up.
Look for yourself.
As I said. Blushing.
Filthy pirate.
The sea has turned to blood,
a sailor washed ashore.
Talking about the Trident. He
was looking for Jack Sparrow.
The same pirate who saved
a witch from the gallows.
- She's no witch.
- But you are.
- And you're going to help us.
- You're afraid, Lieutenant.
As ships burn in the
night, you want
to know if you can save your own.
If the Trident is real?
You're going to read
that wall for me.
Or you will die. The
British Empire will have.
The Trident and rule
the sea. I want
to know where that
pirate is going,
with that witch.
Your destiny is in these
stars. I will set your course.
Bwa. Spaghetti walls.
Why did I bother coming to you?
The dead are hunting us
down and you do nothing.
Nothing, You call this nothing?
You're drunk and you're sleeping.
My point exactly, I am
doing two things at once.
You can't save the unsavable mate.
Like it or not Jack,
you're going to help me.
I will break my father's curse.
Next time you raise a sword, boy.
Be the last to die.
Ooh.
Might I suggest you entice
her with a bit of flattery.
I'm here for my
father, nothing more.
I knew it, absolutely
smitten with her.
Now, a bit of discretion
when courting a brunette.
Never pursue her sister.
But if you cannot avoid
the charming sister,
kill the brother, savvy?
No, I do not savvy.
Who hurt you? By the way that
little sliver of knowledge...
will cost you five pieces.
I'm not paying you for that.
Never say that to a woman.
Just because you
can't see something
doesn't mean it's not there.
Like the map?
We have to find it.
It's the only link to who I am.
Who my father was.
So we've both spent our lives,
searching for our fathers.
Perhaps you and I are
closer than you think.
The sun is up. And
so is your time.
And not to disagree, but the
precision of our accord,
ends at sunrise.
This be but first light, far
from a fully rising sun.
And I know you to
be a man of honour.
Honour, you know nothing of me.
I know what it likes to be
bested by Jack Sparrow.
- He's an enemy to us both.
- You don't know who I am.
I've heard stories of a mighty
Spanish captain. El
Matador Del Mar.
A man who scourged the sea. Hunted
and killed thousands of men.
No, no, no. Men, no, no.
No.
Pirates?
Pirates.
Pirates had infected the
seas for generations.
Taken the life of my father
and his father before.
So I vowed to end this
plague once and for all.
And that's what I did, I
destroyed dozens of ships.
The last ones joined together
to try and defeat me.
But they soon realised
it was hopeless.
Nothing could stop
the Silent Mary.
Hit them below the water line.
Vamo, vamo.
Hang on tight.
The sea was finally... pure.
Their wretched flags would
no longer stain the sea.
They are begging for mercy.
Mercy? Mercy.
There's no mercy.
Make ready.
- Adios.
- Fire.
It's up to you now, Jack.
This compass... points
towards what you want most.
Never betray it.
The Devil's Triangle.
The last of their ships were
burning before my eyes.
And in that moment of... victory.
It's when I heard it.
Hey.
Hold on, Capitan.
One ship was trying to
escape through the smoke.
It's a lovely day
for a sail, innit?
And there.
In the crow's nest, there
was this young pirate boy.
The way I see it, it's
just the two of us left.
If you surrender to me now,
I'll let you live, simple.
He stood there, looking
like... Like a little bird.
And from that day he earned
himself a name that would...
haunt me for the rest of my days.
Jack de "Sparrow".
Right then, you surrender to
me now, and I'll let you live.
I shall let you live.
This boy.
This boy was mocking my power.
So I chased him. Knowing
that I would run.
My knife along his
neck, and when he
was dead, I would finish finally.
With pirates's life.
Follow him men.
To the gunnels. Grab some lines.
Prepare the boot leg.
Port side.
Throw it now.
Boot leg turn.
What's all this?
Tribute... Sir.
He took everything from me.
And filled me with... rage.
And pain.
And here is where the tale ends.
Not yet Capitan, there.
Found as promised.
So she's saying she's got the map,
but she's the only one
who can follow it?
- So we should shoot her?
- Leave her be.
She will take us to the Trident.
You've been saying that for hours.
Two things we know are true,
the stars don't shine by day.
And she, forgot the donkey.
How can we go to a spot, where
no land exists on any map?
This chronometer keeps the
exact time in London.
I'm using it to make an
altitude measurement.
To determine longitude.
Only then will we find
our exact spot at sea.
So you expect to find the
Trident with a timepiece?
Yes.
My calculations are
precise and true.
I'm not only an astronomer.
I am also a horologist.
No shame in that dear.
We'll all have to earn a living?
No, I'm a horologist.
So was my mum. But she didn't
crow about it as bad as you.
You're saying your mother
was academically inclined?
More like, err,
horizontally, reclined.
Horology is the study of time.
And she was always
looking at her watch.
I can vouch for that.
So no one can find the
X, but you, right?
No.
- And the donkey?
- Ship to the aft.
Salazar.
Jack, the dead will not rest
until they get their revenge.
Dead?
No, no, the dead
- were never part of this deal.
- We should've never followed
a luckless pirate
and a witch to sea.
Right, that's it. Kill them all.
Kill me and, and. I'll be dead.
And then the other dead won't
be able to have their revenge.
Against me,
- Being dead.
- What?
- Which will anger them even more.
- He's right.
That's right.
Are all pirates this stupid?
Yes.
What are we going to do?
As Captain.
Might I suggest.
Mutiny? You had to
suggest a mutiny?
Carina, the dead are coming.
Well. I choose not to believe
in supernatural nonsense.
Do you not see what's behind us?
- Drop them.
- Si.
Drop them.
What are you doing?
Men on that ship are
looking for Jack.
And Jack is on this boat.
I'm going to swim for it.
How dare you do exactly what
I would do if I were you?
- Carina stop.
- No, no, no, don't stop.
- This has gone far enough.
- No, it has not.
Listen not to him,
carry on, carry on.
- Ayy, she was almost finished.
- I saw her ankles.
You'd have seen a lot more, if
you'd kept your cakehole shut.
Kill the Sparrow.
That's not good, is it?
Keep rowing man. Faster. Faster.
No, that's it.
I'm going with her.
You would leave me for some
horologist in her knickers?
Yes.
You men are all alike.
Shark.
Henry.
Doesn't seem to be working.
No, we'll be fine, we'll be fine.
Vamos.
- How do they do that?
- We have to swim for it.
I'll distract them.
Now.
Henry.
Hai. Jack Sparrow.
Jack Sparrow.
Spanish?
- Ghosts.
- Ah-ow.
They're unable to step on land.
- I knew that though.
- Ghosts.
Carina.
You will soon pay for
what you did to me.
No, no, no. There's no
need to bother really.
- Carina.
- I have no time to chat.
- Because me map's just run away.
- I will be waiting... for you.
Why would you be waiting for me?
Why would he be waiting for me?
Pirates.
Scrum.
Captain?
Jack always told me
that if anything
should ever happen to him...
He wanted you to be captain.
Yes, but the men
voted for you, yes?
Well, you've got a captain's hat.
"Be that as it may"
them were his wishes.
So be a good lad and
take the wheel.
And... you,
Take the captain's hat.
This is the proudest
moment of my li...
We will beat your captain to death
until he reveals where
they're heading.
- Carina.
- I know what's ailing you boy.
You've got the unscratchable itch.
Carina is the only one who can
help us find the Trident.
- And I'm not in love with her.
- Love?
Who said anything about love,
what are you talking about?
The unscratchable itch.
Scabies, I'm talking
about scabies.
Small mites that
burrow under the skin.
Certainly ailing me,
has done for years.
Oh, no.
Hangman's Bay,
STRANGERS NOT WELCOME.
Help.
- Help me. Help.
- Carina.
- Henry, help me.
- Help her.
By rule of the King,
I sentence you all to death.
I think we should tell each other
where our treasures are buried.
Just in case one of us survives.
Oh, good idea.
- You go first.
- My treasure is buried.
Between two crossed palm trees
in an unmarked grave in Aruba.
What about yours?
I haven't got any.
You promised me Jack's blood.
But Jack be trapped.
- He can never escape that island.
- He's on land.
Hello.
I upheld our deal.
Me men and myself will go ashore.
The scurvy traitor will be yours.
- On me honour.
- Honour?
What honour, hombre? What honour?
- You don't know what honour is.
- Spare me my life.
And I'll fetch you the Sparrow.
Tenemos un acuerdo...
(Do we have an accord?)
An accord?
Wake up Sparrow.
Wake up, Sparrow.
- It's time to pay your debt.
- Pig?
Pig Kelly?
- Me old mate.
- Mate?
Do you hear that boys?
This lying pirate owes
me a plunder of silver.
And luck has brought
him to Hangman's Bay.
Where he can settle his
debt, here and now.
And I will, I will
Pig. Name your price.
Her name is Beatrice.
And she's my poor widowed sister.
What, what is that?
She's been looking for
a respectable man.
- But you'll have to do.
- Royce, let's get on with this.
No why? Why...?
To make an honest
woman of her, Jack.
Congratulations, it's
your wedding day.
Let us begin?
We'll honeymoon in the barn.
No, no, no. Now Pig.
How can I honestly make an
honest woman out of it?
That, her. I mean. Her.
- What are those things?
- Our children.
Best not look them in the eye.
Bring the best man
and the bridesmaid.
I looked it in the eye.
Place your hand on the Bible.
- I've got scabies.
- So do I.
Place your hand on the Bible.
I'm a bed wetter.
Say I do.
Or I'll put a bullet
in your skull.
Jack, they're going to kill us.
- I don't care.
- Just say I do.
- Last chance Jack.
- Wait. Surely.
- This is not legal.
He's right.
Does any man here object
to these nuptials?
- I do.
- Congratulations.
You may kiss the bride.
- Do you like seafood, do you?
- Come on.
Jack. We meet again.
Hector.
This is me bestest mate
in the whole world.
I always knew you'd
settle down, eventually.
Did you bring me a gift?
That'll do.
You look marvellous. Got
quite a spring in your step.
Has your leg grown back?
Captain, shouldn't we be
getting back to Salazar.
Trade Mr Sparrow's
life in for our own?
Ay, that we could. But I've come
for the Trident of Poseidon.
You're gonna double
cross the dead?
You did promise.
And with it I'll gut the dead
that stole my command of the sea.
As much as I love this plan.
No vessel can outrun that
wretched hull of a ship.
But there be one, Jack.
The fastest ship I know.
The Pearl, trapped in that
bottle by Blackbeard.
Five winters ago.
By the power of that
blaggard's sovereign blade.
I hereby release the Black Pearl,
to her former and rightful glory.
Get rid of the.
It's coming.
It's coming. It's coming. Coming.
Stand aside. Stand aside.
It's coming.
It's shrunken.
Why doesn't it unshrink?
Maybe it's cold.
She needs the sea.
She was a fine ship.
There be room for
only one captain.
- Filthy beast.
- Time to race the dead.
The only safe place is the land.
Why are we going
away from the land?
Anyone?
Captain, your map is incomplete.
I can take us to the Trident,
if you'd only trust me.
Did you not hear
anything I just said?
So you be saying that
that star is pretending
to be a map?
Sir, there is no
island, on any map,
to support what the woman says.
Captain, you don't have
to understand her.
Just believe her.
Anyone?
We had something sharp,
I could pick that lock.
You're not gonna find
anything sharp in here.
Keep still, ya bilge rat.
Captain. Oh please, I don't
wanna be Captain any more.
Release them.
Sir, you wouldn't allow a
woman to steer your ship?
She will follow her star.
Or we'll all die together.
The Black Pearl. She sails again.
Yeah.
This ship. Those ghosts.
There can be no
logical explanation.
The myths of the sea
are real, Carina.
I'm glad you can finally
see you were wrong.
Wrong?
Perhaps I had some doubts.
This is the worst apology
I've ever heard.
Apology? Why would I apologise?
Because we've been chased by
the dead, sailing on a ship,
raised from a bottle. Where
is your science in that?
Fine, I will apologise.
Go on, then.
Well then, one could argue
that you owe me an apology.
As my life has been threatened
by pirates and dead man.
Which you now believe
in, sorry to say.
Apology accepted.
I'm going to the lookout.
I'm glad you see it my way.
12 degrees to port.
- Ready the guns.
- Aye. Ready the guns.
Those pirates are going
for the Trident.
Where did you get that from Missy?
I know this book, stolen
from an Italian ship,
- many years ago.
- Stolen?
No, you're mistaken.
There was a ruby on the cover...
I would not soon forget.
This was given to me by my father.
He was clearly a man of science.
He was clearly a common thief.
The memory of my father
will not be befouled...
by the tongue of a pirate.
This diary is my birth right.
Left to me on the steps
of a children's home.
Along with a name
and nothing else.
Oh, so you're an orphan?
What be you called?
Brightest star in the
north gave me my name.
- That would be Carina?
- Carina Smyth.
- So, you do know your stars?
- I'm a Captain.
I know which stars to follow home.
Smyth?
Smyth is quite an unusual name.
Did we not once know
someone, called Smyth?
Shut your trap.
What was her name.
It's right on the
tip of me tongue.
Do you wanna loose that tongue?
Margaret Smyth.
Aye, shall we make an accord then?
Or, shall I tell you know who.
What we both know to be true.
We both take the
secret to our graves.
You mean, it is true?
I was bluffing.
I'm not.
You kill me, you got nothing
to bargain the dead with.
So you need me.
I'll have to be frank Hector.
You are very, very ugly.
So how could you produce a
fetching creature such as that?
Margaret died.
I summoned as much honour
as a worthless
blaggard ever could.
I placed the infant in an
orphanage, never to see her again.
I thought the ruby might
afford her some easy life.
But I never imagined she'd
take those scribblings.
And make a life of her own.
Life that's led her back to me.
I'd say this puts me in a rather
favourable position, daddy.
- Tell me what you want.
- I want me compass.
216 barrels of rum. And a monkey.
- You want Jack?
- Dinner.
I want to eat him. I
want to eat that monkey.
No deal Jack. A clever
young woman such as that,
would never believe that a swine
like me could ever be her blood.
And the Trident will be mine.
Redcoats.
Prepare to fire.
Man the guns.
She comes starboard.
We shall fight to the last.
The Pearl will not be
taken from me again.
Sir.
Only the British Empire will
hold the power of the sea.
What ever happens,
stay your course.
Jack Sparrow? Jack Sparrow?
I've come with the butcher's bill.
Where is he?
Defend yourselves
men. To the death.
Hurry up man, what did you...
sharpen it with butter?
There's nowhere to hide.
Let's be brave, save the Pearl.
This has to be it.
- It has to be here.
- Find that land.
Or we'll all die.
We're nearly there.
It's here somewhere.
Have you found what you're
looking for yet, miss?
I'm trying.
The stars will soon be gone.
Carina.
Henry. Look, the island is there.
You found it.
The island.
Land.
Get to the midding.
Carina.
Henry.
They took Henry.
The Trident be all
that can save him now.
Then we have to find it.
Where is it?
It has to be here.
Look at it Jack.
It's the most beautiful
thing I've ever seen.
This is what my father
wanted me to find.
The rocks?
No, no. Not rocks, stars.
This is the map no man can read.
This island is a perfect
reflection of the heavens.
One star's missing, quickly.
We have to find the
Trident to save Henry.
Hector.
I think you should know,
she's a horologist.
Why isn't it glowing?
Finish it, Carina.
The missing star.
For my father.
Aye.
Do it for him.
There.
- Posiedon's tomb.
- This way.
Capitan.
You know the danger. Don't do it.
We have no choice. Jack is on
land going for the Trident.
Capitan, there must
be another way.
Once you possess the living,
there is no coming back. You
will be trapped in his body.
Forever.
The Trident will set me free.
- Time to kill a Sparrow.
- No.
- Look Jack, there it is.
- The Trident.
Jack.
You cut me, you cut the boy, Jack.
- Henry.
- No.
Hola, Sparrow.
No.
Sparrow, Sparrow.
Henry, you've woken
him up. Please.
Henry wake up.
Oh, piss off.
Henry. Wake up, he's killing Jack.
Henry.
- Power of the sea.
- What?
- The power of the sea.
- To release the power of the sea.
All must divide.
If the Trident holds
all the power, then...
Then every curse is held inside.
As I told you before.
Surrender to me now.
And I will let you...
- Live.
- Do you want me to surrender?
- Maybe.
- This is where the trail ends.
No.
Divide.
Henry.
Henry. Divide.
Break.
Break the Trident and you'll
break every curse at sea.
Adios, Sparrow.
All curses have broken.
Yes.
- The Pearl. My Pearl.
- Climb.
Move, fast.
Hold it steady boys,
don't let it slip.
Jack.
Faster.
Lift, anchor.
Get the anchor up, quick.
Stop, stop, bring it up.
Bring it up.
Capitan.
Oh, crap.
I've got ya.
Who am I to you?
Treasure.
Hold on.
Hector.
More to starboard.
Pirate's life, Hector.
You were right.
I don't know.
For a moment I had
everything, Henry.
Now it's all gone again.
It's not all gone, Smyth.
Barbossa... My name is Barbossa.
- Maybe Jack was right.
- About what?
The unscratchable itch.
Why did you do that for?
Just checking it's truly you.
That you're not still a ghost.
- It's me.
- Then I was.
- Wrong.
- Slightly in error.
Although one...
Apology accepted.
The Dutchman.
- Henry?
- Yes father.
Oh, look at you son.
How did you do it?
- How did you break the curse?
- Let me tell you a tale.
The tale of the greatest
treasure known to man.
That's a tale I wanna hear.
What a truly revolting sight.
Make way.
Captain Jack Sparrow on deck...
Indeed.
Welcome back, Captain.
I thank you very much,
coming through.
- Captain.
- Thank you, I remember you.
- Cheers, thank you.
- Oh good.
Master Gibbs.
The ship is yours Captain.
Aye, thank you.
Monkey.
Thank you.
What be our heading captain?
We shall follow the stars,
Master Gibbs.
Aye... aye, Captain.
I have a rendezvous beyond
my. Beloved horizon.