AGATHE: Once upon a time,
in the hidden heart of France...
a handsome young prince...
lived in a beautiful castle.
PLUMETTE: Poof! Poof!
Although he had
everything his heart desired...
the prince was
selfish and unkind.
COGSWORTH: Master, it's time.
He taxed the village...
to fill his castle with
the most beautiful objects.
And his parties with
the most beautiful people.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
♪ (SINGING) ♪
♪ Oh, how divine ♪
♪ Glamour, ♪
♪ music and magic combine ♪
♪ See the maidens ♪
♪ so anxious to shine ♪
♪ Look for a sign ♪
♪ that enhances chances ♪
♪ She'll be his special one ♪
♪ What a display ♪
♪ What a breathtaking, ♪
♪ thrilling array ♪
♪ Ev'ry prince ♪
♪ Ev'ry dog has his day ♪
♪ Let us sing with passion, ♪
♪ gusto, fit to bust, oh ♪
♪ Not a care in the world ♪
- (KNOCKING ON GLASS)
- (ALL GASP)
(THUNDER CRACKING)
AGATHE: Then one night...
an unexpected intruder arrived
at the castle...
seeking shelter
from the bitter storm.
As a gift, she offered
the prince, a single rose.
(LAUGHING)
(ALL LAUGH)
Repulsed by her haggard appearance...
the prince
turned the woman away.
Hmm.
But she warned him not to be
deceived by appearances.
For beauty is found within.
When he dismissed her again...
the old woman's outward
appearance melted away.
(WOMAN GASPS)
To reveal...
a beautiful enchantress.
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
The prince begged
for forgiveness,
but it was too late.
For she had seen that
there was no love in his heart.
Chip! Chip! Oh, my!
As punishment...
she transformed him
into a hideous beast.
And placed a powerful spell
on the castle...
and all who lived there.
(THE BEAST ROARING)
As days bled into years...
the prince and his servants
were forgotten by the world.
For the enchantress had erased
all memory of them...
from the minds
of the people they loved.
But the rose she had offered
was truly an enchanted rose.
If he could
learn to love another...
and earn their love in return
by the time the last petal fell...
the spell would be broken.
If not, he would be doomed to
remain a beast for all time.
As the years passed...
he fell into despair
and lost all hope.
For who could ever
learn to love a beast?
(ROOSTER CALLING)
♪ (SINGING) Little town ♪
♪ It's a quiet village ♪
♪ Ev'ry day like the one before ♪
♪ Little town ♪
♪ Full of little people ♪
(CHURCH BELL TOLLING)
♪ Waking up to say ♪
(BELL CONTINUES TOLLING)
- Bonjour!
Bonjour!
♪ There goes the baker ♪
♪ with his tray like always ♪
♪ The same old bread ♪
♪ and rolls to sell ♪
♪ Every morning ♪
♪ just the same ♪
♪ Since the morning ♪
♪ that we came ♪
♪ To this poor ♪
♪ provincial town ♪
Good morning, Belle!
Good morning, Monsieur Jean!
Have you lost something again?
Well, I believe I have.
The problem is,
I can't remember what!
Oh, well.
I'm sure it will come to me.
Where are you off to?
To return this book
to Père Robert.
It's about two lovers
in fair Verona.
Sounds boring.
SCHOOL BOYS: (SINGING)
♪ Look there she goes ♪
♪ That girl is strange, ♪
♪ no question ♪
♪ Dazed and distracted ♪
♪ Can't you tell? ♪
♪ Never part of any crowd ♪
♪ 'Cause her head's ♪
♪ up on some cloud ♪
♪ No denying ♪
♪ she's a funny girl that Belle ♪
♪ Bonjour, good day, ♪
♪ how is your family? ♪
♪ how is your wife? ♪
(MAN GRUNTS)
♪ I need six eggs ♪
♪ That's too expensive ♪
♪ There must be more ♪
♪ than this provincial life ♪
Ah, if it isn't
the only bookworm in town.
So, where did you run off to
this week?
Two cities in Northern Italy.
I didn't want to come back!
Have you got
any new places to go?
I'm afraid not.
But you may reread any of
the old ones that you'd like.
Thank you.
Your library makes
our small corner of the world feel big.
(BIDS GOODBYE IN FRENCH)
Bye.
ALL: (SINGING)
♪ Look, there she goes ♪
♪ The girl is so peculiar ♪
♪ I wonder ♪
♪ if she's feeling well ♪
♪ With a dreamy far off look ♪
♪ And her nose stuck in a book ♪
♪ What a puzzle to the
rest of us is Belle ♪
♪ Oh! Isn't this amazing ♪
♪ It's my favorite part ♪
♪ because you'll see ♪
♪ Here's where ♪
♪ she meets Prince Charming ♪
♪ But she won't discover ♪
♪ that it's him ♪
♪ 'Til chapter three ♪
♪ Now it's no wonder ♪
♪ That her name means "beauty" ♪
♪ Her looks have ♪
♪ got no parallel ♪
♪ But behind that fair façade ♪
♪ I'm afraid she's rather odd ♪
♪ Very different ♪
♪ from the rest of us ♪
♪ She's nothing ♪
♪ like the rest of us ♪
♪ Yes, different ♪
♪ from the rest of us ♪
♪ Is Belle ♪
GASTON: Look at her, LeFou.
My future wife.
Belle is the most
beautiful girl in the village.
That makes her the best.
But she's so well-read.
And you're so...
- athletically inclined.
- I know.
Belle can be as argumentative
as she is beautiful.
Exactly! Who needs her
when you've got us!
Yes...
But ever since the war,
I've felt like
I've been missing something.
And she's the only girl
that gives me that sense of...
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
I don't know what that means.
♪ (SINGING) ♪
♪ Right from the moment ♪
♪ When I met her, saw her ♪
♪ I said she's gorgeous ♪
♪ and I fell ♪
♪ Here in town there's only she ♪
♪ Who is beautiful as me ♪
♪ So I'm making plans ♪
♪ to woo and marry Belle ♪
♪ Look there he goes ♪
♪ Isn't he dreamy ♪
♪ Monsieur Gaston, ♪
♪ oh, he's so cute ♪
♪ Be still, my heart ♪
♪ I'm hardly breathing ♪
♪ He's such a tall, dark ♪
♪ Strong and handsome brute ♪
(GIRLS SQUEAL)
It's never gonna happen,
ladies.
(GIRLS SIGH)
♪ -(SINGING) Bonjour ♪
♪ - Pardon ♪
♪ - Good day ♪
♪ - Mais, oui ♪
♪ - You call this bacon ♪
♪ - What lovely flowers ♪
♪ - Some cheese ♪
♪ - Ten yards ♪
♪ - One pound ♪
♪ -'Scuse me ♪
♪ -I'll get the knife ♪
♪ - Please let me through ♪
♪ - This bread ♪
♪ - Those fish ♪
♪ - It's stale ♪
♪ - They smell ♪
♪ - Madame's mistaken ♪
♪ - Well, maybe so ♪
♪ There must be more ♪
♪ than this provincial life ♪
TOWNSFOLK: Good morning
♪ Just watch I'm going ♪
♪ to make Belle my wife ♪
TOWNSFOLK:
Oh! Good morning
♪ Look there she goes ♪
♪ A girl who's strange but special ♪
♪ A most peculiar mademoiselle ♪
♪ It's a pity and a sin ♪
♪ She doesn't quite fit in ♪
♪ But she really is a funny girl ♪
♪ A beauty but a funny girl ♪
♪ She really is a funny girl ♪
♪ That Belle ♪
Good morning, Belle!
Wonderful book you have there.
Have you read it?
Well, not that one.
But, you know, books... (CHUCKLES)
For your dinner table.
Shall I join you this evening?
Sorry, not this evening.
Busy?
No...
So, moving on?
No, LeFou.
It's the ones
who play hard to get
that are always
the sweetest prey.
That's what makes Belle
so appealing.
She hasn't made
a fool of herself
just to gain my favor.
What would you call that?
Dignity?
It's outrageously attractive,
isn't it?
WOMAN: Gaston!
Mmm.
(MUSIC BOX PLAYING)
♪ (SINGING) How does a moment ♪
♪ last forever ♪
♪ How can a story never die ♪
♪ It is love we must hold on to ♪
♪ Never easy but we try ♪
♪ Sometimes our happiness ♪
♪ is captured ♪
♪ Somehow a time and place stand still ♪
♪ Love lives on ♪
♪ inside our hearts ♪
♪ And always will ♪
Oh.
Belle.
Hmm.
Could you...
Hand me a...
Thank you.
And I also need...
No. No. No.
Actually...
yes, that's exactly
what I need. Thank you.
- Papa, do you think I'm odd?
- Odd?
My daughter? Odd?
Where did you get an idea like that?
I don't know. People talk.
This is a small village,
you know.
Small minded as well.
But small also means safe.
Even back in Paris,
I knew a girl like you,
who was so...
ahead of her time.
So different.
People mocked her.
Until the day they all found
themselves imitating her.
Please, just tell me
one more thing about her.
Your mother was...
fearless.
Fearless.
(EXCLAIMS)
So...
what can I bring you
from the market?
A rose.
Like the one in the painting.
You ask for that every year!
And every year you bring it.
Then I shall
bring you another.
You have my word.
- Goodbye, Papa.
- Goodbye, Belle.
- Come on, Philippe.
- (PHILIPPE WHINNIES)
You know the way.
I'll see you tomorrow!
Right.
Tomorrow, with the rose.
(CHUCKLES)
Stay safe.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
GIRL: What are you doing?
The laundry.
Come! Come!
(CHURCH BELL TOLLING)
"The blue bird..."
"That flies..."
"over the dark..."
"wood."
That was amazing!
What on earth are you doing?
Teaching another girl to read?
Isn't one enough?
We have to do something.
(MEN GRUNTING)
You are the wildest...
most gorgeous thing
I have ever seen.
Nobody deserves you.
But at least I know
our children will be beautiful.
Am I catching you
at a bad time?
- What is it, LeFou?
- A certain damsel is in distress.
Ah. It's hero time.
I'm not done with you yet.
Me, neither.
GASTON: Belle! I heard you had trouble
with the Headmaster.
He never liked me either.
Can I give you a little advice
about the villagers though?
They're never going to trust
the kind of change you're trying to bring.
All I wanted was to teach
a child to read.
The only children you should
concern yourself with...
are your own.
I'm...
not ready to have children.
Maybe you haven't
met the right man.
It's a small village, Gaston.
I've met them all.
Well, maybe
you should take another look.
Some of us have changed.
Gaston...
we could never
make each other happy.
No one can change that much.
Oh, Belle.
Do you know what happens
to spinsters in this village
after their fathers die?
AGATHE: Coins? Got any spare coins?
They beg for scraps,
like poor Agathe.
This is our world, Belle.
For simple folk like us,
it doesn't get any better.
I might be a farm girl.
But, I'm not simple...
and I'm never going to
marry you, Gaston.
I'm sorry!
(EXHALES)
Can you imagine?
Me? The wife
of that boorish...
brainless...
♪ (SINGING) Madame Gaston, ♪
♪ can't you just see it ♪
♪ Madame Gaston, ♪
♪ his little wife ♪
♪ Ugh! ♪
♪ No, sir, not me, ♪
♪ I guarantee it ♪
♪ I want much more ♪
♪ than this provincial life ♪
♪ I want adventure ♪
♪ in the great wide somewhere ♪
♪ I want it more than I can tell ♪
♪ And for once it might be grand ♪
♪ To have someone understand ♪
♪ I want so much more ♪
♪ Than they've got planned ♪
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(PHILIPPE NEIGHS)
The woods are lovely.
I only wish I recognized them.
Do you know where we are,
Philippe? Because I don't.
(WHINNYING)
It's all right.
It's all right, Philippe.
Hmm.
Yes, we can go this way.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
Go on. To the right.
That's it. Steady!
Walk on!
One path closes...
another one opens.
It's all right, boy.
It's just a bit of snow.
In June.
Mind your step.
It's slippery.
(NEIGHS)
(GROWLING)
Go! Go, Philippe!
Come on! Come on!
- (HOWLING)
- Whoa.
(WOLVES GROWLING)
Come on!
Go! Philippe, go! Go, go!
Whoa!
(MAURICE YELLS AND GRUNTS)
(PHILIPPE WHINNYING)
(GRUNTING)
(GROWLING)
(EXCLAIMING)
Philippe!
Good boy.
Go, boy. Go!
(WOLF HOWLING)
Oh, Philippe,
you saved my life.
Well done. Yes.
They'll have to get
their dinner somewhere else,
won't they? (CHUCKLES)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTS)
Look!
There's hay.
And water.
You're all set, my old friend.
I'll go pay my respects
to our unwitting host.
Whoever that may be.
Hmm.
Thank you.
Thank...
Hello?
Sorry to intrude.
I'm just a traveler...
seeking shelter
from the storm.
Sorry to disturb you.
Anyone home?
Anyone awake?
He must have
lost his way in the woods.
Shut up, you idiot!
Excuse me?
Hmm.
Beautiful.
Extraordinary.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
A man of taste.
He was talking about me.
Oops!
(MAURICE STUTTERS)
Well, wherever you are...
I'm just going to warm myself
by the fire.
(COUGHS)
That's better.
Oh, much better.
(DISTANT CLATTERING)
Ooh.
Thank you.
Mum said I wasn't supposed to move
because it might be scary.
Sorry.
It's all right.
I, uh...
I cannot...
thank you enough
for your hospitality.
I'll...
bid you adieu...
(THUNDER CRACKING)
and good night.
Come on, Philippe! Go! Go!
No, wait, wait, wait!
Roses. I nearly forgot.
We're safe here.
I promised Belle a rose.
(EXCLAIMS)
(GROWLING)
(GRUNTING AND HUFFING)
There!
- (THE BEAST ROARING)
- (WHIMPERING)
(WHINNYING)
(PHILIPPE WHINNYING)
Philippe!
What happened?
Where's Papa?
Take me to him!
(WIND BLOWING)
(PHILIPPE WHINNIES)
LUMIÈRE: Look, Cogsworth.
A beautiful girl!
COGSWORTH:
Yes! I can see it's a girl.
I lost my hands, not my eyes.
But what if she is the one?
The one
who'll break the spell?
Who said that?
Who's there?
(MAURICE COUGHS DISTANTLY)
Uh-oh.
(MAURICE CONTINUES COUGHING)
Papa?
Papa, is that you?
Belle!
How did you find me?
Your hands are ice.
We need to get you home.
Belle, you must leave here
at once!
This castle is alive!
Now go, before he finds you!
Who?
(THE BEAST GROWLING)
Who's there?
Who are you?
THE BEAST: Who are you?
I've come for my father.
Your father is a thief.
Liar!
He stole a rose.
I asked for the rose.
Punish me, not him.
No!
He means forever.
Apparently, that's what
happens around here
when you pick a flower.
A life sentence for a rose?
(ROARING)
I received
eternal damnation for one.
I'm merely locking him away.
Now, do you still wish
to take your father's place?
Come into the light.
(GASPS)
Choose.
Belle, I won't
let you do this.
I lost your mother.
I won't lose you, too.
Now, go.
Go! (COUGHS)
All right, Papa. I'll leave.
I need a minute alone with him.
(GRUNTS)
Are you so cold-hearted...
you won't allow a daughter
to kiss her father goodbye?
Forever can spare a minute.
When this door closes,
it will not open again.
I should have been with you.
Oh, no, no.
Belle, listen to me.
It's all right.
Now go.
Live your life.
And forget me.
Forget you?
Everything I am
is because of you.
I love you, Belle.
Don't be afraid.
I love you too, Papa.
I'm not afraid.
And I will escape. I promise.
What?
You took his place.
He's my father.
He's a fool.
And so are you.
Belle...
Papa!
- (GROANING)
- Don't hurt him!
- Papa!
- MAURICE: No!
I'll come back!
I promise!
(GRUNTS)
(GASPS)
LUMIÈRE: Forgive my intrusion,
mademoiselle...
but I have come to escort you
to your room.
My room?
- But I thought...
- LUMIÈRE: Oh, what?
That "Once this door closes
it will not open again"?
(IMITATES ROAR) I know.
He gets so dramatic.
- Hello.
- (GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
- Ooh!
- (SHRIEKS)
Oh, you are very strong.
This is a great quality.
What are you?
I am Lumière!
And you can talk?
COGSWORTH:
Well, of course he can talk.
It's all he ever does.
Now, Lumière,
as head of the household...
I demand that you put her
back in her cell at once.
What do you want to be
for the rest of your life, Cogsworth?
A man, or a mantle clock?
Ready, miss?
- Trust me.
- COGSWORTH: Oh...
LUMIÈRE: You must forgive
first impressions.
I hope you are
not too startled.
BELLE:
Why would I be startled?
I'm talking to a candle.
Candelabra, please.
Enormous difference.
But consider me at your service.
The castle is your home now...
so feel free to go
anywhere you like.
Except the west wing.
Which we do not have.
Why? What's in the west wing?
- Oh, nothing.
- COGSWORTH: Nothing.
- Storage space.
- COGSWORTH: Storage space.
- That's it.
- COGSWORTH: That's it.
Yes, that's it.
COGSWORTH: This way, please.
To the east wing.
LUMIÈRE: Or as I like to call it,
the only wing. (LAUGHS)
Watch your step,
s'il vous plaít!
(BOTH EXCLAIM)
Welcome to your new home.
It's modest, but comfortable.
It's beautiful.
LUMIÈRE: But of course!
Master wanted you to have
the finest room in the castle.
(COUGHS) Oh, dear.
We were not expecting guests.
PLUMETTE:
Enchantée, mademoiselle.
Don't worry.
I'll have this place spotless
in no time.
This plan of yours
is dangerous.
I would risk anything
to kiss you again, Plumette.
No, my love. I've been
burned by you before.
We must be strong.
How can I be strong
when you make me so weak?
(COUGHS)
(SNORING)
Is everything here alive?
Hello. What's your name?
- (BOTH LAUGH)
- That is a hairbrush.
(HIGH PITCH VOCALIZATION)
Do not be alarmed.
This is just your wardrobe.
Meet Madame De Garderobe.
A great singer.
When she can stay awake.
Cogsworth! A diva needs
her beauty rest. (YAWNS)
Stay with us, Madame.
We have someone
for you to dress!
(GASPS) Finally...
a woman.
Pretty eyes.
Proud face.
Perfect canvas. Yes!
I will find you something
worthy of a princess.
Oh, I'm not a princess.
Nonsense!
Now, let's see
what I've got in my drawers.
- (GASPS)
- Oh!
How embarrassing.
Froufrou, come help Mama.
(BARKING)
(GASPS)
(EXCLAIMS IN SPANISH)
Subtle. Understated.
I love it!
(BIDS GOODBYE IN FRENCH)
Froufrou, send my love
to the maestro.
(SNORING)
GASTON: Picture it, LeFou.
A rustic cabin...
my latest kill
roasting on the fire...
adorable children running
around us as my love...
rubs my tired feet.
But what does Belle say?
"I will never marry you,
Gaston!"
You know,
there are other girls.
A great hunter doesn't
waste his time on rabbits.
♪ (SINGING) Gosh it disturbs me ♪
♪ to see you, Gaston ♪
♪ Looking so down in the dumps ♪
♪ Every guy here'd ♪
♪ love to be you, Gaston ♪
♪ Even when taking your lumps ♪
♪ There's no man in town ♪
♪ as admired as you ♪
♪ You're everyone's favorite guy ♪
♪ Everyone's awed ♪
♪ and inspired by you ♪
♪ And it's not very hard ♪
♪ to see why ♪
♪ No one's slick as Gaston ♪
♪ No one's quick as Gaston ♪
♪ No one's neck's as ♪
♪ incredibly thick as Gaston ♪
♪ For there's no man in town ♪
♪ half as manly ♪
♪ Perfect, a pure paragon ♪
♪ You can ask ♪
♪ any Tom, Dick, or Stanley ♪
♪ And they'll tell you ♪
♪ whose team they prefer to be on ♪
♪ Who plays ♪
♪ Darts like Gaston? ♪
♪ - Who breaks ♪
♪ - Hearts like Gaston? ♪
♪ Who's much more than the sum ♪
♪ of his parts like Gaston? ♪
♪ As a specimen, ♪
♪ yes, I'm intimidating ♪
♪ My, what a guy, ♪
♪ that Gaston ♪
♪ I needed encouragement ♪
♪ Thank you, LeFou ♪
♪ Well, there's no one ♪
♪ As easy to bolster as you ♪
Too much?
Yep!
♪ No one fights like Gaston ♪
♪ Douses lights like Gaston ♪
♪ In a wrestling match ♪
♪ Nobody bites like Gaston ♪
♪ When I hunt, ♪
♪ I sneak up with my quiver ♪
♪ And beasts of the field ♪
♪ say a prayer ♪
Aah...
♪ First I carefully aim for the liver ♪
♪ Then I shoot from behind ♪
♪ Is that fair? ♪
♪ I don't care ♪
♪ No one hits like Gaston ♪
♪ Matches wits like Gaston ♪
♪ In a spitting match ♪
♪ nobody spits like Gaston ♪
♪ I'm especially good ♪
♪ at expectorating ♪
ALL: Ooh!
♪ Ten points for Gaston! ♪
Thank you. Thank you.
When I was a lad
I ate four dozen eggs
♪ Every morning ♪
♪ to help me get large ♪
♪ And now that I'm grown ♪
♪ I eat five dozen eggs ♪
♪ So I'm roughly ♪
♪ the size of a barge ♪
(GIRLS SQUEAL)
- (ALL CLAPPING RHYTHMICALLY)
- ALL: Hey! Hey!
Hey!
- Hey!
- (SIGHS)
Hey!
Hey! Hey!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
(ALL WHOOPING AND CHEERING)
(YELLS AND GRUNTS)
(EXCLAIMS)
(MAN YELLS)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
(MEN GROANING)
(ALL CHEERING)
(GIGGLING SHRILLY)
♪ Who has brains ♪
♪ Like Gaston ♪
♪ - Entertains ♪
♪ - Like Gaston ♪
♪ Who can make up ♪
♪ these endless refrains like Gaston ♪
♪ I use antlers ♪
♪ in all of my decorating ♪
♪ Say it again ♪
♪ Who's a man among men? ♪
♪ Who's a super success? ♪
♪ Don't you know? ♪
♪ Can't you guess? ♪
♪ Ask his fans ♪
♪ and his five hangers-on ♪
♪ There's just one guy in town ♪
♪ Who's got all of it down ♪
♪ And his name's, G-A-S-T ♪
♪ I believe there's another 'T' ♪
♪ It just occurred to me ♪
♪ that I'm illiterate ♪
♪ And I've never actually had ♪
♪ to spell it out loud before ♪
♪ Gaston ♪
(ALL CHEERING)
(LAUGHS)
Oh, LeFou, you're the best.
How is it no girl
has snatched you up yet?
I've been told I'm clingy,
but I really don't get it.
Please, please.
Someone, someone.
- You, help...
- Whoa, whoa.
You must help me.
It's Belle!
He's got, he's got Belle.
She's locked in a dungeon.
TAVERN KEEPER: Who's got her?
A beast!
A huge, horrid,
monstrous beast!
(LAUGHTER)
My daughter's life
is in danger.
Why do you laugh?
It's not a joke.
His castle is hidden
in the woods.
It's already winter there.
Winter in June?
- (ALL LAUGH)
- Crazy old Maurice!
Listen to me!
The beast is real.
Do you understand?
Will no one help me?
I'll help, Maurice.
What?
You will?
Everybody...
stop making fun of this man at once.
Captain, thank you.
Don't thank me, Maurice.
Lead us to the beast.
(PANTING)
Come.
Hmm.
Oh.
Mama! There's a girl in the castle!
Yes, Chip, we know!
What kind of tea
does she like?
Herbal, oolong...
chamomile...
I'm too excited!
Slow down before
you break your handle.
- Heads up, Mrs. Potts.
- Oh.
(GRUNTS)
THE BEAST: Lumière!
- COGSWORTH: Oh!
- Be calm. Let me do the talking.
You're making her dinner!
Well, we thought you might
appreciate the company.
Master, I just want
to assure you...
that I had no part
in this hopeless plan.
Preparing a dinner, designing
a gown for her, giving her...
a suite in the east wing!
You gave her a bedroom?
No, no, no.
He gave her a bedroom.
This is true.
But if this girl is the one
who can break the spell...
then maybe you could start
by using dinner to charm her.
- Good thinking, Cogsworth.
- What?
That's the most
ridiculous idea...
I've ever heard.
Charm the prisoner!
But you must try, Master.
With every passing day...
we become less human.
She's the daughter
of a common thief.
What kind of person do you
think that makes her?
Oh, you can't judge people...
by who their father is,
now can you?
You'll join me for dinner.
That's not a request.
Gently, Master.
The girl lost her father...
and her freedom in one day.
Yes, the poor thing is probably in there,
scared to death.
MRS. POTTS: Exactly.
Just a minute.
You see? There she is.
Now, remember, be gentle.
- Kind!
- Charming!
Sweet!
And when she opens the door,
give her a dashing,
debonair smile.
Come, come. Show me the smile.
- Oh, mon dieu!
- Oh, no.
Will you join me for dinner?
You've taken me
as your prisoner
and now you want
to have dinner with me?
Are you insane?
- (GRUNTING)
- Uh-oh. He's losing it.
Oh, dear!
I told you
to join me for dinner.
And I told you no.
Ooh! What time is it?
What's happening?
I'd starve before
I ever ate with you.
Well, be my guest.
Go ahead and starve.
If she doesn't eat with me...
then she doesn't eat at all.
Idiots!
You can't talk to us
like that. I forbid it.
Uh... Oh. Am I too late?
Shame, I was really going to
tell him off this time.
Oh, Master, you've returned.
- (EXCLAIMS)
- (LAUGHS)
- Oh, very funny.
- I got you there.
Show me the girl.
(RUMBLING)
Another petal fell.
Lumière...
I grew three more feathers.
And I just plucked yesterday.
I know, darling.
(EXCLAIMS)
I'm getting more
metallic every day.
Oh, no. It's happening again.
Pardon me.
Oh, everyone, calm yourselves.
- We still have time.
- Mama...
am I ever going
to be a boy again?
Oh, yes, Chip.
You'll have your days...
in the sun again.
You just leave it to me.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
I told you to go away.
Don't worry, dear.
It's only Mrs. Potts.
Oh!
Oh, aren't you a vision!
How lovely...
to make your acquaintance.
It's a very long journey.
Let me fix you up...
before you go.
I have found...
that most troubles
seem less troubling...
after a bracing cup of tea.
Slowly now, Chip.
(CHIP GIGGLES)
Pleased to meet you.
Wanna see me do a trick?
Chip!
That was a very brave thing
you did for your father, dearie.
Yes.
We all think so.
I'm worried about him.
He's never been on his own.
Cheer up, my poppet.
Things will turn out
in the end.
You'll feel a lot better...
after dinner.
But he said,
"If she doesn't eat with me,
then she doesn't eat at all."
Mmm, people say
a lot of things in anger.
It is our choice
whether or not to listen.
You coming, poppet?
Go!
They are coming. Final checks,
everyone! Tout de suite!
No, you don't!
If the master finds out
you violated his orders
and fed her he will blame me!
Yes, I will make sure of it.
But did you see her
stand up to him?
I am telling you,
this girl is the one.
They must fall in love
if we are to be human again...
and how can they fall in love
if she stays in her room?
Hey, Chapeau,
you missed a spot.
You know
she'll never love him.
A broken clock is right
two times a day, mon ami...
but this is not one of those times.
Stand up straight!
It's time to sparkle!
Mmm! I have no taste buds,
but I can tell this is exquisite.
Off! Off me while I work!
Pepper, get cracking!
Salt, shake a leg!
Not so loud! Keep it down.
Of course, of course!
But what is dinner...
without a little music?
Music?
Maestro Cadenza,
are you ready?
(MAESTRO CADENZA CHUCKLES)
It has been so long
since I have performed.
I can barely even
remember how.
(PLAYS CHORDS
AND STOPS ABRUPTLY)
- Ah!
- Ooh!
Another cavity.
Maestro,
your wife is upstairs...
finding it harder and harder
to stay awake.
She's counting on you
to help us break this curse.
Then I shall
play through the dental pain.
Maestro, play quietly, please.
Oh, quietly.
Sotto voce! Of course!
Are there any other
tasteless demands...
you wish to make upon
my artistry?
No, that's it.
MRS. POTTS:
There you are, dear.
Ma chère mademoiselle.
It is with deepest pride
and greatest pleasure...
that we welcome you tonight.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Here! And now...
we invite you to relax.
Let us pull up a chair...
as the dining room
proudly presents...
♪ (MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
- (STOPS ABRUPTLY)
- (MAESTRO CADENZA EXCLAIMS)
Your dinner!
♪ (MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING) ♪
♪ (SINGING) ♪
♪ Be our guest, be our guest ♪
♪ Put our service to the test ♪
♪ Tie your napkin ♪
♪ 'round your neck, chèrie ♪
♪ And we'll provide the rest ♪
♪ Soup dujour, ♪
♪ hot hors d'oeuvres ♪
♪ Why we only live to serve ♪
♪ Try the gray stuff, ♪
♪ it's delicious ♪
♪ Don't believe me? ♪
♪ Ask the dishes ♪
(LAUGHING)
♪ They can sing, ♪
♪ they can dance ♪
♪ After all, miss, ♪
♪ this is France ♪
♪ And a dinner here ♪
♪ is never second best ♪
♪ Go on unfold your menu ♪
♪ Take a glance ♪
♪ and then you'll ♪
♪ Be our guest, ♪
♪ oui, our guest ♪
♪ Be our guest ♪
Ooh!
♪ Beef ragout ♪
♪ Cheese soufflé ♪
♪ Pie and pudding en flambé ♪
♪ We'll prepare and serve with flair ♪
♪ A culinary cabaret ♪
♪ You're alone ♪
♪ and you're scared ♪
♪ But the banquet's ♪
♪ all prepared ♪
♪ No one's gloomy ♪
♪ or complaining ♪
♪ While the flatware's ♪
♪ entertaining ♪
♪ We tell jokes, I do tricks ♪
♪ With my fellow candlesticks ♪
♪ CHORUS: ♪
♪ And it's all in perfect taste ♪
♪ That you can bet ♪
♪ Come on and ♪
♪ lift your glass ♪
♪ You've won your own free pass ♪
♪ To be our guest ♪
♪ If you're stressed ♪
♪ It's fine dining we suggest ♪
♪ Be our guest ♪
♪ Be our guest, ♪
♪ be our guest ♪
♪ Life is so unnerving ♪
♪ For a servant ♪
♪ who's not serving ♪
♪ He's not whole ♪
♪ Without a soul to wait upon ♪
♪ Ah, those good old days ♪
♪ when we were useful ♪
Eh, Cogsworth?
♪ Suddenly those good old days are gone ♪
♪ Too long we've been rusting ♪
♪ Needing so much more than dusting ♪
♪ Needing exercise, ♪
♪ a chance to use our skills ♪
(GRUNTING)
♪ Most days we just lay ♪
♪ around the castle ♪
♪ Flabby, fat and lazy ♪
♪ You walked in ♪
♪ and whoops-a-daisy ♪
♪ It's a guest, ♪
♪ it's a guest ♪
♪ Sakes alive, ♪
♪ well, I'll be blessed ♪
♪ Wine's been poured ♪
♪ and thank the Lord ♪
♪ I've had the napkins freshly pressed ♪
♪ With dessert, ♪
♪ she'll want tea ♪
♪ And my dear, ♪
♪ that's fine with me ♪
♪ While the cups ♪
♪ do their soft-shoeing ♪
♪ I'll be bubbling, ♪
♪ I'll be brewing ♪
(ALL VOCALIZING)
♪ l'll get warm, piping hot ♪
♪ Heaven's sakes, ♪
♪ is that a spot? ♪
♪ Clean it up, we want ♪
♪ the company impressed ♪
♪ We've got a lot to do ♪
♪ Is it one lump or two? ♪
♪ For you, our guest ♪
♪ She's our guest ♪
♪ ALL: ♪
♪ Be our guest, be our guest ♪
♪ Our command ♪
♪ is your request ♪
♪ It's been years ♪
♪ since we've had anybody ♪
♪ Here and we're obsessed ♪
♪ With your meal ♪
♪ With your ease ♪
♪ Yes indeed, ♪
♪ we aim to please ♪
♪ While the candlelight's ♪
♪ still glowing ♪
(LAUGHS)
♪ Let us help you, ♪
♪ we'll keep going ♪
♪ Course by ♪
♪ Course! ♪
♪ One by one ♪
♪ 'Til you shout, ♪
♪ "Enough, I'm done!" ♪
♪ Then we'll sing you off to sleep ♪
♪ As you digest ♪
♪ Tonight you'll prop your feet up ♪
♪ But for now let's eat up ♪
♪ Be our guest ♪
♪ Please be our guest ♪
Pudding?
(LAUGHS)
I don't understand why
you're all being so kind to me.
Surely, you're as trapped
here as I am.
Don't you ever want to escape?
The master's not
as terrible as he appears.
Somewhere deep in his soul,
there's a prince...
of a fellow who just waiting
to be set free.
Lumière mentioned something
about the west wing.
Never you mind about that.
Off to bed with you, poppet.
- Good night.
- Nighty-night.
MRS. POTTS: Straight to bed.
(PANTING)
What are you doing here?
What did you do to it?
Nothing.
Do you realize
what you could have done?
You could have damned us all!
Get out of here!
Go!
(PANTING)
LUMIÈRE: Checkmate. Again.
Wait! No! You cheated again.
Mademoiselle,
what are you doing?
Getting out of here.
- Stop!
- (LUMIÈRE GRUNTS)
Go! Go! Froufrou!
Yes, Froufrou. Stop her.
LUMIÈRE: Don't let her leave!
- MRS. POTTS: Stop her!
- (BARKING)
No! No! Froufrou!
COGSWORTH: No!
No, it's not play time!
LUMIÈRE: Not now, silly boy.
COGSWORTH: Bad dog. Bad dog!
LUMIÈRE: No! No! No!
Please don't go!
It's dangerous!
Oh, my!
(PANTING)
(HOWLING)
- (GROWLS)
- (ALL HOWLING)
(PHILIPPE WHINNYING)
(GROWLING)
- (GROWLS)
- (GASPS)
(SNARLING)
(GROWLING)
(YELPS)
(GROWLS)
(GROWLING)
(ROARING)
(WOLVES HOWLING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GRUNTS)
(THE BEAST BREATHING HEAVILY)
(WHISPERING)
You have to help me.
You have to stand.
(THE BEAST BREATHING HEAVILY)
(WOLVES HOWLING)
MAURICE: No!
I'm sure this is the way.
Do you hear those wolves?
That means we're getting
very close to the castle.
Look, enough is enough.
We have to turn back.
Stop!
That's it! There it is!
That's the tree!
I'm sure of it.
It was downed
by lightning at the time.
But now...
it's resumed
an upright position...
through some sort of...
magic or other.
You really wanna marry
into this family?
So, that means...
that the castle is that...
No.
No, it's...
(WHISTLES
AND BLOWS RASPBERRY)
That way.
Definitely, that way.
I am done playing
this game of yours.
Where is Belle?
The beast took her and she...
There are no such things
as beasts.
Or talking teacups.
Or magic!
But there are wolves,
frostbite, and starvation.
Deep breaths, Gaston.
Deep breaths.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
So, why don't we just turn around?
Go back to Villeneuve.
I'm sure Belle is at home,
cooking up a lovely dinner.
If you think
I've made all this up...
then why did you offer to help?
Because I want to marry
your daughter!
Now, let's go home.
Belle is not at home.
She is with the...
You say beast one more time...
I will feed you to the wolves!
Gaston! Stop it! Breathe!
Think happy thoughts.
Go back to the war.
Blood.
Explosions. Countless widows.
- Widows.
- Yes. Yes.
- (EXHALES)
- That's it.
That's it.
(CHUCKLES)
Maurice!
Please, forgive me, old bean.
That's no way to talk
to my future father-in-law...
now is it?
Future father-in-law?
Yeah!
You will never marry
my daughter.
(GRUNTS)
I saw that coming.
If Maurice won't
give me his blessing...
then he is in my way.
Once the wolves
are finished with him...
Belle will have no one
to take care of her but me.
For the sake of exhausting
all of our options...
do we maybe wanna consider
a slightly less...
gruesome alternative?
Are you coming?
Yah!
(WOLVES HOWLING IN DISTANCE)
(THE BEAST GROWLING IN PAIN)
That hurts!
If you held still,
it wouldn't hurt as much.
Well, if you hadn't run away,
none of this would have happened.
Well, if you hadn't frightened me,
I wouldn't have run away.
Well, you shouldn't have been
in the west wing.
Well, you should learn
to control your temper!
(GRUNTS)
Try to get some rest.
Thank you, miss.
We are eternally grateful.
Why do you care
about him so much?
We've looked after him all his life.
But he's cursed you somehow. Why?
You did nothing!
You're quite right there, dear.
You see, when the master
lost his mother...
and his cruel father
took that sweet, innocent lad...
and twisted him up
to be just like him...
we did nothing.
LUMIÈRE: Let him sleep.
YOUNG PRINCE: (SINGING)
♪ Days in the sun ♪
♪ When my life ♪
♪ has barely begun ♪
♪ Not until ♪
♪ my whole life is done ♪
♪ Will I ever leave you ♪
♪ Will I tremble again ♪
♪ To my dear one's ♪
♪ gorgeous refrain ♪
♪ Will you now ♪
♪ forever remain ♪
♪ Out of reach of my arms ♪
♪ Oh, those days in the sun ♪
♪ What I'd give ♪
♪ to relive just one ♪
(YAWNS) 'Night, Mama.
♪ Undo what's done ♪
♪ And bring back the light ♪
♪ Oh, I could sing ♪
♪ Of the pain ♪
♪ these dark days bring ♪
♪ The spell we're under ♪
♪ Still it's the wonder of us ♪
♪ I sing of tonight ♪
♪ How in the midst ♪
♪ of all this sorrow ♪
♪ Can so much ♪
♪ hope and love endure ♪
♪ I was innocent and certain ♪
♪ Now I'm wiser but unsure ♪
♪ Days in the past ♪
♪ I can't go back ♪
♪ into my childhood ♪
GARDEROBE:
♪ Oh, those precious days couldn't last ♪
♪ One that my father ♪
♪ made secure ♪
♪ I can feel a change in me ♪
GARDEROBE:
♪ Oh, hold me closer ♪
BELLE: ♪I'm stronger now
but still not free ♪
ALL:
♪ Days in the sun ♪
♪ Will return ♪
♪ we must believe ♪
♪ As lovers do ♪
♪ That days in the sun ♪
♪ Will come shining through ♪
What happens
when the last petal falls?
The master remains
a beast forever.
And we become...
- Antiques.
- Knick-knacks.
Lightly-used houseware.
Rubbish.
We become rubbish.
I want to help you.
There must be some way
to break the curse.
Well, there is one.
It's not for you
to worry about, lamb.
We've made our bed
and we must lie in it.
(MAURICE BREATHING SHAKILY)
(HOOTING)
Drink.
(SIPPING)
(EXHALES)
Thank you, Agathe.
BELLE: "Love can transpose
to form and dignity."
"Love looks not with the eyes"
"but with the mind
and therefore..."
"And therefore is winged Cupid
painted blind."
You know Shakespeare?
(GRUNTS)
I had an expensive education.
Actually, Romeo and Juliet's
my favorite play.
(GROANS) Why is that not a surprise?
I'm sorry?
Well, all that heartache
and pining and... (RETCHING)
So many better things to read.
Like what?
Well, there are a couple of...
things in here
you could start with.
(GASPS SOFTLY)
Are you all right?
It's wonderful!
Yes. I suppose it is.
Well, if you like it so much,
then it's yours.
Have you really read every one
of these books?
What?
(SCOFFS)
Well, not all of them.
Some of them are in Greek.
Was that a joke?
Are you making jokes now?
Maybe.
(BELLE CHUCKLES)
(SHRIEKS EXCITEDLY)
(LAUGHS)
(SLURPING)
BELLE: "The air is blue
and keen and cold...
"and in a frozen sheath,
enrolled."
"Each branch, each twig..."
"each blade of grass seems
clad miraculously with..."
"glass."
(BIRDS CHIRPING IN DISTANCE)
I feel as if I'm
seeing it for the first time.
Is there any more?
(LAUGHS) Um...
"But in that solemn silence
is heard the whisper..."
"of every sleeping thing."
"Look. Look at me."
"Come wake me up."
"For still here I be."
(NEIGHS SOFTLY)
(SHUSHING)
(SINGING) ♪There's something sweet
and almost kind ♪
♪ But he was mean ♪
♪ and he was coarse and unrefined ♪
♪ And now he's dear ♪
♪ and so unsure ♪
♪ I wonder why ♪
♪ I didn't see it there before ♪
(GRUNTS)
(LAUGHS)
(CHUCKLES)
♪ She glanced this way ♪
♪ I thought I saw ♪
♪ And when we touched ♪
♪ She didn't shudder at my paw ♪
♪ No, it can't be ♪
♪ I'll just ignore ♪
♪ But then ♪
♪ she's never looked at me ♪
♪ That way before ♪
(BOTH SLURPING)
(CHUCKLES)
♪ New, and a bit alarming ♪
♪ Who'd have ever thought ♪
♪ that this could be ♪
♪ True that ♪
♪ he's no Prince Charming ♪
♪ But there's something in him ♪
♪ That I simply didn't see ♪
PLUMETTE:
♪ Well, who'd have thought? ♪
MRS. POTTS:
♪ Well, bless my soul! ♪
♪ - Well, who'd have known? ♪
♪ - Well, who indeed? ♪
♪ And who'd have guessed ♪
♪ They'd come together on their own ♪
MRS. POTTS: ♪It's so peculiar
Wait and see ♪
ALL: ♪We'll wait and see
A few days more ♪
♪ There may be something there ♪
♪ That wasn't there before ♪
And here's a thought...
♪ Perhaps there's something there ♪
♪ That wasn't there before ♪
- (PLUMETTE CHUCKLES)
- CHIP: What, Mama?
♪ There may be something there ♪
♪ That wasn't there before ♪
What is it? What's there?
I'll tell you
when you're older.
Okay, I'm older!
(SCOFFS) Chip...
(LAUGHING) You are a one.
What are you reading?
Nothing.
Guinevere and Lancelot.
Well, actually...
King Arthur
and the Round Table.
Knights and men
and swords and things.
Mmm.
Still...
it's a romance.
All right.
I never thanked you
for saving my life.
Well, I never thanked you...
for not leaving me
to be eaten by wolves.
(LAUGHS)
(ALL CHATTERING EXCITEDLY)
BELLE: They know
how to have a good time.
Yes. But when I enter the room,
laughter dies.
Me too.
The villagers say that
I'm a funny girl...
but I'm not sure they mean it
as a compliment.
I'm sorry.
Your village sounds terrible.
(SIGHS) Almost as lonely
as your castle.
What do you say we run away?
Another little gift
from the enchantress.
A book that truly allows you
to escape.
(BLOWS)
How amazing!
It was her cruelest trick of all.
It was just another curse.
The outside world has no place
for a creature like me...
but it can for you.
Think of the one place
you've always wanted to see.
Now find it in your mind's eye.
Then feel it in your heart.
Where did you take us?
Paris.
Oh, I love Paris.
What would you like to see first?
Notre Dame...
The Champs-Élysées...
No?
Too touristy?
It's so much smaller
than I imagined.
(SINGING)
♪ This is the Paris of my childhood ♪
♪ These were ♪
♪ the borders of my life ♪
♪ In this crumbling, dusty attic ♪
♪ Where an artist loved his wife ♪
♪ Easy to remember ♪
♪ Harder to move on ♪
♪ Knowing the Paris of my childhood ♪
♪ Is gone ♪
What happened to your mother?
It was the one story
Papa could never bring himself to tell.
I knew better than to ask.
Oh. A doctor's mask.
Plague.
(BABY CRYING)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
You must leave now.
BELLE'S MOTHER: Quickly...
before it takes her too.
(BABY BELLE CRYING)
I'm sorry I ever
called your father a thief.
(WHISPERS) Let's go home.
LEFOU:
This is some storm, huh?
At least
we're not tied to a tree
in the middle of nowhere...
surrounded by bloodthirsty wolves.
You know it's not too late.
We could always turn back...
It's just...
every time I close my eyes...
I picture Maurice stranded alone.
And then when I open them...
he's...
Maurice!
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
Gaston...
did you try to kill Maurice?
(ALL MURMURING)
Maurice!
Thank heavens!
I've spent the last five days...
- trying to find you.
- You tried to kill me.
You left me to the wolves.
GASTON: Wolves?
It's one thing to rave
about your delusions.
It's another to accuse me
of attempted murder.
JEAN: Maurice...
do you have any proof
of what you're saying?
Ask Agathe. She rescued me.
GASTON: (LAUGHING) Agathe!
You'd hang your accusations
on the testimony...
of a filthy hag?
No offense, Agathe.
Monsieur LeFou.
He was there. He saw it all.
Me?
You're right.
Don't take my word for it.
LeFou...
my dearest companion...
did I...
your oldest friend
and most loyal compatriot...
try to kill the father
of the only woman I've ever loved?
Well, it's a complicated question
on a number of accounts...
(GASPS)
But no.
- No, he did not.
- (PEOPLE MURMURING)
You...
- (GRUNTS)
- (PEOPLE GASP)
(MAURICE GROANS)
Maurice...
it pains me to say this,
but you've become a danger
to yourself and others.
No wonder Belle ran away.
You need help, sir.
A place to heal
your troubled mind.
Everything's going to be fine.
Just fine.
THE BEAST: Well, I saw her
in the ballroom...
and said, "You're making
everything look so beautiful."
"We should have
a dance tonight."
I never imagined
she'd actually say yes.
What was I thinking?
LUMIÈRE: No, Master.
It's perfect.
The rose has only four petals left
which means tonight...
you can tell her how you feel.
I feel like a fool.
She will never love me.
Do not be discouraged.
(SPITS)
She is the one.
I wish you'd stop saying that!
(SIGHS)
There is no "one."
You care for her, don't you?
Well, then,
woo her with beautiful music
and romantic candlelight.
Yes, and when
the moment's just right...
- (GIGGLES)
- Well, how will I know?
You will feel slightly nauseous.
Don't worry, Master.
You'll do fine.
MRS. POTTS:
Just stop being so nervous
and tell Belle how you feel.
Because if you don't...
I promise you'll be drinking cold tea
for the rest of your days!
- In the dark.
- Covered in dust.
- Dark and very, very dusty.
- (DINGS)
Start with the hair.
Women love nice hair!
I'll take
the fingers and toes.
Chapeau, brush those teeth.
They need it.
LUMIÈRE: Dip, dip.
Snip, snip.
Polish the nails.
Shine the horns.
PLUMETTE:
Eyes closed. Poof, poof.
LUMIÈRE:
And to top it all off...
Voilà!
Okay, I can fix this.
(SIGHS)
Oh! Beautiful!
But something is missing.
Oh, yes.
The finishing touch.
MRS. POTTS: (SINGING)
♪ Tale as old as time ♪
♪ True as it can be ♪
♪ Barely even friends ♪
♪ Then somebody ♪
♪ bends unexpectedly ♪
♪ Just a little change ♪
♪ Small to say the least ♪
♪ Both a little scared ♪
♪ Neither one prepared ♪
♪ Beauty and the Beast ♪
♪ Everjust the same ♪
♪ Ever a surprise ♪
♪ Ever as before ♪
♪ Everjust as sure ♪
♪ As the sun will rise ♪
♪ Tale as old as time ♪
♪ Tune as old as song ♪
♪ Bittersweet and strange ♪
♪ Finding you can change ♪
♪ Learning you were wrong ♪
♪ Certain as the sun ♪
♪ Rising in the east ♪
♪ Tale as old as time ♪
♪ Song as old as rhyme ♪
♪ Beauty and the Beast ♪
♪ Tale as old as time ♪
♪ Song as old as rhyme ♪
♪ Beauty and the Beast ♪
(SIGHS)
♪ I haven't danced in years. ♪
I'd almost forgotten the feeling.
(EXHALES)
It's foolish, I suppose...
for a creature like me to hope...
that one day he might earn
your affection.
I don't know.
Really?
You think
you could be happy here?
Can anybody be happy
if they aren't free?
My father taught me to dance.
I used to step on his toes a lot.
You must miss him.
Very much.
Would you like to see him?
I'd like to see my father.
(INAUDIBLE)
Papa!
What are they doing to him?
He's in trouble!
Then you must go to him.
What did you say?
You must go to him.
No time to waste.
(GASPS SOFTLY)
No...
you keep it with you.
Then you'll always have a way
to look back on me.
Thank you.
(EXHALES)
Oh...
(SIGHS)
Well, Master,
I have had my doubts,
but everything
is moving like clockwork.
True love really does win the day!
I let her go.
You what?
Master, how could you do that?
I had to.
But why?
Because he loves her.
Then why are we not human?
Because she doesn't love him.
And now, it's too late.
But she might still come back.
No.
I set her free.
I'm sorry I couldn't do
the same for all of you.
Now, go.
Our time is almost past.
- Come, my love.
- (SIGHS)
(SINGING)
♪ I was the one who had it all ♪
♪ I was the master of my fate ♪
♪ I never needed anybody in my life ♪
♪ I learned the truth too late ♪
♪ I'll never shake away the pain ♪
♪ I close my eyes ♪
♪ but she's still there ♪
♪ I let her steal ♪
♪ into my melancholy heart ♪
♪ It's more than I can bear ♪
♪ Now I know ♪
♪ she'll never leave me ♪
♪ Even as she runs away ♪
♪ She will still torment me ♪
♪ Calm me, hurt me ♪
♪ Move me, come what may ♪
♪ Wasting in my lonely tower ♪
♪ Waiting by an open door ♪
♪ I'll fool myself ♪
♪ she'll walk right in ♪
♪ And be with me for evermore ♪
♪ I rage against the trials of love ♪
♪ I curse the fading of the light ♪
♪ Though she's already flown ♪
♪ So far beyond my reach ♪
♪ She's never out of sight ♪
♪ Now I know ♪
♪ she'll never leave me ♪
♪ Even as she fades from view ♪
♪ She will still inspire me ♪
♪ Be a part of everything I do ♪
♪ Wasting in my lonely tower ♪
♪ Waiting by an open door ♪
♪ I'll fool myself ♪
♪ she'll walk right in ♪
♪ And as the long, long nights begin ♪
♪ I'll think of all that might have been ♪
♪ Waiting here for evermore ♪
This man is weak.
Please!
He needs a hospital...
not an asylum!
(GRUNTS)
Have you ever seen the inside
of a mad house, Maurice?
You wouldn't last a week.
Just give me your daughter's hand,
and I'll set you free.
Never.
Take him away!
(HORSE WHINNYING)
Stop!
Papa.
MAURICE: Oh, Belle.
I thought I'd lost you.
Let him out! He's hurt.
We can't do that, miss.
But we'll take
very good care of him.
My father's not crazy.
Gaston, tell him!
You know how loyal I am
to your family...
but your father's been making
some unbelievable claims.
It's true, Belle.
He's been raving about a beast...
in a castle!
I've just come from the castle
and there is a beast!
You'd say anything to set him free.
Your word is hardly proof.
You want proof?
Show me the Beast!
(ALL GASPING)
(ALL MURMURING)
There's your proof.
This is sorcery!
Look at this beast!
- Look at his fangs!
- (ALL EXCLAIM)
His claws!
No. Don't be afraid.
He's gentle and kind.
(ALL MURMURING)
The monster has her under his spell.
If I didn't know better,
I'd say she even cared for him!
He's not a monster, Gaston.
You are!
The Beast wouldn't hurt anyone.
I've heard of the effects
of dark magic...
but I've never before seen it
with my own eyes!
This is a threat
- to our very existence!
- (ALL AGREEING IN UNISON)
We can't have her
running off to warn the beast.
Lock her up too.
- No!
- TOM: Come here!
- (GRUNTS)
- Shut up!
BELLE: You won't get away
with this, Gaston!
- MAURICE: Oh, Belle!
- (PEOPLE MURMURING)
Gaston,
with all due respect...
Do you want to be next?
Fetch my horse.
Stand guard!
Don't let them escape.
This creature will curse us all
if we don't stop him.
(ALL AGREEING IN UNISON)
Well, I say,
we kill the beast!
ALL: Kill the beast!
(ALL AGREEING)
(SINGING)
♪ We're not safe until he's dead ♪
♪ He'll come stalking us at night ♪
♪ Set to sacrifice our children ♪
♪ To his monstrous appetite ♪
♪ He'll wreak havoc on our village ♪
♪ If we let him wander free ♪
♪ So it's time to take some action, boys ♪
♪ It's time to follow me ♪
(ALL SHOUTING)
♪ Through the mist, through the wood ♪
♪ Through the darkness and the shadows ♪
♪ It's a nightmare ♪
♪ But it's one exciting ride ♪
♪ Say a prayer, then we're there ♪
♪ At the drawbridge of a castle ♪
♪ And there's something ♪
♪ truly terrible inside ♪
♪ It's a beast ♪
♪ He's got fangs, razor sharp ones ♪
♪ Massive paws, ♪
♪ killer claws for the feast ♪
♪ Hear him roar, see him foam ♪
♪ But we're not coming home ♪
♪ 'Til he's dead ♪
♪ Good and dead ♪
ALL: ♪Kill the beast! ♪
♪ Light your torch, ♪
♪ mount your horse ♪
♪ Screw your courage ♪
♪ to the sticking place ♪
ALL: ♪We're counting
on Gaston to lead the way ♪
♪ Call it war, call it threat ♪
♪ You can bet they all will follow ♪
♪ For in times like this ♪
♪ They'll do just as I say ♪
♪ There's a beast running wild ♪
♪ There's no question ♪
♪ But I fear ♪
♪ the wrong monster's released ♪
ALL: ♪Sally forth, tally ho
Grab your sword, grab your bow ♪
♪ Praise the Lord, and here we go ♪
Show me the castle.
At least he has finally
learned to love.
A lot of good that does us
if she doesn't love him in return.
No. This is the first time
I've had any real hope she would.
- (HORSE WHINNYING IN DISTANCE)
- Did you hear that, Mama?
Is it her? Is she coming back?
LUMIÈRE: Could it be?
PLUMETTE: (GASPS) I told you!
Sacré bleu!
Invaders!
MRS. POTTS: Ruffians!
Well, there you go.
So much for true love.
Man the barricades...
and hold fast!
Move aside!
♪ (SINGING) Hearts ablaze, banners high ♪
♪ We go marching into battle ♪
♪ Unafraid, although ♪
♪ the danger's just increased ♪
MOB: ♪Raise the flag, sing the song
Here we come, we're fifty strong ♪
♪ And fifty Frenchmen can't be wrong ♪
♪ Let's kill the beast! ♪
(GRUNTING)
COGSWORTH: We need help.
- I have to warn the Beast.
- Warn him?
How did you get away from him?
He let me go, Papa.
He sent me back to you.
(STAMMERS) I don't understand.
Where did you...
He took me there.
I know what happened to Maman.
Then you know
why I had to leave her there.
I had to protect you.
I've always tried to protect
my little girl.
Probably too much.
I understand.
(KISSES)
Will you help me now?
It's dangerous.
Yes.
Yes, it is.
I could try to pick the lock.
After all...
it's only gears and springs.
But I would need...
something long and sharp.
Like that.
Perfect.
(PEOPLE SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
(PANTING)
Oh, excuse me, Master.
(STAMMERS)
I'm so sorry to disturb you.
She's not coming back.
No.
They're breaking down the doors!
Doesn't matter now.
Just let them come.
MOB: (SINGING) ♪Kill the beast!
Kill the beast! ♪
This isn't working!
I know what to do.
MOB: ♪Kill the beast!
Kill the beast! ♪
♪ Kill the beast! ♪
(PEOPLE GROANING)
Are you not
the least bit concerned...
that this castle might be haunted?
Don't lose your nerve, LeFou.
MAN: Where are we?
This place seems familiar.
Like I've been here before.
Oh, hello, there.
You must be the talking tea cup.
And you must be...
his grandmother.
(GASPS) Grandmother?
- Attack!
- (GASPS)
Oh, hello! (LAUGHS)
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
(MEN GROANING)
- (DINGING)
- (GROANING)
Gaston! (SCREAMS)
(GROANS)
Gaston.
Help.
Sorry, old friend.
It's hero time.
Ooh, ouch!
(EXHALES)
Hello.
Oh, uh...
I believe this is yours.
(PHILIPPE WHINNYING)
She's very headstrong.
Do you have children?
- (ALL SHOUTING)
- (GASPS)
PLUMETTE: No one
to protect you now, huh?
(PLUMETTE GIGGLING)
CHIP: One, two, three, four...
- five, six, seven, eight...
- (GROANING)
Good show, Chip, my boy.
(LAUGHS) Excellent!
- The infantry's arrived.
- (EXCLAIMS)
Now, go and teach them a lesson. Go.
Yes, those are called books,
you third rate musketeers.
Oh! I'm off.
(SCREAMS)
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
Just a clock.
(LAUGHS) Come here...
little boys.
I spin you this way.
I put it on.
- Yes, pretty little boys. Yes!
- (SCREAMING)
Beautiful!
Go, be free!
Be free. Be free!
(ALL SHOUTING)
(EXCLAIMS)
How do you like your tea?
- Piping hot?
- (ALL SCREAMING)
Or boiling?
Oh!
Mr. Potts!
(SCREAMING)
Mama!
Thank you!
(BOTH GRUNT)
- (BLOWS RASPBERRY)
- MRS. POTTS: Take that!
Nicely handled!
Well, I used to be
on Gaston's side...
but we are so
in a bad place right now.
- You're too good for him, anyway.
- Yeah.
Should we get back to it, then?
(MEN GRUNTING)
MAESTRO CADENZA: (LAUGHS)
Such sweet music.
- Stand back.
- Silence that harpsichord!
MAESTRO CADENZA: What? Uh-oh!
GARDEROBE: Maestro!
Darling! At last!
I'm coming, my love.
This is it!
The fat lady is singing.
(VOCALIZING)
(ALL SHOUTING)
Bravissima!
(ALL GROANING)
LUMIÈRE: (LAUGHS)
Watch your toes!
(ALL SCREAMING)
(LUMIÈRE LAUGHING)
LUMIÈRE: That's it! Go! Go!
- (VOCALIZING AND GIGGLING)
- LUMIÈRE: Bon voyage.
(ALL SCREAMING)
Safe trip home.
And stay out!
(ALL CLAMORING)
(MEN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
Hello, beast.
I'm Gaston.
Belle sent me.
Are you in love with her?
Did you honestly think
she'd want you?
(GROWLS)
(GROWLING)
Belle!
Where is he?
When we return to the village...
you will marry me.
And that beast's head...
- will hang on our wall.
- Never!
(GRUNTING)
- (YELLS)
- (BELLE GASPS)
GASTON:
I'm coming for you, beast.
(GRUNTING)
(GROWLING)
- No!
- Belle?
Belle!
You came back!
- I tried to stop them!
- THE BEAST: Stay there!
I'm coming.
(GROWLING)
(GRUNTS)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
Gaston!
- No!
- (GROWLS)
(GASPS)
Don't let me go.
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
Please.
I'll do anything.
Don't hurt me, beast.
I am not...
a beast.
- (GROWLS)
- (GRUNTS)
Go!
Get out!
Don't!
It's too far!
(GROWLING)
- (GUNSHOT)
- (ROARS)
BELLE: Please!
Come on.
(ROARS)
(WHIMPERS)
(SCREAMING)
(THE BEAST BREATHING HEAVILY)
You came back.
Of course I came back.
I'll never leave you again.
I'm afraid
it's my turn to leave.
We're together now.
It's gonna be fine.
At least I got to see you.
One last time.
(BREATHES SHAKILY)
No!
Please, no.
(SOBBING)
Come back.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
LUMIÈRE: We did it, Plumette!
Victory is ours.
- Oh...
- Plumette?
Plumette?
Oh, my darling, Plumette.
Oh, no.
GARDEROBE:
Maestro, you were so brave.
Goodbye, my love.
MAESTRO CADENZA: Amore.
No! Don't leave me!
(CRYING)
(WHIMPERING)
MRS. POTTS: Chip!
Chip!
Have you seen Chip?
He ran off.
(CRYING)
Where is my little boy?
- CHIP: Mama!
- Oh, no!
Mom!
Lumière...
(STAMMERS) I can't...
speak.
It's all right, Cogsworth.
I can't...
Lumière...
my friend.
It was an honor to serve...
with you.
The honor was mine.
(BELLE SOBBING)
Come back.
Please don't leave me.
I love you.
(GASPING)
(CHUCKLES)
(RUMBLING)
(BARKS)
Oh. Maestro!
(GASPS AND COUGHS)
MAESTRO CADENZA: Madame!
Maestro! (LAUGHING)
(GASPS) Ooh.
- Lumière!
- Ah?
Cogsworth, we beat the clock!
- (LAUGHS)
- Mon ami!
LUMIÈRE: Plumette!
Plumette!
Oh. Mon amour.
Oh.
(PLUMETTE MOANS)
- (GASPS)
- Oh. Oh.
(BOTH WHOOPING)
(BOTH SHOUTING)
Chip! Look at you!
You're a little boy again!
What did I tell you, darling?
You smell so good!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(ALL TALKING EXCITEDLY)
MAESTRO CADENZA:
Froufrou, finalmente!
Darling?
Oh! Mr. Potts!
Beatrice! I remember!
I do!
CLOTHILDE: Henry?
Henry!
Oh! Oh, dear.
Oh!
I've been so lonely.
Turn back into a clock.
Lumière, look!
Oh, my Prince!
Hello, old friend.
Oh! It's so good to see you.
You saved our lives, mademoiselle.
CHIP: Belle! It's me!
It's Chip!
♪ (SINGING) ♪
♪ Tale as old as time ♪
♪ Tune as old as song ♪
♪ Bittersweet and strange ♪
♪ Finding you can change ♪
♪ Learning you were wrong ♪
(LAUGHS)
MRS. POTTS:
♪ Winter turns to spring ♪
♪ Famine turns to feast ♪
♪ Nature points the way ♪
♪ Nothing left to say ♪
♪ Beauty and the Beast ♪
♪ What? What is it? ♪
♪ How would you feel ♪
♪ about growing a beard? ♪
- (GROWLS)
- (BOTH CHUCKLE)
♪ GARDEROBE AND CHORUS: ♪
♪ Certain as the sun ♪
♪ Rising in the east ♪
♪ Tale as old as time ♪
♪ Song as old as rhyme ♪
♪ Beauty and the Beast ♪
♪ Tale as old as time ♪
♪ Song as old as rhyme ♪
♪ Beauty and the Beast ♪
♪ WOMAN: (SINGING) ♪
♪ How does a moment last forever? ♪
♪ How can a story never die? ♪
♪ It is love we must hold on to ♪
♪ Never easy but we try ♪
♪ Sometimes our happiness is captured ♪
♪ Somehow a time ♪
♪ and place stand still ♪
♪ Love lives on inside our hearts ♪
♪ And always will ♪
♪ Minutes turn to hours ♪
♪ Days to years then gone ♪
♪ But when all else has been forgotten ♪
♪ Still our song lives on ♪
♪ Maybe some moments ♪
♪ weren't so perfect ♪
♪ Maybe some memories not so sweet ♪
♪ But we have to know some bad times ♪
♪ Or our lives are incomplete ♪
♪ Then when shadows overtake us ♪
♪ Just when we feel all hope is gone ♪
♪ We'll hear our song ♪
♪ and know once more ♪
♪ Our love lives on ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ How does a moment last forever? ♪
♪ How does our happiness endure? ♪
♪ Through the darkest of our troubles ♪
♪ Love is beauty, love is pure ♪
♪ Love pays no mind to desolation ♪
♪ It flows like a river through the soul ♪
♪ Protects, proceeds, and perseveres ♪
♪ And makes us whole ♪
♪ Minutes turn to hours ♪
♪ Days to years then gone ♪
♪ But when all else has been forgotten ♪
♪ Still our song lives on ♪
♪ How does a moment last forever ♪
♪ When our song lives on ♪
♪ WOMAN: (SINGING) ♪
♪ Ah ♪
♪ Tale as old as time ♪
♪ True as it can be ♪
♪ Barely even friends ♪
♪ Then somebody bends unexpectedly ♪
♪ MAN: ♪
♪ Just a little change ♪
♪ Small to say the least ♪
♪ Both a little scared ♪
♪ Neither one prepared ♪
♪ BOTH: ♪
♪ Beauty and the Beast ♪
♪ Everjust the same ♪
♪ Ever a surprise ♪
♪ Ever as before ♪
♪ And ever just as sure ♪
♪ As the sun will rise ♪
♪ MAN: Oh ♪
♪ WOMAN: Hey ♪
♪ Ah ♪
♪ MAN: Ooh ♪
♪ BOTH: Uh-huh ♪
♪ Everjust the same ♪
♪ And ever a surprise ♪
♪ Ever as before ♪
♪ And ever just as sure ♪
♪ As the sun will rise ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ WOMAN: ♪
♪ Tale as old as time ♪
♪ Tune as old as song ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ BOTH: ♪
♪ Bittersweet and strange ♪
♪ Finding you can change ♪
♪ Learning you were wrong ♪
♪ MAN: Certain as the sun ♪
♪ WOMAN: Certain as the sun ♪
♪ MAN: Rising in the east ♪
♪ WOMAN: Tale as old as time ♪
♪ MAN: Song as old as rhyme ♪
♪ BOTH: Beauty and the Beast ♪
♪ WOMAN: Tale as old as time ♪
♪ MAN: Song as old as rhyme ♪
♪ BOTH: Beauty and the Beast ♪
♪ MAN: (SINGING) ♪
♪ I was the one who had it all ♪
♪ I was the master of my fate ♪
♪ I never needed anybody in my life ♪
♪ I learned the truth too late ♪
♪ I'll never shake away the pain ♪
♪ I close my eyes but she's still there ♪
♪ I let her steal into
my melancholy heart ♪
♪ It's more than I can bear ♪
♪ Now I know ♪
♪ she'll never leave me ♪
♪ Even as she runs away ♪
♪ She will still torment me ♪
♪ Calm me, hurt me ♪
♪ Move me, come what may ♪
♪ Wasting in my lonely tower ♪
♪ Waiting by an open door ♪
♪ I'll fool myself ♪
♪ she'll walk right in ♪
♪ And be with me for evermore ♪
♪ I rage against the trials of love ♪
♪ I curse the fading of the light ♪
♪ Though she's already flown ♪
♪ So far beyond my reach ♪
♪ She's never out of sight ♪
♪ Now I know she'll never leave me ♪
♪ Even as she fades from view ♪
♪ She will still inspire me ♪
♪ Be a part of everything I do ♪
♪ Wasting in my lonely tower ♪
♪ Waiting by an open door ♪
♪ I'll fool myself she'll walk right in ♪
♪ And as the long, long nights begin ♪
♪ I'll think of all that might have been ♪
♪ Waiting here for evermore ♪