Vishal Kapoor has
just now retired hurt
The ball has hit him hard
at a sensitive spot.
Since then two batsman have been
declared out in three overs.
Now the last batsman
is taking his place.
Will Kapoor be able to recover
and win this match for KKR?
KKR requires
only 10 runs to win the match.
And the last over begins now.
You cannot go inside.
All of you just stand here, and watch.
It's paining.
I will not be able to play.
Relax, Kapoor.
Mayekar, why are you
stalking me like a witch?
Hold on to his back.
Mili, we need to confirm
the Sambhalgarh case today.
Will you go?
- Where? What about me?
Don't be such a sissy, Kapoor?
You're absolutely fine now.
Look, this is the third
time I cancelled my honeymoon.
I've been married for 6 months.
My wife will leave me.
The |PL's over now..
..and there's no guy
in your life either.
Please go, please.
Don't take advantage of
my situation, Mayekar.
And what about my patients?
Is the pain any better?
- No.
Wait. Hold on to his back.
I'll handle all your patients,
I'll look after them.
I swear.
He's done for.
What are you doing Mili?
The pain has gone.
Now go,
blast them out of the ground.
Be careful.
Go for it.
Come on, come on!
You still use strange methods.
And you keep them at bay.
Only when required.
That's exactly why you're a
perfect fit for that king.
Please, please, please go.
- Okay, done.
I am saving your marriage.
Thank you so much.
Thank you. Thank you.
And Kapoor hits a Six!
He has won the match.
Patience, Yuvraj.
Suraj Maan Singh won't
sell his palace so easily.
We've been trying for three months.
He refuses to meet.
As your lawyer in this case,
and in this deal..
“My advice is that your trip
to Mumbai is a waste of time.
Take my advice,
return to Sambhalpur.
We'll bring him to you.
Thank you very much,
Mr. Malhotra, for your advice.
You've been making me
wait for three months.
But I feel there's
no point in waiting.
It's clear that our views..
..on this case are
completely different.
Maybe our paths should
be separate as well.
Excuse me, Yuvraj.
- Ah, Karishma.
Your seafs been confirmed..
..with King Suraj Maan Singh.
- Oh, wonderful.
Thank you so much.
Yuvraj, what are you doing?
Mr. Malhotra, what are
you still doing here?
Don't think, move ahead.
Excuse me.
- Yes, mom.
You couldn't meet up with
Suraj Maan Singh, could you?
He won't agree so easily.
By the way, interesting news.
Dr. Shaw; has arranged".
..a new Physiotherapist
for your dad.
Have you told dad?
I haven't told him yet.
But he's going to have to do it.
Okay, I will be back by tomorrow.
Okay, son. See you tomorrow.
All the best.
I apologize, your highness.
Do it propefW-
I'll do it right now.
Your highness.
- Ramsevak.
Jaidev can't handle
the chores in here.
From tomorrow he will
clean the cars outside.
Okay.
Your highness!
Hello, Shekhar.
Had a good day?
Well, I had it as good
as others, I suppose.
Yuvraj isn't coming today.
His plate..
And Divya's late again.
If she isn't here in three minutes.
..you can remove her plate.
Divya! Hair!
Sorry, Mom.
Hello, Dad.
- Hello, clear.
Discipline is not
a bad thing, Divya.
Yuvra1 Vikram Singh Remote.
Sir.
I suppose it's not a coincidence..
..that you're sitting here.
No, sir.
So you believe, that.
...I will sell my 600
year old ancestral palace..
..in this 50 minutes flight.
That you'll trap me
here and get your deal.
You're stuck somewhere else, sir.
Our offer is saving you.
Look, sir.
We don't need to talk here..
..if you confirm our
meeting for next week.
Excuse me, sir.
Black coffee for him,
with 1 spoon sugar.
And black tea without sugar for me.
Sure, sir.
By the way Shekhar,
Dr. Shetty called.
Your new physiotherapist,
Dr. Chakravany's arriving day after.
What's the score, Ramsevak?
40? 42?
I've no clue, your highness.
I know, Shekhar,
no one has stayed that long.
Maybe she won't either.
But for once, if you just try..
...then maybe we could..
- I never called..
..or drove anyone away.
And what's the point
in getting well?
No one listens to me anyway.
Coffee for me.
What did you say her name was?
Dr. Chakravany.
Dr. Mrinalini Chakravany.
She's a sports physiotherapist.
She works with the IPL teams.
She's from Delhi.
I hope she's from South Delhi.
Lord, you know everything.
No need to be formal with You.
All I want is Mili to find a guy..
..then I'll setup a
tent in her wedding..
...and throw a thank you party.
And if he's from
Sambhalgarws royal family“.
..then that's even better.
So Lord,
don't ever pay any heed to her.
Especially her last line.
You keep quite. Stan eating.
Ashrafi, you're too good!
The chicken's too good.
Should we do September then?
Plan for that?
September sounds fine.
Your planners are
arriving next week.
Rathore?
You're in Mumbai
and you didn't call.
But, how can anyone
compete with you?
Nausher.
Nausher Bandookwala.
He's been with me
since the 5th grade.
Nausher, this is my fiancé Kiara.
- Congratulations.
And my sympathies, Kiara.
You're marrying a business machine.
Bandook!
- Rathore's a failure.
Just grab hold of him and marry him.
Otherwise, he'll be a
spinster like my father.
No, seriously.
I am my father's only mistake.
- You're right.
But seriously Rathore,
what will you do if she runs away?
I mean...you have your business.
But alone and lonely at
75...that's a tough life.
My, God. You're so beautiful.
You're really pretty.
She's so beautiful.
Beautiful. Beautiful.
Catch you guys, soon.
Remote, ca“ me.
Call your old friends.
- Okay.
He's sweet.
That he is.
Where were we?
Wedding in September.
Mr. Sharma's son
has become an actor.
Manju, please don't start this again.
- Why not?
I mean...this isn't natural.
It's been two years,
forget about a husband..
..you don't even have a boyfriend!
You are famous now.
You fixed Dhoni's injury in the
middle of the match..
..and helped him win.
You work for the IPL.
Granted Dhoni, Sehwag, etc. are
elderly and married.
But you cou|d've been in the news
with some young player at least.
Manju, keep your
one-track mind to yourself.
Seriously, Manju.
You're just too much.
She's happy, isn't she?
You see, Mili scares off the boys.
And they run away.
Maybe you like girls.
Oh please! Shut you mouth.
Like girl, huh!
This time...if not an Indian
cricketer, then Indian royalty!
And if you don't like any of them..
...then you can marry
some boring doctor of CA.
I won't attend that marriage.
Manju, he's as old as dad.
And you know...l am not
interested in boys right now.
And no one stays.
Mili, after meeting Shaina..
...I felt like I met my soul mate.
And there's nothing
common between us.
Forget it, Mili.
You can never control your mouth.
And you will never change.
Mili, don't you understand
the meaning of being formal?
Keep your feet down.
Isn't this formal?
It's not my fault.
You shouldn't take
old breakups to head...
And in any case,
those idiots weren't good for you.
It was just bad luck, dear.
Fate changes in even] 2 years.
And you just came
out of a bad phase.
So you can add 2 years
for even] silly boyfriend.
Now it's only going
to be good luck, dear.
Manju, you're just too much?
Just listen to me Manju..
..this King is old and married.
And I don't want to get married.
I am fine single.
Now say hi to Sumati.
Hi.
Are you happy now?
Did you get the recipe
for the pickles?
No Manju, I am riding in a Ferrari.
Like I said,
there's a transport strike.
I took the wrong flight.
..and arrived a day earlier.
That's why..
Oh!
Oh my God!
Oh...
Manju will go crazy.
I'll have to take a picture.
I no longer have the charisma,
nor do you.
Even you're growing
old in my company.
Absolutely wrong.
A man grows old in
his mind, not his body.
Oh! flowers!
And you are?
Dr. Mili Chakravany.
Ahh, Dr. Chakravany.
The 40th physiotherapist.
- May I?
What on earth are you doing?
Get away from my feet.
30"‘!-
Take her to Ramsevak.
Come, madam.
- Good day.
Please take a seat,
her highness will be here shortly.
Cool.
WOW!
Hi, Dr. Mili Chakravany.
Ramsevak!
Careful.
Let go. Leave it.
Thank you.
Oh, God.
Oh God, it's so heavy.
How on earth did anyone wear this?
It's been in our
family for 400 years.
That old.
Don't you have
junk-sellers in Sambhalgarh?
Bad joke.
How beautiful.
Are those real pearls?
Of course they are real pearls.
Ramsevak, please show
Dr. Chakravany her room.
She must be tired.
- I am..
Dinner is at 8.
See you there.
Aunty.
You can call me your highness.
Your highness, your heels
are too high for your age.
You can wear slippers at home.
Even oﬂhotic slippers
might be good for you.
Otherwise you can suffer
from plantar fasciitis.
Ramsevak. Excuse me please.
See you.
'Great start Mili .'
Thank you, Ramsevak.
I request to take your leave, madam.
Just Mili.
Cool.
Awesome.
I request.
30"‘!-
Sorry, I am late.
Hi, Ramsevak.
Hi, Queen. Hi, King.
Thank you.
Hi, I am Mili.
- Divya.
Nice to meet you.
'Oh no!'
Sorry!
Chicken. Thanks.
You people are quite formal.
We Punjabis are quite cool,
you know.
I mean there's no place for
formality on the dining table.
I thought you're Bengali?
No, I am a Punjabi.
Actually. . .Nlanju's a Punjabi. .
..and we've all taken
after her, even dad.
Manju is your sister?
No, Manju is my mother.
It's my mother!
I'll keep it in my pocket.
So do you have a boyfriend?
No. I don't have a boyfriend.
Are you serious?
When I was your age, I had two.
But I was a bit confused.
Divya is preparing for Oxford.
And, Dr. Chakravany,
we don't talk while eating.
30"‘!-
Actually, I thought you all
must be so busy the whole day..
..that, dinner must be the
only time you get to talk.
So I thought even l..
Dr. Chakravany.
Ramsevak, please tell
her the rest of the rules.
Chicken's a bit undercooked.
How will the patient get better
in this atmosphere?
But something needs to be done.
Chocolate!
Load shedding here too?
'A thief in my room.'
Thief!
'Good looking thief!'
'How do I hit her?'
Who are you?
- Who are you?
I am from Delhi.
If you try to flirt with me,
I'll teach you a lesson.
This is my room and keep that down.
'This is my. .'
Oh..
This isn't my room.
But who are you?
Vikram Singh Remote.
King Shekhar Singh's son.
Oh, prince.
You're a prince?
Who are you?
- Mili.
Mili Chakravany.
Dr. Mili Chakravany.
I am the physiotherapist...
of, King Shekhar Singh Rathore.
Ahh...the doctor.
Your room's the other one.
You don't look like a prince at all.
'Shut up Mili, shut up!
Why do you talk so much.'
Why? Should it be seen on my face.
Flirting with a girl who is asleep..
..those aren't the
manners of a prince.
And getting in
someone's bed at midnight.
..and kicking him, that's
more like a doctor, isn't it?
Revenge!
Well, that's okay. Scores settled.
Oh, girlfriend.
Doctor, its midnight
and I want to sleep.
Please, go.
She's pretty.
'Snob.'
So what do I call you?
Prince. Junior majesty, Viku.
Viku is nice.
Doctor.
- Yes.
Can you go to your room, please?
Good night prince Viku.
- Good night.
Chocolate!
- Doctor!
'Definitely a snob.'
'Trouble.'
This is good.
There's sensation in your legs.
Come on, let's exercise now.
That's all for the day.
I am not interested in exercising.
Sambhalgarh is a beautiful place.
So take a look around..
..and go back home after a few days.
Delhi isn't a bad place
either for sightseeing.
And if I wanted to have fun..
...I would've never come to
this curfew-stricken place.
Come on! Let's exercise.
I never do anything against my will.
'Even the King is a snob.'
Ramsevak, please call his will..
..because he never does anything
that goes against his will.
Ramsevak.
Excuse me, please.
Thank you.
'Doesn't he want to get better?'
'Majesty's will'
Do as you please,
I'll leave too.
What do I do?
Looks better now.
Three hour session in one hour.
It's alright, Mili.
These kings were always lazy.
Don't give up.
Maybe he'll get interested
after seeing your interest.
Listen to me, Gautam.
I love you.
L...l can change for you
completely, Gautam.
Divya, he's not worth it.
He's really not worth it.
If that silly Gautam loves you“.
..then let him change himself.
Give me the phone!
I'll talk to him.
Everything will be cleared now.
Give me the phone!
"Love is a Game."
“Gautam: No, no. l..
Oh...so you want to act?
But please don't tell anyone.
I have to focus only on my studies.
But you can do both.
- Mother will never understand.
Then talk to Vikram?
Vikram's always busy.
If it doesn't concern his business..
..then he doesn't have time for it.
Shall I rehearse
this scene with you?
I have a lot of free time.
Remove, mark my word.
Kiara will leave you and come to me.
Of course, we can't invite you
to the wedding.
But we'll send you the pictures.
Rathore, hello?
- What?
Nothing.
It's dad's new physiotherapist.
New physiotherapist?
Checking her out!
Even I want to.
This girl is trouble.
Doctor!
Hold on, Viku, almost done.
It's best you don't do
these things in these clothes.
Why?
You don't have any
dearth of free time.
You can do it during day.
I have free time because
the patient isn't willing.
Don't be sad.
And what do you care?
If they don't value you,
then come back.
Just ignore these kings.
They act so high and mighty.
Everyone is strange in this family.
They never talk to each other.
And her highness!
Every time she sees me it's as though
she wants to take a bite at me.
Hold on.
Ask that prince
to talk to his father?
He's their only son.
He'll explain his father.
Manju, he's a big bore.
Prince Vikram Singh Remote.
Careful, doctor.
- Yes.
I just need one book...
Sorry!
After the 1st World War,
the plane was given to him.
I really don't
understand how they managed.
..to get it into a room this..
What are you doing?
You can't sit on that.
Sorry. It was for my Facebook.
Dr. Chakravany,
your first session..
..is from 10 to 1, right?
- Yes.
I suggest you focus on that.
Visiting time for
tourists is from 5 to 7.
You can join them.
- Right, aunty.
I mean.. your highness.
Actually, I wanted to talk to you.
Shekhar uncle doesn't
want to exercise.
I feel he doesn't want to get well.
Doctor. Please.
Either you can help
Shekhar or you can't.
If you can't help him..
..then your tickets
to go back will be arranged.
Now, please excuse me.
Come in.
Hi, Viku.
Sorry!
Trouble is here.
Are you checking me out?
That's fine. There must not
be much to look at around here.
I couldn't stop myself.
You may?
Look, Viku, there's still
sensation in your dad's legs.
This is a big thing.
There is a lot of
scope for improvement.
'There is scope of
improvement here also'
I don't think anyone has
motivated him to exercise.
And he doesn't want to get
better himself, you know.
And everyone here is
busy with either business..
..or rules and regulations.
'Please hurry up I've to go.'
You can't just wash your hands off..
..from your responsibility
by calling a doctor from Delhi.
You have to be
slightly involved, partner.
Doctor...
'I don't know why
I keep calling that.'
you won't understand
our lifestyle.
And anyway,
why would he listen to me?
You are the doctor.
But you're his son.
When Manju drifts
a little offtrack..
“Only I can bring her back.
Take advantage
of being his only son.
Use your power.
Look, if you are
incapable of handling this..
..then you may please leave.
I'll arrange for someone else.
I wonder what the
problem with everyone here is?
Whenever I tn/ to talk to someone.
..they all wriggle
their way out of it.
That's why 40 doctors
have left before.
And as for me,
I've treated Sehwag and Kapoor.
When I feel that I can't handle it,
then I'll leave.
Sorry!
I don't think I can have
any influence on him..
...but, I will still try.. Alright?
Really?
Thanks, Viku.
Doctor!
Ramsevak, what's going on?
It's a small little party.
Prem Singh's son got
admitted to an MBA program.
Party!
Take a seat.
Move aside.
This is my glass, okay!
What's his son's name?
Krishna.
To Krishna!
Krishna!
One more.
This is how you party!
Ramu uncle,
I am going back to Delhi.
So soon?
My father was right.
Never spend more than
15 minutes with your patient.
They don't respect you.
Come, tell me your problem.
Take your prescription,
pay your fee and go.
They're treating me like
a live-in son-in-law here.
Shekhar uncle is a good man,
you know.
Had he come to my home..
..| would've cured him in 10 days.
Have you seen the ambience here?
Forget him..
no one can get better here.
His Majesty is filled with regret.
What?
He lost his elder
son in that accident.
Amber.
He was just 20 years old.
His Majesty had gifted
him a sports car.
Both father and son
went out for a drive.
Ambar was driving too fast.
He didn't survive the accident.
His Majesty was in coma for
6 months after the accident.
Her highness handled everything.
Since then she changed drastically.
Everyone was so happy.
The King and Queen would play polo.
Party every daY-
Everything is ruined, Mili.
Good morning, Papa.
Oh!
Son, where did the
sun rise from today?
May I come in?
- Of course.
How are you?
Fine. Absolutely fine.
Good, thank you.
I see.
Is your cigar stock okay?
It's okay.
Good.
Papa!
Your doctor,
Dr. Mili Chakravany.
She was saying that.
..you aren't focusing
on your exercise.
I see. So now she's got to you.
I think it's time to drive her away.
Yes.
No!
If you don't want
to exercise, then..
..it's quite alright,
it's your wish.
There's no point in trying, is it?
Right.
I'll take your leave,
I have a meeting.
Of course.
Go. Wish you all the best.
Nice catching up with you.
He is here.
Dr. Chakravany, I guess it's
time to drive you out of here.
I was thinking the same thing.
- What?
Together we should drive
Dr. Chakravany out of here.
What?
She's completely useless.
Now I am just Mili.
And I was wondering,
now that I am here..
...I should enjoy the
royal life for a few days.
A common man doesn't
get such opportunities.
Right, Ramu uncle?
Teach me something about wine!
You really won't make me exercise?
Not at all.
What if Nirmala finds out?
Other than you and me,
only Ramu uncle knows about it.
Yes, Ramu uncle is our old butler.
Right, Ramu . .uncle?
Master.
Cheers.
Divya is so cute.
What's this!
What are you doing to the Queen?
There was a time..
...when I was an expert
in “sticking my leg“.
The famous "tang adana"
This is my favorite
photo of you two.
Taken by that American, right?
He should be thankful...
..that he wasn't killed
after taking this photo.
I was so angry.
And your father,
he was laughing like crazy.
Later he bought it.
Framed it and presented it
to me on our anniversary.
Well, at least this
way we could capture..
..your famous "tang adana" moment.
That time is gone,
and so are my legs.
That's no problem.
We'll bring that time back.
What's this?
Tennis.
Press A and serve.
What!
Serve!
Point!
Iwin.
Ready!
Turn!
Bravo tiger!
Rinsing your mouth with wine!
I'm seeing this for the first time.
Now I understand where
dad's wine collection is going.
You scared me.
And Shekhar uncle gifted
this to me personally.
Actually, it's a bribe..
..so I don't make him exercise.
Come, sit down.
Feel at home.
'The snob is looking handsome.'
Drink this.
Cheers!
Doctor.
Mili.
I saw dad happy after a long time.
Prince, just wait and
watch what happens next.
'VVhat now?'
- 'VVhat now?'
So...how's your fiancé?
Kiara, right?
She is fine.
Can I ask you something?
Were you a frog
before you kissed Kiara..
...Ol" are YOU one now?
Think. Think.
You have kissed Kiara, right?
And...your boyfriend?
No. I am completely off men.
They can't handle my
spontaneous personality.
They say "Don't do this,
don't do that"..
"Don't dress like that"..
- Don't sit like that.
Yeah . Sorry!
Anyway,
all that sobbing and crying“.
...heart-breaking after 'The End'.
Can't handle it.
So... are you going to party
in the kitchen again today?
You saw?
Why didn't you come inside then?
It was really fun.
Oh! 'VVe Kings don't
party with our subjects.'
Something like that.
It's the opposite, actually.
It troubles them, and..
..we don't have time for all this.
That's what Divya
was saying as well.
S he's very sweet.
Does she want to go to Oxford..
..or is it because of your mother?
Mother's decisions for
Divya are absolutely right.
And what about what Divya's wants?
Someone should ask
her what she wants.
Mili, this is the Rathore family.
Discipline is everything .
Divya is a Rathore as well..
..and she will do
what's right for her.
And someone else will
decide what's right for her.!
May God bless you with some sense.
You know, you should..
I had to Skype Manju.
Okay, bye!
Mili.
I want to run away from home.
What?
You will pass your exams, cheer up!
I know how, let's get you
an interesting hair color.
Actually no,
her highness will kill me.
We can at least change
your nail polish.
Black or purple?
It's not that. I want to act.
This time won't come back.
True.
But running away!
Study.
I am going to send this doctor back.
Is she even a doctor?
She's always jumping
around or chatting.
She keeps talking to Divya.
Doesn't let her study.
Always interferes in everything.
But dad looks really happy.
That's exactly why I
haven't sent her back yet.
What are you doing?
Are you ready for the ride of your life?
- Oh my, God!
Move away! Move away!
So fast.
He'll fall.
Like Formula 1...
I really had fun today.
Life can still be fun,
Shekhar uncle..
..but you just don't allow yourself.
Shekhar uncle,
I know what happened 10 years ago.
It's not your fault.
Ambar... It was destiny.
It wasn't your fault.
You're still holding
on to that incident.
Let it go.
Otherwise moving ahead
will be really difficult.
Dr. Chakravany, we have never
mentioned that incident.
..for 10 years, so what
made you bring it up?
He's my patient, your highness.
Half his problem is his guilt.
If he can face it, then there's
a lot of scope for improvement.
Maybe...he can walk again.
No need to give Shekhar
false expectations, doctor.
We left no stone
unturned in his care.
And we never will.
I am his doctor, your highness.
I cannot lose hope of
him getting better again.
You're not convinced,
I understand.
But as long as I am here,
I'll do the best I can.
Ca“ Dr. sham.
Mom!
- Give me the phone!
Calm, Mili. Calm down.
Ram Sevak.
Why would I call
if it wasn't urgent?
He's out of town.
When is he coming back?
Shekhar uncle, wait.
Three weeks“!
Oh, come on.
Mili. Mili.
Move, Ramu uncle,
I want to talk to my patient.
You can't run, so
you'll have to listen to me.
Maybe I am just another
doctor for you..
..but for me, my
patients are not just my job.
If you're stubborn, then so am I.
What does this mean that you
don't want to get well?
If you don't want to get well,
then why call me?
Look... you have another son,
and a daughter.
At least try for their sake.
I understand that the Queen is
not an easy woman to live with.
But what else can the poor woman do?
She has to handle everything“.
..and you're having an
affair with this chair.
You're living with a 10 year
old stow, your Majesty!
As long as I am here,
I'll wait for you until 11 o'clock.
Final?
Now you may 9°-
She is right, dad.
If brother Ambar was alive..
..he too would've
said the same thing.
I think I said too much!
No, no, you did the right thing.
These people never
talk to each other.
Anyway, forget it.
What's done is done.
So, tell me..what's happening?
- You tell me!
How's junior Rathore?
He is a royal bore.
Actually...he's a little sweet too.
I called him a frog.
He'll have a change of head,
note it.
Manju, you have a one-track mind.
Have fun, bye.
- Bye.
The horse moves two and half steps.
Check...
...and mate.
Yes!
67...
68...
69...
Enough!
- Nonsense.
You've been doing 120
for the last two days.
You'll have to do 150 today.
Good morning, papa.
Good morning
Hi, Viku.
Look, my son's here.
Let me go now.
Viku, you can use his eyes,
ears, nose anything.
..but his legs won't stop.
Dad, I am off to
meet Suraj Maan Singh.
Surajgarh Palace.
Do me a favor, take her along.
But your exercise
will be left incomplete.
I'll complete it with Ramsevak.
- Promise?
Absolutely.
I'll go change.
But, dad,
I am going for a meeting.
Take her along, son.
You can do your work..
..and she'll take a
look around Surajgarh.
And these old legs
will get a day's rest.
Take care. Have fun.
Ramsevak, bring my wine.
It's a day off.
So, Viku, why are we
meeting Suraj Maan Singh?
Not we, I am meeting him.
'VVhy did I get her!'
That's what I said.
Fine, why are you
meeting Suraj Maan Singh?
'Patience Vikram'.
Because I want to buy Surajgarh..
..and he doesn't want to sell.
Why will he sell it? It's his call.
'Put your feet down.'
Because he can't afford it.
And I will build a hotel there.
Only if he sells it?
Would you...wou|d you please
put your feet down?
Sorry!
Ucrazy !u
'Snob!'
Doctor, please control
yourself a little.
Call me Dr. control, Viku.
Damn missed.
Now this will be
one high powered meeting.
Your Highness.
Welcome, Prince.
This is Dr. Mili,
dad's physiotherapist.
And he's Suraj Maan Singh.
- Hi.
Your house is really beautiful.
My family's been looking
after it for 600 years.
Prince, come shoot.
Or has business
turned you into a sutler.
Pull!
Veeru!
Doctor.
Would you like to shoot too?
- No, she's against violence.
Of course. I love 'Sho|ay'.
Oh, God!
on my»
May I...
Thanks.
Put the gun butt on your shoulder.
- Okay.
Hands over there.
Pull!
Thanks, Veeru.
That's so cool.
Is something going
on between you two?
No.
- No. No.
At least there's nothing on my end.
I don't know about him.
Doctor. You're very beautiful.
Thank you.
Come, I'll show you Surajgarh.
Sure.
- Shall we finish the meeting first?
Prince...what would you choose..
..between a beautiful
doctor and a business deal?
I will wait.
Does this Prince trouble you?
He is a snob, but he is not so bad.
I heard, once there were
300 queens living here.
Not Queens, their keeps.
That King is very intelligent.
So he is.
He called me for a meeting,
but avoided it altogether.
He said I am very beautiful.
And if you begin to like me,
then I shouldn't reciprocate.
'She is beautiful indeed'
But please, don't get
restless worrying about it.
'Snob'
Can I ask you something?
You could be a little sensitive,
he's selling his home.
It's not easy.
I know. But he dug his own grave.
People make mistakes,
haven't you ever made one?
'She..'
I try not to.
'S nob S ingh Rathore'
Why are we stopping here?
Come, I'll treat you to
the best tea in this area.
Cool.
Greetings Sir, please sit.
Daulatji.
- Yes.
Bring us two cups of tea.
'Raja Da Dhaba.' (Raja's eatery)
'The snob could be normal also'
'Beautiful eyelashes'
What now?
You can be normal,
and you're quite popular as well.
Here you go.
Thank you.
I have a meeting in Sambhalgarh.
It'll take half hour.
So you can take a look
around in the market.
Good idea!
I want to buy earrings for Manju.
And...the silver here is
very famous, isn't it?
Right.
See you in half an hour, okay!
- I'll pick you up from here.
Bye, Princey.
'Acting audition'
Hello.
Actually,
Mister I will be back later.
She is not picking up.
'Maybe I should give a try'
Mister, where's Ganga Theatre?
Straight ahead.
Thank you!
Welcome, Madam. Welcome!
Madam, Hollywood's come to India.
Careful!
Come.
Hi!
~ Hi!
Mili Chakravany, Physiotherapist.
I have a friend who..
- Madam.
Yes. - Will you shift a
little to the right, please?
Okay?
Serve her a cold drink,
she must be thirsty.
Give it.
I have a friend,
she's a good actor.
Thank you!
- Welcome!
Drink it.
Actually, even I like acting.
But my friend..
- Madam, in a while.
First close your eyes.
And take deep breathes.
I am in a meeting.
- Viku!
Mili, I am busy.
You're always busy.
Are you drunk?
This girl isn't coming to the point.
Hey...the girl's been kidnapped.
What?
Are you deaf?
She's been kidnapped.
What do you want?
Viku!!
One million.
Okay.
Yeah!
I am texting you the address.
Be there.
And yes, if you inform the police..
..then you know the consequences.
Yes!
Please tell Mr. Nakamoro I have to go.
Stupid girl got herself kidnapped.
"Praise the Goddess"
Congratulations.
- Why?
You're the first hostage
of our kidnapping business.
Really?
- Yes.
When I got my first patient,
I was happy too.
Half an hour was all I said.
She's really so much trouble.
"O sweet heart."
Someone shut her up,
she is driving us crazy.
“L forgot what comes next.“
"O sweet head..."
Keep quiet!
Here's your money.
Return my guest to me.
Prince!
Dharam Singh?
You?
Greetings, Prince. Greetings.
You've kidnapped our guest,
Dharam Singh.
Are you out of your mind?
Pardon me, Prince.
We didn't know she's your guest.
I thought she's a tourist.
Bring her here quickly.
Do you want to get me killed?
- Yes, yes.
We didn't do anything.
We didn't do anything, I swear.
- Viku!
Bring her.
- Hi!
Now get out of here.
I don't want to see any of
you in Sambhalgarh again.
Viku, you're so heroic.
What a rescue.
I feel sick. I need to breathe.
I don't understand how you
got yourself kidnapped.
..in just half an hour?
WE!
You and who?
Is there anyone else?
I... permission...
How could you be so stupid?
Sorry, there was an audition.
Never mind.
But, Viku, you saved me.
Mili, you are drunk.
Hi, Manju, what's up?
Petrol is up, I am up,
your father's up.
K's down, idiot's still sleeping.
You say?
- Nothing!
I am just getting ready for work.
And your Prince Vikram?
How's he?
Will you be a princess?
Forget Vikram!
You're just interested in him.
I just grew up doing silly stuff.
If you had straightened me up then..
..| might've settled down by now..
..mothering 2 or 3 kids.
What did you do now?
I kissed the frog!
Oh no, you kissed that bore?
But he's engaged.
Oh, that's terrible!
You shou|d've told me
earlier that he is engaged.
What now?
I don't know.
Mili. - Manju,
I can't think straight right now.
Okay, bye. Bye.
- Mili.
Oh, God!
Manju.
What do I do now?
- Hold on! Hold on!
Breathe. Deep breaths.
Are you calm now?
Look, talk to him
clearly and end this story.
That's the best.
Good idea!
Good...good idea!
Good idea, Manju.
I love you.
Vikram, I wanted to talk to you.
I think...
Vikram your papers...
Hi, your highness.
It's such a pleasant day,
isn't it?
I'll take Shekhar uncle
out for exercising.
Vikram!
- Yes.
Thank you.
Oh no!
30"‘!-
Mili!
Yes!
'VVhat do I say!
Why is he here!'
Hold on!
I can do this.
Hi!
~ Hi!
Are you busy?
Can we talk?
Sure.
'He is looking so hot'
'VVhat has she done to this room'
'How do I do this?'
'Vikram forget about last night'
‘What happened last night.
'VVhat do I say?'
Listen.
Yesterday...
- Yesterday?
'Eyes'
'Don't stare at the legs'
What happened yesterday between us..
Oh, yesterday.
Don't think about it.
These things happen.
'Idiot!'
Not with me, with people...
Generally in life.
'VVhat is she saying?'
Right?
So maybe we should forget it.
Obviously, you don't need to ask.
You were just.
.. completely drunk.
Absolutely drunk.
'Please kiss me Vikram.'
'I want to kiss you.'
We were wrong?
Yes.
And, so what even if we were right.
I mean...
Nothing's possible between us,
I mean..
'VVhy can't be there anything?'
..you know..
Yeah!
You and I are very different people.
'And I am going to marry Kiara.'
Yes.
And I won't change myself for anyone.
Right. I think that's
the right thing to do.
'Good, you said it.. now get out.'
So...
'Don't go.'
- 'Stop me'
I am...glad we had this conversation“.
..and it's over.
'Can I hold you?'
- 'Please.. don't.'
Okay. 8077'!'-.
Friends, high-five!
High-five!
Cool. Goodnight.
'This is for the best'
Goodnight.
'This is best.'
Thanks. Goodnight.
Goodnight.
High-five.
Why are you troubling me
so early in the morning?
If you can't sleep..
We're going to exercise here today.
'In an effort to
be away from your son'
It's been so many years
since I last came here.
WOW!
'NO, NO, NO, NO!'
Oh! Vikram!
Vikram, didn't you sleep last night.
Good morning, dad.
- Good morning.
'VVhy is he here?'
Good to see you up here.
- Mi|i's idea.
I had completely forgotten
how beautiful it is up here.
I am going to Mumbai today.
- I see.
'Vvhy?
- 'To be away from you, Mili.'
Don't work so hard,
you'll become boring.
Bye, dad.
Bye, Vikram.
Bye, Mili.
Let's exercise.
You kissed the girl,
not her mother.
It's not funny.
I am not being funny.
A boy and girl meet.
They develop an attraction.
They kiss.
It happens with everyone.
It happened with you too,
that's it.
She says the same thing.
She's a smart girl.
Is she hot?
She's hot.
What will I tell Kiara?
What do you want to tell Kiara?
Rathore, I hope you
aren't feeling guilty?
Maybe.
I've invited her home tomorrow.
You invited Kiara?
You invited Kiara home?
Are you mad?
Do you know anything about girls?
Okay.
In the last 36 hours, you
saved Mili from the kidnappers.
Fine.
You kissed her in your
inebriated state.
Okay.
Later, you gave
high-fives to each other..
..and now you two are best friends.
Fine.
But now...you've inviting Kiara..
..in the same house where Mili is.
That is too much.
It's cruelty against women.
If you want to talk to Kiara,
then do it in her home.
And don't tell her anything
about your 'Mili Adventure'.
Nothing.
Little more. Little more up.
Amazing.
I'll call everyone.
- No, no, no.
Let's give them a surprise.
- Okay.
Let's do little more.
- That's the spirit.
Wait.
You think I'll be able to do
anything until the wedding?
Whose wedding?
Vikram's marriage, with Kiara.
Didn't anyone tell you
the wedding is in December!
Hi, Vikram.
- Hi.
Congratulations!
F0 r?
I heard you're getting
married in December.
You two look really good together.
Running away?
I don't know.
Of course, you should
do what your head says.
But have you tried speaking to Vikram?
Brother Vikram, he's just like mother.
Although he looks modern..
..but his thoughts are outdated.
Okay, Manju, nice speaking to you.
It felt really nice.
Yes, yes.
- Bye!
Mili, have you lost your mind?
I'm peeling oranges in my bedroom.
..and you're introducing me
to royalty.
Why don't you call?
- Yes, Manju, we couldn't talk.
But I am busy with Shekhar uncle.
He wants to be able to walk until..
..Vikram's wedding in December.
I see. So his marriage has
also been fixed. Wow!
When his wife comes home..
..you can help her exercise as well.
Have you planned to be
on their wedding welcome committee?
Hi, Mili.
Hi, Vikram!
Where's dad?
He's gone downstairs,
I am talking to my mom.
Manju, Vikram.
Vikram, Manju.
Hello, ma'am.
Vikram Singh Remote.
Hello. Nice to meet you too.
I have to go look for dad,
so...hope to see you soon.
Bye.
Bye, Mili.
- Bye, Vikram.
You love him!
- No, I don't.
Okay, bye. I have to go.
Sir.
Prince.
- Sir.
Tomorrow at 5 pm.
Yes, sir.
And yes, bring Dr. Mili along.
I've got a stiff neck.
Don't come without her.
Sir?
Hi, Vikram.
Hello, Mili.
Yes, Viku.
Your fan club is growing.
- What?
I mean Suraj Maan Singh's called
me for a meeting in the morning.
And he's insisted that
you come along too..
..as he's got a stiff neck.
Oh...are you feeling jealous?
I don't have those
old age problems.
So, do you have one of
those youngsteﬁs problems?
Like deceptive appearances..
Thanks.
Tomorrow morning at 11am.
Is Suraj Maan Singh selling his house?
Yes.
I don't want to see him like this.
That's how business is done.
It's not like with you doctors.
Noble, selfless.
Who said doctors are selfless?
The only difference is,
we only benefit..
..when our patients benefit.
I don't know whether
it was a good idea..
..to come here and surprise Mili.
At someone e|se's home. Manju!
She's our daughter.
We can surprise her
whenever we want.
And we aren't here to
cause them any inconvenience.
We're staying at a hotel,
and also paying for it.
We're not staying with them.
This girl I tell you...
I've tried calling her
15 times, but..
...I wonder where she's
disappeared to without her phone.
This must be an antique.
Hello.
I am Nirmala Devi Rathore.
Are you Dr. Chakravany's parents?
- Yes.
I am Pratik, Mi|i's father.
And she's Manju, her mother.
- Hello.
Take a seat.
30"‘!-
Actually, we came here
to surprise Mili.
But we were shocked instead.
The girl's missing!
You've maintained
the house quite well.
Thank you.
But Mi|i..
Dr. Chakravany isn't missing.
She's gone to meet
King Suraj Maan Singh..
..with my son Vikram.
What?
He sprained his neck.
They will be back by evening.
Is it far?
About 300 kilometers.
I hope...this time she is travelling
in a car, not like the last time.
She is travelling by car.
Vikram's gone with her.
Well, actually you're so sweet,
I didn't mean anything.
Just like that.
Excuse me.
That's an antique,
if you don't mind.
By the way, Mili was saying..
..that you have to follow a lot of
rules and regulations here.
Does your husband agree?
Hello, hello, hello.
Manju, we've already met.
Hello.
You're looking really smart in this coat.
- I see.
You must be Pratik?
Hello!
She's my daughter Divya.
Hello.
- Hello.
Sit, sit, sit.
No one has ever been able to
force me to do anything.
But your daughter is stubborn.
I've never seen a doctor like her.
She is scolding me to better health.
Greetings Sir!
Come, Prince.
Hello, Dr. Mili.
- Good afternoon.
Do you still have a stiff neck?
It wasn't there since this morning.
- That's Good.
So the Prince is adamant on
separating me from my palace.
He brought you along.
Sir, I tried hard that
this doesn't happen.
But people never listen to me.
Sir!
Yes, Prince.
On to business.
Take a look.
- May I take your leave.
Be nice.
Sir..
Sir, there's an idea in my mind.
Don't try to haggle anymore.
I've made up my mind, because..
..you've accepted my
terms and conditions.
And that is that.
Sir, I was thinking.
...let's run Surajgarh in partnership.
Your residence wing will stay
dedicated to you.
We'll build a hotel in
the rest of the area.
You won't have to sell your property.
In fact, your contribution to
the business will be your palace..
..and ours will be our finance.
Vikram...
Sir, I feel if you stay here..
..it will add to the
heritage value of the place.
You'll also be on
the board of directors.
Like I said, your
privacy will be guaranteed.
I wasn't wrong.
Your game is really unique.
Lets shake hands.
Farmer.
Let's celebrate!
Radheshyam!
Champagne!
No, no, no..abso|ute|y not.
You're our guests today.
- So sweet.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
I'll make the arrangements.
Sit, sit, sit, be comfortable.
Have some biscuits.
Young man,
you will stay here tonight.
Radheshyam has prepared
the royal suite for you.
No, no, we should go home.
Nonsense!
- Nonsense!
You have to stay here tonight.
That's my order.
Viku, he's right.
I don't want to die young.
I am too hot.
Please come.
Careful.
Hey..
What happened?
You're making me have
strange thoughts, Viku.
'Me too.
Alone all night, with him?
No, no, no.
What are you saying, Manju?
- Nothing.
Go to sleep.
Even/thing's wrong.
What if she got emotional?
What's the point staying guard,
when the dog ate the flour.
You can't trust boys.
They will kiss first
and later say sorry.
Best friends.
Oh, God!
No, Manju.
It's time to talk openly.
Come on, Manju.
Buck up.
'Should we sleep together
on the same bed'
'Nothing will happen!'
'That's a lie'
I'll sleep there.
Safe.
'Oh no.'
- 'Oh no.'
Good night, Mili.
Good night, Viku.
Mrs. Chakravany,
what happened?
In the middle of the night.
My days and nights
have become the same..
..since this has happened.
Look, I'll straight come
to the point.
What can be done about
this Kiara character?
Sorry, what?
Your son Vikram loves
my daughter Mili.
He's told you about
the kissing, right?
But Vikram's engaged. Right?
He didn't tell you.
Your son Vikram kissed
my daughter Mili.
Since he kissed her,
that means he loves her.
But he's engaged.
And my daughter Mili
is stuck in the middle.
So you will have to talk
to him, isn't it?
Please, please, Mrs. Chakravany.
I don't know anything about it.
When they come back tomorrow.
...all your misconceptions
will be cleared.
For me, my 8 hours
of sleep is very important.
For now, get some rest, please.
What?
Goodnight, Mrs. Chakravany.
Goodnight?
They are all the same.
Royal madhouse!
What happened? Can't sleep?
- No.
I can't either.
Something looks
different here, doesn't it?
What happened?
I'm getting strange
thoughts again, Viku.
What are you, Mili?
You say whateveﬁs on your mind.
No filter.
Why hesitate in speaking the truth?
Yeah, but that doesn't mean
you speak what's on your mind.
You should keep some
things concealed in your heart
Yes.
So that...when we're
old we have some regrets.
“L wish I had said that,
or done that“
I am not like that.
I say whateveﬁs on my mind.
It's quite cold tonight.
Here, take this.
Vikram!
I am in love with you.
Mili, please..
Vikram!
Sorry, Vikram is here.
I'll call you later.
Mother.
Vikram!
- Hello.
Vikram, Divya isn't at home.
It's what I was afraid of.
She ran away.
Look at this letter.
She's written that
she'll be back in a few days.
Look at her handwriting.
She still erases her
mistakes with her spit.
Where has Divya gone?
She hasn't written anything.
Don't worn].
Mi|i's handwriting was bad as well.
Yes, but she never ran away.
And it's possible that.
..Divya couldn't find
an eraser in a hum].
So she...
Vikram, is it the 27th today?
- Yes. It is.
Why?
There's a Bollywood
Star Reality Show..
..which is being
held in Jaipur today.
So, what has a Bollywood
show got to do with Divya?
Divya wants to be an actress.
I'll find out.
Dr. Chakravany, since you had..
...such heart-to-heart
discussions with Divya..
..then she might
have told you that.
..we don't want her to do this?
Didn't you think it was your
responsibility to tell us?
Or to warn her?
She's just a kid.
Or it doesn't make
a difference to you?
Your highness, that's not it.
Divya wanted to go herself.
So that's why you took
this decision for my daughter.
Don't forget, Doctor.
You're here for Shekhar's treatment.
Not for Divya's career counseling.
Don't.
- Excuse me. Don't say that.
Even she is low on tolerance.
But still she stayed put
for your husband's treatment.
Hold on, Manju.
Your highness, please try
to understand Divya's situation..
Doctor Chakravany,
this is beyond your understanding.
..so please don't even tn].
- Excuse me, madam.
Actually, even we are pan Rajputs.
He's a Bengali and I am a Punjabi.
But we have Rajput
blood in our veins.
I am not talking to you.
Dr. Chakravany, your thoughts.
“Your interference
in other's lives..
Have you ever thought about
its outcome?
You encouraged a 17
year old kid to run away.
How irresponsible.
But, your highness, I did no such thing..
- Enough.
Let's go, Mili.
There is no need
to explain her anything.
Come on.
It's because of your over-discipline.
Are you happy now?
Happy-
- Wait, Manju.
Mother.
What happened?
I've informed the Jaipur office.
They're checking whether Divya's
name is on the list or not. - Okay.
And I've informed the
commissioner of Jaipur.
He's posted his men at
the venue and stations.
They will let us know.
Son..
- Vikram!
Divya is 17 year old.
She's a grown up now.
Dr. Chakravany, please.
Don't give us anymore
advice on my daughter.
Enough!
How much more humiliation
are we going to endure?
Oh yes.
She believes that you and
Dr. Chakravany love each other.
Manju?
Thank God.
I don't believe in such nonsense.
Nonsense?
Hello. It's a fact.
Look, there's guilt
in your son's eyes.
Pardon me, madam.
We're better than this.
At least our children
don't hide anything from us.
Nor do they run away.
Excuse me.
Hold on, Manju.
Hello.
See. . .everyone's left.
Vikram.
Yes.
Thank you, Mr. Mishra.
Please keep us informed.
Vikram.
- Not now, Mili.
Vikram, Divya's fine.
Believe me, she's just acting out..
- She's just 17 years old, Mili.
Vikram, even you were 17..
...when you handled
everything with her highness.
I was the same age..
..when I went away from home
to study.
If she wants to do
something on her own at this age..
..then what's the problem.
The problem is that this
doesn't happen in this family.
Why am I even explaining
this to you?
You won't understand.
I don't understand what
kind of a brother are you..
..who couldn't win his
younger sister's confidence.
If you had supported her.
..then she might
have never run away.
That's what you won't
understand, Mili.
You do as you please.
You don't care about.
..how it does or
doesn't affect others.
That's exactly what
you did last night.
But here, we think about each
other before doing anything.
That's not fair...
Yes, I do what I want.
But I do it only when the other
person wants the same thing..
..and can't do it.
What difference does it make, Mili?
Why don't you understand.
..there's a big
difference between you and me.
We'll spend all our lives
erasing this difference.
We should have something
common between us to be happy.
But there's nothing common
between you and me, Mili.
I agree.
Mom!
DiVya!
Oh, thank God. Are you fine?
How could you do this, Divya?
How dare you?
What is this?
What did you do to your hair?
Mother, sister Mi|i..
"Sister" Mi|i..?
Of course.
"Sister" Mili.
I am sure that
audacious girl encouraged you..
..to take such a disgusting step.
Running away from home..
..and this preposterous hairdo.
We||...your "sister" Mi|i's gone.
You won't do such
a thing again, okay?
But, mom..
- Enough of this audaciousness.
I need a crocin.
Mom, I am not being rude.
Sister Mili wasn't wrong.
I see.
Is this why she told you
to run away from home?
Don't blame Mi|i..
..she didn't tell me to run away.
I came back because of her.
It was my plan to run away.
I was planning for a year.
But she said if I run away
from home..
..then I'll accept my defeat.
And we're Rajputs.
We don't run away.
We face our problems.
Like you did when
dad met with an accident.
I didn't understand it then.
But I understood this when
I was sitting alone at the station.
That's why I came back.
And I will go only
when you let me go.
I am very tired.
Just.
Go to your room!
Dinner at 8...
Hello.
Good morning, Kiara.
Mili dear.
Excuse me, please.
Vikram! Listen!
Ramsevak, it's been so long..
..since I didn't stick my
foot in anyone's business.
It's been very long,
your highness.
Well, let's practice.
Greetings, your highness.
Yes, Ramsevak.
The master has called you.
Now?
Is he fine?
What is it, Shekhar?
Do you need something?
Nirmala, pick up that folder.
Yeah!
Shekhar, what are you doing?
Oh my, God!
Your leg...
Why didn't you tell me?
I was waiting for the right time.
Shekhar..
I want to tell you something else.
I saw Divya run away...
...but I didn't tell anyone.
How could you?
- I thought Diyva is our daughter.
She will handle it.
And I was right.
How could you...
It's been 10 years since
the accident, Nirmala.
For 10 years I stayed
glued to this chair..
..and time left me behind.
Everyone stopped
laughing in this house.
How could we laugh?
You were stuck in this chair..
..me with my responsibilities,
and our kids..
..matured before their age.
Exactly, our kids have grown up.
You raised them alone.
And expanded this business..
...and kept the honor
of this palace intact.
You did all this.
Now Vikram will handle it.
Himself and this business.
Let it go.
Let it go, Nirmala.
It's so easy to say, Shekhar.
Let it go.
Nirmala,
this family has lost one son.
That void can never be filled..
..but we have two more kids.
Why are we distancing
ourselves from them?
That's exactly what Mili
was trying to explain us.
How long will it take us
to understand such a small thing?
Oh my, God!
I want my life back.
I want my Nirmala back.
My, God. Shekhar.
Careful. Careful.
Mili.
You turned out to
be better than master..
...in 'sticking your Leg'.
More tea?
Did you have tea?
Yes!
It seems he didn't sleep all night.
Vikram, where did you
go without informing us?
Dad, mom, I have to..
Tell you something.
These days everyone's talking
in a dramatic way in our house.
But it's good.
I am not complaining.
Go ahead.
Yesterday. . .l . .
L...went to see Kiara
at her house, and..
So Vikram Singh Remove".
..you're here to break
off our engagement?
I am sorry.
Kiara, I feel guilty for
putting you in this situation.
But I feel if I don't do it now..
...I'll only be hurting
everyone later.
And everything else
doesn't matter as much as..
Vikram, it's okay.
But...this girl and you..
I can't understand.
I can't understand either.
But since she left..
..there's nothing else
I can understand.
Don't worn] about me.
I'll be okay.
I'll get over it.
And who knows...
..maybe fate has some
adventure in-store for me too.
Kiara and I aren't getting married.
I want to marry someone else.
If she agrees.
I know she's trouble.
She does everything wrong.
She doesn't fit in, but..
..even her wrong actions
seem right to me.
I need her. We need her.
Why are you telling that to us?
Vikram, if you marry her.
Then she'll always embarrass
us with her actions.
Or maybe we'll all learn to laugh.
There's a ticket
to Delhi in your room.
You'll get a car at the airport
And Vikram, please clean up
before you go, please.
Go for it, son.
Your dad is sticking
his foot in things again.
Now if you move, you might
be able to catch the plane.
Manju, stop it.
You're putting
Asharffs job in danger.
I've become too hotheaded.
I'm just cooling it down.
Otherwise my head will explode.
Then don't forget
to blow a whistle first.
Be quiet.
You didn't say a word out there.
You kept sitting quietly.
And you're having fun now.
Hi, is this
Dr. Mili Chakravany's house?
You must be Kabir.
Vikram Singh Remote.
May I. . .come in?
Sir...it's important
for me to meet Mili.
What is this?
You and who?
Split personalities.
He's trying to prove
as if he walked here.
Did we invite you?
Mili won't meet you.
- Manju.
You will have to tell us
what you need from Mili.
Sir, please if you trust me at all..
- Trust!
We don't trust you at all.
Always showing off.
Mi|i..
Mili isn't here.
Then where is she?
- We won't tell you.
After returning from Sambha|garh..
...Mili was very disturbed.
So...she needed some help.
Therapy-
Sir, I need to meet her right now.
Please, sir.
Dude, I'm telling you again.
Take my advice.
Mili has lost her mind.
Let's avoid it!
Which doctor is treating her?
You wait here, I'll get the tickets.
So this is her therapy?!
Oh no!
Mili.
Mili!
Vikram!
Mili, listen to me.
- I don't want to talk to you.
Mili, listen..
Kiara and l..
-Speak up,
Mili, l..
'.
I mean..
There's nothing common between us.
Mili!
I love you!
Oh..
He's dead!
When we're old and
my limbs don't work..
...I'll need a doctor like you.
Polish off my wine collection.
We'll have to win over
many more Suraj Maan Singh's.
And who will chatter
at the dining table?
Who will mom say "disgusting" to?
If you leave?
So please...
Mili...
...marn/ me!
That's my sister.
Viku.
Viku, l..
Not like this.
We will need to ask Manju.
I guess he's style's been
totally ruined.
Did you talk to her?
What now?
Now I've to talk to you.
Talk to me?
Why? Haven't you
talked to me enough?
Please prepare for Mi|i's wedding.
With me.
Whichever date Mili chooses.
And that...Kia...Kai..
What's her name?
- Kiara.
We aren't engaged anymore.
For the first time I spoke my mind.
That's my daughter Mi|i's style.
Not yours.
And why should we
say yes for the wedding?
He's crazy.
We...we..
Who we?
You and your army?
And secondly.
- Oh, stop it, Manju.
I love your daughter.
I'm politely asking for
her hand in marriage, so say yes.
Otherwise I'll elope with her.
And once I do that.
..you won't be able to get connect with
her on Skype, Facebook or Facetime.
When she gets sweet,
chubby and pregnant.
..but I still won't
let you meet her.
We'll have 3 or 4 cute kids as well.
But I won't let them
meet their grandma.
I won't upload their photos either.
So now?
Is it a yes...or
do I elope with her?
Did you hear what he's saying?
Are you saying yes,
or do I run away?
Say it.
This is not fair.
Everyone's making me
look like the villain.
I am not the villain here.
I am the bride's mother.
So, Manju, is it a yes or no?
Say yes.
Say yes, Manju.
Ok then...fine.
I say yes.
Yes! Yes! Yes!
Where were we?
Bore.