NARRATOR: Let us tell
an old story anew,
and we will see how well yöu know it.
Once upon a time,
there were two kingdoms
that were the worst of neighbours.
So vast was the discord between them
that it was said only a great hero
or a terrible villain
might bring them together.
In one kingdom
lived folk like yöu and me,
with a vain and greedy king
to rule over them.
They were forever discontent,
and envious of the wealth
and beauty of their neighbours.
For in the other kingdom, the Moors,
lived every manner of strange
and wonderful creature.
And they needed
neither king nor queen,
but trusted in one another.
In a great tree
on a great cliff in the Moors
lived one such spirit.
Yöu might take her for a girl,
but she was not just any girl.
She was a fairy.
(BRANCH CRACKS)
(GASPS)
There yöu go.
And her name
was Maleficent.
Good morning, Mr Chanterelle!
- I love yöur cap!
- Oh. (CHUCKLES)
No. No, don't do it!
- Ahh!
(WALLERBOGS LAUGHING)
(SQUAWKS)
Ha! Yöu missed me!
- Good morning.
Lovely work, girls!
Whoo..hoo!
(FAIRIES CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY)
- What's all the fuss about?
- The border guards have discov...
Why do yöu get to tell her?
I want to tell her!
THISTLEWIT: I want to!
There are rules, Flittle.
I tell this time, yöu tell next time.
FLITTLE: No, yöu told last time,
so I should tell this time,
and Thistlewit next time.
Tell me what?
Fine!
(EXHALES)
Thank yöu.
Maleficent, the border guard...
The border guards have found
a human thief at the pool of jewels.
I'm sorry.
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
She's always in a hurry,
with her big wings.
Humans, here.
I hope there's not another war.
(SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE)
I'm not afraid.
Besides, I have never
seen a human up close.
Come out!
BOY: No. They mean to kill me.
And besides, they're hideous to look at.
(GRUNTS)
That's extremely rude.
Don't listen to him, Balthazar.
Yöu're classically handsome.
(SPEAKS NATIVE LANGUAGE)
It's not right to steal,
but we don't kill people for it.
Come out.
Come out this instant!
Are yöu fully grown?
No.
I believe he's just a boy.
And yöu're just a girl.
I think.
Who are yöu?
I'm called Stefan.
I'm Maleficent.
(SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE)
Yes, right.
Yöu have to give it back.
Give what back?
(SIGHS)
If I knew yöu would throw it away,
I would have kept it.
I didn't throw it away.
I delivered it home,
as I'm going to do for yöu.
Someday, yöu know, I'll live there.
In the castle.
Where do yöu live now?
In a barn.
So yöur parents are farmers, then?
My parents are dead.
Mine, too.
We'll see each other again.
Yöu really shouldn't
come back here, yöu know.
It's not safe.
And if I made that choice,
if I came back, would yöu be here?
Perhaps.
- Ow!
- What's wrong?
Yöur ring.
Iron burns fairies.
I'm sorry.
I like yöur wings.
NARRATOR: Maleficent thought of
how Stefan cast away his ring,
he who had so little in the world,
so that their hands might touch again,
and her heart was moved.
Thus did the yöung thief
who had hoped to steal a jewel...
STEFAN: Maleficent!
...steal something far more precious.
STEFAN: Maleficent?
Maleficent!
After all these weeks,
look who came back.
I thought it worth the risk.
So, what do yöu do for fun?
(YELLS)
(MALEFICENT LAUGHING)
Whoa!
(SPITS)
(LAUGHS)
NARRATOR: Stefan and Maleficent
became the most unlikely of friends.
And for a time it seemed as if,
in them at least,
the old hatred between men and fairies
had been forgotten.
As it will, friendship slowly
turned into something else.
And on her 16th birthday,
Stefan gave Maleficent a gift.
He told her it was true love's kiss.
But it was not to be.
As the years passed,
Stefan's ambition
pulled him away from Maleficent,
and towards the temptations
of the human kingdom.
While Maleficent,
the strongest of the fairies,
rose to become
the protector of the Moors.
Maleficent often wandered alone
and sometimes wondered
where Stefan might be,
for she had never understood
the greed and envy of men.
But she was to learn.
For the human king
had heard
of a growing power in the Moors,
and he sought to strike it down.
SOLDIER: Guard, halt!
Guard, halt!
There they are,
the mysterious Moors
where no one dares to venture
for fear of the magical
creatures that lurk within.
Well, I say crush them!
(ALL CHEERING)
(SOLDIERS MURMURING)
Go no further!
A king
does not take orders from a winged elf.
(SOLDIERS LAUGHING)
Yöu are no king to me.
- Bring me her head.
SOLDIER: - Battalion!
Advance!
Arise and stand with me!
(RUMBLING)
SOLDIER: Hold the line!
(SOLDIERS CHATTERING
NERVOUSLY)
(GROWLING)
SOLDIER 1: It's the dark creatures!
SOLDIER 2: It's the dark creatures!
(SNARLING)
(ROARING)
HENRY: Charge!
(YELLING)
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING)
(SOLDIERS GROANING)
(SOLDIER SHRIEKS)
(SOLDIER SCREAMING)
(SCREAMS)
(SOLDIERS GROANING)
(ROARS)
Yöu!
(SCREAMS)
(GROANS)
To the king!
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING)
(GRUNTS)
(ALL GROAN)
(PANTING)
Yöu will not have the Moors!
Not now, nor ever!
Yöu... (GROANS)
(ROARING)
(SNORTING)
HENRY: When I ascended to the throne,
I promised the people
one day we would take
the Moors and its treasures.
Each of yöu
swore allegiance to me
and to that cause.
(HENRY COUGHING)
Yöur Majesty.
(CONTINUES COUGHING)
Defeated in battle.
Is this to be my legacy?
I see yöu waiting for me to die.
It won't be long. But what then?
I will choose a successor
to take the throne
and care for my daughter.
Who among yöu
is worthy?
Kill the winged creature.
Avenge me,
and upon my death
yöu will take the crown.
(SIGHS)
Maleficent.
Maleficent!
(STEFAN SIGHS)
So, how is life with the humans?
Maleficent, I've come to warn yöu.
They mean to kill yöu.
King Henry will stop at nothing.
Please, yöu have to trust me.
NARRATOR: They spoke
of many things,
and the years faded away.
And she forgave Stefan
his folly and his ambition,
and all was as it had been long ago.
- Yöu thirsty?
- Mmm.
Maleficent?
(EXHALING SHAKILY)
(PANTING)
(GROANING)
(GASPS)
(SOBBING)
(WAILING)
(MALEFICENT WAILING)
(SOBBING)
(GASPS)
What is this?
I have avenged yöu, sire.
She is vanquished? (COUGHING)
Oh, yöu have done well, my son.
Yöu have done what others feared to do.
Yöu will be rewarded.
I shall do my best
to be a worthy successor,
Yöur Majesty.
(GROANS SOFTLY)
(EXHALES)
(GROANING)
(DISTANT CAWING)
(CAWS)
(BLOWS)
(CAWING)
(DOGS BARKING)
I've got yöu!
- Yöu wicked bird!
- Into a man.
(GASPING) It's a...
(BARKING CONTINUES)
(GRUNTING)
It's a demon!
(DOGS WHIMPERING)
What have yöu done
to my beautiful self?
Would yöu rather
I let them beat yöu to death?
I'm not certain.
Stop complaining.
I saved yöur life.
Forgive me.
What do I call yöu?
Diaval.
And in return for saving my life,
I am yöur servant.
Whatever yöu need.
Wings.
I need yöu to be my wings.
(CAWING)
I present to yöu the first of his line,
His Royal Highness King Stefan.
(EXCITED MURMURING)
He did this to me so he would be king.
(SCREAMING)
Now what, Mistress?
(GASPS)
FAIRY: Her wings!
(CAWING)
(GROWLING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
It's a girl!
(WOMEN GASPING)
ALL: It's a girl! It's a girl!
(EXCITED CHATTER)
(CAWING)
(GRUNTING)
(EXHALES)
Well?
Well, I saw nothing.
But there's been a, um...
What?
Child.
King Stefan and the Queen
have had a child.
Oh.
There will be a christening.
They say it's to be a grand celebration.
A grand celebration for a baby.
How wonderful.
NARRATOR: All manner of folk
came to the christening,
even a trio of fairies
who sought to foster
peace and goodwill.
Oh, look, there's the baby!
I love babies!
Can yöu just concentrate, please?
- Oh!
- I'm not telling yöu again.
Greetings, Yöur Majesty.
I am Knotgrass
of the Moorland Fair Folk.
I'm Flittle, Yöur Kingship.
And I'm Thistlewit, Yöur Royalnesses.
They bring gifts for our daughter.
These are not just any old gifts,
for, yöu see, we're magic!
And very good with children.
(SIGHS)
Very well.
Sweet Aurora, I wish for yöu
the gift of beauty.
(BLOWS)
(COOING)
My wish is that yöu will never be blue,
only happy, all the days of yöur life.
(SNEEZING)
Sweet baby,
my wish for yöu is that yöu find...
(ALL GASP)
(WIND HOWLING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
FAIRIES: (WHISPERING) Maleficent!
(ALL MURMURING)
Well, well.
(CHUCKLING)
What a glittering assemblage,
King Stefan.
Royalty,
nobility, the gentry,
and...
(CAWING)
(LAUGHING)
How quaint.
Even the rabble.
I must say
I really felt quite distressed
at not receiving an invitation.
Yöu're not welcome here.
(MOCK WHIMPERING)
Oh.
(LAUGHING)
Oh, dear.
What an awkward situation.
Yöu're not offended?
Why, no.
And to show I bear no ill will,
I, too, shall bestow a gift on the child.
No! We don't want yöur gift!
KNOTGRASS: Stay away
from the princess!
THISTLEWIT: Yes, stay away!
(CROWD GASPS)
FAIRIES: om
Ow!
Hmm...
Mmm.
Listen well, all of yöu.
WHISPERING VOICES: Listen well, all of yöu.
The princess shall indeed
grow in grace and beauty,
beloved by all who meet her.
That's a lovely gift.
Don't do this.
But
before the sun sets on her 16th birthday,
she will prick her finger
on the spindle of a spinning wheel
and fall into a sleep like death,
a sleep from which
she will never awaken.
Maleficent, please don't do this,
I'm begging yöu.
I like yöu begging.
Do it again.
I beg yöu.
All right.
The princess can be woken
from her death sleep,
but only by
true love's kiss.
This curse will last till the end of time!
No power on Earth can change it.
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(MALEFICENT CACKLING)
NARRATOR: King Stefan
ordered his men
to seize every spinning wheel
in the kingdom.
The wheels were broken and burned,
that they might never be used,
and thrown into the deepest
dungeon in the castle.
Secretly, he entrusted
the safety of the child
to the magic of the pixies,
who would take her
to a remote hideaway
for 16 years and a day.
Stefan shut himself behind
the walls of his castle
while his soldiers rode far and wide
to hunt Maleficent down.
But she made walls of her own,
that the Moors might
never again suffer the touch
of any human.
And she revelled in the sorrow
that her curse had brought.
(MALEFICENT LAUGHING)
The fairies began their charge
to raise Aurora in a snug
little cottage in the woods.
FLITTLE: Oh, no! Is this it?
Looks dreadful.
Come on.
(AURORA COOING)
Oh, we need a smaller...
Ooh! Baby.
(AURORA CRYING)
Or bigger bodies.
No, what we need is a proper disguise.
What do yöu mean?
Well, we have to blend in, don't we?
We have to be big enough
to look after this baby.
So, gather around, ladies. (PANTING)
Get ready. One, two, three, grow!
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
Oh, that's worked quite well.
That's very nice.
Now, there will be no questions asked.
We are no longer fairies.
We are three peasant women
raising our orphan child in the woods.
- Yes.
- So, uh, no more flying.
- No flying?
- No, no, and...
(CRYING)
...no magic.
- No magic?
- Yes, yöu heard.
FLITTLE: It's in the middle of nowhere.
THISTLEWIT: At least
no one will find us here.
(CONTINUES CRYING)
(CAWING)
There yöu are.
Why are yöu always hiding?
Come on. There yöu go.
(CAWING)
(AURORA CRYING)
Hmm.
It's so ugly, yöu could
almost feel sorry for it.
(SNARLING)
I hate yöu. Beasty.
(CLATTERING)
NARRATOR: The fairies were
perhaps unequal to their task.
(CRYING)
Why is she crying?
I think she might be hungry.
Then feed her!
Oh.
(CONTINUES CRYING)
THISTLEWIT: (SINGING) ♫ Hungry baby ♪
There yöu are.
There yöu go.
(CAWING)
(AURORA CRYING)
(HISSING)
It's going to starve
with those three looking after it.
(AURORA CONTINUES CRYING)
(SNORING)
(MUTTERING)
It tickles. (LAUGHS)
(CRYING CONTINUES)
(CAWING SOFTLY)
(COOING)
(SUCKING)
(GASPS) What?
Yöu're cheating.
I saw that!
- We're starting again.
- Suit yöurself.
Greedy, bloated goat!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
"Bloated goat."
Stop doing that.
I'm not doing anything.
Well, someone is.
It's not me.
Yöu two are having a go at me,
and I will not tolerate...
Stop it!
(GASPING) Why...
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(ALL SHRIEKING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
No! Oh!
This is all yöur fault!
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(FAIRIES SHRIEKING)
Oh...
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
Oh, come on. That's funny.
NARRATOR: As the days went on,
Stefan darkened,
further consumed
by paranoia and vengeance.
CAPTAIN: Burn it all down!
SOLDIER: Yes, sir!
Flame!
(SOLDIER SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
Release!
(ALL CHEERING)
(SOLDIERS SCREAMING)
Run!
(GROANS)
(MALEFICENT LAUGHING EVILLY)
STEFAN: Yöu failed me.
The wall cannot be burned.
It is indestructible.
(GROANS)
Nothing is indestructible!
Not the wall!
Not Maleficent!
Not even her curse!
Bring me the iron workers.
Ow!
- Ow!
Yöu!
(FAIRIES YELPING)
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
MALEFICENT: Oh, look.
(AURORA LAUGHS)
The little beast is about
to fall off the cliff.
(CAWING)
(AURORA SCREAMS)
(LAUGHS)
(CAWS)
What?
(SIGHS)
AURORA: Hello.
Go away.
Go.
I don't like children.
(CAWS)
AURORA: Up, up.
Mmm. Go along. Go, go, go.
NARRATOR: As Maleficent had said,
Aurora did grow in grace and beauty.
Pretty bird.
(CAWS)
Far away from the lofty palace
that she remembered not.
(CAWING)
(LAUGHING)
And as the seasons changed
and the flowers grew,
so did she.
(LAUGHING)
Hello.
That's it.
There yöu go.
She wondered at the world about her,
and at what lay beyond
the fearsome wall of thorns.
MALEFICENT: Hmm.
Curious little beasty.
But she was not the only one
who wished to get through.
Shh.
Look.
Is that her? Is that Maleficent?
I don't know.
Bring them to me.
(GROWLING)
No, it's just a silly peasant girl.
(HOWLING)
(BLOWS)
(SOLDIERS TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(WOLF GROWLING)
(HORSES NEIGHING)
SOLDIER: Steady.
(HOWLING)
(WOLF SNARLING)
(SOLDIERS CLAMOURING)
(SOLDIERS MURMURING)
ALL: It's her!
(WOLF GROWLING)
(SOLDIERS WHIMPER)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(BOTH GROAN)
Whoa!
(SCREAMING)
(ALL GROANING)
Hmm.
(GASPS)
How could yöu do that to me?
Yöu said anything I need.
Yeah, but not a dog.
It was a wolf, not a dog.
It's the same thing.
(SCOFFS)
They're dirty, vicious,
and they hunt birds.
Fine.
Next time I'll turn yöu into a mealy worm.
Well, I'll be a mealy worm, gladly.
Anything but a filthy, stinking...
(CAWS)
I wonder.
Wow.
(FAIRIES SQUEAKING)
(GASPS)
I know yöu're there.
Don't be afraid.
(CHUCKLES)
I am not afraid.
Then come out.
Then yöu'll be afraid.
No, I won't.
I know who yöu are.
Do yöu?
Yöu're my Fairy Godmother.
What?
Fairy Godmother.
Yöu've been watching over me
my whole life.
I've always known yöu were close by.
How?
Yöur shadow. It's been following me
ever since I was small.
Wherever I went,
yöur shadow was always with me.
I remember yöu.
(CAWING)
Pretty bird. (CHUCKLES)
(CAWS)
This is Diaval.
(GASPS) Hello, Aurora.
I have known yöu
since yöu were a little one.
It's everything I imagined it would be.
Oh, it's just so beautiful!
I've always wanted to come...
(BLOWING)
(CREATURES CHIRRUP)
Good night, beasty.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Yöu mock me.
I know what yöu're doing.
I know exactly what yöu're doing.
Sire?
Yöur presence has been
requested by the Queen.
Leave me.
Sire, she is not well.
The nurses are fearful
that she won't make it through the night.
Shh.
Can yöu not see
we're having a conversation?
When the curse fails,
Maleficent will come for me.
And on that day,
I will be ready.
They're so beautiful.
(CREATURES CHIRRUP)
(WALLERBOGS LAUGHING)
(AURORA LAUGHING)
(LAUGHING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
I revoke the curse.
Let it be no more.
I revoke my curse!
Let it be no more!
WHISPERING VOICES: This curse will last till the end of time.
No power on Earth can change it.
Do all the Fair People have wings?
Most do.
Then why don't yöu?
All the other fairies fly.
I had wings once.
They were stolen from me.
That's all I wish to say about it.
What colour were they?
Were they big?
So big they dragged behind me
when I walked.
And they were strong.
They could carry me above the clouds
and into the headwinds.
And they never faltered,
not even once.
I could trust them.
(MALEFICENT SCREAMING)
(GASPS)
(PANTING)
She's coming. She's coming.
(COUGHS) Where are yöur workers?
Uh...
In their beds, Majesty.
Get them back to work without delay.
They're exhausted, sire.
But I'll have them
back to work at first light.
I need them back to work now.
It's the wee hours.
Aye.
It is the wee hours.
So wake them up.
Sire?
So wake them up,
and get them back to work now!
We're running out of time! Go, now!
(PURRING)
Aurora?
Come here.
Sit.
There's something I need to tell yöu.
What is it?
There is an evil in this world,
and I cannot keep yöu from it.
I'm almost 16, Godmother.
I can take care of myself.
I understand.
But that's not what I have to tell yöu.
I have a plan.
When I'm older,
I'm going to live here
in the Moors with yöu.
Then we can look after each other.
Yöu don't have to wait until yöu're older.
Yöu could live here now.
Then I will.
I'll sleep in a tree
and eat berries and black nuts
and all the Fair People
will be my friends.
I'll be happy here for the rest of my life.
I'm going to tell my aunties tomorrow.
Until tomorrow.
Oh, I'm so excited!
(AURORA LAUGHING)
AURORA: Aunties, I'm almost 16.
I need a life of my own.
No. I love yöu very much,
but it's time to say goodbye.
Yöu've been very good to me,
except the time
yöu accidentally fed me spiders.
(GASPS)
Hello.
I'm sorry to bother yöu,
but I'm on my way to King Stefan's castle
and I've become hopelessly lost.
- Can yöu help me?
- Oh!
Oh, I'm sorry. That was my fault.
I rushed in too...
Forgive me.
It's that way.
The castle.
What's yöur name?
It's Philip.
Hello, Philip.
What's yöurs?
Aurora.
Hello, Aurora.
Well, it was nice meeting yöu.
And once again, my apologies
for being such a clumsy fool.
Yöu're forgiven.
That's good.
I'd best be off, then.
Good bye.
Will yöu be back this way?
Nothing could stop me.
Then I'll see yöu soon.
Very soon.
(HORSE NEIGHING)
- Goodbye, Philip.
- Goodbye, for now.
(CAWING)
Stop doing that.
Well?
That boy's the answer.
(LAUGHING)
- No, Diaval.
- Yes!
True love's kiss, remember?
It can break the spell.
True love's kiss?
Have yöu not worked it out yet?
I cursed her that way
because there is no such thing.
Well, that might be how yöu feel,
but what about Aurora?
(SIGHS)
That boy could be her only chance.
It's her fate, anyway.
Go ahead.
Turn me into whatever yöu want.
A bird, a worm.
I don't care any more.
I'm so happy we're leaving tomorrow.
We are not leaving tomorrow.
Tomorrow is Aurora's 16th birthday.
KNOTGRASS: And Stefan
told us to take her back
the day after her birthday.
No. He said on her birthday.
KNOTGRASS: No.
The day after her birthday.
- On.
- After.
- On, on, on!
- After, after, after!
Oh, stop it! (GASPS)
Oh!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
What?
(GASPS)
How could yöu?
(BOTH CONTINUE LAUGHING)
(DOOR OPENS)
I need to talk to yöu about something.
Oh, yes, sweetie, what is it?
(DOOR CLOSES)
I'm sorry to have to tell yöu this,
but I'll be 16 tomorrow.
Oh. Oh, yes.
I'm leaving home.
See here, yöung lady.
I did not spend 16 years
in this miserable hovel
with these two imbeciles...
(BOTH GASP)
Shush! So that yöu could
ruin it on the last day.
We are taking yöu back
to yöur father with...
My father?
Yöu told me my parents were dead.
I think yöu better come and sit down.
Fairy Godmother!
I'm here.
When were yöu going to
tell me that I'm cursed?
Is it true?
It is.
My aunts said it was an evil fairy.
I... I can't remember her name.
They said
it was...
Maleficent.
Is that yöu?
Are yöu Maleficent?
No!
Don't touch me.
Yöu're the evil that's in the world.
It's yöu!
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Find the boy!
(CAWING)
STEFAN: I need every available man
on the east wing now.
There should be no guards at the gate.
I want her to walk right in.
GUARD: Sorry to disturb, Yöur Majesty.
We found this urchin at the gate.
She claims to be the princess.
Father.
It's me, Aurora!
Yöu look just like yöur mother.
They brought yöu back a day too soon.
I told those three idiots!
Lock her up in her room.
Go.
Prepare the men. Maleficent's coming.
FLITTLE: It's so good to be small again!
Look at my feet!
I love my tiny little feet!
Pay attention! We have to find Aurora,
or the king will have our heads!
(WHISPERING VOICES)
WHISPERING VOICES: Aurora.
(GASPS) Wait!
Princess?
(HORSE NEIGHING)
I'm looking for a girl.
Of course yöu are.
I need a horse.
(CAWING)
WHISPERING VOICES: ...into a sleep like death.
Aurora.
Come on, Diaval!
(WHISPERING VOICES)
WHISPERING VOICES: Aurora.
Faster, Diaval, faster!
WHISPERING VOICES: She will prick her finger
on the spindle of a spinning wheel
and fall into a sleep like death.
No power on Earth...
A sleep like death.
(HORSE NEIGHS)
It's done.
(SOBBING)
DIAVAL:  They pulled the guards.
He's waiting for yöu in there.
If we go inside those walls,
we'll never come out alive.
Then don't come. It's not yöur fight.
Huh.
Thank yöu very much.
"I need yöu, Diaval."
"I can't do this without yöu, Diaval."
MALEFICENT: I can hear yöu.
Look at her.
Look at what yöu've done.
She's only sleeping.
She's only sleeping, yöu say?
She's only sleeping
forever!
(FAIRIES WHIMPERING)
- What about the kiss?
- Yes! True love's kiss!
True love does not exist.
But it's her only chance, Yöur Majesty.
(GRUNTS)
(GASPS)
(GROANING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
DIAVAL: Mistress.
(GASPS)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(GRUNTS)
Hmm.
What are we going to do?
We can't give up, can we?
Come on, girls.
But we don't even know where to start.
True love doesn't just fall
from trees, yöu know.
(GROANS)
(BOTH STRAINING)
PHILIP: Pardon me.
I'm embarrassed to say
I don't know where I am.
In King Stefan's castle.
This is where I'm meant to be.
Odd that I can't recall how I got here.
Why have yöu come?
My father sent me to see the King.
KNOTGRASS: Who is yöur father?
King John of Ulstead.
ALL: A prince!
(FAIRIES GRUNTING)
Aurora.
THISTLEWIT: He knows her.
Why is she sleeping?
She's trapped in an enchantment.
Isn't she beautiful?
The most beautiful girl I've ever seen.
Do yöu want to kiss her?
Very much.
KNOTGRASS: Go on, then.
PHILIP: I wouldn't feel right about it.
I barely know her. We've only met once.
FLITTLE: Haven't yöu ever
heard of love at first sight?
Kiss her!
Go on.
An enchantment, yöu say?
ALL: Oh!
Kiss her!
Yöu didn't do it properly!
It's supposed to be true love's kiss!
I was certain he was the one.
What are yöu doing?
KNOTGRASS: We have to keep looking.
I told yöu.
I will not ask yöur forgiveness
because what I have
done to yöu is unforgivable.
I was so lost
in hatred and revenge.
Sweet Aurora,
yöu stole what was left of my heart.
And now I have lost yöu forever.
I swear, no harm will come to yöu
as long as I live.
And not a day shall pass
that I don't miss yöur smile.
(SIGHS)
Hello, Godmother.
Hello, beasty.
No truer love.
She's here, sire.
Are we going back to the Moors now?
If that is what yöu wish.
(YELLS)
(GASPS)
(SCREAMS)
GUARD: We've got her!
(YELLS)
- Stop!
- Get back!
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
(CAWING)
(GUARDS LAUGHING)
(GRUNTS)
(BOTH STRUGGLING)
No!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Into a dragon.
(EXHALES)
(GROWLING)
(SOLDIERS SCREAMING)
(GROANING)
SOLDIER: To the other side.
(SCREAMING)
MALEFICENT: Run, Aurora!
(PANTING)
(ROARING)
SOLDIER 1: Get back! Hold it steady!
Pull to the left! Pull!
Hold the line!
(SOLDIER SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
Look out. Hold yöur line.
(GASPS)
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING
INDISTINCTLY)
(GROWLING)
(HEAVY FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
(HELMET CLATTERING)
(DRAGON SCREECHING)
SOLDIER 1: Close in.
SOLDIER 2: Bring it down!
(GROANING)
(SHIELDS THUDDING
RHYTHMICALLY)
Hmm!
Enough!
(THUDDING STOPS)
How does it feel, hmm?
To be a fairy creature without wings
in a world where yöu don't belong?
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS) Kill her!
Kill her!
(SOLDIER GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
Shoot!
(ALL SCREAMING)
(ROARS)
Ahh!
(GRUNTS)
Shoot her!
SOLDIER: Take aim!
(GROANING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(YELLING)
(SCREAMING)
(CONTINUES SCREAMING)
(GROANS)
(CHOKING)
It's over.
(COUGHING)
(GASPING)
(GROWLING)
Ahh!
(BOTH STRUGGLING)
NARRATOR: Maleficent brought
down her wall of thorns
and took off her crown.
And she invited Aurora to see
how the Moors had been once,
long ago, when Maleficent
was but a child
and her heart was bright.
For now, it was again.
But that was not all.
KNOTGRASS: Oh, there she is.
Hurry up. They're waiting.
Wait for me!
KNOTGRASS: We present
this crown to our little Aurora,
for whom we have sacrificed
the best years of our...
Never mind.
Our kingdoms have been unified.
Yöu have yöur queen.
(ALL CHEERING)
NARRATOR: So yöu see,
the story is not quite as yöu were told,
and I should know,
for I was the one
they called Sleeping Beauty.
(CHEERING CONTINUES)
In the end, my kingdom
was united not by a hero
or a villain, as legend had predicted,
but by one who was
both hero and villain.
And her name was Maleficent.
(CAWING)
"Hope You've Liked & Enjoyed The Movie"
Copyright from ecOtOne™
WOMAN: (SINGING) ♫ I know yöu ♪
♫ I walked with yöu once upon a dream ♪
♫ I know yöu ♪
♫ That look in yöur eyes
is so familiar a gleam ♪
♫ And I know it's true ♪
♫ That visions are seldom all they seem ♪
♫ But if I know yöu ♪
♫ I know what yöu'll do ♪
♫ Yöu'll love me at once ♪
♫ The way yöu did once upon a dream ♪
♫ But if I know yöu ♪
♫ I know what yöu'll do ♪
♫ Yöu'll love me at once ♪
♫ The way yöu did once upon a dream ♪
♫ I know yöu ♪
♫ I walked with yöu once upon a dream ♪
♫ That gleam in yöur eyes
is so familiar a gleam ♪
♫ And I know it's true ♪
♫ That visions are seldom all they seem ♪
♫ But if I know yöu ♪
♫ I know what yöu'll do ♪
♫ Yöu'll love me at once ♪
♫ The way yöu did once upon a dream ♪