Hurry, hurry, step this way.
Get your tickets now.
Don't be shut out, friend.
Step this way.
See the most wondrous sights
imaginable...
pulled from the four corners
of the Earth.
Acts to delight, to thrill
and to mystify!
Walk through these gates and
into a world of wonder!
She is here, ladies and gents,
live and in person.
That gun-slinging, sharp-shooting
honey-pie of the Wild West.
He has traveled the world and
baffled the crown princes of Europe.
He will amaze!
He will astound!
The Great and Powerful, Oz!
I always knew that I was
destined for show business.
And now look at me.
A magician's assistant.
To think, an hour ago I was
just...
selling oil cakes on the midway.
Yes, well, opportunity comes...
when you least expect it,
my dear.
Wow!
What a get-up.
You won't need this.
Oh.
You are playing the simple
country girl.
Oh!
A gift, in honor of your debut.
Now, this belonged to my
grandmother.
A tsarina from Mirkutsk, and
a decorated war hero.
Your grandmother?
Yes. She was killed in battle,
the poor thing.
Which battle?
Uh-huh.
Well, there are so many.
You've heard of the Battle
of Kreplach?
No.
No? Good.
That's where she died.
And this music box was the
only thing to survive.
But I know that Grammie would
want you to have it.
Professor!
Frank!
The sock is on the door.
We're rehearsing.
How many times do I have to
tell you to knock?
Knock.
I knocked.
What is it?
Showtime.
Why didn't you say something?
Only a half a house.
Here's the take.
Pitiful.
All right,
this is your cut.
For you, the applause will be
approbation enough.
Well, how do you think I feel?
A man of my talents...
I should be playing the Orpheum
Circuit!
Instead of some dusty podunk...
in a second-hand jacket,
falling apart at the seams.
You're gonna have to patch
this thing again.
Again?
Yeah.
Let's go.
Hat!
Hat.
Hat. Okay.
You're the new girl, huh?
Yes.
Good, we needed a new one.
The last one left us.
Poor thing.
Suffered from a broken heart.
Attack.
Heart attack.
But she's resting comfortably
now in Abilene...
expected to make a full recovery.
Perhaps you'd like to join her.
Now, remember, when I ask for
a volunteer...
I raise my hand.
You are overqualified for this
job, my dear.
Let's go make some magic.
Ladies and gentlemen...
the show has already begun.
There are still a few seats
left.
Don't miss your chance to see
Oz, the Great and Powerful!
Journey with me now, across
those deserts...
to the mystical lands of the
Arabian Peninsula.
For 5,000 years...
her lonely spirit has been
trapped.
But tonight, we will attempt
to free her.
I shall require a volunteer
from the audience.
Anyone.
How about you, madam?
Oh!
Yes, I would like to volunteer.
How kind of you.
Please.
Just remember what I told you.
A simple country girl, ladies
and gentlemen.
Now, you have nothing to fear,
just so long as you believe.
For when you do believe...
anything is possible.
You are growing sleepy.
Your eyelids become heavy.
Sleep!
Come, Fernanda!
Allow yourself to merge with
this woman before me.
Can you hear me, oh, Queen
Fernanda?
Yes.
Then rise.
Rise!
I command you to rise!
Rise from your tomb of sand.
Rise as your spirit...
I see a wire!
You are mistaken, sir.
I am not!
There is a wire!
There is a wire holding her up!
A wire?
I see it, too.
It's right there.
Clear as day.
Can't you see 'em'?
He's fooling us.
A wire!
What need have I of wires?
Frank.
Make me walk!
What's that?
Make me walk.
Not now, kid.
Let us leave the wonders...
But I believe in you.
Look, it's not much, but it's
all that we have.
Whatever you could do.
I would make you walk?
It's just...
It's just that...
Well, go on, then.
Make the girl walk.
Make the kid walk.
Come on, you big phony.
Yeah, come on!
I would make her walk, of course...
but unfortunately there is a
distemper in the ether tonight.
Make the kid walk, you big phony.
You see?
I'm sorry, but...
Thank you.
Oz, the Great and Powerful.
Why didn't you close the damn
curtain sooner?
I was dying out there.
There was nothing you could
have done.
I didn't really think it was
that bad.
Of course not.
You're just a trained monkey.
You know, you shouldn't be so
mean to me all the time, Professor.
After all, I'm the only friend
you've got.
Friend?
You're not my friend, Frank.
I don't need a friend.
What I need is someone who knows
when to close the damn curtain.
It's a woman.
Ah!
Finally some good news.
You want me to wind up a
music box?
No.
Not for this one, Frank.
Hey, Annie.
Hello, Oscar.
Hmm.
You look lovely.
Thank you.
What is this?
Gingham?
You know it is.
It was a wonderful show.
Oh, don't tell me you watched
that debacle.
I don't know why you didn't just
tell that poor girl the truth.
What truth? That I'm a fake?
They would have had my head.
And worse, they would have
demanded a refund.
Come on, have a seat.
I'll get you some tea.
Ooh!
It's been a long time.
I haven't seen you since...
The last time you rolled into
town.
It's not often enough, Oscar,
seeing you once every few months.
Well, it is a traveling circus.
How's everything on the farm?
How's your ma'?
She didn't send me a pie this
time.
I hope she's not mad.
I meant to write.
I need to tell you something,
Oscar.
That's never a good start to
a conversation.
John Gale asked me to marry
him.
That's why I've come.
I thought you should know.
Oh.
I think that's... that's
wonderful, Annie.
I said I had to think about it.
Oh, men love that answer.
I wondered what you thought
I should do.
You could do a lot worse than
John Gale.
He's a good man.
So are you.
No.
I'm not.
I'm many things, but a good man
is not one of them.
But you could be.
If you wanted to.
Well, that's just it.
I don't want to.
See, Kansas is full of good men.
Church-going men that get
married and raise families.
Men like John Gale.
Men like my father...
who spent his whole life
tilling the dirt...
just to die facedown in it.
I don't want that, Annie.
I don't want to be a good man,
I want to be a great one.
I want to be Harry Houdini
and Thomas Edison...
all rolled into one.
That's all I ever wanted for
you, you know.
Greatness.
Then you understand.
I do.
But do you?
Uh, Professor, you need to
look outside.
No, Vlad, please.
It was his grandmother's.
Ah!
I'm gonna rip him in half!
No, please!
Get off!
It was just his grandmother's
music box.
It meant nothing.
Oz!
I have to go.
Congratulations on the engagement.
Oscar.
I'll see you in my dreams.
Oz!
I'm gonna rip your head off!
Zim Zallah Bim!
Oz!
There he is!
He's out here!
No, Vlad!
Don't hurt him!
Vlad!
Vlad, no!
Whoa!
I'm gonna crush you, Oz!
I'm gonna crush you!
Oz! Where are you going?
Mr. Baum, I'll catch up with
you in Milwaukee.
Half of that balloon is mine!
And the other half is mine!
All right, you loafers!
Roll up those tents!
Oz!
No, no, no.
You're not getting away!
Where's my thing?
Come here.
Get him down, Clowny.
No, you don't!
Oh, no, you don't!
Ah!
So long, sucker!
Get back here!
Oz!
Oz, you're gonna need these!
Throw it!
Now!
Hat!
Ha-ha!
You're a dead man!
Farewell! Au revoir!
Auf Wiedersehen!
Run!
No, no, no, no, no!
No!
Whoa!
Please, I don't wanna die!
I haven't accomplished
anything yet!
Just get me out of here and
I'll do great things!
Please!
Give me a chance!
I promise!
I promise.
I can change.
Thank you.
Thank you!
Come on, come on!
Oh, no!
No, no. No, no.
Come on, buddy.
I can't swim.
No! I can't swim.
Somebody, help me!
Thank goodness.
I thought I was dead.
Unless you're an angel.
Am I in heaven?
There is still hope for me!
You won't regret this!
I saw you fall from the sky.
Oh. Uh... Yes, my balloon hit,
uh, an inverted thermal.
I couldn't compensate.
I'd get out of the water if
I were you.
Oh.
It's actually quite nice.
I'd be more concerned with
the River Fairies.
Their teeth are small, but
very sharp.
River Fairies?
What's a River Fairy?
Ow!
Get off!
Psst.
Go on, get out of here.
Spiteful little things, aren't
they?
Where... where am I, exactly?
Where do you think you are?
I have no idea.
It's...
It's like no place I've ever
seen.
You're in Oz.
Oz?
But that's my name.
Oscar Zoroaster Phadrig Isaac
Norman...
Henkle Emmanuel Ambroise Diggs.
But everyone calls me Oz.
I knew it!
The king's prophecy was true.
He said that a great wizard
bearing the name of our land...
will descend from the heavens,
and save us all.
And here you are.
Here to claim your throne.
"Claim my throne"?
You mean, like a king's throne?
Well, yes.
Because you will be our king.
Your king?
Like, in a palace, with a crown
and a scepter?
Yes, a beautiful scepter and
a grand palace.
Was that a gold scepter?
Yes, there's more gold than
you could ever imagine.
And Oz will now be what it
once was.
Because you are the Wizard,
aren't you?
I'm the Wizard.
What was that?
The Wicked Witch's minions.
They've been sent here to
kill you.
Kill me?
A wicked witch?
What?
Oh!
We better hurry or your reign
will be over before it's begun!
Whoa!
Oh! Whoa!
Oh!
Come on!
In there!
Give me your leg.
Huh?
Oh... Perhaps the Wicked Witch
has summoned them back.
I don't think I like witches.
What?
I... I, too, am a witch.
I am Theodora, the Good.
You're not a witch.
Of course I am.
Where are all your warts?
Where's your broom?
What would I do with a broom?
Fly.
With a broom?
Never mind.
You were afraid?
That something might happen
to you.
So, this Wicked Witch...
just how wicked is she?
She's as wicked as they come.
She poisoned her own father.
That's pretty wicked.
He was a king and a wizard,
like you.
But she wanted the throne all
to herself.
Poor man.
But my sister chased her away
from the Emerald City.
I can't wait for her to meet you.
She was starting to doubt you'd
ever come, but now she'll see.
And you're going to fix everything.
Yeah.
You know what I think we need?
A little music.
Is that magic?
In a way.
It's a music box.
You've never seen one?
Well, this belonged to my
grandmother.
A tsarina from Mirkutsk.
Go on.
I want you to have it.
No one's ever given me anything
just because they wanted to.
A pretty girl like you?
With the visage of Helen of
Troy, no less?
I'm sure you have dozens of
admirers.
You don't know much about
witches, do you?
Maybe not, but I'm told I'm
a fast learner.
May I have this dance, milady?
Now you're gonna tell me no one's
ever asked you to dance before.
No one ever has.
Then it's high time that you
learned.
Put your hand here.
And your other hand here.
Nice, isn't it?
It's incredible.
Yeah.
Here I thought I'd live a
lonely life...
and then you showed up.
Not only are you the Wizard...
but you're the person I belong
with.
Well, we sure get along.
And...
And?
And.
Like you said, we belong together.
Oh!
I was hoping you would say that.
Yeah.
Help me!
Somebody, save me!
That poor little creature.
Wizard, we must save him.
Somebody, help me.
Oh, no, no, no.
Allow the Wizard.
Help me!
Come on!
Of course I'll save this...
little talking monkey in a
bellhop's uniform.
You, mister!
Please, hurry up.
Do you have anything sharp?
Like a knife or something.
How about your teeth?
What kind of teeth you got?
Calm down, it's gonna be
all right.
You gotta get me out of
these vines.
Calm down.
I'm gonna die.
It's gonna eat me.
Don't worry. These vines aren't
gonna eat you.
Not the vines, the lion!
Lion?
We're gonna die.
We're gonna die!
Eat him first!
Zim Zallah Bim!
Be gone, coward!
Fear my greatness!
You were wonderful, Wizard.
"Wizard"?
You mean the prophecy was true?
Indeed.
All right, well, I've saved
the day.
It was nothing, just a little
prestidigitatic display.
Shall we to the palace?
Yes!
Good day, sir.
Wait, please, sir.
My name is Finley.
My master's home was ransacked
by the Wicked Witch's baboons.
And I've been hiding in these
woods ever since.
But now you've saved my life,
oh, Wizard.
So I hereby swear a life debt
to you.
No... no need.
From this moment on I shall be
your loyal and faithful servant...
until death.
Well, he is cute.
All right, you're hired.
Wonderful.
Let's shake on it!
My bag, monkey.
Surely.
You must travel light.
I got it.
You two run along.
It's the Emerald City.
Just down this hill, along the
Yellow Brick Road.
Wow.
It'll all be ours now.
It's a good thing green is
my favorite color.
You are going to make the best
king Oz has ever known.
Thank you.
And I will be so proud to be
your queen.
My queen?
We'll spend a lifetime together.
But right now, there's thousands
of people in Oz...
waiting to witness your miracles.
Thousands?
That's a big show.
Phew!
What now, Wizard?
Monkey, tell me again about
that life debt.
I devote my life to you.
Mmm-hmm.
Whatever you wish, whatever
you want.
It is my sworn duty to deliver
for you...
until the end of my days.
Mmm-hmm.
And there's no getting out
of it?
None, sir.
It is irrevocable.
Good.
Because I'm not the Wizard.
Oh, sir, your sense of humor is
as boundless, as it is wondrous.
You remind me...
Monkey.
I'm not the Wizard.
Well, you could have told me
before I sealed the life debt.
It's too late.
You got to come clean for that
innocent young girl.
I'll deal with her later.
As my new assistant, all you
need to know are the three "ups".
Show up, keep up, shut up.
But...
What's the third "up"?
Right. Now, listen, I'm
depending on you.
We need to convince the good
people of Oz...
that they've found their wizard.
Hello, Knuck.
Theodora, we've been expecting
you.
I shall blow a fanfare.
No, no, no, no.
No. Not now.
This is the Wizard.
How do you do, sir?
This is the Wizard?
Is there a problem?
Yeah.
Halt.
All hail the Wizard.
The mightiest of mighties.
The greatest, most powerful...
and most genuine of real and
true wizards.
Thank you.
A wizard above scrutiny, with
no covert agenda...
or subversive intention,
whatsoever.
A wizard of the highest moral
rectitude.
He's just a real, good, solid
wizard, everyone.
The Wizard, here he is.
How'd I do?
Forward, march!
Hello?
Guys?
Can I get in the carriage?
Can I please get in the carriage?
I shall blow a fanfare.
Not now.
Is that it?
Is that my throne?
Do you like it?
I do so hope you like it...
because I've been personally
watching over it...
awaiting your arrival.
Oh...
Much obliged.
Praise be you are here at last...
and the prophecy shall be
fulfilled.
Oh, this is a glorious day
for us all.
And may I add, you're as handsome
a king as we've ever had.
Flatterer.
Who is this fetching woman?
This is my sister.
I am Evanora, the royal advisor.
I have been protecting the
Emerald City...
whilst we awaited your arrival.
I am here to serve you as I
served the king before you.
Well, I look forward to being
served.
Oh, sister, I like him already.
Oh... my scepter.
Oh, yes, go on then, have a seat.
How does it feel?
Fits like a glove.
Goodness. Knuck will show you
to your chambers...
and then we can, uh...
we can chat more later.
Can't wait.
Monkey? My bag.
Yes, Wizard, right away, oh,
great and powerful one.
Thank you, sourpuss.
Whoa!
My name is Knuck!
Isn't he wonderful?
Didn't I say he would come?
You dare escort that oaf
in here...
and allow him to climb on
the hallowed throne?
And why not?
He is the Wizard.
"The Wizard."
Or so he says.
Did it not occur to you...
that he might be an imposter in
league with the Wicked Witch...
and sent here to kill us?
The Wicked Witch?
Don't be ridiculous.
Oh, I'm not the one who's
underestimating her cleverness.
Or maybe it's you I'm
underestimating.
Have you finally joined her
side, sister?
I am on no one's side.
You know that.
I simply want peace.
It's all I ever wanted, and
the Wizard can do that.
He's a good man.
Oh, what do you know about goodness?
Deep down, you are wicked.
I am not wicked!
That temper really is wasted
on you.
Do you honestly think...
that I could conspire against
you, with her?
You are my sister and I love you.
All right.
But I do need proof that he
is who he claims to be.
But he has already proven
himself.
Not to me, he hasn't.
Thank you for the tour.
It's my job.
Giving tours?
Taking care of the king.
Of course.
And on that note...
I was thinking it might be
nice to have a royal feast.
Maybe a grand roast.
You know...
my sister has been telling me...
that your magic is really
quite powerful.
Oh, really?
Yes, uh, boggling to the minds
of all who witness it.
Oh, I do wish I could see it
for myself.
Yes.
Why not show me now?
Now?
Here.
All things in good time.
And a good time for all things.
So wise, so true.
Well, um, there is one last
room...
that I would like you to see.
The royal treasure of Oz.
It belongs to whoever is king.
It's all right, Wizard.
Go and enjoy your riches.
It's mine!
Mine!
Oh, no more second-hand suits
for you, baby!
Nothing but the silks and satins!
Ali Baba!
And one of these things!
What is this?
A chalice.
A chalice!
I've always wanted a chalice.
And now I've got one.
Well, uh, not quite yet.
You see, you only become the
king...
after you defeat the Wicked
Witch.
That's the prophecy.
And since you haven't done that
yet, you're not...
I'm not actually king.
Not yet, no.
You still have to get rid of
the Wicked Witch.
Right.
And killing her won't be easy.
No, I don't suppose it will be.
Mmm.
Wait a minute.
No one said anything about
killing anybody.
Oh. Well, if you're not
interested in being king...
that's all right with me.
We can just forget about the
whole thing.
The gold and the rubies, the
chalice.
I'm interested!
I...
I'm just not too keen on killing
a lady.
She's not a lady.
She's a wicked witch.
And your magic is the only thing
strong enough to destroy her.
All you have to do is journey
to the Dark Forest...
and destroy her wand.
Her wand.
Yes.
It's the source of all her power.
Without it, she dies.
I haven't even said goodbye to
Theodora. She will be upset.
I will talk to her in the
morning.
I will tell her how much you
love her, how much you...
No.
No, don't... don't say anything.
All right. I will say whatever
it is you want me to say...
but are you going to save us
all, or not?
I'm your wizard.
We're really gonna do this?
How hard could it be to kill
a wicked witch?
Hard.
Really hard.
It's very, very hard to kill
a wicked witch.
And what about that poor girl,
back there?
I think she really liked you.
She'll get over me.
They always do.
She's a pretty young witch.
There'll be plenty of wizards
knocking at her door.
Oh, every lie you tell gets us
one step closer...
to the Emerald City dungeon.
Then don't think
of them as lies.
Think of them as stepping stones
on the road to greatness.
Wait, I got it.
We'll turn around and go back.
You'll come clean.
You apologize for lying about
being the Wizard...
and for lying to that poor
girl. Okay?
You gotta really seem contrite.
You gotta sell it.
Maybe you could even cry. Can
you cry? I could cut up an onion.
We're not going back.
We're gonna find this wicked
witch...
steal her wand...
I'll get that big pile of gold...
and you can have a nice pile
of bananas, all right?
Bananas.
Oh, I see.
Because I'm a monkey, I must
love bananas, right?
That is a vicious stereotype.
You don't like bananas?
Of course I love bananas.
I'm a monkey, don't be ridiculous.
I just don't like you saying it.
How about this?
We offer to wash all the windows
in the Emerald City...
for an entire year.
Uh-huh.
They'd have to forgive us.
Or, we could give them a little
help with their infrastructure.
I noticed some yellow brick
potholes, back there.
That looks bad.
We're not going down there.
Someone might need our help.
Not that you care.
Get back here!
You get back here!
We gotta get the Wicked Witch.
What are we doing over here?
What happened here?
Hello?
Hey, there.
Are you all right?
Don't worry, we're not gonna
hurt you.
This is Finley.
Hi.
My name is Oz.
Are you...
are you the Wizard?
You've heard of me.
Everyone has.
Good. Then you know there's
nothing to be afraid of.
So, just come on out of there.
But I can't.
Oh.
All right, hold on.
Get this off of you.
Oh, no.
I'll never get back together.
Don't worry.
I think I have something.
Give me that bag.
I, uh, packed something.
There it is.
What is that?
Magic in a bottle.
Magic?
Let's give it a try.
All right.
Just give it a little dab.
Like so.
Okay.
Should work.
There we go.
Ta-da!
Oh, no, no, no!
They're coming back!
It's okay.
They're gone.
The Wicked Witch sent them.
Why?
Last night...
the whole town was celebrating
out in the streets...
because we had heard that you
finally arrived.
Me?
Everyone was so happy.
But then...
but then those things flew in.
And then...
and then they...
Here we go.
Last piece.
Would you like to try to stand?
There.
All right.
There we go.
Easy.
Okay.
I'm gonna let you go.
Oh!
Okay.
Now walk to me.
I don't think I can.
I think you can.
Come on.
All right.
You did it.
Thank you.
All right, this is it.
Just head on down that way,
about two, three hours.
You'll hit the Emerald City.
Tell them I sent you, they'll
take great care of you.
Nice meeting you.
But...
I wanna go with you.
What?
Aw...
On a witch hunt?
No, you're just a little girl.
I'm not as delicate as I look!
That didn't hurt.
I'm coming with you.
Listen, we have one rule in
show business.
Never work with kids, or animals.
And I'm already working with
this thing.
Relax.
The answer's no.
Oh, no, no, no.
Don't... don't do that.
You're fine.
You're gonna leave me alone!
Look, you're... you're fine.
On a road, in the middle of
nowhere?
All you have to do is take
the Yellow Brick Road.
You'll get there.
It's crying again, what do
I do?
Oh, no.
Off.
Come on, off.
Off of there!
Scat! Get off!
Please let me come with you.
No!
Get off of there!
I promise I won't bother you!
No dolls on the witch hunt!
Please, let me come!
Fine.
Fine!
You wanna come, come.
We'll all go, it'll be a big
party.
Great. Let's go kill ourselves
a witch!
You'll die, you'll die, you'll
die!
Did those crows just say we
were gonna die?
They did.
Wizard?
Come on.
I'm scared.
Think there are ghosts out here?
No.
Of course not.
Evil spirits, maybe?
The undead?
Will you stop that?
No.
Get off!
Something's got my tail.
Something's got my tail!
Will you calm down?
No!
What is it?
Look out!
I wanna go home!
Hey!
Hat!
Thanks.
Look out!
Come on.
Hate the Dark Forest.
Oh, my gosh.
That was close.
Where are we?
This must be the place.
So, how are you gonna kill
the Wicked Witch?
All I need to do is get her
magic wand.
Once I destroy that, she's
finished.
Why don't you just use this?
It's got a knife!
Where'd you get that?
I'm made of china.
I gotta protect myself somehow.
Give me that.
Hey!
Honestly.
Honestly yourself.
Look.
That must be her.
Come on.
She put down the wand.
But how are we gonna get it?
Hey!
Now, listen up.
Here's the plan.
The Wicked Witch is the triangle.
Monkey, you're the X.
I'm the O.
China Girl, you're the squiggly
line.
I wanna be a heart.
Can I be a heart?
All right, fine.
You're a heart.
Okay, now, heart stays here...
as O makes his way over here.
X counters thusly.
Clear so far?
Bless you.
Good work.
You just sneezed away the plan.
Sorry.
Never mind.
Just go over there and make
some of your animal noises.
I'll grab the wand when she's
not looking.
Get out of here.
Yes!
Come on, come on.
Oh, no!
Moo!
A cow?
Come on, come on.
Hurry!
I got it!
Break it.
Break it, Wizard.
All right.
Break it!
Did you say "Wizard"?
No!
Are you really the Wizard?
Um... that's a complicated
question.
I mean, what is a wizard?
I...
Um...
I'm the Wizard.
Then there's hope.
What's going on?
Not sure.
I sneezed the plan away.
I have waited so long to
meet you.
So, we've never met?
Certainly not.
I'd remember a thing like that.
You've never been to Kansas?
What is Kansas?
Is that where you're from?
My, you must have traveled very
far to get to the Land of Oz.
I did.
I'm Glinda, the Good.
The Witch of the South.
I thought Evanora was the
Good Witch.
Evanora is the true Wicked Witch.
Conniving and as cruel as
they come.
She's fooled most everyone,
including her own sister.
She made everyone believe that
I poisoned my father...
but it was her.
Then...
she's the one who destroyed
my village?
I'm so sorry, child.
Here's your wand.
Sorry I mooed.
And to think, you almost killed
Glinda for a bit of gold.
A bit?
There were mountains of it,
buddy.
Not that I was going to do it.
I wasn't really going to break
your wand.
Follow me.
Okay.
No.
No, no, no, no, no.
It cannot be!
Curse you, Glinda.
You should be dead.
I'll see you dead, yet.
Curse you and your pretty
little face.
Sister?
Sister, the Wizard is missing.
I've looked everywhere, but
he's gone.
What is it?
Where is the Wizard?
Where's the Wizard?
With Glinda.
Then it's happening.
Oh, sister, he's fulfilling
the prophecy.
He'll bring her darkness to the
light and peace to the land.
Yes, I'm certain that's what
is happening. It must be.
Where did you get that?
This?
Oh.
It was a gift.
From him.
He came to my chambers last night.
Oh, how we danced!
For hours, it seemed.
Oh, I can still feel his body
pressed against mine.
Oh, sister, you were right
about him.
He is the great Wizard.
He must be, to make me feel
the way I feel.
Oh, no.
Not you, too, sister?
He said we would rule Oz
together.
He said I would be his queen.
Did he?
Are you quite sure it wasn't
you who said it to him?
You fool!
Serves you right.
I want Glinda and that wizard
torn to shreds.
Do not fail me a second time.
Fly!
On the day my father died, we
lost a kind and noble leader.
And a dark shadow was cast
across this land.
I've had to stand alone
against Evanora and watch...
as towns were destroyed, children
were orphaned...
and my heart was broken.
I've been unable to protect the
good people of Oz by myself.
With only faith in my father's
prophecy, I've waited.
For you...
great Wizard from Kansas, to
come and set things right.
Oh.
So, that's the prophecy.
Um...
you see, when I agreed to
be king...
I didn't realize how complicated
all of this was.
She knows.
What?
Evanora knows you know the
truth now. Look!
Oh, no.
Uh...
What do we do?
Wizard, now is the time.
The time?
Use your magic.
Oh...
My magic.
Yes. Uh...
I think we should run.
Run?
Yeah.
You heard the Wizard.
Run!
Let's get out of here!
Let's go!
They're gaining on us!
What are you doing?
Is... is that gonna stop them?
I don't know.
Nice work.
We lost them.
Phew!
That was close.
Yeah.
Wait, I hear something.
They're getting closer!
Wait for me!
Look out!
Monkey!
Little China Girl!
Wizard!
I'm over here!
Help! Catch me, please!
Got you!
Are you all right?
Yes.
I'm okay, too.
Just go!
Great!
A bunch of fog.
This is her big idea on how
to save us?
Well, it was the best I could
do, under the circumstances.
Uh...
Oh, okay.
Whoa!
Catch her!
Get me!
Don't let go!
Monkey, grab her!
Pull my tail.
Ow!
Not so hard.
They're getting closer!
What do we do?
Just do what I do.
Unless you've got something.
Uh...
No, you go.
Wait.
What are you doing?
Wanda!
Where are you going?
She said to do what she did.
Just because she jumped off
the cliff...
you're gonna jump off the
cliff?
I have wings.
What about me?
Come on!
Um...
Whee!
Whoa!
Oh! Oh!
Wow.
Whoa!
Oh!
Oh, oh, oh!
These things go kind of fast,
huh?
Hey, is... is that a wall?
Of sorts.
It repels our enemies and
protects us from harm.
But we're headed straight
for it.
Yes, we are.
And going very fast.
How do you, uh...
Does this thing have any brakes?
Uh...
I'm going too fast!
I'm gonna die!
You needn't worry, Wizard.
It's a magic wall.
And all good-hearted souls get
to pass through.
I'm gonna die!
Wanda!
Oh!
It's beautiful.
They've waited a long time
for you, Wizard.
All hail the great and powerful
Oz!
Hail!
Thank you!
Wow, you're a wonderful crowd.
You put the "merry" back in
"the merry Land of Oz."
Hi, what's your name?
You're very beautiful.
Oh, thank you.
Girls, listen, I am not a toy.
I am not a toy!
Oz!
Hello!
What?
No fireworks?
What are fireworks?
Remind me to show you, sometime.
Glinda, I didn't know if you'd
like these, or these.
They're both so beautiful,
I couldn't possibly decide.
We need your help, Wizard.
Please save us!
You know, I should tell you,
um...
I might not actually be a wizard.
Yes, I know.
Oh.
At least, not any kind of wizard
we were expecting.
You could tell?
I can also tell you're weak,
selfish...
slightly egotistical, and
a fibber.
I see. Anything you don't know
about me?
Whether or not you'll save
my people.
Uh, no. I just told you I'm
not the Wizard.
But they don't know that.
If you can make them believe,
then you're wizard enough.
These are desperate times,
after all.
Can you make them believe?
Will I still get that gold?
Uh-huh.
Good people of Oz.
Your Wizard is here!
What's the matter, sister?
Look at how happy they are.
Do you think she'll be his queen?
Well, of course she'll be
his queen.
What did you expect?
You can't compete with Glinda's
charms.
No one can.
Oh, God.
Sister, it hurts.
Such is a broken heart.
Your precious wizard did that
to you.
Make it stop.
Would you like me to?
One bite, is all it takes.
One bite, and your world will
change forever.
One bite, and your heart will
become impenetrable.
One bite, and you and I will
finally share the throne.
Unless you'd rather see Oz
and Glinda there.
You're the wicked one.
Not Glinda!
Sister, you lied to me.
It's nice, isn't it?
How clear everything becomes.
What is happening to me?
Oh, it's just your heart
withering away.
Fear not, Theodora, for soon you
will feel nothing at all, except...
beautiful wickedness.
Sister?
Oh, sister, you're hideous.
I can cast a simple enchantment...
and have you looking just the
way you were before.
No!
This is who I am, now.
I want him to see me like this.
I want him to know that he was
the one who made me this way.
Oh, dear.
It's imperative that you behave
like the great leader...
that they think you are.
Morale is essential, if we have
any hope of defeating Evanora.
And I assume you have a plan.
No.
You have a plan.
You're going to lead us into
battle and take back the throne.
And do we have an army to help
do this?
Of sorts.
The Quadlings, Your Highness.
You're soldiers?
No, sir.
Farmers, mostly.
Farmers?
But you can fight.
No, sir.
Many of us can hoe.
Oh, you can hoe.
And I can work with iron.
That's good.
I bake bread.
Yummy.
I can sew.
Not so helpful.
I can make a scarecrow.
Ah!
Well, that'll come in handy.
It might.
Hmm.
And these are the Tinkers.
Are you kidding me?
We're tougher than we look,
Wizard.
What they lack in stamina, the
Tinkers make up for ingenuity.
They can build anything.
And I'll tell you what else.
We can build anything.
Yeah, I got it.
And we're prepared to storm
the Emerald City.
If you don't keel over, on the
way there.
Ow!
And, finally, the Munchkins.
Please tell me, you gentlemen
can fight.
No.
But we make pretty clothes.
Also, we sing.
Uh, no, that won't be necessary.
I like it, I think it's cute.
I hope you like it.
The prophecy was clear...
the wind would bring you here.
And so it was a man named Oz...
would magically appear.
All right, enough.
So, sound the battle call.
The Wicked Witch will fall.
And so it is the wondrous Wiz...
will come to save us all!
All right, that's enough!
Munchkins, stop!
They do make beautiful clothes.
All right.
Now listen, Wanda.
Glinda.
Guys, um, take five.
Uh, Glinda, these are all very
lovely people.
But do you honestly believe that
they can kill a wicked witch...
and an army of flying baboons?
I don't expect them to kill
anyone.
What do you mean?
I mean the good people of Oz
are forbidden to kill.
Forbidden to...
You want me to lead an army
that can't kill?
If this was easy, we wouldn't
need a wizard, would we?
Somethings wrong!
Look!
What is that?
The wall!
What's happening?
The Wicked Witch isn't powerful
enough to get through the wall.
It looks like she's managing.
Not by herself, she isn't.
What does that mean?
Is someone helping her?
Everyone, take cover!
Run quickly!
Take cover!
Get the children to safety!
Run!
Glinda!
There's so much good here.
It sickens me.
Ah!
Still think your Wizard can
save you from the likes of me?
Speak up, or I will tear out
your tongue!
Now, who is that?
Don't you recognize me, Wizard?
Have I changed so much?
Theodora?
May I have this dance?
Huh?
Hey, hey!
I get it!
You're a little upset!
Theodora, stop.
You're hurting him.
Theodora, what happened to you?
You happened to me.
This isn't you.
It's your sister.
She's worked her magic on you.
I'd hoped you'd be able to
see through her.
Oh, Glinda, so naive.
Just like your father.
That's why it was so easy for
my sister to kill him.
She only killed a man, not what
he believed in.
Begone, Witch, before the Wizard
makes mush of you!
Oh.
How sweet.
You all believe in him.
Well, so did I, once.
And as for you...
my pretty one...
when I return with my sister
and her army...
the Yellow Brick Road will be
red with the blood...
of every Tinker, farmer and
Munchkin in your kingdom.
You underestimate us, Theodora.
We are a strong and united
people.
And now the Wizard is here
to lead us.
And as for your Wizard...
he will be the first to die.
And you will all see that he
is nothing but a deceitful...
selfish and extremely mortal man.
Give me that!
It was a broom that you wanted.
Wasn't it, Wizard?
It's all right.
It's all right!
She's gone now.
Don't be frightened.
Now that the Wizard is with us...
Wizard?
Leaving?
But you promised to help us.
Yeah, well, that was before
I knew what we were up against.
An army and yet another wicked
witch?
This one bent on destroying
everyone, especially me?
We can defeat them.
There must be something.
Something we haven't thought of.
Something that we're not seeing.
Something we're just on the
verge of.
Glinda.
You need a real wizard.
Better yet, a general.
But you're all I have.
So, you're not the wizard
I was expecting.
So, you don't have the powers
I thought you'd have.
But you're here.
There must be a reason.
Maybe you're capable of more
than you know.
Glinda, I wish I had the answer.
But I'm just a con man.
I'm a carnival magician.
I'm just not the man you want
me to be.
Someone needs to tuck me in.
Yes, of course.
Allow me.
My papa used to do it.
I see.
Perhaps you'd prefer the Wizard,
then?
Yes, please.
All right.
In you go.
Here you are.
Uh-uh.
Just a moment.
Bring forth the covers, now.
Yes, ma'am.
Comfy?
All right.
Goodnight.
Do you grant wishes?
Do I what?
Grant wishes.
The old wizard could grant
wishes.
Ah.
People would travel to the
Emerald City...
and ask him for things.
And if they were good and
noble wishes...
he would grant them.
Is that right?
Do you know what I'd wish for?
Hmm.
A pretty dress?
To have my family back.
I know.
I'm sorry.
I can't grant wishes.
I'm not that kind of wizard.
That's what I thought.
Um, you see, where I come from
there aren't any real wizards.
Although, there is one.
Thomas Alva Edison.
The Wizard of Menlo Park.
A truly great man.
Did he grant wishes?
No.
But he could look into the
future and make it real.
He created the electric light,
the phonograph.
He created a camera that could
take moving pictures.
Pictures that move?
Yeah.
Can you imagine?
And all he had was a little
bit of wire and some glass.
With almost nothing, he made
the impossible real.
Is that the kind of wizard
you are?
It's the kind of wizard I'd
like to be.
Well, you are that kind.
I can tell.
I'd rather you grant wishes,
but that's a good wizard, too.
Goodnight, Wizard.
Glinda.
I've got it.
What have you got?
I've got a way out of this mess.
What is this?
A battle plan.
It's all in there.
Illusion, misdirect, sleight
of hand.
Look...
I know I'm not the wizard
that you were expecting...
but I might just be the wizard
that you need.
You said you were just a con man.
Precisely.
Nothing but a trickster?
A terrible cheat?
The best there is.
The carnival magician's going
to put on a show.
I'll put on the show of a
lifetime.
The likes of which the Land of
Oz has never seen!
Magic, mystery, prestidigitation!
It'll be my greatest trick, yet.
Tinkers, gather around!
Quickly, now.
This is what you're gonna build.
Where I come from, this is
called a praxinoscope.
Although, I've made a few
modifications.
It allows you to project an
image into space.
Impossible.
Nothing's impossible if you
put your mind to it.
Bully.
Bully!
These three roads all lead to
the Emerald City.
To the east are the deadly
poppy fields.
We'll have to steer clear of them.
Why is that?
One good whiff and it's
everlasting sleep.
And we're not exactly a terrifying
army when we're awake.
All right.
We'll steer clear.
Or maybe not.
In the conjuring business,
flash is always good.
Gives the audience a little "wow".
You gentlemen will be combining
sulfur rock, nitrate of potash...
and charcoal to create what is
commonly known as black powder.
Whoa!
Mr. Quimby, we need 200 bales
of hay...
delivered to the main road
by noon.
Mr. Zim, have the Quadling
carts...
Looks good.
My very own Winkie Guards...
soon you will be facing Glinda
and her army of weaklings.
And when they see our towering
might...
they will run and flee for the...
hills and...
No!
We shall not let them flee!
We shall show them no mercy!
Now, I've added this adjustable
lens to your design...
along with a few other things.
Have a look.
Yes!
Edison himself would be proud.
Now, there's something else
I need you to do.
But I'd rather you just keep
it between us.
Yes?
Do you know how to build a
hot air balloon?
This is all very impressive...
but you still haven't told me
how you plan...
to get this thing into Emerald
City.
Relax.
I know someone.
What do you mean, you know
someone?
Hello, Wizard.
Well, well, well.
If it isn't ol' Sourpuss.
My name is Knuck!
Now, you two be nice to each
other.
Let's move it, Wizard.
Can you give me a break?
I'll break your nose!
Guess I'm up.
Time to do what I do, right?
Cue the con man.
Would you stop? A con man
couldn't have done all this.
You're much more than that.
Well, then, it looks like I've
got you fooled, too.
The only person you've got
fooled, is yourself.
For protection.
Not that you need it.
Great people of Oz.
Today we fight to free the
land...
from the villainy of the
Wicked Witches.
We are few...
but we are mighty!
Quadlings!
Tinkers!
Bully!
Munchkins!
We face great odds, but we are
armed with our courage...
our hard work, and most of all...
our faith in one another.
We have nothing to fear, as long
as we believe.
For when we do believe...
anything is possible!
Onward!
Halt!
Good day there, fellow Winkie
guardsman.
What is your business here?
Supplies for battles.
We bring supplies for battle.
I was told of no such delivery.
Where are your papers of transit?
Why this delay?
Do you not recognize me?
I'm Knuck, the City Herald.
Sir, I'm just trying to do my...
What I meant was...
Hmm?
Let them pass!
Let them pass.
What's this?
They dare march on us?
Tear them apart!
Fly!
It's a trick.
Pull!
Retreat!
Curse you!
Oh, it's not over yet.
The fog is lifting!
Quadlings, fall back.
Into the woods!
Watch out!
Ah!
Away with her.
Oh!
Herald.
Great Wizard.
Who's this?
Emerald City underground.
Unload the carriage.
Yes, sir.
To the rear.
Let's go!
Let's go.
You two, get the trolley.
Everything's ready.
All we need now is you.
Yeah, come on.
I just have to do one thing,
first.
There's no time.
Get this carriage in position.
Yes, sir.
Hurry!
I told Glinda you would do this.
She said I was wrong about you.
I guess I wasn't.
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about that thing
the Tinker built.
The balloon.
What balloon?
That's my cue.
All right, you guys.
Just remember, stick to the plan.
Stick to the plan?
The plan was you.
We're supposed to stick to you.
You guys will do great.
So long.
Come back!
We can't do it alone.
Wizard!
Wizard, I don't know what to do!
Citizens of Emerald City...
witness what happens when you
defy me.
Glinda did very well for herself
today, I'll admit.
Leave her alone!
Unchain her, you witch!
We know the truth.
You poisoned the king!
Guards!
Get them under control.
The citizens of Emerald City
will not tolerate this!
We will not!
Silence!
Ooh.
What should I do now?
I'd get your sister and fly
out of here.
Really?
While you still can.
Well, I think I'm going to do
something quite different...
and I'm going to do it...
ooh, very, very slowly, because...
I just can't take the sight
of that...
pretty, pretty face.
Ooh, I'm going to wipe out
your light...
until there is nothing left
but my darkness.
I have been waiting for this
for a long time.
Oh, no.
He said it was going to be his
greatest trick, yet.
Did he tell you the trick was
on us?
How predictable.
I knew that buffoon of yours
couldn't be the Wizard.
Out of my way!
Give up, Glinda.
Why do you continue to resist?
Because I believe in the Wizard.
So did I, once.
Behold!
Your Wizard!
Where is he going?
He's abandoning us.
How could he?
No!
Aw!
Not so great and powerful,
after all.
You, there!
Move back!
Hey!
Hello, monkey.
Oz!
I thought you were dead.
Shh.
You were crying pretty hard.
Was that for me?
Oh, no. Some of the smoke got
in my eyes.
Oh, right.
Wow, you fooled everybody.
That was your greatest trick,
yet.
That was just the opening act.
Let this be the final word.
Your prophecy is dead.
Like the king who spoke it, and
the wizard who tried to fulfill it...
all dead.
It's showtime.
And they will be joined in death
by Glinda, the Good.
Farewell.
Say hello to your daddy for me.
The dreams of the people live on.
Fear me not, good people of Oz.
Fear me not.
For it is I...
the great and powerful...
Wizard of Oz!
More tricks?
After everything.
How dare you defy us!
Dare?
How dare you, wicked sisters?
No one defies Oz!
Guards.
Destroy him.
Forward!
Attack!
Guards!
Come back here, this instant!
You thought you could kill me?
Me?
Thanks to you, I've shed my
mortal shell...
and taken my true ethereal form.
I'm now more powerful than ever!
I'm invincible!
Do you still doubt me?
Doubt you?
I defy you!
Beautifully done, sister.
Thank you.
Hurry.
You're taking too much time.
Hold...
hold...
They think they're winning.
Turn it back on!
What?
Oh, we got a loose wire.
Oi!
Screw's stuck.
Hold on.
Use this.
Got it.
Right.
This can't be.
You cannot defeat me.
I'm immortal!
I am the great and powerful
Wizard of Oz!
Now witness and observe...
as I unleash the stars!
Behold!
So, those are fireworks.
He is the Wizard.
We got Evanora.
She's on the run!
All right!
We got one!
Yeah!
Come back here, you coward!
Glinda.
It's you.
And you said that I was the
weak one!
I may not be able to kill you.
Now.
Okay.
But I can kill the one you love.
Higher.
I'm trying.
Ready!
Fire!
Begone, Wicked Witch!
Begone!
I hate you.
Begone, forevermore!
The Witch is gone!
The Witch is gone! Yes!
Whoo-hoo!
Bully, bully!
I knew we could do it.
Right.
Theodora, I know your wickedness...
is not your doing.
And should you ever again...
find the goodness within you...
you are welcome to return.
Never!
Not so fast.
You and I aren't finished yet.
You have the throne, Glinda.
What more could you want?
You can't give me that.
You took what mattered most
to me.
My father.
I'll never again feel the
comfort of his kindness...
but I'll settle for the freedom
of his people.
Of course, Glinda.
I think at the very least, they
deserve that.
What's the matter, Glinda?
Out of bubbles?
I don't need them.
Bubbles are just for show.
What have you done?
Look what you've done to me!
Now everyone will see you as
you truly are.
In the name of my father, I banish
you from the Emerald City...
never to return.
Good people of Oz...
I have here a missive from the
great Wizard, himself.
"With little more than pluck
and belief...
we made the impossible happen.
As your Wizard, I hereby decree...
the Land of Oz will forever
be free."
Okay.
Close the curtains, please.
I'm trying.
All right.
Let's give it a try.
Is it on?
Is this thing working?
It's wonderful.
Well.
If it isn't the most beautiful
witch in all of Oz.
Hi, Glinda.
Hello, Wizard.
Well done, Tinker.
Your machine works beautifully.
That's just workmanship.
What you displayed was real
courage.
Your father would have been
more than proud.
He would have marveled at the
woman you've become.
Zim Zallah Bim!
Excellent work, everyone.
Now we're ready, in case anyone...
wants to speak with the Wizard.
Now, remember...
Oscar Diggs died...
so that the Wizard of Oz
could live.
When those witches come back,
and they will come back...
we're going to need everyone
to believe.
Your secret's safe with us.
Good.
And now it's time for some
gifts.
Gifts?
Gifts!
Knuck, not now.
What kind of gifts?
Well, you know I can't grant
wishes...
so this will have to do.
First, the Master Tinker.
To the man who can make
anything, my lucky...
thingamajig.
May it assist you in the
reconstruction...
of the Emerald City.
I will cherish this forever.
Thank you for your faith in me.
And now, for Sourpuss.
My name is Knuck!
Sourpuss, I grant you something...
you are in need of most.
Something that, where I come
from...
can turn the saddest day...
into a happy one.
I don't want that.
It is yours.
Take it back.
I cannot.
Knuck...
you look nice with a smile.
You do look nice.
Thank you.
Finley, you stood by my side...
when any monkey in his right
mind would have flown away.
To you, I give something that
I've never given to anyone.
My friendship.
Now you're my partner.
You're my friend.
That's all I ever really
wanted.
My turn, my turn.
Come here.
I'm afraid I can't give you what
I know you want most of all.
All I can offer you is this.
It's us.
I know it's not the family
that you had in mind.
It's perfect.
Thank you.
I wonder what you're gonna get.
Oh, I don't need anything,
child.
You better have something
for Glinda.
But of course.
I've saved the best for last.
For you...
a sight envied by all and seen
by none.
You'll be astounded...
by what you find behind the
curtain.
Oh, my!
It's very tight in here.
It's nice, isn't it?
I know what you're up to,
Wizard.
What?
I'm just giving you a tour.
And I want to thank you.
For opening my eyes.
And what do you see?
That I have everything I ever
wanted.
For the record, I knew you had
it in you, all along.
Greatness?
No.
Better than that.
Goodness.
Now, Knuck.