This is
the story of a puppy.
His name is
El-i
Elliot.
His name is Elliot.
You got it.
He is going on an
adventure
An adventure.
What's that?
An adventure?
You don't know what an adventure is?
What we're on right now.
Out here in the wild,
not another soul in sight
for hundreds of miles,
with just the stars to guide us.
Is it scary?
Well, that's the other thing about adventures.
You gotta be brave.
Are you brave?
Of course you are.
I think you are the bravest boy
I've ever met.
Momma.
Are you gonna eat me?
As long as people have been
going into these woods,
there have been stories
about the Millhaven dragon.
How does that song go again?
They come from the North, right?
Way up there in the mountains
where few people have ever been.
But sometimes,
a dragon gets lost from its family
and winds up very, very far from home.
They say it lives in these very woods.
That you can hear its roar at night.
They say this, they say that,
but, as far as I know...
not one soul has ever
actually seen this dragon.
Except me.
You saw a dragon?
I sure did.
What'd it look like?
Well, it was green.
Green all over.
Except for his eyes.
His eyes were red.
Like hellfire.
Before I could even blink,
it rears back its head,
opens its mighty jaw,
and shoots out.
So, I wasn't gonna waste my breath I...
rolled out the way, scrambled to my feet
ready for the fight that was gonna come.
But as I raised my rifle
the dragon comes at me
with one swipe of its claw
knocks the gun right out of my hands.
Now, now what?
Things are really not looking good here.
But I wasn't gonna be done. Not yet.
I just took out my pocket knife.
And as the dragon set upon me,
I drove it home.
Scaring the kids again, Dad?
No, no, no.
I was just giving them a leg up
on what's out there in those woods.
Well, I'm out in those woods every day
and while I have seen bears and bobcats
and just about every type
of bird you can imagine.
I have never seen a dragon.
Just because you don't see something,
doesn't mean it's not there.
And just because you say it's true,
doesn't mean it is.
But, I'm headed out there right now.
I'll let you all know if I see anything
big and green and breathing fire.
Mr. Meacham, I believe you.
Well, I'm glad you do.
See, my daughter,
she knows a thing or two but
only if it's staring at her in the face.
If you go through life only seeing
what's right in front of you
you're gonna miss out on a whole lot.
See, and that's where
you guys have the upper hand.
Because mark my words
that dragon is still out there.
And if you were to go
out there to those woods
where no one ever goes,
then you might find him.
Unless, he found you first.
Gotcha!
Hey, Elliot!
What was that for?
Come on, Elliot!
Elliot?
Elliot!
Come on!
Higher!
What are you looking at?
This way?
We're pretty far from home.
There you are.
No one's gonna cut you down now.
You ready to go, Grace?
Yeah.
Just a second.
Come on, Grace. Not again.
I'm just settling a score.
One for Jack. One for you?
Yeah. Something like that.
Aren't you two supposed
to be getting hitched?
Yep! Just keeping him on his toes.
Look.
Elliot!
Pete and Elliot
are
going
and
then
Then they go down, and down,
and down!
And then...
I wonder where that lady came from.
Don't worry.
I won't let her hurt you.
Good night, Elliot.
Elliot.
Timber!
Hey, Gavin.
Did Jack give the okay to cut this deep?
Don't worry about Jack.
Just keep cutting.
Who said it was okay to be here?
I just go where they tell me.
Where's Jack?
There he is!
This is so out of line, Jack.
You're not supposed to be cutting
anywhere near this deep.
I didn't know anything about this either.
This wasn't my call, Grace.
Then, whose was it?
Of course.
Let me handle this, please?
You don't handle it.
That's the problem.
You're right, and Gavin is Gavin.
He's my brother.
Hey, I have to get to school.
Could you wait in the truck, sweetheart?
We'll just be a minute.
Let's go through the maps.
Let's review them.
Hello?
Wait!
Where are you?
How'd you get up there?
Come on!
Slow down.
You're pretty good at this.
Help!
Don't let go!
No!
Don't!
I'm hurt!
How old are you?
Five?
You're pretty big to be a five-year-old.
What's your name?
Pete.
You look like a Pete.
My name's Natalie.
Natalie!
Daddy!
What were you thinking?
You can't run away like that.
What happened to you?
I fell out of a tree.
You fell out of a tree?
What were you doing in a tree?
Following him.
His name is Pete.
Hey.
Pete? Is that your name?
Pete?
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
Where'd you come from?
Do you know where your parents are?
Your family?
Hey.
Where'd you get that?
Wait!
Elliot!
Pete!
Tthere, little buddy.
Where are you going so...
Hey!
Hey, kid! Come back here.
Hey. Come on, boy!
Careful, Gavin!
Doesn't matter.
The sheriff, the rangers, everybody else
are gonna be locking this site down
until they figure out
where that kid came from.
Hey, you hear that?
Don't change the subject, Gavin.
Every time I try and take some initiative
you shut me down.
If we hadn't been cutting out here
we never would've found
that kid in the first place.
We're doing good work here, Jack.
And we need a big score
to help us compete.
What about a few years from now
when we have nothing left to cut down
because you keep jumping the gun?
Where are you going?
Where do you think?
You're not the only family
I gotta worry about.
Let me know how Pete's doing, will ya?
What's wrong, Gavin?
Jack giving you a hard time?
Oh, you know Jack.
He's just sore because
his girlfriend's stepping on his toes.
Redheads, man.
Look out!
What was that?
Let's go hunting.
Pete.
Time to wake up, Pete.
Momma?
Elliot?
How's he doing?
Pretty well, all things considered.
No signs of malnourishment
or serious exposure.
He might have a bump to the head, but
Lucky kid.
Yes sure. Super lucky.
How just...
How'd he get out there?
My guess, he was
on a picnic or a camping trip.
He wandered off from his
family, got himself lost.
Sure, but...
When? It looks like he's been out there for...
Who knows how long.
And he had this.
You sure that's yours?
Pretty sure.
Here we are. All fixed up.
Hey Natalie.
How you feeling?
It was just a scrape. Where's Pete?
I'm gonna take Natalie home Danny,
then head back out to the forest.
Maybe there's something
out there some...
clue or something.
Could you call me when he wakes up?
Of course.
When he wakes up,
I think it would be best
to take things slowly.
One step at a time.
Let him know he's safe.
We don't know what he's been through.
We put in a call in to Social Services.
They'll know exactly how to handle this.
For the time being,
he'll be just fine right here.
Actually, he's gone.
Who's gone, sweetheart?
Pete.
Elliot!
Oh, my goodness!
Macy, stop!
Don't you bark at our dog!
Kid, stop!
Wait, wait!
Damn it! Stop right there.
I've got him.
He's on the corner of Main and
He was on the corner of...
I've lost him.
Hey, look.
Hey, sit down!
Awesome!
Pete!
It's okay.
We're not gonna hurt you.
I promise. All right?
Come here.
Hold on. Hold on.
It's okay. Hold on. Hold on.
Breathe. Breathe.
Breathe.
Hey, guys!
Come check this out.
Hey.
Fresh.
Not even a day old.
What do you think?
A bear?
You ever seen a bear that big?
Thought I did once.
Turns out it was just Bobby's sister.
All right, let's catch me some rabbits.
I'll bring him home tonight.
Okay, thank you so much, Sheriff.
You take care of yourself.
Thank you.
Bye.
Remember, any problems I'm the guy.
Will do.
Hey, Pete.
Don't worry,
you don't have to go
back to the hospital.
We're going to my house.
Okay.
Here we are.
Need a little help?
Pete, no! Wait!
Wait!
Wait! Wait, wait.
You are fast.
Oh, my goodness.
What's wrong, honey?
Are you hungry?
Let's go inside.
Let's go get something to eat.
I want to go home.
I know.
Where is your home?
Can you tell me?
How about this?
If you come inside with me now,
then tomorrow,
I'll take you back out to the woods
and you can show me exactly where you live.
How does that sound?
You know, when I was a little girl
I wanted to live in the forest
more than anything.
I loved being out there.
It was so fun with,
the squirrels,
the birds,
the trees.
So, when I grew up,
I made it my job to protect the woods,
and everything in them.
Which I suppose includes you.
And Elliot?
Who's Elliot?
Grace?
Are you sure about this?
It's just until we found out
where he belongs.
Who knows maybe being around
someone his own age will help him,
open up.
Maybe he'll tell us where he came from.
You don't touch it. You eat it.
Like this.
I gotta admit,
living out in the woods,
doing things his own way,
sounds like a boy after your own heart?
I think we're lost.
Gavin knows what he's doing.
You said that three miles ago.
The river's up around that bend.
We can just follow that,
and we'll be back where we started.
The river's back that way.
We've been going in circles.
I've never been out this far before.
Do you know where we are?
Look at this.
What on Earth?
You've got to see this.
You think that kid did all this?
What would a kid be doing this far out?
Hey, guys! Look at this.
Run!
Hurry up!
Come on! Faster! Run!
Wait for me!
Come on. Get up, get up!
Start the truck!
Where's Gavin?
Come on, man!
Wait!
Come on, let's go!
Go, go, go!
What is that?
Drive, man! Go!
Gavin, come on!
What was that?
Did you see that?
It was a monster!
No, man, that was a demon.
It was a monster demon.
It was a dragon!
You put the needle on, and
Let it play.
So that's me,
and that's my dad.
That's his brother.
There's Grace. That's my family.
Family.
That's what we are.
Put your head here,
scooch down,
and...
now you're five years old.
Now you're six, and now you're seven,
now you're eight, now you're nine
and now you're 10.
I was out here, at the Eastern Pad.
That's the last time
I remember having my compass.
But that's...
Fifty miles east.
From where we found him.
I haven't read that book in forever.
Someone gave it to me when
I was learning how to read, so...
It's okay, buddy.
It's just a phone.
Is this Elliot, Pete?
Is Elliot a person?
No.
Well, what is he, then?
Grace,
it's the Sheriff.
He wants to talk to you.
Hello?
Hey, Grace. How's our mystery boy?
Still a mystery.
Any news?
Well,
Pat went digging through
our missing persons files.
He had to go pretty far back but...
it's not good news.
Poor Pete.
I know.
I just got off the phone
with Social Services.
They're gonna take custody
of him tomorrow morning.
Pete,
is Elliot your imaginary friend?
What's imaginary?
Well, it's where you make
someone up in your head,
so that you have someone to talk to.
It keeps you from being lonely.
Are they funny?
Sure.
Do they fly?
I guess they can do
whatever you want them to.
That's what makes them imaginary.
Are you my imaginary friend, too?
I'm real.
So is Elliot.
Good job, buddy.
Mommy, there's a monster outside.
I need to get back to him.
He gets scared when I'm gone.
He looks like a dragon.
What's a dragon?
That's a dragon.
Like the song.
What song?
There's a song that my dad used to sing.
It's about dragons and where they live.
♪ Go North, Go North ♪
♪ With wings on your feet ♪
♪ Go North with the wind ♪
♪ Where the three rivers meet ♪
♪ Now plant yourself down ♪
♪ side the tallest tree ♪
♪ Measure the stars ♪
♪ shining one two and three ♪
♪ Look all around you and see ♪
♪ Deep in the forest there dragons will be ♪
What's North?
It's a direction.
How do you get there?
Well. You could look at a map.
Or you could follow the North Star.
If you follow it as far as you possibly can
you get to the mountains.
And that's where you'd find them.
The dragons, I mean.
Hey.
I haven't heard that song in forever.
Natalie,
do you think I could talk
to Pete alone for a moment?
Okay.
See you in a minute, Pete.
Hey, come here.
You found this for me,
didn't you?
Where the trees ran away.
My dad gave this to me on my 10th birthday
so that if I ever got lost,
I'd know how to find my way back home.
Pete honey,
do you remember how
you got to the woods?
It was a long time ago, wasn't it?
We were on an adventure.
You know,
I lost my mom when
I was not much older than you.
I know how hard it can be.
But I want you to know,
you are not alone.
I know.
You do?
I have Elliot.
Can you tell me more about Elliot?
Who is he?
He's my friend.
This is Elliot?
He must be a very special friend.
He doesn't like most people.
But I think he'd like you.
He would?
You'll see.
Tomorrow.
When I go home.
You're coming with me, right?
Of course.
You're very brave.
Did you know that?
You might be the bravest boy
I've ever met.
Gavin?
Jack.
What happened to you?
You remember those stories
that Meacham used to tell us?
About dragons?
He wasn't making them up.
We tracked it,
and there was a treehouse.
I tried to shoot it,
but it just ripped the gun
right out of my hands
and bent it like it was nothing.
Gavin, I can't just head out
to the woods in the middle of the night
because you think you saw a dragon.
Think I saw? Jack, I know what I saw.
Yeah.
You don't believe me.
I'll tell you what we'll do.
We'll call the forestry,
we tell them what you saw
and then they can go and deal with it.
Fine. I get the picture.
I thought I could count on family.
Gavin.
Don't worry. See you in the morning.
Elliot Gets Lost.
This is the story of a little puppy.
His name is...
Elliot.
Yeah.
He is going on an adventure
with his family.
They are going camping in the forest.
Elliot has
Wait.
This isn't how I tell it.
Would you like me to stop?
No.
I like it.
Elliot has never been so excited.
Elliot and his boy play,
while Mom and Dad set up the tent.
He is right where he belongs.
You looking for something?
Oh. You scared me.
Why aren't you asleep?
The same reason you're not, I suppose.
I guess you heard about the boy.
I did.
You know, word travels fast in this town.
How long has he been out there?
Six years.
Six years?
Nobody can survive
in that forest for six years.
At least not alone.
Well.
He says...
He says he wasn't alone.
He drew this?
He says it's his friend from the forest.
And it reminded me of...
I know what it reminded you of.
That one?
How old was I when you drew this for me?
Maybe five or six.
Just before your mother passed away.
I remember then,
you hung on every word I ever said.
You were so full of questions.
Dad.
What did you really see out there?
Please, don't tell me another story.
Just tell me what you remember.
What I remember?
What I remember is, I was out hunting...
and the sun was shining down,
and wind was blowing through the trees.
And I remember thinking,
Boy, this is exactly where I belong.
I stopped by a creek to get a drink.
Suddenly I realize
I wasn't in the sun anymore
and I looked up to see
what was blocking the sky.
And what did I see but...
a dragon?
I see a dragon.
I've never been so scared in my life.
But when I raised my gun to shoot,
suddenly there was this feeling, this...
It was like magic.
There's no other word to express it.
It was magic.
So I put my gun down,
and just sat there...
sat there across the creek from each other,
just, just looking.
I just sat there looking.
And then the dragon turned and
disappeared into the woods.
And I remember thinking,
I am one lucky guy.
Of course, nobody believed me.
I knew what people
were saying about me.
I must admit, there were times when
I thought, Maybe they're right.
But then I thought about the magic.
It changed the way I see the world
the way I see trees,
the way I see sunshine
the way even I see you.
I wouldn't trade that for anything.
So, I'm not gonna try to
convince you. I quit that.
But maybe...
maybe can you just be open to...
looking.
I know those woods.
I know those woods
like the back of my hand.
I couldn't have missed a dragon.
Well, you missed Pete.
Pete.
Wake up, honey.
Good morning.
You heading out already?
Yup.
Bright and early.
I'm gonna head over to the mill.
Talk to Gavin about something.
Call me if you need anything.
We'll be fine.
You sure?
Absolutely.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Nothing, I just got...
turned around.
Hey, Pete
I was thinking maybe
we could bring someone with us.
Someone who might know Elliot, too.
Is that okay?
Hey, Jack.
Morning.
Hey, Calvin.
You seen Gavin?
He and Woodrow took a truck
out to the new cut down
with some of the other boys.
What for?
Something about going hunting.
Hunting?
I don't know.
Jack Magary.
Hey, Jack.
Didn't you say Grace was
planning on bringing Pete by?
Yeah, she left an hour ago.
She hasn't shown up yet.
We've got these people standing here.
Don't quite know what to do.
Okay. Okay, thank you, Sheriff.
I gotta go.
This way!
Kids, hold on a second.
Elliot!
I've never seen this part
of the forest before.
Come on!
Cool.
How did you do this by yourself?
Elliot helped. I think he's hiding.
Elliot?
Oh, no, Pete, wait
I'm going in after him.
Grace, wait.
Give it a minute.
Grace?
Dad.
Come on.
What did I tell you?
Magic.
Elliot.
What did I tell you?
I got him!
Gavin?
Grace?
No! No, wait!
Stop!
Get those kids outta here!
Don't kill him! Tranqs only!
Gavin, what are you doing?
He's not dangerous!
He's not gonna hurt.
Will you stop!
I got him!
No!
Stop!
Elliot!
Here we go! Come on, get up!
No!
Bobby, take the shot!
Stop! Elliot!
Fly!
Come on!
Come on! Go! Go!
Elliot.
Watch out!
What is that?
Daddy?
Natalie?
Gavin, what is this?
This...
is the Millhaven dragon.
And I just caught it.
What's the matter, boys?
Ain't you ever seen a dragon before?
Come on.
Pull it into the warehouse.
Into the warehouse.
Check it out, boys. Check it out!
Pete, Grace didn't
mean for this to happen.
She's a beauty, isn't she?
Or he?
It?
Whatever it is.
Just trust me.
Get here as quick as you can.
Natalie.
I need you to wait here
with Pete for a minute, okay?
What's going to happen to Elliot?
I don't know,
but I'm going to go find out, okay?
I just need you to stay here.
Okay? Will you stay here for me?
Okay.
Thank you, sweetie.
Pete, we'll fix this.
I promise.
Okay, then.
Now you've caught it.
What do you plan to do with it?
What am I going to do with it?
Yeah.
Well I know exactly
what I'm going to do with it.
You, you don't have a clue, do you?
Okay, look.
I haven't got it totally figured out yet.
But I'll tell you this...
This thing is gonna put me on the map.
I mean folks will come from miles...
Gavin.
Jack can have the mill.
The dragon is mine.
No, no, no! Stop. Stop.
What are they doing to him?
They're trying to find out
what he is and where he came from.
And why they've never seen him before.
Hey, what are you doing?
Get those guns out of here.
He came from the woods,
just like I did.
Are you serious?
Why can't they just let us go?
We'll go away.
We'll never see anybody again.
It'll be just like it used to be.
But I don't wanna never see you again.
Are you insane?
You have no idea
what this thing is capable of.
And you do?
Yeah.
If he wakes up,
he could take out the whole town
and everyone in it.
Jack, he's a monster.
It's not a monster.
It's an animal.
And it's hurt and it's scared.
Grace, wait.
You need help.
You need Pete.
Did you see that?
Did you just see that?
I sure did.
Let's go.
Up there.
Guys, move. Sheriff!
Sheriff! Sheriff!
Jack.
No, out of the way. Back off.
Sheriff!
Out of the way! Sheriff!
Thanks for coming.
Jack, what's so big
I had to call out the cavalry?
You really have to come inside and see this.
Gavin.
Let me just say one thing first here.
What my brother called you about,
belongs to me, okay?
I caught it fair and square.
So, if anyone tries to tell you
any different, it's mine.
It belongs to me.
I wanna see!
Why are we standing outside?
Can we go in and take a look at it?
Elliot, are you okay?
What's going on in there?
Now, I gotta warn you.
This thing is dangerous.
Me and my crew are the only ones
who know how to deal with it.
So, when you get in there, just stay calm.
Don't startle it.
Don't want anyone getting
eaten on my watch.
Gavin, wait.
Listen, Grace,
we're not in the forest anymore,
so what's in there
You can sit out here
and talk about what's in there
until you're blue in the face.
I just want to see it. Now step aside.
We're waiting over here. Come on.
Push it open.
What's the deal here?
Excuse me, Sheriff.
Seems to be stuck.
Okay, come on. Who's in there?
Hey, open up.
Elliot.
Can you fly?
Hit it harder!
I don't see anything.
It was right here.
What was right here?
It got out.
Come on, we gotta find it!
Make a hole!
What got out?
You gotta see for yourself.
Come on.
Abner, check the yard.
Woodrow, take the south side.
Sheriff, can you get your men to spread out?
We need to call in a chopper,
because this dragon can fly.
A dragon?
Jack, you dragged me all the way
out here for a dragon?
I don't know how to explain it,
but he's telling the truth.
It was here.
It's still in there.
What?
The dragon.
The dragon is still in there.
We have to help them.
How do we get him out of here?
Do you know how to drive?
Sort of,
but my dad's truck doesn't
have this many buttons.
Stop what you're doing, young lady.
Your feet don't even reach the pedals.
Scoot over.
Wait!
I don't want to hurt your friend, son.
I just want to help.
Get in.
Okay, let's see here if this
Hey, old buddy.
You better buckle up.
Hold on tight!
I thought I put it in reverse.
Oh, my...
That isn't real, is it?
Follow that dragon!
Hey! Hey!
Sorry about that.
Tell that dragon to hang on.
We've got company.
Attention all units.
We're eastbound on Millhaven Road,
in pursuit of a...
A dragon! It's a dragon!
You can't say dragon over the radio.
Elliot!
Fly!
Come on.
Faster!
That's Meacham!
Pull over!
Hey, pull over!
Not a chance!
That's my dragon!
He's not slowing down.
He's not stopping.
He'll stop.
That fool's out of his mind.
Stop!
I'm trying.
He ain't that crazy.
Okay, hang on tight.
We're going to have to do this another way.
Elliot! No!
Hey!
Jack.
Stop!
You have to stop!
Jack!
They're not gonna hurt us.
Please!
Stop! Elliot, stop!
Don't hurt them! I need them!
I need them.
Jack, get out of there!
Gavin?
Break the glass!
Come on, I got ya!
Come on, Elliot!
Daddy!
Fly!
Let's go. Go!
Come on!
Daddy!
No, Grace.
Come on, Elliot.
Come on.
I know.
Pete.
Pete! Wait!
We can't stay here anymore.
People know you're here.
They'll come looking for you.
But I can't disappear.
But I don't want to leave you.
Honey, look.
No one ever
saw that dragon again.
And I never told another tale about it.
I didn't have to.
Not after that day.
Folks looked high and low but,
it was nowhere to be found.
Some said he flew to another forest,
far, far away.
But those were just stories.
Time marched on.
Children got older.
Trees growed taller.
Tales growed taller, too.
By and by,
even the best ones
come to an end.
But I know someone,
who would tell you otherwise.
There's one little boy
who could tell you the whole story.
He could even tell you
what happens next.
He knows that the North Star
shines brightest of all.
He knows that there's
magic in the woods,
if you know where to look for it.
He knows his dragon is still out there.
And maybe,
if you're lucky,
that same boy,
the bravest boy I've ever met,
he could tell you where to find him.