Mist coming in--
--Like something is brewing,
about to begin--
--Can't put me finger on what lies in store--
--But I feel what's to happen,
all happened before--
Mrs Travers.
Like pink clouds on sticks.
Excuse me?
The cherry blossoms,
I was trying to think of what it looks like--
The car should be here, by now.
May I use.. the phone?
I cancelled it.
- You--?  What?
Pamela!
- Mrs Travers.
Mrs Travers...
Why would you cancel the car?
- I shan't be going.
We've been through this.
- I've changed my mind.
- You made an agreement.
Do you understand?
A verbal agreement.
Why in the world are you speaking to me
as if I am a neonate?
He's going to--
- What? What is he going to do? Sue?
He is very welcome to every penny
I don't posess.
Look----I've represented you for a long time.
I like to think of you as a friend--
I like to think of it,
believe me I know it's not reciprocated.
I would never,
suggest you do something that would cause you
anguish but there's no more money Pamela
-- Mrs Travers. Simply no more.
Sales have dried up, no more royalties.
You refuse to write further books so-
Do you understand? I'm..
I'm..frightened,
you don't understand what that means.
I know what he's going to do to her--
- she'll be cavorting and twinkling!
Careening towards a happy ending like a kamikaze--
--We've been trying to do this deal for twenty years!
He's agreed to both your stipulations.
No animation,
script approval--
- Use her to pay my bills? If I believed..
in a hell I'll be sitting in its waiting room--
--script approval! He's never granted
anything like that before! I don't know what else to do!
Where is Polly?
- I fired her.
It's just as well. It seems
I can't afford her anymore anyway.
You don't know how much she means to me.
Polly?
Of course not Polly!
For God's sake.
Los...Angeles.
You have only to go there and work for two weeks.
Collaborate.
You haven't signed the rights over, yet.
- Yet!
You must make it work Mrs Travers--
- Oh I must, must I?
You need the money. I don't want you to see you--
- Stop saying money! It's a filthy, disgusting word!
I am picking up the telephone Mrs Travers--
I..I have final say?
- You do.
I have final say.
And if I don't like what they are doing to her?
Then, You don't sign the papers.
He cannot make the film unless
you grant the rights.
It's an exploratory trip--
What do you say?
I want to keep my house.
mm..hhm?
Excuse me ma'am,
have you seen my daughter?
I was quite sure,
I had left her around here somewhere!
Her name is Helen,
no, erm.. Shirley,
No, erm.. good lord;
I've quite forgotten!
Could it be Prunella?
- No!
Pamela?
- No, no...no. No!
I'm sure I have a special name for her..
- Ginty!
Why, thank you ma'am!
Ginty it is of course!
Now, have you seen her?
- It's me!
Gosh! So it is!
Well, thank goodness for that!
I was positive, I was going to be beheaded for losing..
Her Highness.. The Royal Princess
Ginty Mc Featherfluffy!
You can't lose me!
Never. I promise.
I will never lose you!
You ready?
Are you sure?
C'mon! The adventure is about to begin!
C'mon.
Line: 84   (Silen=83.62) (EMedp=1.985)
Line: 85   (Silen=80.21) (EMedp=2.171)
Can I help you?
- I'm perfectly capable thank you.
They've used all the space;
...so greedy.
- I'll take it Madam.  I can put it up in front.
I don't want it up there. I would it here,
in the corresponding holding area
for my assigned seat!
The flight's closing in just a few moments Madam.
I'll have to take it.
You can move mine instead.
It's the grey one.
- Thank you.
Will the child be a nuisance?
It's an eleven hour flight.
Er-- no,--
- Jolly good.
I hope we crash.
Where is he carriage?
A carriage? Who needs a carriage?
But, there's so many...
- Every leisurely stroll is a gift, Darling!
It's a gift!
Now, Biddy..
are up staying?
You're coming with us?
- Mmm, hm.
Excellent!
Thank you so much.
For everything.-: D
Thank you, Miss.
Hurry up, everyone!
We mustn't be late the train.
All aboard!
Everybody ready?
Yes.
See you soon Katie Nanna!
- Take care, love.
Everybody ready?
Walking bus!
Left, right..left...
Miss?
Thank you.
Left. Left, right left...
And, one, two three-
New town,
new job, new bank.
New life.
Come on, my little ducklings!
Left, right left..
C'mon, come along!
Hold!
Allora--
Ginty, Come on, my love.
Pilot:"Ladies and Gentlemen,
we begin our descent into Los Angeles."
Fiery dust, I see.
Travers? P.L. Travers?
- Mrs.
Welcome, Mrs P.L. Travers!
Welcome to the City of Angels.
Let me take those.
I'm perfectly capable of-- Oh, nevermind.
Sun came out to say hello just to you.
Don't be preposterous.
It smells. Like--
Jasmine.
--chlorine and sweat.
It's dreadful.
Absurt.
You okay back there Mrs P.L. Travers?
It's not Mrs P.L. It's just Mrs--
Oh, it's too hot.
No problemo!
No problemo! We got a brand new
air conditioning system, Missus;
Just about make you feel like
you're in good old Engerland again!
Things they can put in cars these days--
Gosh almighty.
No problemo.
And, here we are. Ma'm.
Thank you.
- Ma'am?
Would you like me to unpack for you ma'am?
Young man, if it is your wish to handle ladies garments;
May I suggest, you take employment in a launderette.
Odd.
Oh, Dear.
For Heaven's sake...
What on earth..
Oh no, no, no.
No, no, no.
This will never do.
Absolutely, no pears.
No pears.
A palace!
Complete with mighty steed.
And chickens.
Oh, my..
We'll build beautiful memories here my angel.
Girls, come on.
--in this house, you get to share room.
How old do you think i am?
A five years old...
I suppose.
And you can stay there
until you learn the art of subtlety.
There you are.
Don't worry!
There's nothing wrong with your television set.
This is a pixie bell,
the sound is much too high for human ears.
Oh, there you are Tink!
Hey! What..Hey!
Get that stuff off of me!
You know, if you're familiar with our story
of Peter Pan.
You know, a little sprinkling of fairy dust
can make you fly!
Where are you going, Tink?
Haven't you forgotten something?
Off!
That's how we deal with you.
Good morning Mrs!
- It's not Mrs, it's-- Oh, nevermind.
We're just not going to get it right are we?
What's that?
Will it be the same..
driver every day?
- Yes ma'am! I'm all yours.
Hey, Sun came out again!
You say it like you're surprised.
As if the sun is particular about whom it appears.
It seems you think that I am responsible,
for it's miraculous dawning every day.
For heaven's sake, it's California!
It certainly is!
I would so much rather be accountable for the rain.
Oh, that's sad.
Sad is entirely the wrong emotion.
I shan't bother explaining why;
it'll just...Zip!
Okey dokey.
The rain brings life!
So does the sun.
Be quiet!
- Yes ma'am.
I'll get that, Sir!
Got it?
- Yes, sir.
Good morning! Pamela!
It is so discomfiting to hear a perfect stranger
use my first name.
Mrs Travers. Please.
I do apologize,
Mrs Travers.
I am Don DaGradi, the script writer.
Co-script-writer.
I shall certainly be having my say Mr. DiGraydi.
Gradi.
Wonderful! I welcome your input.
- If indeed we ever sign off on a script.
Right, uhmm..
this is the rest of your team,
This is Dick and Bob Sherman! Music and lyrics.
Boys, this is the one and only Mrs P.L. Travers,
creator of our beloved Mary.
Poppins.
- Who else? - Mary Poppins.
Never ever, just Mary.
A pleasure to meet you, though I  fear
we shan't be acquainted for too long.
Why is that?
- B'cos These books...
simply do not lend themselves
to chirping and prancing.
No. Certainly not a musical.
Now, where is Mister Disney?
I should so much like to get this started and finished
as briskly as is humanly possible.
Perhaps, one of you can point me in his direction.
That'd be superb..wonderful. Thank you.
We were hoping to give you
a little tour of the studio.
No thank you.
Walt just wants to show the place off.
No one likes a show off.
Mrs Travers-- it's quitea long way--
Not a musical?
I am perfectly capable of walking.
Good morning.
- Good morning, Dolly..
Could you let Mister Disney know
I have arrived please?
Absolutely, please have a seat.
Oh, no. There's no need.
He'll be just a.. a moment, Mrs.Travers.
Why don't we sit.
She's here!
A word of advice Mrs Travers, if I may.
You may. Whether I heed it or not
will be another matter entirely.
Uhm. It's just that he can't stand being called Mr Disney.
We are all on a first name basis here.
Well,
there ya are at last!
Oh, my dear gal!
You can't imagine how excited I am to finally meet you!
Hum-- well, It's an honour, Mister Disney.
- Oh Walt, you gotta call me Walt.
‘Mister Disney?was my old man.
Isn't that right, Don?
Absolutely, Walt.
Tommie, say hello to...
the one and only Pamela Travers!
It's so nice to meet you.
Ya know, I can't believe it. P.L. Travers,
right here, in my office,
after all these years-- almost twenty of ‘em.
Yes.
- Twenty. Long. Years.
Wish ya coulda?seen me then Pam!
As lean as a whippet I was! A race horse!
Well, anyway...
here you are. Look at you!
I could eat you up!
That wouldn't be appropriate.
You know what.
When Diane here was...
seven years old--
can I get you a drink? Coffee? Soda?
A pot of tea would be most welcome.
Anyway, She was seven years old
and I was walking past her room..
and there she was on her bed reading
to her sister Sharon,
and well, thsoe gals were giggling
their little socks off!
Tommie,
A hot tea for Pamela and Me.
She's a doll.
Anyways,
I asked them girls, what's so funny??
And Diane said to me, why daddy,
Mary Poppins!?
Well, I didn't even know what a Mary Poppins was!
And then she gave me your book.
And oh, by gosh! My imagination was caught on fire!
Absolutely, ON FIRE!
And those embers have burned ever since-- as you know.
- I do.
Yes.
- Twenty years!
So you keep saying--
A man cannot...
break a promise he's made to his kids.
No matter how long it takes for him..
to make it come true..Now,
You might've kept me dangling all this time,
but now, I gotcha!
Gotcha indeed!
Mister Disney, if you have
dangled then it is at the end of a rope
you have fashioned for yourself.
I was perfectly clear, when you approached me
20 years ago..that she wasn't for sale
and I was clear again when you approached me the following year,
and clear again when you approached me every annum
for the subsequent 18 years.
Quite honestly, I feel corralled, --
Oh no, Pam, the last thing I wanna do is to make you feel--
- Would you mind, my name, is MRS Travers.
I promised them.
That's a fact. You got kids?
- No, not precisely...
I have never, I absolutely never, gone back on a promise
i made to either one of my daughters.
That's what being a daddy is all about right?
Is it?
Our motion picture isn't just going to make my kids happy.
It's going to make ALL kids happy!
Adults too...
B'cos, my guys are gonna do things with it that are,
well, are revolutionary.
Pam, REVOLUTIONARY! Your Mary Poppins is gonna literally
fly off the pages of your books!
Thank you, Tommie.
This magical woman who has only lived in your head,
you're gonna be able to meet her, speak to her, hear her sing.
Now, this singing, I am glad you've come to that.
oh, Milk in first, please.
Then, the tea.
And a spoonful of sugar.
You don't mean for this film to be a musical?
I absolutely do!
No.
- No?
Mister Disney, Mary Poppins..
does not sing.
Yes she does!
When?
- In your books!
Those aren't songs!
They're recitations.
She is not a giddy woman,
she does not jig about!
Singing is frivolous and wholly unnecessary,
for a governess, an educatress. No.
It would just ruin it.
I won't have her turned into
one of your silly cartoons.
Now...Pam,
I want you to know--
that the last thing I would do,
the very last thing,
is tarnish a story, I have cherished.
Now, the pages--
pages of your book are worn down to tissue,
They  are dog eared and falling out.
B'cos,  I have poured over them gripped, tormented.
Because I love her, Pam.
I love Mary Poppins,
you... you got to share her,
with me.
Nothing happens without your say so.
Quite right.
- It's all here, in the rights agreement.
As approved by your agent,Dermot.
- Diarmuid.
Darmitt.
A live action film. No animation.
Live action.
Here's a pen.
I'll like that on tape.
- On tape?
Your promise-- and all the discussions we have here
-- on tape.
Ah huh, there you are.
Mary Poppins and the Banks's,
they're family to me.
I understand now.
I do.
Well then!
Shall we begin?
Let's make something wonderful.
Let's see if that's at all possible.
Woah.
Damn.
Testing, one, two.
What is all this...
jollification?
- We have a whole script to get through.
It's gonna be a long day Mrs T.
Mrs..
Mrs Travers.
We could save a starving country
with benefaction from this room alone!
Ugh, It's so vulgar.
Could you, turn on--
Now, Let us begin.
Scene one.
- Scene one. Ext.
Exterior Cherry Tree Lane.
- Ext? What's Ext?
Exterior. It means
the scene is taking place outside.
Ah, I see, an abbreviation.
Oh, I'm sorry Mr DaGradi,
did you feel you should--?
No, No, please be my guest,
Mrs Travers.
Yes, I do think it's best.
I've the most practise.
Readings of my books you know?
Absolutely.
- Anyway--
Scene one. Exterior.
17 Cherry Tree Lane, London. Day.
Yes. That's good, that can stay.
- That's just the scene heading!
--Though I do think we should say number 17,
instead of just 17,It's proper. Yes?
- No one's going to see it.
I will see it.
Write it down, write it down,
chop chop.
Is that on the tape?
We got that?
Ahh..Yes.
-Very good.
-- onwards.
I'm sorry to interrupt.
Is this a joke?
Excuse me?
- Do you think you are a comedienne?
I'm sorry I don't understand.
Unbelievable.
I think we are all set with..with..
thank you.
Scene One. Exterior. Number
17 Cherry Tree Lane. London. Day.
Bert, a one-man band- The rumour is that
this is to be your Mr.Van Dyke. Is that right?
We do hope so!
- Well, we'll see about that.
It's a horrid idea.
Dick is one of the greats.
Dick Van Dyke?!
- Yes.
Robert, my dear,
Olivier is one of the greats, Burton, Guinness
- greats without question. I can assure you..
I can assure you--
that Dick Van Dyke is not!
Bert, a one-man band plays to a small gathering
outside the gates to the park.
Bert says--
You can do Bert.
Thank you. Ahhmm?
Guys..shall we...
give it a whirl?
What's happening?
What're you doing?
Alright Ladies and gents, comical poem,
suitable for the occasion--
--extemporized and thought up
before your very eyes!
Alright, here we go--
Room here for everyone gather around,
The constable's "responstable."
Now, how does that sound?
- No no no no... no no no.
Responstable
is not a word.
We made it up!
- well..
un-make it up.
Irresponstable.
There's my girl.
Ahhh,
That's it, boy. Albert c'mon.
Give Ginty a kiss.
There you go.
Poor old Albert;
he's your secret uncle you know?
But a miserable,
horrid witch turned him into a nag.
Why did she do that?
Because she hated the sound of his laugh.
Poor Uncle Albert! How can we fix him?
We have to teach the witch
how to be happy again.
How?
I'm not quite sure darling.
Do you want to know
what it feels like to fly Ginty?
Albert. You old nag.
Come here.
You trust me?
- Yes.
Yah!
Nobody walks.
Leisurely stroll's a gift.
Beautiful ain't it?
If you like that sort of thing.
I do.
We do find it helps to have a visual.
Plus, It's fun!
No, no, no. Goodness me, no.
- No?
The Banks house doesn't look like that!
No No.
My house is a terraced house
with a pink door, white bricked
with a crack in the gable.
- Okay,  we get it. The house is not what you pictured.
The window frames are lead-lined
and the flower boxes grow pink nasturtiums
to go with the pink door.
We got that?
Oh dear, it's all a big mistake.
It's all wrong.
It's all wrong?
- It's too grand!
The Banks's are -
normal, everyday sort of people.
This isn't normal. It isn't everyday!
They're not aristocrats!
Oh, Do I even have to say it?
Um-- i'm afraid so.
Why in the world have you made
Mrs Banks a silly suffragette?
- I wonder if Emmeline P
would agree with that adjective--
Quite possibly, looking back.
- It does seem
strange that Mrs Banks allows
her children to spend all of their time
with the nanny when she has no job to speak of--
Are you calling Mrs Banks neglectful?
- Yep.
No! Of course not!
We just felt that if she had a job
it would go some way to explaining--
- Being a mother is a job.
A very difficult job and one that not everybody is up to,
that not everybody should have taken on in the first place!
I will NOT have her called Cynthia!
Absolutely not. It feels unlucky.
At least something warm,
something a bit..
sexy.
How about Mavis?
Sybil?
- Great.
Prudence?
- Gwendolyn?
Winifred!
I could go with Winifred.
Yes, that's because it's very good.
This isn't Mr Banks? This isn't him.
- Yes, that's him Mr.Banks.
He has a set of moustaches!
In the books he--
- I told the illustrator I didn't like the facial hair
but she chose to ignore me.
Now, this time around..
This is MY film and I shall have MY way.
Mrs Travers, it was a specific request, from Walt.
Why?
I think he identify..
- He didn't, he doesn't, Mr Banks is clean shaven!
Does it matter?
Does it
mattterrrrrrr?
You can wait outside!
I shan't say it again Robert.
What is wrong with his leg?
He got shot.
Hardly surprising.
Can I expect anymore drama from anyone else?
Why do you do that?
For you my dear!
Tell me, Gintamina.
Which kind of kisses do you prefer..
Scratchy ones or silky ones?
- Silky ones.
Well then, Swish!
Swoosh!
A man must shave
for to spare his daughter's cheeks!
Swish!
SUPERCALIFRAGILISTICEXPIALIDOCIOUS.
- Stop! Stop! Stop!
What on earth are you talking about?
Supercali--? Supercali--
or whatever the infernal thing is!
- It's something to say when,
when you don't know what to say!
- Well I always know what to say.
If you so much as step one foot in here
with that tray I shall scream!
One cannot live on cake alone!
Hit me with it.
She has a lot of-- ideas.
Ya? What kind of ideas?
The name Cynthia has been changed to Winifred.
Fine, fine.
She won't approve Dick Van Dyke.
The sketches of the Banks house
make it look too opulent,
there must be no hint of romance
between Mary Poppins and Bert,
she wants to know why Mr Banks
has been given a moustache, --I asked for that.
Yes. They did tell her that
but she wants to know why.
Because, I asked for it.
Right. Of course.
Uh-- the tape measure Mary Poppins uses to record
Jane and Micheal's height must be a roll tape,
not a ruler,
She only wants green vegetables and broth,
I don't know what that is
but she wants it in the room from now on
and oh! She doesn't want the colour red in the film--
at all.
I've simply gone off the colour.
We can't make the film without the colour red!
The film is set in London for pete's sake.
- And?
There's buses and mail boxes
and guards uniforms-- heck!
The British flag!
I understand your predicament Mr Disney, I do.
I just-- hm-- I don't know what it is,
I'm just suddenly very anti-red.
I shan't be wearing it ever again.
Is this a test Pamela?
Are you requiring proof
of how badly I wanna make you happy
so that we can create this beautiful thing together?
I took you at your word Mr Disney?
and it seems my first stipulation has been denied.
There will be many more,
so-- perhaps we should just call it quits;
and I should hand you back these.
Alright.
No red in the picture.
What?! Walt?
He doesn't have the rights--
Quite.
Tommie!
Scotch Mist.
What do you think?
What do I think I-- what?
- You're a woman.
That's a canny observation Walt.
What am I missing here?
You think the female of the
species has some sort
of psychic insight
when it comes to others of her kind?
We don't.
You'll get yourself an ulcer with all that unriddling.
Give it up.
That woman.
Good afternoon Ma'am.
What can I fix you?
A pot of tea.
If you please.
Sure thing.
Thank you. Tea is a balm for the soul
don't you agree?
Girls, will you please just..
In you go.
Alright?
Ahoy Goffs!
- Father!
Ahh, that's better.
What a wonderful surprise!
Did you finish early?
couldn't stop thinking about
my beautiful girls on this--
beautiful day in this beautiful place..
.. and I thought to hell with it!
Don't you have work to do?
- But--
Buts are for goats my love!
I'll put in extra hours tomorrow.
A gift of a pear, for my lady.
Now...What are we playing?
-The hen got out and we've been trying
to catch her!
That's no hen!
That's Aunt Ellie,
your mother's horrendiferous sister!
That's a made up word!
- Yes, it is.
Hury! Catch her before she flies away on the--
- West Wind!
West Wind!
--darling, it's just that um--
a little scared--
--Meg sweet,
I had a throat scratch
But, the bank is getting you down again?
Perhaps my sister--
- no!
God no!
No. I can endure.
I will endure. For the girl's sake--
Just, please--
not Ellie.
She's a Foul fowl.
It's gotta be like a slogan!
- Her prescription for life.
An apple a day.
- A stitch in time!
Time and tide wait for no man.
Sugar!
Sugar?
- Yeah.
Jeff had vaccination day at school yesterday.
No ouch.
- No ouch?
Sugar. They put it in a cube.
- Medicine in sugar?
Cube's an odd word.
Spoonful?
You need sugar with sugar.
Well, Morning!
May I walk with you?
I'm sure your country doesn't have any laws
against it..
Nope. Go back to the chorus.
Chorus..Just a spoonful of sugar
helps the medicine go down!
medicine..
It's missing...?
WAIT! She always does what's unexpected.
She goes UP the bannisters.
So, go up.
Just.. a... spoonful of sugar
helps the medicine go down.
That's it. That's it!
Man is in the forest.
I want you to play that..
for him. Walt?
It's just a chorus--
Tell us what you think.
He knows dum dum
Will help dum dum dum duuuum!
For a..a spoonful of sugar
helps the medicine go down--
the medicine go do-own,
medicine go down;
Just a spoonful of sugar
helps the medicine go down.
In a most de da dee daaa!
We'll work out the other lyrics.
- You see how it goes up on the word down?
It's ironic.
- Forget ironic, it's iconic.
I won't be able to stop singing that for weeks!
Well, It seems enormously patronising to me.
The very sort of annoying tune
you would have playing in your themed park I daresay.
All giddy and carefree, encouraging
children to face the world unarmed.
All they need is a spoon and some sugar and a
brain full of fluff and they're equipped with life'stools.
Wonderful!
What's your point Pam?
- MRS Travers! Please.
My point is that, unlike yourself, Mary Poppins is
the very enemy of whimsy and sentiment.
She is truthful,
She doesn't sugar coat the darkness in the world
that these children will eventually come to know.
She prepares them for it,
she deals in honesty!
One must clean one's room;
it won't magically do it itself!
This entire script is flim flam!
Where is its heart?
Where is its reality? Where...
.. is the gravitas?
No weight Mister Disney!
See?
No whimsy or sentiment says the woman..
who sends a flying nanny with a
talking umbrella to save the children.
You think Mary Poppins is saving
the children Mr Disney?
Oh dear.
Mr Belhatchett!
- Good afternoon.
Allow me--
I want you gone.
Ginty!
Sweet thing! What are you doing here?
You said today was ice cream day.
Ice cream day! Yes! I did!
What kind of father am I?
Come here.
Are you fired again?
Ah, yes it does seem that--
- No sweetheart--
No. He isn't.
Darling, wait inside for a second.
If you can't straighten up for your own sake.
Do it for your daughter.
Irresponsible.
We share a Celtic soul, you and I.
This world..
is just an illusion, Ginty old girl.
As long as we hold that thought dear,
they can't break us.
They can't make us endure
their reality.
They can bloody as it is.
Money, money, money.
Don't you buy into it Ginty!
It'll bite you on the bot!
I loathe this place, Mr Russell.
It's bringing up these-- it's..
it's so hot and stuffy I--
..feel as I am being attacked.
These odd dreams,
like my subconscious is after me.
Punishing me..
for entertaining the idea that I might..
... hand her over.
I am at war with myself Mr Russell.
The script is ghastly,
empty pack, exactly as I expected--
Yes, a few more days and then I'll decide--
Serves me right. Money, money, money.
Bit me on the bot.
All around the cathedral
the saints and apostles
look down as she sells her wares.
Although you can't see it
you know they are smiling
Each time someone shows that he cares--
Though her words are simple
and few listen,
listen, she's calling to you--
Feed the birds, tuppence a bag
tuppence,
tuppence a....
...bag.?/i>
That'll work.
She's going to say no isn't she?
The woman is a conundrum.
My world was calm,
well ordered,
exemplary
Then came this person,
with chaos in her wake.
And, now my life's ambitions go
with one
fell blow
It's quite a bitter pill to
take.
Inspired by someone we know?
You'll have to ask Bob.
She might surprise us all.
No! No..she won't.
You don't know that.
- No, I do. I do know it,
I know it only too well.
I've fought this battle from her side.
Pat Powers,
he wanted the mouse
and I didn't have a bean in my pocker, back then.
He was this big, terrifying...
New York producer and I was just a kid
from Missouri, with a sketch of Mickey.
It woulda?killed me, to give him up.
Honest to god, that would've killed me.
That mouse, he is family.
Go home.
The world..
is an illusion Ginty, old gal.
Ahh, the Countess- Mary Sparklestick!
Pray tell me,
what are you concentrating so hard on?
I am laying eggs!
Really!? Fabulous!
Today, I am a hen.
Indeed! I can see the feathers
sprouting as we speak!
Helen Goff, would you lay the table for supper please?
- I'm not Helen!
She can't possibly lay a table;
she's busy laying eggs!
Helen, would you lay the table for supper please?
- She's laying!
I'm sorry!
I should--
- Ginty?
Don't you ever stop dreaming Ginty my love.
You can be anyone you want to be.
Anyone.
- I want to be just like you.
Don't.
Ya alright Mrs?
DON:Mrs Travers?
Mrs Travers?
We were just saying that we'll like to play you
the song in the bank.
Would that be good?
Fidelity Feduciary Bank.
So you have tuppence?
May I be permitted to see it?
No, I want it to feed the birds!
Michael says,
Fiddlesticks boy!
Feed the birds and what've you got?
Fat birds!
But! If you invest your tuppence
wisely in the bank
Safe and sound--
Soon, that tuppence safely invested in the bank--
Mrs Brill said Father's presenting the medals.
He is indeed!
On behalf of the bank.
Maybe, he will pin one on me,
for the maple.
He might.
- Where is Father?
I think, he is practising his speech somewhere.
In the hands of the directors
who invest as propriety demands.
Father--
Why is he speaking for the bank?
He's the manager..Sir.
He looks terrible.
Good afternoon, distinguished guests,
our biggest supporter, Mr Randolph Belhatchett
and his lovely wife,
ladies and gentlemen, boys and girls!
I'm honoured to be here on behalf of
the Belhatchett Bank of
Australia.
Shortly, it will uh..
It'll be my very pleasant duty to present the awards
to our uhhm..
our young performers.
But before,
I begin,
I'll like to say a very few words
to our very youngest citizens about the er,
about the.. er
the role...
of the Bank in our community.
When you deposit tuppence
in a bank account,
Soon..
- Soon you'll see,
that it blooms into credit of..
a generous amount
Semi-annually!
And you'll achieve that sense of stature
As your influence expands.
To the high
financial strata
That established credit now commands--
You can purchase, first and second trust deeds
Think of the foreclosures!
Bonds! Chattels! Dividends!
Shares!
- Bankruptcies!  - Debtor sales!
Opportunities!
All manner of private enterprise!
Shipyards! The Mercantile!
Collieries!
Tanneries!
Incorporations! Amalgamations!  Banks!
Uhmm. Thank you kindly.
Thank you.
It's a marvellous thing..
to encourage children to open accounts.
marvellous!
My daughter, the Princess Ginty--
she's-- uh.
How old are you?
Come up here.
Come here, Ginty.
Ginty has an account--
and that's good.
Give her a drink!
I mean.. give her a hand.
I shall return in just a few moments,
to present the awards.
But right now,
I need to relieve myself.
Give us your shoulder, Ginty, will you?
I'm busting.
There's a good girl.
It works.
- It's getting great.
Why did you have to make him so cruel?
He was not a monster!
Who are we talking about? I'm confused.
You all have children, yes?
- Yes.
And do those children make letters for you,
do they write letters, make drawings...
And would you tear up those gifts?
In front of them?!
It's a dreadful thing to do! I don't understand!
Why must father, tear up
the advertisement, his children have made;
and throw it in the fireplace!?
Why won't he mend their kite?
Why have you made him so unspeakably, awful?
In glorious technicolor?
For all the world to see.
You claim to make them live--
why can't he?
They.. live well?
I can't bear it.
Please don't--
Please don't.
I'll feel like I let him down again.
Mrs Travers?
I don't suppose,
you can give me any more
for the pain?
When will enough be enough, Travers?
I've brought you something father.
Be a darling Ginty, my old pal!
Come here.
I'm sick.
Help father out won't you?
You know, In my washroom--
there's a bottle of medicine
that father needs.
- Mother took it away.
- Godammit!
I wrote a poem father.
It - it won first prize, at school.
Shall i read it to you, father?
Mrs?
I, uh, brought you a tea.
- It's blasphemy to drink tea from a paper cup.
Everything okay, mrs?
Would you like me to drive you home?
All the way to England?
Yes, please.
You got family, back there Mrs?
- You're an impertinent man, you know?
You ask an awful lot of questions that have
absolutely, no relevance to you
being able to carry out your duties.
I know! I do, do that. Yes!
- And you have no barometer.
Let us say, that I haven't
family who'll notice, whether I was halfway
across the world or sitting, in my living room.
Make a little furrow, there.
I gotta kid.
Well, most people do.
Jane--
What a terrific kid.
Beautiful, little girl.
She's got a of problems though.
She's Handicapped, you know?
She's in a wheelchair.
See? That's why I concern myself
with the weather so much.
Sunny day, she can sit out in the garden.
Rainy day, I have to leave her cooped up inside.
Worry about the future,
but, you can't do that.
Only today.
Hmmm.
- Yeah.
Now look.
It's a band stand.
- Ahh!
A river!
- Lake.
Hey, Hey..Hey!
I sure would like to take her there!
Wouldn't that be nice?
I know you gave it to him.
Take care of your sisters.
I know you love your father more.
But, one day..
you will understand.
Mother!
Mother?
It's time to go home.
I'm sorry.
Oh, my God!
Mrs Travers! Yes?
Pam! Walt.
Mr Disney.
I'm Callin?to..uh check up on you.
I understand, things didn't go so well today.
Something about Mr. Banks?
They went as well as
they've gone every other day;
that I've been here. I don't recall special
phone calls from you on any of those other evenings.
Pam, What's this all about?
Really?
I'm wondering what I have to do
to make you happy.
- Ha!
- And, you've been wondering that too, Aren't you?
You know,
you've never been to Disneyland!
That's the happiest place on Earth!
Tommie!
Cancel my morning tomorrow.
I'm taking a ride with my favorite author!
No, no no, please, Mr. Disney.
I cannot tell you how uninterested,
no, positively sickened, I am..
at the thought of visiting your...
your dollar printing machine!
For crying out loud. When does anybody
get to go to Disneyland, with Walt Disney himself?!
Disappointments are to the soul,
what the thunderstorm is to the air.
Hello?
He hung up!
Gangs, We gotta fix this.
Father, winds from the east.
The Aunt.
Now,
I've brought every new fangled treatment
available in Sydney.
Close your mouth please Biddy,
we are not a codfish.
Now, I see a multitude of jobs
that need to be done!
They've been so worried-- I've--
- Do stop babbling nonsense!
I'm here now
and I shall fix everything.
I thought I had made it quite clear,
that you two were to begin helping.
Hmm?
Spit spot!
Where are we--? This isn't the way.
Change of venue this morning, apparently.
Ugh.
Wow!
There he is!
Living, breathing.
Oh boy!
Oh, I can get that.
Mrs.Travers, Welcome to the Magic Kingdom!
Is it all like this?
Yup! Isn't it wonderful?
Do you always get everything you want, Walter?
Pretty much!
With the exception of the rights
to my books of course!
Well, War ain't over yet Pam!
War ain't over yet.
I love you so much! Can I--?
Sure, sure..there you go.
Pre-signed?
Hey, You should get hers too.
This woman's a bona fide genius!
Tour starts this way, Pam!
Hot dog!
Whoa, move along,
move along.
Each section of the park, has a high point.
So, you can get your benefits.
In Adventureland there is a tree--
This is a fun fact. A titbit.
- Tidbit.
It got three million leaves,
four million flowers.
Gosh.
- And they said only God could make a tree!
Where did she come from?
- Who?
Oh, I think you know who.
She flew in through the window, one day.
Through the window huh?
It's just that easy, isn't it Mrs Travers?
You see those spirals?
Plated with 24 carat gold.
Now, I know you don't wanna be here
so I'm gonna take you to one ride--
My favourite amusement,
and then.. I'll set you free.
Mrs Travers, I would be honoured
if you would take a ride on Jingles, here.
She's Mrs Disney's favourite horse.
No, thank you. I'm happy to watch.
Now, there's no greater joy,
than that seen through the eyes of a child.
There's a child in us all.
- Maybe in you Mister Disney,
but certainly not in me.
Get on the horse Pamela!
Now, When we first met,
you said to me they're family.?
I said what?
Mary Poppins,
the Banks's, they're family.
The boys have had an idea
for your Mister Banks.
I think it'll make you happy.
- You brought me all the way out here, to tell me that?
Oh, no..No. I brought you all the way out here
for monetary gain.
Had a wager with the boys,
that I couldn't get you on a ride.
I just won 20 bucks.
Yah!
All the garments are half done.
Good morning, Mrs Travers!
What horrors have you in store for
my beautiful characters today?
You, sit here.
What're you upto?
We were thinking about..
what you said,
and..you are right.
Mr Banks isn't cruel. He isn't.
So, we've got a new ending for the film.
Oh god, I hope you like it.
Michael says, he mended it! It's wonderful!?
However did you manage it?
He mended the kite?
With...
tuppence for paper and strings
You can have your own set of wings.
With your feet on the ground
You're a bird in flight!
with your fist holding tight,
To the string of your kite .
Oh oh oh oh!
Let's go fly a kite.
Up to the highest height,
and send it, soaring
Up through the atmosphere.
Up where the air is clear.
Oh, let's go fly a kite.
And then, Mrs Banks runs to her house.
She gets the suffragettes ribbon.
And says,
“A proper kite needs a proper tail don't you think?!?/i>
Oh, oh oh!
Let's go fly a kite.
Up to the highest height,
Let's go fly a kite...
and send it soaring,
Up through the atmosphere.
Up where the air is clear.
Oh, let's go fly a kite!
When you send it flying up there;
All at once you're lighter than air
You can dance on the breeze over
houses and trees with your fist holding tight,--
To the string of your kite.
Mr Disney! Walt!
I'm sorry to interrupt.
It's just she's--
She's dancing!
Mrs Travers. She's dancing with Don!
Oh, Oh Oh Oh!
Let's go fly a kite.
Up to the highest height.
Let's go fly a kite
and send it soaring..
Up through the atmosphere.
Up where the air is clear.
Oh, let's go fly a kite!
Oh! He fixes the kite!
Oh, I love it!
Though proper English would be
-let us go and fly a kite.?
Let us go..and fly a..
But, I might be willing to overlook that.
Alright!
Very good!
Father?
You're quite right? You know,
It is beautiful. Exquisite.
It's always new.
So, Jolly Holiday's in?
- By all means.
Wonderful!
- I do have a question about it actually.
How in the world does Mister Disney
propose to train penguins to dance?
I've heard about his implausibly leaved trees.
So, I assume he does have some insane penguin wrangling
scheme but it does seem rather far fetched.
Can you train a
penguin to dance?
No.
I don't think you can train--
- They're animated.
They are what?
- Cartoons.
What?
Are we getting real penguins?
Good afternoon Mrs Travers!
I'm here to see Mister Disney.
Mrs Travers!
I'm terribly, sorry..Walt.
It's Alright Tommie, just close the door.
Never let anybody see me smoking.
I'll hate to encourage bad habits.
Please, sit down.
- I shall not sit in the seat of a trickster! A fraudster! A sneak!
Pamela--
- MRS TRAVERS. PLEASE!
Mrs Travers, what hasyou so upset now?
Penguins!
Penguins have very much upset me,
Mister Disney!
Animated, dancing penguins!
Now, you have seduced me with the music Mr Disney,
yes you have. Those Sherman boys have quite turned my head;
but I shall not be moved
on the matter of cartoons, Sir.
Not.. one inch!
It's a sequence--
You promised me. You promised me
that this film would not be an animation!
And it isn't!
So, they're real penguins?
No, they're animated.
But, the actors you see...
the actor is very very much real.
You foolish old woman.
Pamela! Pam!
Dolly, would you be so kind
to ring my driver, he can come collect me?
Yes, Ma'm.
-Thank you.
Here we are, Mrs.
- Thank you.
It's been a pleasure driving you Mrs.
No one likes a fibber.
- NO..no. No.
I really have enjoyed it.
Didn't know who you were at first
and then guess what?
You found out?
- I was telling my daughter all about my day..
and how I was driving this nice writer lady,
Mrs Travers for Mr Disney.
and uh--
And--
And, she made me go to her bedroom
and  bring her this!
Can't stop reading it. You know..
I'm very slow mind you.
Would you like me to sign it?
Would you?!
I'll be honoured.
To..
Jane.
and her dearest father--
I've just this instant realized
I don't know your name.
Ralph.
Pamela.
You're the only American
I have ever liked, Ralph.
May I ask why?
No. Now,
take this--
Albert Einstein,
Van Gogh,
Roosevelt,
Frida Kehlo..
- Kahlo.
What is this?
- They all had difficulties.
Jane, can do anything,
that anyone else can do.
Do you understand?
Oh.
I almost forgot,
turn it aroud.
Walt Disney!
Hyperactive behavior and deficiencies in concentration.
It explains everything!
Thank you, Mrs.
She has come and gone, huh?
- Yeah, Flight left 10 minutes ago.
Beverly Hotel, front lemousine..
First class plane ticket back to England,
Wait, Goff? Who's Helen Goff?
That's her. That's her real name.
She acts so, hoity toity British
and she's really an Aussie.
Then, who's Travers?
I've been talking to the wrong person.
He is gone.
No, no..no you mustn't.
Let her go, Margaret.
I dropped the pears.
I'm sorry, daddy.
Helen, dear girl...
You promised, you would fix everything.
Hello, house.
Oh, dear god!
It was one heck of a job getting a seat..
on the very next flight, let me tell you.
Mrs.Travers..
I could sure use, a nice pot
of English tea, about now.
Here we are.
Allow me.
The milk goes in first. Milk.
I remember.
And, a spoonful of sugar?
I think, I'll have whiskey.
Oh well, when in Rome!
You've come to change my mind. Haven't you?
To beat me into submission.
No, no. I've come because, you misjudge me.
Yeah.
How do I misjudge you?
You look at me and you see
some kind of Hollywood King Midas.
You think, I've built an empire and that I want to use your
Mary Poppins as just another brick in my kingdom.
- And don't you?
If that was all it was,
would I have pursued an cranky,
stubborn dame like you for twenty years?
I would have saved myself an ulcer!
No, you expected me to disappoint you
and so, you made sure I did.
Well, I think life disappoints you, Mrs Travers.
I think it's done that a lot. And i think,
Mary Poppins is the only person in your life who hasn't.
- Mary Poppins, isn't real.
- That's not true.
Oh, no. She's real as can be to my daughter's
and to thousands of other children--
adults too.
Been there as a nighttime comfort
to a heck of a lot of people.
Well, Where is she when I need her?
Hm? I open the door to Mary Poppins
and who should be standing there..
...but Walt Disney!
Mrs Travers, I am so sorry.
I hoped--
this would be a magical experience for you,
for all of us.  But I let you down--
and in doing so, I've broken
a twenty year old promise I made to my daughters.
I've been wracking my brains,
trying to figure out why this has been so hard for you and I--
Well...
You see, I have my own Mr Banks.
Mine had a moustache.
So, not true that Disney
created man in his own image?
But it is true that you created yourself
in someone else's, yes?
Ever been to Kansas City, Mrs Travers?
Do you know Missouri at all?
I can't say I do.
- Well, It's mighty cold there in the winters. Bitter cold.
My dad, Elias Disney, he owned a newspaper delivery route there.
Thousand papers. Twice daily.
The morning and an evening edition.
Dad, he was a tough businessman.
He was a...
..save-a-penny anywhere you can type of fella;
So, he wouldn't employ any delivery boys,
no, no..no. he just used me and
my big brother Roy.
I was uh, I was eight back then.
Just eight years old.
Like I said, those winters were harsh..
and old Elias didn't believe in new shoes until,
the old ones were worn right through.
Honestly, Mrs Travers, the snow drift
sometimes they were up over my head!
We'd push through it like wading through molasses.
And the cold and the wet would be
seeping through the shoes.
Skin peeling from our faces.
sometimes, I'll find myself sunk down in the snow,
Just waking up, cuz I must've passed out
or something, I dunno.
Then, it's time for school, i was too cold
too wet,
to figure out an equations and things.
Then, it was right back out into the snow
again to get home just before dark.
My mother would feed us dinner..
..and then, it was time to go right back out again,
for the evening edition.
You best be quick there Walt,
get those newspapers up on that porch,
and under that store and doors..
or poppa's gonna loose his temper again
and show you the buckle under his belt.
Now, I don't tell you,
all this to make you sad Mrs Travers,
I don't. I love my life.
I think it's a miracle. And I loved my dad.
He was a wonderful man.
But, rare is the day..
where I don't think of that little boy
delivering newspapers in the snow.
And old Elias Disney with his strap and fist..
and I'm just so tired--
Mrs. Travers.
I'm tired of remembering it, that way.
Aren't you tired too, Mrs Travers?
We all have our tales but
don't you want to finish the story?
Let it all go and have a life
that isn't dictated by a past?
It's not the children she comes to save.
It's their father.
It's your father--
Travers Goff.
- I don't know what you think you know
about me, Walter.
You must've loved and admired him
a lot to take his name.
It's all about him, isn't it?
All of it. Everything.
Forgiveness, Mrs.Travers.
It's what I learned from your books.
- I don't need to forgive my father.
He was a wonderful man.
No,
you need to forgive Helen Goff.
Life is a harsh sentence to lay down for yourself.
Give her to me, Mrs Travers.
Trust me, with your precious Mary Poppins.
I won't disappoint you.
I swear, that every time a person
walks into a movie house.
- from Leicester to Kansas City..
they will see, George Banks being saved.
They will love him and his kids,
they will weep for his cares,
They will wring their hands,
when he loses his job.
And when he flies that kite,
oh Mrs Travers! They will rejoice,
they will sing.
In movie houses all over the world,
in the eyes and the hearts of my kids, and other kids and
their mothers and fathers  for generations to come,
George Banks, will be honoured.
George Banks will be redeemed.
George Banks and all he stands for will be saved.
Maybe, not in life, but in imagination.
Because, that's what we storytellers do.
We restore order with imagination.
We instill hope, again and again and again.
Trust me, Mrs Travers.
Let me prove it to you.
I give you my word.
Enough.
Make those two changes,
I'm sure everything will be just fine.
Walt, could i get your approval on that please.
What is it?
- Invitation list for the premiere.
Is this everyone?
It's not everyone.
There'll be a premiere in London,
that'll be more convenient for her.
Tommie, this wasn't an easy decision for me.
But, you know what she is like.
We got press interviews, cameras--
I need to protect the picture.
- Okay.
Just answer the door!
I am very pleased to hear that Pamela.
I should think, you'll have a draft very soon.
Polly! Where's that tea?
It's coming along marvelously!
Aren't you going to pour it, for us?
You're perfectly capable
of pouring it yourself.
She's quite the worst maid I've ever had!
So, why do you keep her?
- I don't know, she reminds me of me.
Do you have a title?
- Mary Poppins in the Kitchen.
Wonderful.
Should we start talking about, the film rights?
NEVER again.
- Okay.
Now, tell me, Have you got your tiara
for the premiere?
Oh, I'm not going to that.
Why not?
Hollywood premieres are not for old trout like me.
Anyway, it's not convenient.
He hasn't invited you, has he?
Mary Poppins wouldn't stand for that!
Can I help you?
- I'm perfectly capable, thank you.
As i recall.
Sweet of you.
Walt?
- Hello Dolly!
- Tommie,
you're gonna have to move that meeting with G.E.
What?
Mrs. Travers!
- Me again!
How wonderful to see you.
I'm here for my premiere.
Great!
I didn't receive my invitation,
but I just assumed
the American postal service had
fallen down on the job, as per usual.
I'll have a replacement,
sent to your hotel right away.
You are very kind, Mr Disney.
I knew you wouldn't have forgotten me.
Pam, how could I forget you?
Good evening.
Hello, could you please order me a cab?
Absolutely.
Ralph!
I had a feeling, a certain friend of mine
might be needing me tonight.
Wow!
You look like a million bucks!
Thank you.
Let's get you to that ball, huh?
- Thank you, Ralph, thank you.
This is your night.
None of this would be possible
without you.
Sometimes, the person we love.
Through no fault of his own,
can't see past the end of his nose.
What's the end of his nose.
Now, your dad is a fine gentleman.
And he loves you.
I don't think so.
You should've seen the look on his face.
It doesn't look like his own.
Well, now that don't seem likely, does it?
You know, i met your father..
There he is in that cold,
heartless bank day after day,
hemmed in by mounds of cold, heartless money.
I don't want to see any living thing caged up.
Father in a cage?
They makes cages in all sizes and shapes, you know.
Bank-shaped some of 'em,
carpets and all.
Mary Poppins, You won't ever leave us will you?
Whatever would we do without you?
- I shall stay until, the wind changes.
It's all right.
It's all right, Mrs Travers.
Mr Banks is going to be all right. I promise.
No, no. It's just that--
I can't, I can't abide cartoons!
Ohhh! Let's go fly a kite.
Up to the highest height.
Let's go fly a kite and send it soaring,
Up through the atmosphere..
Up where the air is clear...
Don't leave me.
Never.
I promise.
I will never lose you.
Winds in the East
Mist coming in--
--Like something is brewing,
about to begin--
Can't put me finger, on what lies in store--
But I feel what's to happen,
all happened before--