- Watch it.
- Sorry.
- Everyone okay?
- Sorry!
Let's go from where we left off.
That morning was the first time
I ever saw her.
But before we talk about her,
I have to tell you something about me.
And I'm sorry I have to tell you,
but I do.
When I was a kid, my dad died.
I know it's sad, but it's true,
and it happened.
And it's something
you need to know about me.
But here's the good news.
When he was alive, he was the best.
He was funny and silly and...
He had this amazing porcupine tie
he used to wear all the time.
And when he died,
my mom let me wear it to his funeral.
And after that,
I wore it pretty much every day.
Fighting dinosaurs? Tie.
Eating Sugar Pops? Tie.
Oh, man, those were so good.
Here I am playing the trumpet,
wearing the tie.
And on moving day? You guessed it. Tie.
We were moving to Mica, Arizona.
My mom said she got a good job there
and that it was quiet and far away.
She said we could start fresh.
Just the two of us.
But guess what?
Mica was quieter
than I ever could've imagined.
Nothing ever happened here.
Like, zero things.
It was a town that felt like
something was missing.
And they wanted to win.
They just couldn't.
There were no trophies,
no celebrations, no stories.
Because it had been that way for so long,
it just felt normal.
And as the new kid, that meant I became
the center of attention real fast.
And not in a good way.
And right then, I knew.
If I wanted to survive,
it was better to lay low.
I was gonna have to be
just like everybody else.
Leo?
No one would see me.
No one would hear me.
I was gonna disappear.
And then, on my ninth birthday...
And every birthday after that...
Boom! Another tie.
And another. And another.
Look at these boxes. They're amazing.
Hey, it's a trumpet!
I had no idea who they were from.
But whoever it was, they made sure
that for one moment, every year,
I couldn't forget who I was.
Happy birthday, kid.
- Thank you.
- Be safe.
And that brings us back
to where we started.
Back to my 16th birthday.
Back to the first time I saw her.
Back to when there were
more questions than answers.
And I didn't know what I didn't know.
Leo! Did you see her?
Maybe.
Trust me, you'd know.
- Oh, um, happy birthday.
- Thanks.
Wait, weren't you
at band practice this morning?
Yes, Leo.
You finally found me out.
I watch you practice band.
What are you talking about?
Did you guys see her yet?
Happy birthday.
- Are you guys messing with me?
- What are you talking about?
See you later.
Okay. I think I've told you enough
about me and Mica,
and my secret porcupine ties.
So now, we can get back to her.
And back to when something
was finally about to happen.
Kevin. Come on.
It's fascinating.
Don't you think it's fascinating?
No.
Imagine being popular
for doing absolutely nothing.
They're popular because they're beautiful.
Yeah, Tess, that's not something you do.
The burritos different?
Something tastes different.
Maybe she'll do Hot Seat
and you can interview her about nothing.
Uh, yes.
When're you guys gonna
let me be on the show?
When someone cares about anything you do.
Or even better idea,
let's put the new girl on Hot Seat.
- Uh, why?
- She'd be the perfect guest.
- What's her name anyway?
- Stargirl.
My name is Stargirl.
Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday, dear Leo
- Great job. That was amazing.
- Thank you.
Um, how'd she know your name?
How did she know it's your birthday?
This is Hot Seat,
where even if you can't pay the bills,
the heat is always on.
Wow.
That is terrible.
Also, you should say
the name of the show at the end.
So, like, "Something,
something, something,
"something better than your dumb thing...
And this is Hot Seat."
Do we need new sound effects?
Yes. New season, new material, new guests.
Ooh, Stargirl?
- How about something like this?
- Mmm-hmm.
If somebody
doesn't answer a question...
You're burned.
Oh, that's good.
Yeah, let's keep that one.
You should ask her. She likes you.
She doesn't.
She sang a song to you in the cafeteria,
in front of everyone.
Oh, I got one. Give me.
Okay, ready?
Ask Stargirl to do Hot Seat?
Give me the mic.
- Hey, guys.
- Hey, Mr. Robineau.
Junior year. Gonna be great.
How was your summers?
I actually took a speech and debate class.
Hate to jinx it,
but I'm gonna win regionals this year.
Third time's a charm. What about you, Leo?
I worked at Archie's Dino-tastic
Summer Camp. Again.
Oh, well, that sounds dino-tastic.
Hey, so Leo's new girlfriend
is gonna be on the show.
- She's not my girlfriend.
- Yet.
She's not his girlfriend yet.
You got the Geo Metro. Nice, kid.
Just promise me you won't be
one of those guys
who stops hanging out with his
friends once he has a girlfriend.
- Kevin.
- Promise?
She doesn't like me.
But she does.
Dude, it was just my birthday.
I'm gonna go to F.
C and then down, and then F.
And then, like...
I don't know, I just, like, move these.
Give me love Give me love
Okay.
And then one down.
Give me peace on...
So, Alan Ferko,
you play bass drum in marching band.
Yes.
You're burned!
Okay.
Comments and questions time,
where we take comments...
Camera one, go to audience.
Anyone else?
Literally, anyone else.
Okay. Go ahead, Benny.
So, as a member of the marching band,
do you get, like, free concessions,
like from the concession stand?
Well, not free, no.
But we do get a discount.
How much discount?
- You don't have to answer.
- 20%.
But the rule on Hot Seat is
to answer every question.
Yes, Benny.
As I know you know,
that is literally the point of Hot Seat.
And he answered the question.
- But I didn't hear him.
- 20%.
Okay? It's a 20% discount.
So, could you get me that discount?
I go to every football game.
Ask Stargirl.
Family and friends deal?
Yeah, I can. So,
you can just go to the concession stand
anytime or...
Okay, everybody ready?
Five, six, seven, eight.
We have Mud Frog spirit.
Come on now, let's...
You've been working on
that same problem for 20 minutes.
It's hard.
You sure there isn't, um,
something you wanna talk about?
I'm fine.
Sure, yeah. Well, you know,
if there is anything
you wanna talk about,
- I'll just...
- Okay.
Be sitting here across from you,
- enjoying my dinner.
- Okay.
All right.
And so,
as a result of this unfortunate situation,
we'll no longer be offering Sloppy Joes
in the cafeteria on Wednesdays.
And lastly, I would like to remind you all
that this Friday is the first
football game of the season.
Maybe this year, we'll win one.
Okay. That is everything.
Thank you, everyone.
Principal Sutters, I think you...
Oh! Students, one last thing.
You can now sign up
for this year's speech competition.
The winner, assuming anyone
can beat Mr. Singh's streak...
Yeah, Kevin!
Will go to Tucson to compete
in the regional competition.
So, if you're interested, please see
Mr. Robineau for more information.
All right, Mud Frogs.
Let's look alive!
Blue 42! Blue 42! Set, hut!
Hut, hut!
Come on, let's go!
- Go, go, go, go, go!
- Frank, he's open.
Shake it off, ref!
Ref, who you talkin' to?
And that's half-time
with the Mud Frogs trailing 17-nothing.
Mud Frog fans, don't forget to visit
the concession stand,
and remember,
tonight is two-for-one Mud...
That's right!
Is that...
That's Stargirl.
When some loud braggart
tries to put me down
And say his school is great
I tell him right away
Now what's the matter, buddy
Ain't ya heard of my school?
It's number one in the state
So be true to your school now
Just like you would to your girl or guy
Be true to your school now
And let your colors fly
Be true to your school
I got a letterman's sweater
with a letter in front
I got for football and track
I'm proud to wear it now
when I cruise around
The other parts of the town
I got my decal in back
So be true to your school now
Just like you would to your girl or guy
Be true to your school now
Let your colors fly
Be true to your school
On Friday, we'll be jacked up
on the football game
And I'll be ready to fight
We're gonna smash 'em now
My girl will be workin'
on her pom-poms now
And she'll be yellin' tonight
So be true to your school now
Just like you would to your girl or guy
Be true to your school now
Let your colors fly
Be true to your school
Go, Mud Frogs!
Yeah! Let's go, boys!
Yeah!
Let's go, Mud Frogs!
Let's go, Mud Frogs! Let's go, Mud Frogs!
- That was...
- Let's go, Mud Frogs!
Um, that was...
Thanks, Leo.
- Yes!
- Go, go, go, go, go!
Go!
And that's a Mud Frog touchdown!
Touchdown! Mud Frogs!
What a return to start the second half!
And the Mud Frogs are on the board!
So, Archie, I wanted to ask you something.
I wondered why you were here
on a Saturday.
So, um, there's this...
There's this new girl at school.
- Oh. So, you've met her.
- You know her?
Come on.
She's been homeschooled
by her mom until now.
How do you know her?
She came here to camp for a few years.
How come I never met her?
God. Different hours
'cause of the homeschool thing?
Well, why'd she stop?
New interests.
I never met someone more invested
in learning everything about everything.
She still comes by to visit
every once in a while.
Um, you said her mom. What about her dad?
She's being raised by a solo superhero,
much like your mom.
Anna. She does costumes for the theater.
Ah. They travel a lot.
Argh.
You like Stargirl.
I don't really know her.
But you're thinking maybe if you did,
you might.
She's just so... different.
Talk to her.
There she is.
You're officially our good luck charm.
We're gonna win the next one.
I could feel it.
Hey, Stargirl, I wanna ask you something.
So, last night...
- Did you ask her?
- What?
About Hot Seat.
Oh, uh...
No.
Well, you better ask her
before she gets too popular for you.
Oh.
When you started to follow me
into the desert that day after school,
why did you turn around and go back?
Um...
I... I don't remember.
Were you afraid?
No.
Did you wanna ask me something?
Yes.
My friend Kevin and I
have this show, Hot Seat.
And we were wondering if you
might wanna be a guest on the show.
On Hot Seat.
I don't think so. Um...
But thank you for the invitation.
Are you getting acquainted
with my friend, Cinnamon?
Sort of.
- Are you afraid of rats?
- Sort of.
Do you hear that, Cinnamon? He's a little
bit afraid of you.
Tickle Cinnamon behind the ears.
Go ahead. Don't... Don't be shy.
That's pretty soft.
Stargirl, dinner!
Well, Leo, I have to go in for dinner.
Say good night, Cinnamon.
- Good night, Cinnamon.
- I was talking to Cinnamon.
See you tomorrow, Leo.
Okay. Good night.
Good night, Cinnamon.
Later.
- Hey, where were you?
- Uh, sorry, I lost track of time.
Dinner's on the stove.
You can heat it up or I can.
Thanks, Mom. I'm not hungry.
See the people walkin' down the street
fall in line just watchin' all their feet
They don't know where they wanna go
but they're walkin' in time
'Cause they got the beat
They got the beat
Yeah, they got the beat
See the kids just gettin' out of school
They can't wait to hang out and be cool
Hangin' out till quarter after twelve
That's when they fall in line
They got the beat
Kids got the beat, yeah
Kids got the beat
We got the beat
Jumpin', get down
Round and round and round
'Cause we got the beat
We got the beat, we've got the beat
Yeah, we got it!
- We got the beat
We got the beat We got the beat
Let's go, Mud Frogs!
With five seconds
left on the clock and trailing by four,
the Mud Frogs have the ball on their own
35 with time for one last play.
Let's hear it for the Mud Frogs, fans!
You got this!
Go, Zack! You got this!
Go, go, go, go, go!
Come on!
- Yes! That's what I'm...
- Yes!
A Mud Frog touchdown! The Mud Frogs win!
The Mud Frogs win!
Zack James with the 65-yard run
for the score.
Can you believe it? The Mud Frogs win!
Until that night,
I had always thought
mud frogs were an odd choice for a mascot.
You see, mud frogs spend
most of their time sleeping.
They sleep at the bottom of dry ponds
in the desert, buried in mud for months.
They do this
when there's no food or water.
And then, one day, the rain comes.
And just like that, they're awake.
We were the Mud Frogs.
And we always had been.
We were just waiting for it to rain.
Did you ask her? About Hot Seat?
Oh, uh...
Yeah, no, I asked her last week.
She said she doesn't wanna do it.
You asked her last week
and you never told me?
There was a lot going on.
Did you really ask her?
When she said no, what did you say?
Did you tell her how important it is?
- Tell her about the throne of flames?
- Do you guys wanna sit with us?
- Oh, um...
- Do you think we can all fit?
Benny has, like, nine trays of food.
It's funny you came over here.
We were just talking about you.
- No, we weren't.
- Yes, we were.
- Yeah, they were.
- You were?
Uh, no. You know Kevin.
He's just always joking.
I am?
Okay.
I'm excited for the speech competition.
I signed up, too.
I'm aware.
Yeah, I'm sure of it.
These burritos are super different.
I don't know
how to make plans with you.
You don't have a phone.
You wanna make plans with me?
Yeah. I do.
I work at Archie's in the summer.
He's kind of like my uncle.
I went there as a kid, too.
I know you did.
Did he tell you?
I saw your picture on the wall.
Oh. Right.
- Um, he said it was just you and your mom?
- Yeah.
I think he told me
'cause it's just me and my mom, too.
It's a big part of why
I wanted to go to school.
It's just been the two of us for so long,
And she can be so...
Yeah. It can be like that
with my mom, too.
We travel a lot.
She does costumes for plays,
and she's always talking about
how she wants to sell the house
and live on the road,
but I told her I wanted to go
to a real school.
Am I talking too much?
- No.
- Sometimes, I talk too much and...
No. No, sometimes I'm...
I'm quiet, but I'm just thinking.
- What are you thinking?
- That I like talking to you.
I like talking to you, too.
I'm not usually good with, um, this.
Scream, Leo.
- Why would I do that?
- Why wouldn't you?
'Cause I'm not crazy.
Don't you want the universe to hear you?
I don't have anything to say.
Um...
I don't think I have that in me.
You know, in Iceland, they have
officially designated enchanted places.
Like... Wouldn't that just be great?
If you were walking along
and suddenly there's a sign declaring,
"Enchanted Site.
US Department of the Interior."
They should put one at your house.
Take off your shoes.
What?
We're here.
Close your eyes.
Have you ever done nothing, Leo?
My mom thinks I do it all the time.
No, like... Like really nothing.
Is there a trick to doing nothing?
There's no trick.
You'll find your own way.
What's your way?
Sometimes,
I imagine a giant pink eraser.
I start at my toes,
till everything from my neck down is gone.
And then comes the hard part. My senses.
My nose, my ears, my eyes, my mouth.
If I've done a good job at the end,
there's just nothing.
And then I see and I hear,
but not with my eyes and ears,
'cause they're gone obviously.
Now that I'm nothing,
there's no difference between me
and everything else.
I'm a stone.
I'm a paper cup.
I'm rain.
Did you...
I don't know. I'm nothing.
Who you are on social media
is an extension of who you are
in real life.
Space and privacy are just as important
on there as they are out here.
So, in conclusion, and remember,
I speak from experience,
do not let your mom follow you.
Because after all,
it's not social you-dia or social us-dia.
It's social me-dia. Thank you.
Yeah, Kevin!
Thank you, Kevin. And next up,
we have Stargirl Caraway.
Yes.
Thank you so much.
Did you know that rats
actually like to hang out with other rats?
I hope it's you.
And the winner of this year's
Mica High Speech Competition,
who will go to Tucson
to compete in regionals,
is Stargirl Caraway.
Yes!
Thank you.
And thank all of you for attending.
Wish us luck in Tucson.
Go, Mud Frogs.
She keeps winning
and she's not even trying.
She beat Kevin in speech,
and he's won two years in a row.
- Somehow she's better.
- Okay.
We've won four football games this year.
Before this, we never even won one.
And I think...
Well, no, I know it's her.
What do you mean?
Is she... No, it's stupid.
Is she magic?
Depends on how you define "magic."
She started doing stuff
and we started winning.
Doing stuff?
- She made it rain the other night.
- Excuse me?
- It's stupid.
- No, you're just not making sense.
Since she got here,
things have been different.
But good different.
Some people are just like that.
So is she or isn't she?
You're gonna have to figure that out
for yourself.
Is that coffee?
I... I don't drink coffee.
So what's your deal with that bike?
The kid it belongs to
got it for his birthday,
but then got into an accident.
He's been in the hospital for a few weeks,
but he's better now and coming home.
Wait, are you talking about
Hillary Kimble's brother?
- Is he a friend of yours?
- No.
How do you know that's his bike?
I have my ways.
So why was it at the thrift store?
I don't know.
His family was probably so busy
with everything going on,
they didn't even think about it.
But this way, when he's ready
to get back on, it'll be waiting.
Does she know you're coming?
No.
- So you're just gonna leave it there?
- What else would I do?
I don't know, knock? Leave a note?
That's not why I did it.
At first I thought it was my mom,
you know?
But I know it was you.
The ties. It was you.
The ties I get every year for my birthday.
I never knew who it was from, but...
I have no idea what you're talking about,
Leo Borlock.
- Hi, Mom. I have a friend with me.
- Oh, that's so...
exciting.
Never brought anyone to the house before.
- I'm Anna. What's your name?
- Leo.
Leo.
Uh, okay. Uh, we're gonna go hang out now.
Well, I'll be here.
Oh, if you need anything, anything at all,
just ask and I'll get it right away.
Sure, Mom. Thanks.
Nice to meet you.
Where's all your...
- Glitter and ribbons and magic tricks?
- Yeah.
In my office.
You have an office? Where?
It's a secret.
Oh, man.
This was my dad's favorite.
He'd drive me to school, going to work,
and we'd sing Just What I Needed
at the top of our lungs.
You sing?
I used to.
It's kind of funny
that it was our song, 'cause...
I mean, it's clearly not
about a dad and his kid.
But it's cool that a song can be
about whoever you want it to be about.
It doesn't matter what the words say.
What's this?
Big Star.
Ha...
No, really, um... That's...
That's the name of the band.
I don't, um...
I don't have a record player.
I'll just...
- Right. Yeah. Um, track number four.
- What?
Track number four, it's, um...
It's a song about
who the words say it's about.
Won't you let me
walk you home from school?
Won't you let me meet you at the pool?
Maybe Friday I can
Get tickets for the dance
And I'll take you
Ooh, ooh, ooh
Won't you tell your dad
"Get off my back"?
Tell him what we said
about "Paint It Black"
Rock and roll is here to stay
Come inside where it's okay
And I'll shake you
Ooh, ooh, ooh
Won't you tell me what you're thinkin' of?
Would you be an outlaw for my love?
If it's so, well, let me know
If it's no, well, I can go
I won't make you
Ooh, ooh, ooh
Welcome, fans,
to Leonard Jones Community Field
for tonight's championship game
between the defending champs,
the Rio Canyon Jaguars and their
All-American quarterback, Ron Kovac.
And appearing in the championship game
for the first time in school history,
the Mica Mud Frogs, led by
their up-star quarterback, Zack James.
Tonight's conditions
are partly cloudy skies...
So, Mr. Robineau told me
that I get to take a guest to Tucson.
Do you wanna come with me?
What about your mom?
I'd rather go with you, Leo.
It'll be awesome, seeing you
doing your speech in front of people.
I mean, it's amazing to me
that you can even do that.
You get up in front of all these people
and play the trumpet.
That's different.
I mean, that's all of us.
No one's looking at me.
Besides, being with you is...
What?
Being with you is, like,
the most anyone has ever looked at me
in my entire life.
When some loud braggart
tries to put me down
And say his school is great
I tell him right away
Now what's the matter, buddy
Ain't ya heard of my school?
It's number one in the state
Hey, hey! Take it away!
Get that ball and play!
So be true to your school now
Just like you would to your girl or guy
Be true to your school now
Let your colors fly
Be true to your school
I got a letterman's sweater
With a letter in front
I got for football and track
I'm proud to wear it now
when I cruise around
The other parts of the town
I got my decal in back
So be true to your school now
Just like you would to your girl or guy
Be true to your school now
Let your colors fly
Be true to your school
Do it again, do it again!
We fight! We fight!
Whoo!
On Friday, we'll be jacked up
on the football game
And I'll be ready to fight
We're gonna smash 'em now
My girls will be workin'
on their pom-poms now
And they'll be yellin' tonight
So be true to your school now
Just like you would to your girl or guy
Be true to your school now
Let your colors fly
Be true to your school
Be true to your school now
Just like you would to your girl or guy
Let your colors fly
Be true to your school!
And another first down
for the Mud Frogs
gives them a first and goal
from the Jaguar four.
Come on, Mud Frogs!
Yeah!
Mud Frog touchdown.
Beautiful pass
from quarterback Zack James.
With under six minutes
in the third quarter...
That's mine. That's right, baby.
The Mud Frogs take the lead.
Yes!
And the extra point is good.
And Ron Kovac continues this drive.
He's got a first and goal
from the Mud Frog seven.
Close on him, close on him.
And hut!
And that's a Jaguar
touchdown. Oh, what a pretty reverse.
Ron Kovac firing on all cylinders here...
And that's another third down
conversion for Kovac,
setting up the Jaguars
with a first and goal.
But with 1:12 left on the clock
and still trailing by four,
these Jaguars are gonna need
a touchdown to win.
So the Mud Frogs miracle season
comes down to this.
- Kovac! Kovac! Kovac!
- Can they stop Ron Kovac?
Hit 'em hard, Mud Frogs!
Defense! Defense! Defense!
And a vicious hit
stops Kovac for no game.
And there's an injury timeout
on the field. Injury timeout.
- He's not getting up.
- I don't think he's up.
Where's Stargirl...
What's going on? What...
What is she doing right now?
Wait, what is she doing?
Why is she helping him?
Yeah, she shouldn't.
Stargirl, where you going?
She can't leave. We need her.
She can't just leave.
Hey. I wanted to make sure
you got home okay.
Thank you.
We lost.
In case you were wondering.
Kovac's gonna be okay.
After you left,
the whole team kinda just fell apart.
You... You're our good luck charm
and you left.
They're all angry. They're just angry.
I just want to understand.
Why did you go with him?
When he got hurt,
everyone was cheering
and then no one moved.
That's what you do at a game.
But it's... It's weird, isn't it?
Someone gets hurt
and everyone's
just standing, watching. I...
I don't know.
I just... I couldn't.
I don't know what's gonna happen.
But you're sad right now and...
And I don't want you to be.
I've been listening to the, um...
I wanted to...
Won't ya let me walk you home from school?
Won't ya let me meet you at the pool?
Maybe Friday I can
Get tickets for the dance
And I'll take you
Won't you tell your dad
"Get off my back"?
Tell him what we said
about "Paint It Black"
Rock and roll is here to stay
Come inside where it's okay
And I'll shake you
Ooh, ooh, ooh
Won't you tell me
what you're thinkin' of?
Would you be an outlaw for my love?
If it's so, well, let me know
If it's no, well, I can go
I won't make you
Ooh, ooh, ooh
Hi.
This is what I wanted for you.
But now that it's happening,
it's strange.
Um, I kind of just wanna go to bed.
What's her name?
I'm trying here.
No, it's not you. It...
It's her name.
Huh?
Stargirl.
Excuse me?
It's... Her name is Stargirl.
Oh!
Leo. Shoot. Leo!
What was she thinking?
Stargirl has some nerve.
Why's Stargirl here?
Who does she think she is?
I can't believe she showed up today.
What is she doing here? Go home!
I could explain.
And I think they'd understand.
I... I don't know if it's a good idea.
They just want someone to blame.
Just ask him. Please?
You guys didn't tell me
you were coming here.
We've been coming here for weeks
without you.
You've been busy.
Where's your homework?
- Oh, I didn't bring it.
- Okay, so what do you want?
I just wanted to see you guys.
Now that Stargirl's been shunned,
you want us back?
- Kevin!
- It's not like that.
- It's not?
- I have a girlfriend. It happens.
- Not to us, it doesn't.
- It did to me.
It's really different
and I'm trying to figure it out.
And I promised
I wouldn't be one of those guys.
I'm sorry.
Well,
you never actually promised.
So, really, it's kind of your fault.
Want a slice?
Uh, yeah. Thanks.
So, um, she wants to do Hot Seat.
What?
Do you think that's a good idea?
They're all really mad.
How else is she gonna get everyone
to hear what she has to say? It's perfect.
I can totally see it. A 60 Minutes-style
mea culpa interview, an in-depth expos,
why she did it.
- Are you cool with it, though?
- Why wouldn't I be?
Well, 'cause of the speech competition.
Guys, who cares about
the speech competition? This is huge.
Uh, also, we need promo.
Posters, school paper...
It'll be great.
The whole school's gonna watch.
- Tess, when can we book the studio?
- Frankie still has it until Tuesday.
Greetings, Mica High.
And thank you for coming out
to this very special episode of Hot Seat.
Today, our guest is Mica High's very own
speech champ and controversial
good luck charm herself, Stargirl Caraway.
The hope is we'll get some answers
as to why Stargirl
made the fateful decision
to betray her own school.
Today, we'll be turning up the heat
on Hot Seat.
So, before we get into more recent events,
let's start at the beginning.
- Is your name really Stargirl?
- Yes.
- So you were born Stargirl Caraway?
- Oh, no.
Come on,
you know you can't lie on Hot Seat.
I'm not lying. My name really is Stargirl.
It's just not the name I was born with.
Okay. What name were you born with?
Susan.
So then why Stargirl?
We're made from the dust of dead stars.
Okay, let's turn up the heat.
Um...
What brought you to Mica High
in the first place?
- I understand you were homeschooled?
- I was.
Um... I...
Camera two, go in close on Stargirl.
Yes?
I just wanted to make some friends.
- You have a weird way of showing it.
- Come on. You know how this show works.
Save your comments and questions
for later.
Uh, okay, so I understand that you
came on here today because
you wanted to set the record straight
about what happened at Friday's big game.
Tell us. Why'd you do it?
He was hurt and he was alone.
- He was on the other team.
- And he was killing us.
- Guys, seriously?
- He needed help.
There's coaches and medics for that.
He didn't wanna let go of my hand.
What makes you think
you know what everybody wants?
I... I don't think I...
You're right. You don't think.
Everybody else seems to be able to,
but then you're not like everybody else.
You do all these nice things for people
that are really just selfish.
Like the bike you left my brother.
I went to the thrift store
and asked them who bought it
and when they started to describe you,
I knew who they meant.
Did you even know why the bike was there?
Did it ever occur to you to find out?
I think that's all the time we have...
Go on, Hillary.
My mom didn't think
he was ready for a bike,
but my dad insisted.
After the accident,
my dad took it to the thrift store hoping
someone could at least use it, right?
Then it shows up on our doorstep.
Did you know my brother got so badly hurt
that he'll never ride a bike again?
My parents didn't know
who would do something like that.
So I went to the thrift store,
and, yeah, here we are.
Okay, everyone.
It's time to go home.
It got really hot.
Stargirl, please wait.
We can fix this.
There has to be a way to fix this.
Some things just take time.
Or maybe you don't have to do
all the things that you do.
What do you mean?
You could just hang out.
Like, when it's just us.
So you can go back to blending in.
- This isn't about me!
- It's not?
You were the one
that said you wanted to make friends!
- I do!
- Then listen to them!
Why can't you just be
more like everybody else?
Is that what you want?
I don't know.
But I think you'd be happy.
I think we could be happy.
Stargirl.
Stargirl, come on, I'll drive you home.
I'd rather walk.
It's getting dark.
I know.
Stargirl?
Do you still wanna go with me later?
- To Tucson?
- Yeah.
Yeah. Of course, I do, Susan.
Did you change your speech?
What?
Oh, uh...
Yeah.
What's the topic?
Um, whether or not the government
should be involved in Internet censorship.
Interesting choice.
Well, what happened to...
It was too weird.
We often ask ourselves
how much involvement
the government should have in our affairs.
Especially how it pertains
to how we obtain information.
I don't know why I was giving that speech.
I don't know
why I do a lot of things lately.
I bet you find that, too, right?
And it's because we don't think,
we just do.
We don't take a step back and process.
Everything's so instant these days.
How can we?
Dinner in minutes.
A thousand photographs in one burst.
You have to "like" something this second.
You have to know
how you feel about everything.
You can't be unsure
or confused or change your mind.
There's no time to figure out who you are.
You have to know right now.
Have you ever seen a flower grow?
I mean, of course not.
It's nearly impossible
to wait for anything that takes that long.
But, if you did, it would change you.
It would slow you down.
It would remind you
that real things take time.
And it's magic, too, isn't it?
I mean, so are 1,000 photographs
in one burst,
but a flower.
You plant a seed in the ground
and a whole world develops
and stretches out and opens up.
It's easy to get confused
when we're moving so fast.
And to think we're doing the right thing
when really we're not.
But if we're lucky,
we could find a balance.
We could take a step back.
We could take a breath.
Next time you see a flower sticking up
out of the ground or in a vase,
just remember
that part of what makes it beautiful
is how long it took to grow.
Well done, Miss Caraway. Well done indeed.
Guys, don't forget,
chapters six and seven for tomorrow.
You never know what might be coming up!
We'll make an announcement
tomorrow morning.
Hey.
I'm really proud of you.
I'm sorry.
For what?
Well, I mean,
maybe it was silly, but I...
I guess I thought maybe some of them
would be happy you won.
People aren't happy because they win.
They win 'cause they're happy.
Susan, I...
Were you even listening?
- To what?
- My speech.
Of course.
That was Stargirl.
I'm Stargirl.
Susan didn't win that trophy. I did.
But you were talking about balance and...
I know that you think
that this would make it easier,
but I can't just be somebody else.
But you're Susan. You are.
That's your name.
You're off the hook for the dance,
by the way.
You can't go with someone
who doesn't exist.
- Hey.
- Hey!
I didn't see you at school.
Uh, yeah, I was in and out pretty quickly.
It's cool she won.
You don't really think that.
I do. For real.
Well, then you are the only one.
So, uh, I was, um...
I was thinking about the first day we met.
I got to school, late, of course.
And the playground was completely empty
except for this kid lying in the middle.
I thought you were dead.
I don't know.
Maybe that's all she was doing.
Maybe she was just helping someone
get back up.
I know we haven't talked since the, um...
I'm sorry about the show.
Are you kidding me?
I'm a legend.
It's all anyone's talking about.
That's probably the best thing
that's ever happened to me.
- Good night, Kevin.
- Later.
This came for you.
Is it from her?
Stargirl?
Oh, man.
The Cars.
Were you ever afraid
of what people thought of you
when you were my age?
Like, to the point where
you did things you wish you didn't do?
You just describing a teenager?
Your dad
was one of the only people I ever knew
who was always completely himself.
Do you still, um...
Do you still miss him?
Every day.
I mean, not all day, every day,
but definitely every day.
I don't ever wanna stop missing him.
I don't either.
When we moved here after he died,
it was the first time
I really had to think about who I was.
Your dad was such a big personality
and he just...
He took up so much
space.
And even though it was painful,
I finally had to figure out
who I wanted to be.
Did you?
Well, I know more now than I did then.
I mean, of course,
I just wanna tell you everything.
I wanna give you all the answers,
but those are my answers.
Figuring out who we are is probably
the one thing no one else can do for us.
I think I still have some
of your dad's old records in the garage.
Should we go look?
Everybody's always obsessin'
'Bout what everybody thinks about them
But I don't wanna be like them, no
I just wanna dance, dance
Don't wanna think about nothin'
Just keep the stereo pumpin' and dance
I just wanna dance, dance
Don't wanna think about nothin'
Just put on somethin'
that's bumpin' and dance
With my eyes wide open
I can escape
Whoa oh oh
I'm wakin' up
I'm wakin' up while I'm sleepin'
I'm wakin' up, I'm wakin' up
while I'm sleepin'
Hi.
Nice tie.
Um, you look... You look, um...
- Thanks, Leo.
- You're welcome, Stargirl.
Are you ready for your surprise?
I have no idea.
We have a special request
for this next song
and a special guest
to sing it with us, Leo Borlock!
- What?
- Leo?
You got this.
Leo's gonna sing?
I don't know what song you're doing.
Yeah, you do. You know, The Cars.
By the way, killer tie, man.
Sorry. Sorry.
I don't mind you comin' here
And wastin' all my time
'Cause when you're standin', oh, so near
I kinda lose my mind
It's not the perfume that you wear
It's not the ribbons in your hair
And I don't mind you comin' here
And wastin' all my time
I don't mind you hangin' out
And talkin' in your sleep
It doesn't matter where you've been
As long as it was deep, yeah
You always knew to wear it well
And you look so fancy, I can tell
And I don't mind you hangin' out
And talking in your sleep
I guess you're just what I needed
I needed someone to feed
Just what I needed
I needed someone to bleed
Yeah!
I never said I was sorry.
I'm really sorry.
And just like that, she was gone.
Her mom sold the house.
I imagine they were on the road somewhere.
But even though she was gone,
she was everywhere.
But I still didn't know.
Was it real?
Or was it something else?
Dinosaurs can kind of do a number
on your brain, can't they?
- What?
- They seem magical,
these enormous beasts,
roaming some mystical place.
But they were real.
And they were here.
Look at this bone.
Now there is nothing more real than that.
But that doesn't make it any less magical.
You think things have to be real or magic,
but the best things are both.
She asked me to show you something.
And there, in her office,
I finally saw her.
All her glitter and ribbons
and magic tricks.
Information found just like anyone else.
Only nobody else did find it.
'Cause nobody else cared to.
Who cares about strangers' birthdays?
Or stories about other people?
Who would take the time
for someone they don't even know?
And the time to learn and grow when
they realize they did something wrong?
And even though I couldn't find her,
she still found a way,
every now and then,
to find me.
For a while,
she was all anyone could talk about.
Where did she go? Why did she leave?
And why was she here in the first place?
Did it all happen for a reason?
Or was it just one of those things?
It got to the point
where people started to wonder
if she'd been a ghost or an alien.
Or maybe out of boredom,
we just made her up.
As the years went by,
the stories got more elaborate.
She played every instrument
in the marching band.
She could make flowers
appear out of thin air.
She knew what you were thinking
before you did.
One time, I even heard she could fly.
Later, when those of us
who were there got together,
we would laugh about it.
Laugh at how ridiculous they were,
at how some kids would believe anything.
But as the memories became stories,
and the stories became memories,
even we began to wonder.
She was just a girl, wasn't she?
A girl just like anyone else.
It was silly to even talk about it.
After all, nothing ever happened here.
Nothing at all.
Give me love Give me love
Give me peace on earth
Give me light
Give me life
Keep me free from birth
Give me hope, help me cope
With this heavy load
Trying to touch and reach you
With heart and soul
Oh, my Lord please
Take hold of my hand
And I might understand you
Won't you please Oh, won't you
Gimme love Give me love
Give me peace on earth
Give me light
Give me life
Keep me free from birth
Give me hope Help me cope
With this heavy load
Tryin' to touch you, tryin' to reach you
With my heart and soul
Oh, my Lord please
Take hold of my hand
And I might understand you
Won't you please Oh, won't you?
Don't say maybe Just await me
We can stay here
For as long as we want
Make forever last a while
Leave the light on
After the song
Leaves and goes to a far off ocean
Lay here with me
And I'll catch you
Falling into me Falling into you
Letting go of all the things
I thought were true
Falling into me
as I'm falling into you
It seems so clear
that I don't know what to do
I speak too much
You stay closed off
But I can see
Your thoughts in the stardust
Shining back at me
As I catch you
Falling into me Falling into you
Letting go of all the things
I thought were true
Falling into me as I'm falling into you
It seems so clear
that I don't know what to do
One day I'll be old and ugly
Will you still be thinking of me?
If we were as brave as we are now
And I'll catch you
Thinking of me as I'm thinking of you
Letting go of all the things
I thought were true
As you're falling into me
I'm falling into you
It seems so clear
that I don't know what to do
That's it.