James and Cynthia Green?
- Yes.
- Right this way, please.
Okay.
James and Cynthia Green.
Thirteen Oak Lane Road, Stanleyville.
Yeah.
Wait. You didn't answer
what makes you qualified.
Oh, we know.
There wasn't much space.
We had so much to say.
Also here on page four.
In response to,
"What experience or experiences
"have best prepared you,"
you only wrote "Timothy."
Yes.
The only chance
you two have is
if you put it all on the table.
We agree.
That's why we want
to use our time to tell you our story.
Okay.
There's just one thing.
You're going to find it hard to believe.
This all began last September.
We'd been trying for a number of years,
and Dr. Hunt finally gave us the news.
First of all, you couldn't
have tried harder.
Or done more.
We have explored every medical option
at a great cost to you.
But there comes a point when you...
You have to accept...
I am so sorry.
Hold it!
Come on, honey. Come on. Come on.
Oh! Can you push the button for me?
Push it right there.
Good job! What would I do without you?
High-five!
So we drove back home.
We went back to work
and on with our day.
We'll get 8 puppy.
I don't want a puppy!
- Bye.
Hey, Tommy.
Here you go. I'll see you inside.
Good job.
Like all good stories,
the Stanleyville pencil factory,
this museum and
this town begins with a dream.
Stanley Crudstaff, our patron.
This is his original desk over here.
Please follow me.
You hungry?
Hey, sis!
Uh, just checking in to make sure
you're still up for tomorrow.
We'd be willing to host.
The kids just bought Bart a new grill.
You wouldn't believe it.
Hi, this is Allen Rust
with the Sisters of Mercy Hospital.
Please call me back about
an outstanding balance. Thank you.
Honey.
We're moving on.
You can see we've
got some dirt here.
But in order to
make good growing soil...
...and a good growing bed
for your garden,
you've got to get down
a good 12 to 18 inches.
I can't do it. I can't move on.
Then move out of the way.
For years, we've been thinking about
what our kid would have been like.
Don't.
We can move on tomorrow.
Just for tonight,
can we have a kid?
You heard what the doctor said.
Give it up! Give it up.
There we go. Never give up!
Our kid
would never give up.
You know what else I think?
- I can't.
- Our kid
would have your good heart.
This isn't funny, Jim.
But our kid would be funny.
Not make fun of other people funny,
or burp and fart funny,
but funny like...
Funny like Uncle Bub.
You know that, uh,
that kind of kid that you always believe.
Someone honest.
You want a truth-teller.
Yeah, I do. I want one like that.
But our kid can't be perfect.
I don't want one of
those annoying perfect kids.
How about this?
Honest to a fault.
- Yes! We have a winner.
- Yes! Yes!
- Would our kid be musical?
- Definitely.
Clarinet like me, drums like you, or...
I don't know what kind of instrument.
All I know is our kid...
Our kid would rock!
- Ah! We so agree.
- Our kid would rock!
Write that.
Artistically.
Picasso with a pencil.
Yes.
A glass half-full person.
Love and be loved.
How great an athlete are you picturing?
You were terrible at soccer.
That's not true.
Not true.
I was a big klutz.
All right.
How about this? How about this?
Just once, our kid,
amazing kid.
Got to score the winning goal.
Touchdown! Go, Green!
Yes! That's our kid!
Now what?
We got some rain.
Everything is going to be fine.
Honey, did you say something?
I said we...
What?
I think it's gone.
Jim.
Wait. Wait.
Oh!
Hi.
- Hi.
I'm Timothy.
That's a common name.
Well, can we get you cleaned up?
Yeah, um, do you have a towel?
- Yeah, we do.
- Yeah.
This feels about right.
911.
State your emergency.
Yeah, I'd like to report a missing...
This is Jim Green. 13 Oak Lane Road.
Hey, Jim. It's Marty from the factory.
I'm just picking up a few extra hours.
Oh, Marty.
We have in our possession a...
Ah, God, I don't know how to say this.
Has anybody reported a missing...
Jim? Jim, are you there?
I ran away from home once.
I can't remember why.
And I didn't get very far.
What about you?
Did you run away?
No.
Come on.
I bet your parents are worried and
wondering.
Cindy!
Honey!
There's something you need to see.
Actually there's something
you need to see.
Hi.
Well, look who cleaned up good.
Er...
Mmm.
Hmm!
Hmm?
Hmm.
- Are those...
- Yes. Mmm-hmm.
Please don't ask about my leaves.
- Okay.
- No.
But you can look at them.
If you want.
Not everybody has these.
Yep.
Do you mind
if I...
Sorry.
Now my mind is racing
with even more questions.
Honey, you need to go look out back.
I'll just be right outside.
Hi.
on.
Oh.
Oh, hey! Donnie!
False alarm!
We thought we had a burglar.
It was just a raccoon family
that we, we...
I chased it away, so everything's...
- Everything's fine.
- You sure?
Yeah, we're sure. Everything's good.
Jim, is there something
you're not telling us'?
Yeah.
Uh. no. Why?
Come on, Jim. We're on
strict water rationing.
Turn in your sprinkler,
and we'll let this one slide.
But it rained.
No, it didn't.
Unless it only rained in your yard.
What do you know?
Amazing, huh?
Well, Green, it's your lucky day.
Yes, it is.
There you go. You had the right idea.
Back in there, back in there. All right.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
We really like to eat fresh, healthy food
here. A lot of vegetables
from our own garden.
I guess I'm known primarily
for my tomatoes.
I do a lot of canning.
But I'm also a firm believer
in the late-night snack.
Hey, how is it going?
Good.
This is Jim, and I'm Cindy.
Yeah, feel free to call us...
- Cindy and Jim.
Why would I?
That's no problem. You can...
- Call us Mr. and Mrs. Green.
- Mr. Green.
Not many people do, but...
Mom, really?
Dad.
Can I talk to you, Jim?
- He called me "Mom."
- Yes, he did.
- He called you "Dad."
- I know. I know.
Fifty-four girl names on the list,
and there was one boy, and it was...
Timothy.
Is he for us?
I'm getting that feeling.
-Be careful.
- Yeah.
Careful, careful.
There you go.
It was as if, all of a sudden,
everything had changed.
There he was, leaves and all.
Didn't matter where he came from.
-He was ours.
-Yeah, we were his.
-And we were a family.
-We were a family.
Have we lost you? Are you still with us?
It's kind of crazy, right?
I've heard crazier.
- Really?
- No.
That said, it's your time
to use as you choose.
I just have two words for you.
Tick tock.
-Oh, right.
-Oh.
Okay.
So...
I think she forgot.
Ah, you're always early.
Hello!
Hi.
Hello there.
I'm Timothy.
Nice to meet you, Timothy.
Jim!
I got here last night.
I came from the garden.
Oh.
That's unusual.
Hi, sis! Okay, good.
Well, I'm glad you guys met. Jim?
Yeah!
I'm coming. Hey. Hi, Brenda.
Who was that?
- Oh!
- Are we early?
Oh, gosh.
I didn't think so.
Jim?
There we go.
- Jim!
- I'm on it!
Okay, kiddo,
you ready to meet some people?
- Mmm-hmm.
- Good, because we're not.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Good.
-Okay.
Now, all the kids
you're going to meet today,
they come from their moms' tummies.
Whereas you come from...
- The garden.
- Yes!
I don't know about you,
but I have a tendency to over-share.
So maybe we just keep
some things between us for now.
Like the garden or your leaves.
Why?
Because they may not understand.
Can you understand
that they may not understand?
- I think so.
- Yes?
- Mmm-hmm.
- Good!
Let's go get ready to meet some people.
Okay.
Hold the corner down. Thank you.
Hey. Hey, everybody.
Here's what's happening.
It's no secret that
we've been trying to have a family
and we got some good news.
I know it's all of a sudden.
His name is Timothy.
And please don't ask
too many questions.
When were
you going to tell me,
and how old is he,
and where did he come from?
It was all very sudden
and kind of miraculous.
Huh.
I mean, I thought
you were trying to have a real kid.
I mean, you know, one of your own.
He felt like mine
from the first time I saw him.
I'm sorry.
These are the coals.
I'm going to put that down for a second.
Well, with a little heads-up, I could've
helped with the clothes at least.
Hey, guys-
- Hey.
- Hi.
- How's it going?
- Yeah, good. You know.
- Is it going?
- Yeah.
How's everything going over there?
Who invited him?
I didn't think he would come.
Hi.
- Oh, hello.
- Hey, Timothy.
Hey.
This is my dad.
Hi, Grandpa.
Uh...
Call me Big Jim.
Okay, bye!
Okay.
Timothy, come here.
Grandpa?
This is my Aunt Mel and my Uncle Bub.
They practically raised me.
- Hello, Timothy.
- Hi.
Hello, young man.
Hello, old boy.
Did you know I invented
the peanut butter and jelly sandwich?
Did you know I'm a big fan of your work?
Well, goodbye.
- Hi, I'm Timothy.
- Hi.
Hi. Hi.
Hi.
- Hi.
- Hey.
So you all came from
your mom's tummy?
How was that?
This all you got?
I know.
Who wants to play?
The object, boys and girls,
is to dodge,
so how about we start with you?
Oh!
Out! You're out!
You got to move!
You got to dodge the ball, Timothy.
Come on!
Gotta move, gotta move, gotta move.
Into prison. You're out.
You have to coach him
because he clearly doesn't understand.
Timothy, Timothy. Timothy, Timothy.
Look, it's just down to five kids.
Move your feet. Move around.
Keep an eye on the ball.
You're going down.
Stick and move,
stick and move! Come on!
Oh!
Get in there. Go. Help him out.
Ahh!
Let's just call this...
I don't think this is a good idea.
You're not going
to spoil all the fun, are you?
- No, but... Could you just...
- Go, go, go, go.
Okay. Hey. Here we go,
here we go, here we go!
You got to dodge the ball.
Move your feet.
Take it easy, Big Jim.
This is not the Olympics.
The thing about these kids is
you never know what you're getting.
They have issues sometimes. Medical or
otherwise.
And if he has any issues,
we'll deal with them.
- Like any normal kid.
- Okay.
I mean, that's not normal.
Hey!
Oh, my...
Hey. What did you do that for?
Out! You are... Uh-oh!
- Come on. It's dodgeball.
- Big Jim, honestly.
I can't believe
I'm about to say this,
but what did you say to your father
after he bonked the boy
with leaves in the head?
Hmm. It's complicated.
- I didn't say anything.
- Mmm-hmm.
Really?
But I made a vow
that I would do things
differently than my dad.
I would be much better...
Jim decided that
he would be the father he never had.
What about you?
I decided that
our son would not be
seen as different or weird.
He'd be treated like a normal kid.
Yeah.
Because that's what he was going to be.
Just a... A normal kid.
Incredible.
Good color, strong veins.
Yeah. They're beautiful, aren't they?
Most unusual.
Can you cut them off?
But they're perfectly healthy.
Why would you...
Oh, right.
Timothy, Reggie and I go way back.
He's amazing with plants,
and if there's anyone
who can do this, he's the guy.
You know, when I was your age,
I had a wart on my thumb.
The other kids,
they used to call me "The Warthog."
Kids can be so cruel.
You know, my dad,
he had a doctor burn that puppy off,
and after that,
nobody made fun of me at all.
We don't want anyone
to make fun of you.
That's what this is about.
What do you think?
Okay. Go for it.
Okay.
Okay. You may feel a slight pinch.
Okay. Take a deep breath.
We're here, pal.
This isn't going to work, is it?
No.
You take them
to the doctor, right?
You give them medicine
that doesn't taste good,
they get shots that hurt.
That's the job.
We thought we were doing our job.
What did you put in there?
He's about to fall over.
Anything he might need.
Notebooks, pencils.
There's a box of tissues
on the bottom and some Band-Aids.
There's a whole first aid kit
actually, just in case...
Variety of healthy snacks,
treats and Graham Crackers.
I know you like them.
And then a flashlight
and some batteries.
Mom, I think I can handle it from here.
Oh, there's an extra pair of socks!
- Have a great day!
- Okay, bye!
That's too much pressure.
Have the day you have.
This morning you were late for work,
there's a jelly stain on your sweater.
And frankly you seem
inappropriately cheerful.
I know, but there is good reason.
We've had a young boy come to stay...
ls there something about my expression
that suggests I'm
the least bit interested?
No, ma'am, nothing
about your expression is...
And you continue to talk because...
I'm sorry.
Hello?
Best-case scenario, reduced hours.
Limited layoffs. Limited.
Like you lose your job
and you lose your job.
Not you specifically, but some of you.
Worst-case scenario,
my aunt and my father will have
no choice but to close the factory.
I know.
I don't want that to happen.
Hello?
And I'm not saying that that's...
I'm sorry, Green?
Are we disturbing you?
Hi, honey.
Jim, the school called.
- What's the matter?
- How fast can you get here?
Thank you so much
for coming so quickly.
We take these matters very seriously.
- Thank you.
- Come. Come. He's here.
Timothy!
No!
Hey, who did this to you?
He won't give us the names of the kids.
What happened?
Art project.
Art project?
Let's get this art project cleaned up.
Just let me.
- Jim...
- Timothy.
This kind of thing happened to me
when I was your age.
Yeah.
And all I wanted
was for my dad to have my back,
and he didn't.
So here's what we're going to do.
You're going to tell me the names
of the boys that did this to you.
Okay?
And I will handle it.
Hey, boss.
Green.
I guess
you heard what happened.
Yeah, they called me home.
Yeah, me, too.
What's going on?
Your father's handling this.
I didn't really mind.
Your kid ratted my boys out.
He didn't rat them out.
That was my fault.
So you ratted my boys out.
You can't let people
treat you like this. Come on.
How long you been
at this parenting thing?
Are you really going to
fight all his battles for him?
You think that's wise?
Hi!
It was really important to Jim
that the Crudstaff boys
take responsibility for
what they did to Timothy.
- Yeah.
- And did they?
We were having fun.
He didn't fight back.
He didn't even cry.
It wasn't any fun.
I think what the boys
are trying to say is next Saturday
we're having a birthday party pool bash,
and we'd love it if Timothy would come.
Yes!
Oh, please. Don't tell me
you took him back
to the house of the boys who bullied him.
He really, really wanted to go.
So you let him decide what was best.
I thought it was time
he learned to fight his own battles.
We just forgot to ask if he could swim.
Nice socks, Green!
# Happy birthday to you
# Happy birthday dear Bobby
So was it fun?
- How did it go?
- Were they nice?
Were you the man?
I kicked a girl in the head.
- What?
- Why'?
Well, she tried to pull down my socks.
What? Did she see you?
I don't think so.
Maybe.
I'm sure she didn't see him.
You cannot let anybody
see your leaves, honey.
I know, but
what do I do about the girl
I kicked in the head?
Jim?
Well, if you see her coming,
just run the other way.
- Okay.
- Yeah. Yeah.
You know I saw.
Look.
No.
Just look.
Why?
You'll see.
Wow.
You're not the only one with a secret.
You coming?
Okay.
It's perfect.
Whoo!
Look at that nest!
I get inspired from this street, you know,
for my sculptures and my art.
Yeah.
I always get inspired by nature.
I almost forgot.
Compliments of the Crudstaffs.
And, please, tell your friends.
Thanks.
We're all working hard.
I know. It's going to be fine.
- Jim.
- Hey, honey.
It's not really a good time.
Look out your window.
Remember when he said
he kicked a girl in the head?
- Yeah.
- Is that her?
Because this is too soon.
He's too young.
You told him to run the other way when he saw her and...
he's not running...
Whoa!
See you.
Yeah. See you.
Yes! Yes! Yes!
Timothy?
Timothy!
That night,
our plan was to sit Timothy down,
just as parents. Go right at it.
Right at what?
Well, we were going to have...
"The talk"
...that you have that we
didn't really know how to have.
That was the plan.
The talk, that night.
-Hey, buddy.
-But then...
What is it?
Sweetie, it's your Uncle Bub.
We got to go. Come on.
- Are we too late?
- No, no.
Bubbles is still with us.
I brought your favorite cookies.
If I can get them past the police,
I'll leave you one.
At least it's not ice cream.
Remember the year
that you started to lose your hair
and you convinced Brenda and me
that if we gave you ice cream at night,
it would grow back?
Cinderella, do you remember
that painting you made?
No. What painting?
You know, when your mom was your age
she was quite an artiste.
Not really. I was not.
Oh, she was never happier
than when she had
a paintbrush in her hand.
That's right.
She worked on this
one painting for days.
Wouldn't let anybody see it.
Had to get it right.
You remember that?
No.
It was a self-portrait.
We didn't get it.
It was ahead of its time.
We all laughed.
Boy, did you cry.
You ran away,
and when you came back,
the picture was gone.
You'd thrown it away.
Oh!
I always felt so bad about that.
No!
Oh, Bub!
We're going to
take a little break.
Bubbles, you're going to
have a little rest.
Let Timothy stay, huh?
Okay. You okay?
It's okay, Mom.
Okay.
We're right here.
Hey.
Something you want to ask me?
Is it true you also invented the BLT?
I mean, I would have
brought my kids if I'd known.
- Shouldn't he be resting?
- Maybe you should get him.
- I'm on it.
- No, let them be.
I never thought I'd hear that laugh again.
Next.
After that, we needed to
get Timothy back to just...
- Hi.
-...being a kid.
Coach Cal doesn't see it.
Next.
Help us out here, Coach.
This would be really good for him.
This is the best possible way for him
to make some friends.
Go! Go! Go! Go!
Come on, Green. Let's see what you got.
That's right.
Let's see what you got!
Eye on the ball.
Oh, my gosh!
Take the smiles off your faces.
Is your ankle all right?
He's good.
Come on, Green!
Eyes on the ball!
Oh, dear God.
Why are you smiling?
I can only get better.
Erasers, run it out!
Come on. Hustle up!
- Green.
- Nice job.
Run, run, run!
Don't cut any corners.
Excuse me, Coach, I just want to say
that I'll be working with him
around the clock if necessary
just to get him to the next level.
Oh, tell me you're not
those kind of parents.
The type that get
over-involved, over-invested.
We are definitely
not those kind of parents.
Then we won't have a problem.
- Jim.
- Come on! Run it out!
Come on, Timothy.
Come on, run faster. Yes, yes, yes!
Run it out, Erasers!
What is she doing here?
I don't know.
There are so many girls.
Yeah, okay.
Which means it's possible
to find the right girl.
Use your feet. Your feet.
What your dad wants to say but isn't
is that it would be a mistake
to focus on just one fish
-when there are so many...
- Fish?
Keep your eyes on the ball.
Use the inside of your foot. All right?
Jim! Could you...
What your mom is trying to say...
Right.
Well...
-Uh!
- Okay
Come on.
Listen. I know the feeling.
You do?
When I was about your age, I met a girl.
She was an original.
Creative, artsy type.
So... I know the pull.
Jim? Where you going with this?
What happened with the girl?
I married her. Right.
Not what I had in mind, but...
It's true.
Okay! Keep your eye on the ball,
inside of the foot, stay on your feet! Go!
- Wow!
- Oh! Perfect!
- Perfect, perfect, perfect!
- Look at that!
It's not that
we wanted him to be perfect.
That's what we're looking for!
- We wanted it to be perfect.
- Let's go again.
His childhood.
And just when we started to
get the hang of it at home...
Things got
complicated at the factory.
Looking good, Brian.
Boss wants to see you. In his office.
- Now?
- Now.
You want to see me?
Sit.
Heard your kid joined the Erasers.
Yes. Yes, he did.
Is he good? Hope he's good.
Well...
That's a confidential list.
First round of layoffs.
Of course, my aunt and my father
might decide that that's not enough.
But these are all good,
hard-working people.
Green, you don't decide who we let go.
You'll just be the one to tell them.
Night, guys.
Oh, why couldn't
the skeleton cross the road?
Why, sweetie?
Because it had no guts.
Ooh! I got another one.
Buddy.
Not tonight.
If you will excuse me.
Dad?
That Halloween,
your mom went as a pencil.
- A blue pencil.
- Mmm-hmm.
Hmm.
- It was a good costume.
- It was.
My head was the eraser.
I had seen a lot of pencils,
but I had never seen
one quite like your mom.
Breathtaking.
But I was too scared to even talk to her,
so I wrote her a note.
Yeah.
- What did it say?
- It said...
"it feels to me that with a pencil
"anything is possible."
That is so true.
Hey. Pass me that book. Yeah.
All of these...
All of these notebooks from that day,
I just filled them with ideas
of things that I wanted to make.
Because I thought
to be a part of making something,
that was a great feeling.
God, to think that
we may not be making these anymore.
Why not make a new kind of pencil?
- That's easier said than done.
- Yeah.
Well, you can design it
and you can draw it.
Then you guys can both build it.
I want to write a note to Joni.
Good night.
How do you tell your child
something's not possible?
That it can't be done.
When they believe in you like that.
We didn't want to disappoint him.
No. We got busy.
Not that we thought
that we could do it.
At least Timothy
would know that we tried.
Yeah. We stayed up
all that first night.
We stayed up
several nights after that.
Cindy started making sketches.
Jim started carving
It turns out we weren't
the only ones making something.
Yeah. We both came up
with the idea to use leaves.
Leaves.
See? Now just wind it.
The other way. Yeah. You got it.
Just a little more.
Yeah, see?
Just put it right through.
- Like this?
- That's good.
So we've got
our leaf slurry pretty much ready.
Okay. Right on in.
- Perfect.
- That should do it.
Let's see. Help it...
Help it push it down.
Okay.
Oh, yeah!
Ta-da!
Oh, my gosh!
This is the pencil. You really did it.
- We did.
- You made it.
So we're to believe
that you made a pencil out of leaves?
- Mmm-hmm.
- Well, it was a prototype.
You do realize if any part of
your story doesn't check out,
we are done here.
And we will be
checking it out. Thoroughly.
- And you should.
- Well, good.
Anyway, that Monday
was take your kid to work day.
He started with me.
It was kind of
a celebratory day at work and...
Timothy wanted to be in on it.
Something's missing.
Oh, nonsense. It's you. So...
Very you.
Gentlemen.
And as soon
as he met my boss,
he didn't know to be intimidated by her,
and the next thing you know...
Little man, what do you think of that?
Not much.
Well, that's honest.
Timothy's very honest, ma'am.
That was done by a renowned artist
at great expense.
I would have done it for free.
Are you suggesting
you could do it better?
I can try.
Well, let's find out.
May I just remind you,
ma'am, as his parent,
that he is only ten years old, and...
Don't you have somewhere to be?
Of course I do, but...
- Shoo.
- Okay.
Oh!
Oh, sweetie.
Oh, it's beautiful. It's amazing.
It's amazing.
Oh, no, no, no.
Erase that.
Why?
It turns out, Timothy
was Picasso with a pencil.
So he had
all the qualities you imagined?
Oh, yes.
Yeah, well,
including honest to a fault.
He couldn't help
but draw her exactly as he saw her.
Yeah.
It included an unfortunate
thatch of chin hair.
Mmm.
So, what else aren't you telling me?
Tell her.
Hmm?
I'm waiting.
Sometimes you wear
plaids and stripes that clash.
Hmm.
Your one joke that
you always tell, it's not funny.
No one can appreciate the art in here
because everything
that is special and beautiful,
no one can see
because the curtains are so thick
that the light can't get in.
Not to mention, if someone has a child
who just is born or appears,
say congratulations with a smile.
Say something nice.
I wanted to love you,
and I have tried so hard to like you.
But if someone asked me to be
a pallbearer at your funeral,
I would tell them not by
the hair of my chinny-chin-chin.
And furthermore...
- Cindy lost her job.
- I lost my job.
I didn't regret most of what I said.
But you lost your job.
Make sure all the pencils are good.
So things were going to get harder.
But at least I still had my job.
Yes, he did.
They go in this box.
They go on a little pencil vacation.
And what did you say about
having Timothy with you that day?
- Oh, right.
- That's a lot of trees.
I couldn't help but feel...
Mind if I have one?
...anything was possible.
You want another one?
You want a yellow one?
We got this... You see, we got a whole...
- Right back.
- Good luck, Dad.
So Jim gave it his best shot.
Sir? How you doing?
- Huh?
- Do you have a minute?
No.
Oh, hell. Why not?
Turns out we may all get the axe.
What?
Then I think we got nothing to lose.
What if we made a new kind of pencil?
Come on, Erasers!
Come on! Come on!
Push up the field! Push up the field!
Don't pass it!
How do you score if you pass it!
Kick it! Kick the ball!
- Mom! I'm so thirsty.
- What are you doing?
No, no, no. Get back on D. Back on D!
Come on!
I saw your car.
Didn't know the kid was a player.
What position? Striker?
Uh...
Well, he's taking a break right now.
Oh, well, I got time.
It might be a while.
You know, I'm impressed, Dad.
You never really came to my games.
No. I came.
You were always on the bench.
Come on, Luke.
Find your man. Find your man!
You got to want it!
Oh, here we go.
Come on, I want to see some fight!
To keep you hydrated, sir.
Thank you.
He's a water boy.
No. Dad,
actually, I'm working
on all aspects of his game right now.
And you know what...
Come on, Erasers.
Keep your head in the game.
Let's go, Bobby! Let's go!
Good pass. Good pass.
- All right.
- Yeah. Yeah.
Good eye! Good eye!
Talk to each other!
Erasers, talk to each other!
That's your house, Philip!
Don't let nothing in there!
That's your house!
All this time, it felt like
there was something
Timothy wasn't telling us.
And he was spending
far too much time with that girl.
Was it a problem for you?
Well,
they were up to something,
and we didn't know what.
Can you teach me to do that thing?
You know, that you do with your arms
and you put your head up in the sun.
Well, first, find the light, all right?
Okay.
Just absorb it.
Just soak it in. Think "tree."
- Do you feel it?
- Yeah, I feel it.
Nice.
Maybe you should show your birthmark,
because people might like it.
I don't know.
We didn't know
what he was doing with the girl.
It was fine if he wanted to have a secret
as long as he shared it with us.
So Cindy did
what she thought was best.
Hey!
We need to talk.
Okay, let's talk.
Well, can you wait?
Fine.
I don't think that
you're the best influence on my son,
And I want you to tell me what you know about him
I know a lot.
I thought so.
So you know that he's got...
You know that he's different.
Yeah. It's what I like about him.
Well, it's a hard world
to be different in.
And I don't want him to be hurt.
By you or anyone.
I won't let it happen.
That's good.
What is this?
He's going to be misunderstood.
Lots of people hate anything different.
I wish it wasn't this way, but
I wish a lot of things. I wish...
It took my breath away,
this world they created.
I was wrong
about this, this girl.
You did this?
Yeah. Timothy and I did it together.
I had made a mistake.
We made lots of mistakes.
Yeah, we made mistakes
trying to fix our mistakes.
Isn't that how you know you're a parent?
You seem to forget
what the object is here.
You need to persuade us.
Tell me, what would you do differently?
We'd make better mistakes?
- Better?
- Different. New.
New mistakes.
That's... That's what we'd do.
Yeah.
Put your heart into it, Erasers!
Smarten up out there.
Bobby.
The most amazing thing happened.
I woke up this morning
and I started to draw again.
Oh, God! It must be so nice to
have time to waste.
It was like coming home.
My three are so busy with
their second languages,
their public service work...
Oh, and their upcoming music recital.
Your presence is expected.
Let's go, Erasers! Come on!
Brenda's freaking me out.
What's wrong?
If you're on the bench now,
you'll be on the bench of life later on.
Jim, that is your father talking.
Coach. Coach!
Put Green in!
Come on.
Good, Coach. Thank you.
What are you doing? No, no, no. Jim...
Put...
What's going on?
Oh, great.
Now he's going to do that again.
What?
He's going to uncross his arms,
crack his knuckles,
then he will turn and go.
Yep.
It's fine that he did that to me,
but now he's doing it to Timothy.
Hey, Jim...
Look. Look.
Here, Grandpa Jim.
You know what I feel
really good about?
Bart and I are just grateful
that our kids' school
has a gifted and talented program.
Did you know Timothy is gifted?
How so?
Well...
He always finds the bright side.
He never gives up
and he has a good heart.
That will get you into college.
- He's a great artist.
- Look where that got you.
Get open!
Brenda, I have to say, lam...
What? I'm listening.
He's musical.
- Really?
- Yeah.
What instruments does he play?
"He's musical?"
What possessed you to even say that?
She just kept bragging
about how her kids could do this,
her kids could do that.
So Cindy's sister
has this yearly family concert
that we never seem to miss.
If I'd known
what she was going to pull that day,
we never would have shown up.
Thank you. Thank you.
Brilliant.
Thank you. This year
we are going to dispense
with our traditional encore.
Oh!
Because we have a very special treat.
Sit back and enjoy
the musical stylings of Timothy Green!
You know what'?
We're running late to something.
Go ahead and do the encore because...
No, Mom, it's okay. It's fine, Mom.
Um, Timothy?
- Hey, pal.
- Hey.
It's okay.
Just get him, baby. Just go.
Just get him. Get him.
Just go get him.
Hey, pal?
All my friends know the low rider
The low rider is a little higher
Yeah!
Can we go back and do it again?
No.
I don't think we'll be invited back.
But it doesn't matter
because you were great.
You rock, buddy.
It felt great to rock.
It felt great to have a kid who rocked.
- Good night.
It was all you.
And us, but mostly you.
Hey.
- We were proud of you.
- Mmm-hmm.
Turn the lights off in five, okay?
Good night!
We rocked!
We did.
You know what this means?
I think I do!
This Sunday at the championship game
our son is going to
score the winning goal.
Whoo! Let's go!
Ha! Yeah! Let's go!
All right, way to go, Coach!
No! No!
No, no, no. No, you don't! Not this time!
- You are staying for this one!
- I can't stay.
- You're staying.
- I got lots, I got a lot...
You will not be sorry!
I promise you.
- Okay.
- All right. Come on! Come on!
Yes!
Hey, Jim, how's he going to
score the winning goal
if he's never in the game?
Good point.
Hey, Coach. Coach, I just want
to give you the heads-up.
Timothy Green is
your difference-maker today.
That is your game-changer right there.
You're kidding, right?
Do I look like I'm kidding?
If I put your son in the game,
he wouldn't live to see
his next birthday.
If you don't mind,
we got a game to win.
Erasers, this is our time.
This is our time.
Warm him up, Coach!
Come on, Timothy!
Let's see you run some drills.
How about he runs some drills, Coach?
You better stretch, baby!
What did he say?
- He's going to play.
- Is he going to do it?
Get open! Get open!
That's yours right there!
There you go, son. There you go, son.
All right, Erasers!
Bring the championship home!
Spread out!
"Yes!
-om
- No! Jim!
- No!
Is he okay?
I hope he's okay.
Oh, no!
Time! Time!
It's going to be okay.
-Who's that?
-I have no idea.
- Is that the Henderson kid?
- Maybe.
He's not that good.
He's okay!
He's okay! It's okay.
I can get you some water.
- Way to go.
- Okay.
- Watch this.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
This is what we've been waiting for.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- He's coming in.
- We're going with ten.
- Okay, Coach.
- What?
No, no. Ref, come here.
They've only got ten kids on the field.
What about zero?
Why isn't zero playing?
- I thought he was a mascot.
- No.
No, he's on the team.
There's got to be a rule.
Get the book.
Hundred fifty-four rule or whatever.
Jim, is there a rule?
Coach, you need 11 players on the field.
He doesn't play.
Is he on your team?
Yeah, he's on the team, but...
Then he plays. Let's go, Coach.
Okay, Green, come on. Come on.
Our son's going to
score the winning goal.
I want you to plant your feet
right here, son. Okay?
And whatever you do,
don't move from this spot.
You're safe here, okay?
- Got it, Coach.
- All right. There you go.
Coach, let's go.
All right, buddy. This is what it's about!
This is where you find out who you are.
No more bench of life.
Oh, hit me with a stick.
They're not putting that boy in!
Actually, they are. It's good. Trust me.
Laugh if you want.
My kid is going to
score the winning goal.
Two minutes left in the game.
Who's your daddy?
Has he been drinking?
No, no. He just knows what's coming.
No more bench of life.
Do that thing you're going to do!
This is it. Come on!
Come on,
Erasers, let's go!
You can do it! You can do it!
Let's go! Let me see
some fight, Erasers!
Put some heart into it!
That's what I'm talking about, Green.
That's what
I'm talking about. Keep that up.
Timothy. Timothy.
You got to move your feet. Come on.
No. Stay right there, son.
- Stay right there.
- Don't listen to Coach Cal!
Don't listen to your father!
Timothy, Timothy.
Look at me. Don't listen to Coach Cal.
Move your feet. Move around!
Green, Green. Stay right there.
You're doing great!
Feel it out, Timothy!
Come on, move around!
Chase the ball! Come on!
Way to go. Way to go.
Way to go, Tim.
God, he's doing that thing again.
No, no. Put your arms down.
Arms down.
Get your head in the game, baby!
Get your head in the game.
Get in the game!
Like we worked it, come on!
There you go, Erasers,
there you go!
Yes! Yes!
There it is! There it is!
Get back in! Get back in!
No, no. Put your arms down. Arms down.
No, no, no! Don't do that!
Do something with it! Do something!
- Yes! Yes!
- Come on!
Yes!
That's what we're talking about.
All right, Green!
Come on! That's your house!
Just like we practiced!
Look at his little legs!
I don't believe it.
Oh, believe it, sister.
For years I've been listening to
how perfect your kids are!
Well, look at that! That kid is mine!
I am the mom of that!
Get that kid! Put him on the ground!
Take his knees out!
Put him on the ground!
See? See?
See what happens
when you're there for your kid!
Huh? See what happens
when you believe in him! Huh?
I could have been like that,
because I had skills, but no.
Come on, Timothy! Go! Go!
Go, Timothy! Go!
No!
That's the wrong goal!
Game Bone Crushers!
Oh!
But he...
Just like you practiced it, huh?
When we're dreaming up the kid that
we never thought we would get,
I should have said,
"The winning goal for his team!"
- That's not what I'm saying!
- What are you saying?
Shut Up!
It was a failure of my imagination!
Your mistake was simple!
Oh, my mistake?
So, you think it was my fault?
You needed him to
score for you to make you...
Tell me you didn't love
the idea of rubbing it in Brenda's face.
Oh, please!
You think you're better than your sister,
and you're not.
You are worse than your father!
What?
No.
No, no, no.
Stop it!
I am not the only bad parent
in this house!
Look, it's not a competition
to see who can be the worst parent!
No, I am saying
we're both terrible at this!
We are! We don't know anything!
You're right! We know nothing!
We were monsters out there today.
Stop! Stop fighting!
Oh, God.
I need to tell you something.
Buddy, we want to tell you something.
- No!
- You deserve better.
We will be better parents.
We will do better.
- I promise.
- Please...
Stop.
Your time is up.
- No, it can't be.
- No.
Actually, you ran over.
- By three minutes.
- You have to let us finish.
You have to hear the whole thing.
You have to.
Excuse me.
With all due respect, we're not leaving.
Okay.
Tots, Timbo? There you go.
Get them next year.
- Want some?
- No, thank you.
Boys, come on.
We're going home.
We're going home! What did I say?
No, that's somebody's job.
Let's go.
Mom and Dad?
This is Joni,
the coolest girl you ever hope to meet.
Wow. Hi.
Nice to see you again.
Hi.
Well, okay, bye.
There it is.
Love and be loved.
-Where are they going?
-I don't know.
Let them go. Let them go.
Yeah.
I know we've
had a great time together.
Me, too.
I didn't tell my parents because
they couldn't have
done anything about it.
There's something
you need to know about me.
What is it?
There's nothing I can do about it.
Everything's going to be okay.
Good night.
Oh, good night.
Timothy!
Oh, I am so confused.
Guys?
Oh, hey!
We were spying-
Yeah, we couldn't help ourselves.
- Oh, she's lovely.
- Yeah.
We really like her.
Yeah.
I more than like her.
Well, of course.
Oh, I am so confused.
But it looks like
you just broke up with her.
No. I let her go.
Why would you do that?
Especially if you more than like her.
Yeah.
You don't get it.
He was right.
We didn't get it.
But we were about to.
We just want to work!
Yeah, we want to work.
My grandfather worked for you.
My father did. My brothers.
24 years! He's given you 24 years!
The meeting was about
whether the factory was going to close.
He was right.
Good evening.
I know you're all upset,
but if you could just
give me a few minutes.
You've heard the rumors
that our factory here in Stanleyville
is going to close.
That's what we thought.
As it turned out...
But... But something
unexpected happened.
A little miracle. And here it is.
This is a new kind of pencil
made almost entirely out of leaves.
A new kind of pencil.
The pencil that Timothy
had asked us to make.
It will not only save trees,
but will save our factory.
Don't thank me.
I did not have the vision
to come up with this revolutionary idea.
But allow me to
introduce you to who did.
My son, Franklin Crudstaff.
I can't begin to
describe the feeling of pride I have.
Quite frankly, Franklin,
I didn't think you had it in you.
He didn't.
He didn't have it in him.
The new pencil
was thought up by my parents,
Jim and Cindy Green.
Oh, look here.
It's the boy who kicked the winning goal
for the other team.
Hey, hey, stop, Franklin.
Well, he's obviously confused again.
He shoots. He scores. We lose.
Hey! Enough. Do not pick on my son.
The truth is,
the only reason that
Cindy and I came up
with the idea for the leaf pencil
is because he believed
that we could. He's the reason.
And if you call him a liar,
if you ever so much as
even look at him funny,
you will have to deal with me.
And me.
How touching.
Tell me, how did you
come up with this idea
to make a pencil out of leaves.
Franklin?
Well, it seems kind of obvious, really.
Uh, leaves are everywhere. And, uh...
-...pencil.
- How about you?
Ever since Timothy came to us,
leaves have been a big,
a big part of our lives.
Why?
Well?
Because I have leaves on my legs.
Leaves on your legs.
Yes. Our son, Timothy,
has leaves on his legs.
And we didn't tell
you guys because we were afraid.
And kind of ashamed.
I even tried to cut his leaves off.
Surely you don't
expect us to believe that...
I've seen the leaves.
They're spectacular.
And it's okay to be different.
A little weird, even.
Thank you.
It doesn't matter if
you believe us or not.
I'd like to see the leaves.
It is up to you. You don't have to.
It's okay. It's time.
Oops.
Now that's amazing.
I used to have more.
If this boy can
have a leaf on his ankle,
then we can make
a pencil out of leaves.
Let's all go to work!
Wow!
You guys were incredible.
Timothy, what happened to your leaves?
Oh, you know.
No. We don't know.
He wouldn't tell us.
No. He was quiet.
We were in
the middle of something.
We didn't know what.
But Timothy knew. He stayed calm.
He knew, and he was okay with it.
It was beautiful.
It was really beautiful.
Timothy.
What aren't you telling us?
We should get inside.
- Get inside.
- Come on.
I didn't tell you before
because there's nothing
you could have done.
About my leaves...
What about them?
Please, please tell us.
When my leaves go...
You go, too, don't you?
When?
Now.
No, no.
No, sweetie. You can't.
It's nothing you did.
It's how it's supposed to be.
There's only so much time.
Other kids grow up and move away.
I lose my leaves and move on.
Oh, sweetie, you can't.
There is so much that
we have left to do.
We're just starting
to get good at this.
You're ready.
- You were always ready.
- Oh, baby.
Never give up.
Timothy?
- Timothy?
- Jim.
Oh!
- Yeah?
Oh, Jim.
Here, here, here, here.
What was in the box?
This.
Thank you. I think that's
all we'll need.
That's it?
That...
Thank you.
Dear Mom and Dad.
About my leaves,
I gave them all away.
It's what you do with gifts.
I gave one to Aunt Brenda
so now she can rock.
I wanted Uncle Bub to have one.
And Miss Crudstaff.
Coach Cal got one.
He said it was my best kick ever.
I gave one to Reggie,
because he really liked them.
I left one for Grandpa Jim
where I know he'll find it.
And Joni, she got two.
And for you guys, here's what I know.
If you came to me and said,
"There are two people in the world
"who want you more than anything."
Jim!
"They'll do their best.
They'll make some mistakes.
"And you'll only get them
for a short time.
"But they will love you
more than you can ever imagine. "
Well, when that's true, I'd say,
"So much is possible. "
Hi.
I'm Cindy.
I'm Jim.
And you can call us...
Whatever you want.
I'm Lily.
You want to come inside?
# This gift will last forever
# This gift will never let you down
# Some things are made
from better stuff
# This gift is waiting to be found
# Your heart's in wide receiving
# Been too long buried in the sand
# Some things require leaving
# This gift will fall right in your hand
# Just try to understand
# If you long enough
# And you don't give up
# If you're strong enough
# And you'll be no harbor
# To the sorrow
# Just let it go
# Don't hang your head in sorrow
# Don't give up just before you win
# Don't wait around for tomorrow
# Open up your arms and let it in
# This gift will last forever
# This gift will never let you down
# Some things are made from better stuff
# This gift is ready to be found
# Just you believe it now
# This gift will last forever
# This gift will never let you down
# Some things are made from better stuff
# This gift is ready to be found
# Your heart's in wide receiving
# Been too long buried in the sand
# Some things require leaving
# These things just fall right in your hand
# Just try to understand
# If you long enough
# And you don't give up
# If you're strong enough
# If you long enough
# And you don't give up
# If you're strong enough