[ FRANK ] Are they on?
[ CASEY ] Yep. So,
introduce yourself.
Okay. Hey, I'm Frank.
How you doing?
Don't answer that.
That's rhetorical.
Okay. Let's get you up to speed.
This is a story
about the future.
And the future...
can be scary.
[ CASEY ] Uh...
Um...
[ FRANK ] What?
[ CASEY ] Are you sure you
wanna go with "scary"?
[ FRANK ]  Yes, I wanna
go with scary.
- [ CASEY ] Okay.
- [ FRANK ] Okay.
The future can be scary.
Unstable governments,
overpopulation,
wars on every continent,
famine, water shortages,
environmental collapse...
[ CASEY ] And scientific
breakthroughs,
wonder and beauty...
Could you please just
stop interrupting?
[ CASEY ] I will. Just try to
be a little more upbeat.
- "Upbeat"?
- Yeah, tell them what you like...
I can't tell them anything
if you keep interrupting me.
You're right. Sorry.
As I was saying...
With every second that ticks by,
we get closer and closer...
[ CASEY ] Ooh, I know.
Tell them about when...
[ FRANK ] I can't tell them anything
until I tell them about this.
[ CASEY ] Then, can we please
just start somewhere else?
Fine. Where would you
like me to start?
Well, you keep saying the future
wasn't always this way, right?
It wasn't. When I was a
kid, the future was...
- Different, right?
- Yeah.
Okay, cool. Then, start there.
All right. Well,
when I was a kid,
the future was different.
Flushing Meadows-Corona
Park, World's Fair.
Don't forget your valuables
and enjoy the future.
[ CLANKING ]
BUS DRIVER: Watch
your step, kiddo.
[ GRUNTS ]
[ UPBEAT SONG PLAYING ]
♪ There's a great big ♪
♪ beautiful tomorrow ♪
♪ Shining at the ♪
♪ end of every day ♪
♪ There's a great big ♪
♪ beautiful tomorrow ♪
♪ And tomorrow's ♪
♪ just a dream away ♪
♪ Man has a dream and ♪
♪ that's the start ♪
♪ He follows his dream ♪
♪ with mind and heart ♪
♪ And when it ♪
♪ becomes a reality ♪
♪ It's a dream come ♪
♪ true for you and me ♪
♪ So there's a great big ♪
♪ beautiful tomorrow ♪
♪ Just a dream away ♪
[ GRUNTS ]
Hello, sir.
May I help you?
My name is John Francis Walker.
I'm here to win the $50.
Is that so?
I took it apart because of
the nitrogen compartment.
Seeing as how the bus
ride was kind of bumpy
and you know nitro.
I could've used a hydrogen
peroxide-powered engine.
Bell Labs tested that
with their Rocket Belt
and I guess there
were some issues
with manoeuvrability,
flight duration, and stuff.
It's a jet pack.
Obviously.
[ ATHENA ] You made this yourself?
Athena, what are you doing here?
Did you or didn't you?
[ STAMMERS ] Uh...
What?
Did you make this yourself?
Yeah.
Why?
I...
guess I got tired
of waiting around
for someone else
to do it for me.
[ GOVERNOR NIX ] Does it work?
Um, sure. Yeah.
Mostly.
Just doesn't really, you
know, technically...
[ GRUNTS ]
[ YELLING ]
[ GROANING ]
fly.
[ GOVERNOR NIX ] But if
if did, "You know",
"technically fly," what
would its purpose be?
How would your jet pack make
the world a better place?
Can't it just be fun?
Mr Walker, please tell me you
can do better than "fun."
Any thing's possible.
I don't know what that means.
If I was walking
down the street,
and I saw some kid with
a jet pack fly over me,
I'd believe any thing's possible.
I'd be inspired.
Doesn't that make the
world a better place?
Well, I suppose it would.
If it worked.
Unfortunately...
it does not.
And if it doesn't work,
it has no purpose at all.
Thank you for your
time, Mr Walker.
But I can make it work!
That's the spirit.
Until then, young man,
have fun.
Absolutely not.
I like him.
Athena, no.
What makes you think you're
gonna make this thing fly?
I'm optimistic.
- You're wasting your time.
- I'm not!
Damn contraption.
It's not a contraption!
It doesn't work.
I can make it work.
No, you can't!
I'm not giving up.
Don't turn around. Be cool.
What did I just tell you?
- Sorry.
- Stop talking.
Look over there. Five o'clock.
You know, on a clock?
- Where the five is.
- Oh.
[ SIGHS ]
That way.
I'm going with them.
You count to 20, then follow
us. Don't get spotted.
Who are you?
I'm the future, Frank Walker.
[ INDISTINCT CHATTER ]
Nice. Do you like it?
Oh.
[ MAN ] [ ON PA ] Travel the globe
in Walt Disney's "it's
a small world."
A salute to UNICEF and
children everywhere.
Excuse me.
It's the happiest cruise
ever to set sail.
Sorry.
- Excuse me.
- [ MAN ] Whoa, whoa.
Sorry, folks, you're gonna have
to wait for the next boat.
There'll be another
boat in just a minute.
[ WOMAN ] Oh.
[ GRUNTS ]
[ SONG PLAYING LOUDLY ]
♪ It's a small world after all ♪
♪ It's a small, small world ♪
Whoa.
♪ La, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la, ♪
♪ la, la, la, la ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la ♪
[ SONG FADES ]
Hello?
[ AUTOMATED FEMALE VOICE ] Good afternoon.
Please step aboard
the transport.
[ BELL DINGS ]
The site is active.
Please put on your head protection in
order to prevent significant injury.
"Injury"?
Transport will commence
in Ten seconds.
[ WHIRRING ]
Wait!
- Five...
- Wait!
- Four...
- No!
Three...
Two...
One.
[ DISTORTED YELLING ]
[ ENGINE WHIRRING ]
No, phases one and two took a...
[ GRUNTS ]
[ RUMBLING ]
Whoa!
Ah!
[ GASPS ]
[ FABRIC RIPPING ]
[ SCREAMING ]
[ GRUNTS ]
- [ WHIRRING ]
- Whoa!
[ CLANGING ]
[ GRUNTS ]
Hey! That's mine!
Did you just fix it?
Hey! Whoa.
[ HUMS ]
[ MAN ]1: Hey!
[ MAN ]2: There he is.
- Hey!
- [ WHIMPERS ]
[ SCREAMING ]
[ WHIMPERS ]
Oh!
Ah!
[ GRUNTING ]
[ WIND GUSTS ]
Whoa.
Huh?
[ WHIMPERS ]
[ GRUNTS ]
[ CLICKING ]
[ GROWLS ]
[ YELLS ]
[ WORKERS CLAMOURING ]
[ LAUGHING ]
[ YELPS ]
Whoo!
[ FRANK ] Hey!
[ SCREAMING ]
Whoa! Whoa!
[ ENGINE SPUTTERING ]
- [ ENGINE STOPS ]
- [ PANTING ]
It works now.
[ GROANS ]
[ INDISTINCT CHATTER ]
oh. [ LAUGHS ]
So... what is this place?
[ FRANK ] And then
everything went to hell.
- [ CASEY ] Oh, boy.
- Well, it did.
[ CASEY ] So you gave
them, like, one second
of blue skies and jet
packs and hope...
[ FRANK ] It's important. They
need to know the stakes.
[ CASEY ] I think they can figure out
clocks counting down are bad.
- Do you wanna tell the story?
- No, you're doing fine.
Because if you think you
can tell the story better,
I would absolutely
love to hear you try.
- Wow. Really?
- Really.
Oh, I guess, technically,
I am more qualified.
Are you? How so?
Because unlike you,
I'm an optimist.
[ EDDIE ] Babe, you filming?
It's video.
[ YOUNG CASEY ] I knew it!
[ EDDIE LAUGHS ]
Are you videoing?
JENNY: Okay. Go ahead, sweetie.
Do your thing, Casey.
That's Sirius.
That's Canopus.
That's Arcturus.
Rigil Kentaurus.
Vega, Procyon...
Capella, Betelgeuse.
[ EDDIE ] And why do you love
the stars so much, Casey?
Because I wanna go there.
But it's so far away.
JENNY: It'll take a long
time. A real long time.
What if you get all the way up
there, and there's nothing?
What if there's everything?
- [ FRANK ] Oh, boy.
- [ CASEY ] What?
Are you gonna go through
your entire childhood?
[ CASEY ] You started
when you were a kid.
I'm just giving them context.
[ FRANK ] Just move it along.
Okay? They don't have all day.
[ CASEY ] Cool. You got it.
♪ [ MAN ] [ SINGING ]  Hit it! ♪
[ BLUES ROCK PLAYING ]
[ UNZIPS BAG ]
♪ I was a movin' man ♪
♪ in my younger days ♪
♪ But I've grown out ♪
♪ of my ramblin' ways ♪
♪ I left that road ♪
♪ so far behind ♪
♪ Now I know ♪
♪ on, baby ♪
♪ I got mine ♪
[ STATIC ]
♪ Oh, baby, I got mine ♪
[ RATTLING ]
[ EXHALES ]
♪ Whoa, I got mine ♪
♪ I got mine ♪
♪ Oh, baby, I got mine ♪
♪ Hey! ♪
- NATE: Identify yourself!
- [ PANTING ]
Nate!
If you wake up Dad,
I will crush you.
You shouldn't sneak out.
Well, you shouldn't
still need a wubby.
Dad says it's okay
to sleep with.
That's because he doesn't
want you to grow up.
Were you at the platform again?
What do you do out there?
Are you trying to stop
them from taking it down?
[ SIGHS ] oh.
That would make me a criminal.
And a pretty terrible role model
to impressionable youth
such as yourself.
But if someone else did it...
I'd have to assume they believed
even the teeniest of actions
could change the future.
How can you be sure?
Because I know how things work.
Why are they taking
the platform down?
Because it's hard to have ideas
and easy to give up.
But you won't. Right?
Never.
[ BEEPING ]
Hey, Dad. Heading to school.
- I made you lunch.
- Hey!
Wrap it up,
[ MACHINE WHIRRING ]
How did you do...
You would have gotten it.
[ MOBILE RINGING ]
Yeah, Eddie Newton.
What?
All three cranes?
All right, Douglas.
Thanks for the call. Bye.
Everything okay?
Yeah, the equipment over at
Canaveral is down again.
Weird.
Really weird.
Well, at least you
get the day off.
Actually, they're bringing in
replacement cranes from Orlando
so I will be back
to work by noon.
That's fantastic.
Case.
Yeah?
Nothing's gonna stop them from
taking down that platform.
Nothing. And when we're done...
I'm out of a job.
There's nothing anyone
can do about it.
It's inevitable.
Then you'll find something else.
You're a NASA engineer.
With nothing to launch.
There are two wolves.
[ EDDIE ] Case.
You told me this
story my entire life
and now I'm telling you.
There are two wolves
and they're always fighting.
One is darkness and despair.
The other is light and hope.
Which wolf wins?
Come on, Case.
Okay. Fine, don't answer.
Whichever one you feed.
Good.
Eat.
Come on.
Mutually assured destruction.
Today, any nuclear
country or terrorist
is capable of inflicting damage
on a massive scale
with weapons of...
Environmental entropy.
The polar ice caps aren't
waiting for us to decide
if climate change is real.
Rising coastal waters,
intensifying weather patterns.
They're all punching our
one-way ticket to...
Dystopia. By definition,
"not perfect."
Huxley's Brave New World...
Bradbury's Fahrenheit 451...
Orwell's 1984.
Once considered fiction,
these futuristic novels
are actually happening right now
and they seem to
be getting worse.
Yes, Miss Newton?
[ SIGHS ] Can we fix it?
Sorry?
I get things are bad. But
what are we doing to fix it?
[ SCHOOL BELL RINGING ]
Have a good weekend, everybody.
[ STUDENTS CHATTERING ]
[ SIREN WAILING ]
Newton?
Yeah.
You made bail. Motorcycle
is in impound.
You can pick up your
personal effects over there.
- Newton?
- Yeah.
[ INDISTINCT TALKING ON TV ]
All right.
Okay, one money clip...
$47.32,
one Florida state driver's
license, one baseball cap.
You got one pin,
one pack of Beemans gum, and
I don't know what this is.
Sign here.
That's not mine.
What's not yours?
The pin. I've never...
- [ SCREAMS ]
- [ PIN CLATTERS ]
[ GASPS ]
No way.
- [ GROANS ]
- [ PIN CLATTERS ]
[ PANTING ]
Have I been here the whole time?
I know.
No!
Um, I got it.
[ EDDIE ] You have no idea of
the strings I had to pull
to keep Homeland Security
from pressing charges, Casey.
- This is not just vandalism. All right?
- Uh...
It's NASA. It's
government property.
Have you ever seen this before?
You're not getting it, are you?
I am very upset with you!
I get it, you're
angry. I understand.
But I just need you to look
at it. Does it look weird?
- Don't touch it!
- [ TYRES SCREECHING ]
Why are you yelling at me?
Not while you're driving,
Dad. It's dangerous.
Just pull over.
- Pull over.
- [ SIGHS ]
I swear to God, Case,
if you're on drugs...
I'm not on drugs. Just look.
I need you to be NASA Dad now.
New Frontier Dad. Okay?
All will be explained
as soon as you touch this pin.
What is...
It's not working?
You're not seeing this?
- Stop it.
- [ PANTING ]
Honestly, Casey,
I don't know what's
gotten into you.
[ GASPS ]
- [ SLAMS ]
- [ GROANS ]
[ GRUNTS ]
[ YELLS ]
[ GRUNTING ]
- [ GROANS ]
- [ PIN CLATTERS ]
Oh...
- [ DOOR OPENS ]
- [ GASPS ]
[ SIGHS ]
Middle of the night...
- [ DOOR CLOSES ]
- [ EXHALES ]
[ GASPS ]
[ MAN WHOOPING ]
[ LAUGHTER ]
[ PEOPLE CHATTERING ]
[ SCREAMING ]
[ GROANING ]
DEXTER: A little help, guys?
- [ MAN ]1: Zen move, Dexter.
- [ GROANS ]
- Totally swift.
- [ LAUGHS ]
Come on, idiots. We're
gonna be late for R and D.
[ BEEPING ]
[ CHUCKLES ]
Whoa!
[ WOMAN ] [ ON PA ] The Hover Rail
will be arriving in one minute.
The Hover Rail will be
arriving in one minute.
Oh.
Whoa.
[ BEEPING ]
[ WOMAN ] Are you coming?
You can see me?
We don't have all day.
BOY: Wait for us!
[ WOMAN ] [ ON PA ] Northbound
line now departing.
[ CHILDREN LAUGHING ]
Next stop, Space port.
[ BEEPING ]
[ CHILDREN LAUGHING ]
[ GIRL ]1: Wow! Look at the rings!
BOY: Wow! Cool!
[ MAN ] Be sure to follow
the procedures strictly.
You know how you
need your sleep.
Dad, you're embarrassing me.
Do you promise to
transmit every day?
Even when you're out of range.
Come on, what's the big deal?
We're only going 20
light-years out.
[ WOMAN ] [ ON PA ] Now
arriving, Space port.
[ CHILDREN LAUGHING ]
[ BOTH CHUCKLE ]
[ ENGINE ROARING ]
[ YOUNG ASTRONAUT ]
Come on, please.
I'll be okay.
Hey, guys. Over here.
- [ MAN ] On, hey!
- [ WOMAN ] Hey!
[ YOUNG ASTRONAUT ] Come on,
please! I love you guys.
You're going to make me cry
in front of my friends, okay?
Bye! Bye!
- [ GRUNTS ]
- [ PIN BEEPING ]
[ BEEPING ]
Come on. We saved a
seat just for you.
[ GRUNTING ]
Ugh!
Now you run out of power?
[ SCREAMING ]
- [ CASEY ] Nate, wake up!
- I didn't do it!
Dad changed the password
to his computer.
Do you know it?
You smell like swamp.
Tell me the password and
you can go back to sleep.
Your phone has Internet.
[ SIGHS ] My phone got
soaked in a lagoon.
Fine.
What are we looking for?
[ CASEY ] Here we go.
- Stop! That's it.
- [ CLICKS ]
"Extremely rare collectible pin"
"commemorating the
1964 World's Fair."
[ CASEY ] "Experts and purveyors of the
most extensive selection of space-age"
"collectibles in the world."
Whoa. This site
is like, ancient.
Okay. Give me their number.
They don't have a number.
They don't have a number?
They have an address.
[ CASEY ] Okay, look.
You are gonna tell Dad you
woke up, saw me leaving.
I told you I was going camping with
friends, and I will call tomorrow.
Can you do that for me?
Only if you tell me
what's going on.
[ STAMMERS ]
I think that I saw...
That I went to...
the future.
Can I come, too?
Not yet.
[ SNORING ]
[ GASPS ]
Hello! Ls Casey Newton home?
Uh, no.
She ordered some cookies
and I'm delivering them.
You're a Girl Scout?
Of course I am.
Why aren't you
wearing a uniform?
It's at the cleaners.
Those are Oreos.
Could you please tell me
when Casey will be back?
She went camping
with some friends.
She's gonna be gone
for a couple of days.
Is that what you've
told your parents?
Um...
Yeah.
But it's not true.
Yeah, it is.
No, Nathan. It's not.
- [ GASPS ]
- Don't ask me how I know your name.
I know it the same way I know
that you are lying to me.
Are you from the future?
You clearly understand.
So why aren't you telling
me what I need to know?
That pin thing, it
stopped working.
She went to find another one.
Nathan, where is she looking?
[ HONKING ]
NEIL ARMSTRONG: [ ON TV ]
That's one small step
for man...
- one giant leap for mankind.
- [ CHUCKLES ]
[ EXPLOSIONS ON TV ]
[ CASEY ] [ CLEARS THROAT ] Hello?
Sale this week. Front
three shelves.
70% off.
Oh, no, thanks. I'm not
here to buy anything. Um...
I was hoping that you
could tell me about this.
Hugo!
One second.
[ FAN FARE PLAYING ]
Welcome to Blast
From The... [ GROANS ]
[ MUSIC FADES ]
Thank you for the help, dear.
Well, if you just kept it open,
you wouldn't need my help.
If I kept it open, it would ruin
the effect, which is everything.
Pardon my wife. She has no
respect for showmanship.
Hugo Gernsback. How
may I help you?
She has a pin.
I saw that you were
looking for one online...
Where did you get it?
What can you tell me about it?
I can't tell you anything about it
unless you tell me who gave it to you.
I'm not going first.
[ SIGHS ]
Well, it seems our
business here is done.
It seems it is.
HUGO: Saw something, didn't you?
When you touched it.
Something incredible.
It's real?
Of course it is.
Don't ask me how.
These people have
developed technologies
we haven't even dreamed
of yet. [ CHUCKLES ]
Wait. What people?
Oh.
[ CHUCKLES ]
Have you ever wondered
what would happen
if all the geniuses, the
artists, the scientists,
the smartest, most creative
people in the world,
decided to actually change it?
But where?
Where could they even
do such a thing?
They'd need a place free from
politics and bureaucracy,
distractions, greed.
A secret place where
they could build
whatever they were crazy
enough to imagine.
"Plus Ultra" they
call themselves.
The only way to see it, however,
is through contact
with one of these.
Why did they make them?
What are they for?
Rumour has it
- they were about to go public.
- HUGO: Yeah.
Share what they had built
with the whole world.
Unfortunately, that
never happened.
Why not?
I think we've, uh, shared
enough, young lady.
[ CHUCKLES ]
So, um, as we've
decided to trust you,
please trust us
and tell me, where'd you get it?
Oh, uh...
I don't know.
What do you mean, honey?
Uh...
I kind of got arrested and
it was in with my stuff.
HUGO: In with your stuff?
Yeah, I don't know
how it got there.
[ DOOR LOCKING ]
What was that?
Tell us who gave
it to you. Please.
No one gave it to me!
That's very unlikely,
sweetheart.
Uh, you know what?
I think I'm gonna go now.
Thanks for your help.
$1,000 if you tell me where
you acquired the pin.
I don't know!
- $10,000.
- Was it a girl? A little girl?
I don't know what you
guys are talking about.
Have a nice day. Enjoy
your freak out.
HUGO: Tell us where she is
and you will be spared.
This is a joke, right?
[ GUN CHARGING ]
[ SCREAMS ]
Where's the girl?
[ SHUDDERING ]
I don't... I don't know about...
[ SIZZLES ]
- Ah!
- [ GLASS SHATTERING ]
[ LASER CHARGING ]
- [ GROANS ]
- [ FLOOR CREAKING ]
[ GUN BEEPING ]
- [ TOY BEEPING ]
- [ GASPS ]
HUGO: You will tell
us about the girl.
I don't know any girl.
I told you... [ STAMMERS ]
Where is the girl?
I don't know any girl!
[ GLASS SHATTERS ]
[ GRUNTS ]
We have to go!
Come on. Now!
This is a time bomb. It stops
time, but not for long!
- What?
- Listen to me.
The sphere is collapsing
and you're in the line of fire.
We need to go
or you will die.
[ YELPS ] I'm stuck!
I'm stuck!
But only temporarily.
Take my hand. The
moment you're free...
I'll pull you clear.
Then stay behind me.
Ready?
[ GRUNTING ]
[ GRUNTS ]
The girl.
[ GROANS ]
[ GLASS SHATTERS ]
- [ GROANS ]
- [ METAL CLANGS ]
- [ GRUNTS ]
[ GRUNTS ]
[ YELLS ]
- [ GROANS ]
- [ CLANGING ]
[ GRUNTS ]
Ah!
Look out!
[ TOY BEEPING ]
[ YELLING ]
We have to go.
They're about to self-destruct.
We have to go now!
[ REPEATING ] Crazy
enough to imagine.
Crazy enough to imagine.
[ CAR ALARMS BEEPING ]
[ GASPS ]
[ YELPS ]
Casey, get up,
They'll be coming.
[ CASEY ] What? Who?
- I don't know what... I can't get into...
- I know, I know.
Get in the car, Casey!
How do you know my name?
Just get in the car.
[ BEEPING ]
[ ENGINE STARTS ]
What just happened?
Two AA units targeted
you for extermination.
I saved your life.
They self-destructed.
Wait. "AAs"?
Audio-Animatronics.
They were robots?
No. Advanced anthropomo...
Sure. Okay. Robots.
[ STAMMERS ]
Wait, wait. Who are you?
My name is Athena. I'm the
one who gave you the pin.
The pin? Oh, the pin!
Yes. And I do wish
you hadn't run off
before I had a chance to give you
some rather necessary context.
Context? What are you
even talking about?
How are you driving
a car? Who are you?
I'm a cruder.
[ DISTORTED ] Re...
I'm a...
[ HIGH-PITCHED VOICE ] recruton.
[ SIGHS ]
MALE AUTOMATED VOICE: 60
seconds to self-destruct.
[ CRANKING ]
[ SPEAKING JAPANESE ]
[ CLICKS ]
So sorry about that.
You're one of them?
Obviously.
[ BRAKES SCREECHING ]
Where are you going?
Stop! I'm trying to help you!
[ BRAKES SCREECHING ]
[ GASPS ]
Oh, my God. Oh, my God!
Hey!
[ WHIRRING ]
This isn't happening.
No way!
- [ SCREAMING ]
- [ BRAKES SCREECHING ]
[ SCREAMING ]
Let me out of this car!
Stop yelling!
- Let me out now!
- No!
I will not!
I gave you my very
last pin, young lady,
and I am not about to
let it go to waste.
What do you mean your last pin?
Wait, that place I saw...
It exists?
Of course it does.
But if you don't come with me,
it won't for much longer.
Why not?
Because they built something
they shouldn't have.
Built what?
Do you want to keep
asking me questions
until someone arrives
to murder us?
No.
Then which way do
you want to go?
Backwards, or forwards?
And you can take me there?
I can.
[ SIGHS ]
I'm driving.
[ POLICE RADIO CHATTER ]
Okey-dokey.
You fellas are released. Thanks.
Alrighty, boys.
Fire chief says we're clear
to go in and poke around.
Hopefully they
were out for lunch
and nobody was in there
when she went boom.
[ DEPUTY ]1: Captain.
Afternoon, sir.
Dave Clark, Secret Service.
- [ DOG WHINING ]
- [ CHUCKLES ] Ooh.
[ BARKS ]
Looks like you got
yourself a doozy here.
Secret Service?
Hey, where are they going?
They're securing the premises.
Thanks so much for your help,
but we're going to
take it from here.
[ DEPUTY ]2: Hey, Dale.
I found this just
outside the window.
You ever seen anything like it?
What the hell?
God almighty!
Sale. This week. 70 perce...
Was it a girl? A little
girl? Was it a girl?
A little girl?
You wanna tell me what's
going on here, son?
No, sir. I do not.
Was it a girl? A little girl?
Contact Governor Nix.
Tell him we found the girl.
Veer left!
[ TYRES SCREECHING ]
[ CASEY ] Little more of
a heads up next time.
Hey, here's an idea. Why don't you
just tell me where we're going?
Pittsfield, New York.
What's in Pittsfield, New York?
Someone who can get us back in.
Hold on. You said that you
gave me your last pin.
How many other people
did you give them to?
Not important.
I'm not even your first choice.
I only found you a month
ago when you started
wantonly destroying
government property.
Which happens to go
on my search parameters
for recruitment.
Not to mention
you scored a 73 on the
Feynman/Drummelberg scale.
73? Ls that good?
Wait. Hold on.
Recruitment for what?
I'm not allowed to answer that.
Who's not allowing you?
I'm not allowed to answer
that. And I should warn you,
you keep asking me questions, and my
Countermeasure Protocol will initiate.
Okay. And what does that mean?
I will shut down.
You will not.
Try me.
You said that they built
something they shouldn't have.
Did something happen over there?
- Something bad?
- [ POWERING DOWN ]
[ GASPS ] Son of a...
Please don't answer.
[ LINE RINGING ]
Hey, you've reached Eddie
Newton's cell phone.
Leave me a message and
I will call you back.
[ BEEPS ]
Hey, Dad. It's Casey. Um...
I told Nate to tell you that I was
camping, but I'm not camping.
And I just don't
like lying to you.
But I didn't know how to tell
you the truth because...
Something highly unusual
is happening, and...
Okay. My point is...
I'm fine. I will
continue to be fine.
I'm not on drugs. I
haven't joined a cult.
I won't be gone long.
And I will call again soon.
I love you, Dad.
- [ WHIRRING ]
- [ SCREAMS ]
Oh, my God! Are you okay?
Yes. Fine, thank you.
I thought I broke
you or something.
[ COUNTRY SONG PLAYING ON RADIO ]
♪ The end is coming ♪
♪ what you gonna do? ♪
I should drive.
Casey, I know you have
no reason to trust me.
But I've been looking for someone
like you for a very long time.
Now, please,
pull over.
Of all the people you could
give one of those pins to...
Why me?
Because you're special.
[ LAUGHS ] Yeah. I'm special.
You are.
So, this guy we're
gonna go see...
[ YAWNS ]
what's his name?
His name is Frank.
Frank Walker.
He's special, too.
[ MURMURING ] Frank Walker.
- [ TRUCK SPEEDING OFF ]
- [ GASPS ]
Hey! Wait, what are you doing?
Just great.
- [ DOG BARKING ]
- [ GASPS ]
[ CHAIN RATTLING ]
[ BARKING ]
Where are your paw prints?
That is cool.
[ CHUCKLES ]
I can hear you, you know.
[ FRANK ] Go away. Didn't
you see the dog?
Yeah. It's a hologram.
How did you do that in daylight?
- It's pretty impressive.
- Who are you?
What do you want?
You're Frank Walker, right?
My name's Casey, and I
want you to take me there.
Take you where?
To the place I saw
when I touched this.
[ LOUD VIBRATION ]
[ GRUNTS ]
[ CASEY GROANING ]
Where'd you get this?
A little girl.
Athena.
Where is she?
She ditched me here.
[ SIGHS ]
Of course she did.
Look, wherever you came
from, kid, go back.
No, I want you to take
me there. What I saw...
What you saw is gone.
This, what you're looking for,
it doesn't exist any more.
No. I feel like I have to go.
Like I'm supposed to go.
Why?
Because they're saving a seat on
the rocket ship just for you?
What you saw was a
commercial that was recorded
decades ago.
It was an invitation
that never went out
because the damn
party got cancelled.
You are not supposed
to do anything.
You've been manipulated to feel
like you're part of
something incredible.
Like you were special.
But you weren't.
[ SIGHS ]
You're not.
So that's a no?
[ THUNDER RUMBLING ]
[ RADIO FREQUENCIES TUNING ]
[ MONITOR BEEPING ]
Son of a...
Ah!
Oh, you little...
[ LOCKING ]
You know, I can call
the cops any time.
Any time!
You have...
- I'm giving you five seconds...
- [ LOUD VIBRATION ]
- [ GRUNTING ]
- [ LAUGHING ]
[ GROANING ]
[ CASEY ] I am not leaving!
Either tell me how to
get there or kill me!
If you touch anything in there,
that's exactly what I'll do!
[ GRUNTS ]
[ FRANK ] What are you doing?
I'm touching things!
[ BANGING ON DOOR ]
[ FRANK ] Open this door now!
- [ GASPS ]
- [ FRANK ] I mean it.
I'll knock you out.
[ BANGING ON DOOR ]
Hey, what's this doohickey with
the trombone slidey thing?
[ FRANK ] Leave that
alone. I'm serious!
- Will you take me there?
- No!
Then you're not serious!
[ BANGING ON DOOR ]
YOUNG [ FRANK ] Oh, come on.
You didn't think that was funny?
You're recording this?
If I get you to laugh,
I wanna, you know,
have it for posterity.
I laughed.
You smiled. A smile's
not a laugh.
Everyone laughs.
It's a biological need.
[ ATHENA ] Actually, it isn't.
Sleep is a biological need.
I've never seen you
sleep, either.
Well, sooner or later, I'm
gonna make you laugh.
Until you do, I'm not
gonna stop trying.
Maybe you should.
What?
Stop trying,
Why?
Must we record this?
[ TIMER BEEPING ]
- Get out!
- Wait a second.
- What is that? Ls that a countdown?
- [ GROANS ]
I am not leaving. I deserve to
know what's going on around here.
- You deserve...
- Yeah, I deserve some answers.
- Answers to what?
- I know that you were there.
You don't know anything.
How do you ever leave
a place like that?
Because they threw me out!
They threw me out and they
locked every door back in.
Was it because you built that
something that you shouldn't have?
Who told you that?
And is that it?
The "something"?
If I could tell you the date,
the exact date that
you're gonna die,
would you wanna know?
How would you know?
Let's just say I did.
- What are you, a psychic?
- No, that's not the point.
Then what is your
basis for knowing?
- It's a hypothetical.
- It's a stupid hypothetical.
Oh, just use your
imagination. All right?
- All right.
- Okay.
Let's accept that
there is a world
where I know, with
absolute certainty,
the exact time of your death.
Now, you want me to
tell you or not?
Yeah, of course I
would. Who wouldn't?
But...
what if accepting my
death is what causes it?
So the answer is yes.
I would want you to tell me.
- But I wouldn't believe you.
- You have to believe me.
Why? Don't we, like, make
our own destiny and stuff?
What?
Who are you, kid?
[ ALARM BEEPING ]
ls that bad?
FRANK; Oh!
Oh, hell.
Oh, hell!
They followed you here?
What? Who?
Robots.
I've never seen them before.
DAVE CLARK: John Francis Walker.
You have been permitted to live
based upon your agreed
non-intervention.
You are now harbouring
a fugitive element.
Release her to our custody
or be extinguished.
You have one minute to comply.
- Thanks.
- Don't thank me yet.
[ BANGING ]
[ GASPS ]
- [ GUNSHOT ]
- [ GASPS ]
Wait.
[ GROANS ]
[ GRUNTING ]
Come on!
[ GRUNTS ]
Let's go!
John Francis Walker, by
authority of Governor Nix,
- this unit has been authorised...
- [ GRUNTS ]
[ DISTORTED VOICE ] ...to
extinguish your life.
[ GRUNTING ]
Okay.
[ CONTINUES GRUNTING ]
All right, that's
enough. That's enough!
Come on. Close the door.
Who the hell is Governor Nix?
[ SLAMS ]
Let's go. Come on.
Get in.
How is this a good idea?
[ SMASHING ]
[ EXPLOSIONS ]
[ CASEY SCREAMS ]
[ LAUGHS ]
Move or sink, kid.
You were actually
prepared for that?
- My hat.
- Leave it.
No, no, no. I can't
go without it.
It's my dad's.
Now I get it.
Too smart for your own good.
Father never understood
you, never supported you.
And now you wear his hat as a
badge of rebellion, right?
No. My dad is amazing.
[ GROANS ]
Oh, wait a second.
We're not talking
about me, are we?
Why don't we just get
you to your amazing dad
and pretend this never happened?
Hop on.
- The battery's dead.
- No, it's not.
Then maybe it's the points.
No, it's not.
When's the last
time you checked...
You know, you're not
helping. You...
Get down. Now.
Wait.
Hello, Frank.
Are you going to shoot me?
I'm deciding.
Could you decide in the truck?
Because we really
should get going.
Wait.
Why? So more robots can show up?
She's one of them.
Yeah, I know. Are
you coming or not?
Aw... Move over.
- Frank...
- Not yet.
What are you thinking? Why
would you drag her into this?
I didn't drag her into
anything. I gave her a pin.
She did the rest.
Just like you.
Oh, don't even. Where did
you even find the pin?
I was there. They destroyed 'em.
Not all of them. I made it
out with nearly a dozen.
So you give one to a teenager.
Hey, I got a 73 on the
Feinberg/Dusseldorf scale or whatever.
- You got a 73? That's not possible.
- Hmm.
He's jealous because
he scored a 41.
You know what? I was eleven.
I was eleven!
Hey, don't touch that!
This is a one-kiloton
detonation. It is not a toy.
Do not mess with my stuff.
- You got it?
- Sorry!
I didn't begin with
her, you know.
I wasted years on other
potential candidates.
Potential candidates? For what?
[ CHUCKLING ] That's beautiful.
You still think you're
recruiting, don't you?
Do not ask her any
more questions.
She's gonna do her
countermeasure shutdown thing.
What countermeasure
shutdown thing?
Did you tell her you had a
countermeasure shutdown thing?
She was annoying me.
[ STAMMERING ] You lied?
Ah, get used to that, kid.
One minute, she's promising
you a beautiful future,
the next thing you know, she's leading
it to your house to kill you.
I'm sorry, but time is running
out and you needed motivation.
Motivation for what?
We need to go back over, Frank.
Back over there?
Yes, yes, Frank, we
need to go back over.
Good. Great. That's just great.
You know, hey, I got stung by a
bee. Let's jump on the hive.
That's a terrible analogy.
That's a fantastic analogy. What
do you know about analogies?
You know, you're impossible to
talk to when you're like this.
I am like this because
you derailed my life.
Again.
Frank, it's not personal.
It's just programming.
Ah.
We're here!
[ FRANK ] Where are you going?
This is where your wire
station's located, isn't it?
We need to get to The Spectacle.
- Spectacle?
- Hey.
Are you insane?
They know that you
sent her to me.
They're gonna be waiting for us.
Fine. Give me the Edison tube
and we'll go without you.
I don't have the Edison tube.
It's in your bag.
I have x-ray vision.
When did you get x-ray vision?
Oh, she's full of surprises.
I know all about her surprises.
Chief among them is this.
She doesn't care about you.
All that charm and the sense of
purpose, and the cute little smile...
it's all just software.
It's ones and zeroes. That's it.
Trust me, when you get
there, you're on your own.
What happened to you two?
He thinks I hurt him.
No, you hurt a dumb kid that
was stupid enough to fall...
[ GRUMBLES ]
You were many things,
Frank Walker.
But you were never dumb.
Why don't you just give me
the Edison tube, and...
[ FRANK ] I'm not
giving you anything.
I'm...
All right.
You want in? I'll bring you in.
Why not?
It's better than waiting
around here and getting
hunted and killed,
etcetera, etcetera.
That's the spirit.
"Etcetera"? What's
the "etcetera"?
[ MACHINE POWERING UP ]
What kind of cables are these?
The kind that transmit people.
People? Like us?
What, like a miniature
teleport...
Do I have to explain everything?
Can't you just be
amazed and move on?
This is all wired to
the dish up there.
Are you... Are you
using satellite?
I know how things work.
Well, zippity-doo for you.
Wrap this around
your eyes, tight.
Why?
Because justice is blind.
Just do it, kid.
You want me to put
this over my head?
If this takes off my eyebrows...
Shut up, open your mouth,
tilt your head back.
[ SPITS ] Ugh. What is that?
It's powder. Are
we at van 't Hoff?
Good to go!
[ FRANK ] Good. You set
it for the Tower?
There is still a receiver there?
[ ATHENA ] Last I checked.
How long ago was that?
25 years ago.
Roughly,
They threw you out, too?
[ CASEY ] Okay, guys.
Killer robots.
All right.
It's gonna be bright,
cold, and really loud.
You're gonna lose 90% of your blood
sugar in 1/100th of a second
and you're gonna
wish you were dead.
But then it'll be over.
Don't pee on us.
This sounds spectacular.
Why now? Why her?
Because she hasn't given up.
You think she can fix it.
What makes you say that?
Can she, Athena?
I have no idea.
Let's go find out.
[ VOICE BREAKING ] ls
it... ls this normal?
[ DISTORTED YELLING ]
[ DISTORTED GROANING ]
[ GASPING ]
Thirsty.
[ MOANING ] Dying. I
think I'm dying.
- [ FRANK ] You're not dying!
- I'm dying.
There's Coke in the fridge.
[ GASPING ]
[ PANTING ]
[ GULPING ]
Help yourself.
We have no idea
how many are here
but we're damn sure
they know we're coming.
So, we move quickly.
You follow me.
No questions. Got it?
Got it.
[ BURPING ]
Excuse me.
We're in Paris?
Would you stop being so amazed?
I thought you wanted
me to be amazed.
I want you to stop yammer...
[ MAN ANNOUNCING
OVER PA IN FRENCH ]
Tower's closing.
AW, hell.
Come on.
Now, you and I are gonna
be on a watch list,
but they may not have your facial
recognition profile uploaded yet.
- "May not"?
- May not.
So, you walk over there, you take
this, you tap him on the neck.
If he's human, it
knocks him right out.
- And if it's a robot?
- Uh...
- [ CLANGS ]
- Hey!
You'll just piss it off.
Fantastic.
She's got guts. You
gotta give her that.
[ MAN SPEAKING FRENCH ]
[ CASEY ] Ah, yes, but I
was just, you know...
[ CLANGS ]
Human!
The French hated this thing
when Eiffel first unveiled it
at the Paris World's Fair.
They thought it was an eyesore.
Eiffel didn't care, though. It
wasn't meant to be a monument.
It was meant to
find another world.
Les Quatre Premiers.
Plus Ultra's First Four.
They were a part of all this?
Eiffel, Jules Verne, Tesla,
and Mr Edison.
They designed this antenna
that we're inside.
Wait, what? The Eiffel
Tower is an antenna?
Now I finally answer your question,
you're gonna interrupt me?
Yes.
Tesla designed the antenna to observe
every kind of frequency out there.
Subspace, trans-dimensional,
you name it.
And they found exactly what
they were looking for.
And then Edison tried to take credit for
it, because these two hate each other.
- [ ATHENA ] Frank...
- Because of alternating...
Stay on topic.
Yeah. All right, well...
There were always rumours
of a secret entrance
the Four kept just
for themselves.
A one-way ticket
in case of emergencies.
The Spectacle.
[ PATRIOTIC MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ HORN BLOWING ]
You ain't seen nothing yet, kid.
[ RUMBLING ]
[ INDISTINCT SHOUTING ]
[ SPEAKING FRENCH ]
It's a rocket.
They're coming.
All right.
Buckle up!
[ SPEAKING FRENCH ]
What'd he say?
Pretty much what you'd expect.
Tell him to hang on.
[ SPEAKS FRENCH ]
Whoo-hoo!
[ CAMERA SHUTTERS CLICKING ]
Why are we going back?
We're not. We're going through
to another dimension.
So we blasted into outer space
just to get a running start?
This part may get
a little weird.
[ GRUNTS ]
[ GROANS ]
[ METAL SCRAPING ]
[ ATHENA ] Casey. Wake up.
Casey.
Casey. Wake up.
We're here.
Now what?
You tell me.
I tell you? This was your idea.
I don't have ideas.
I just find the people who do.
- So there's no plan?
- There's a plan.
You just haven't
come up with it yet.
But you should do that soon.
Ah, that's just terrific.
Here, hide this.
Absolutely.
Wait. Ls that the one-kiloton
detonation thingy
you told me not to play with?
Right now, it's our
insurance policy.
There's a good chance they're gonna
try to kill us right out of the gate.
So we're just gonna stand here?
Well, you wanted to
see Tomorrowland.
Here it comes.
Take the bag.
Frank.
David.
You look well.
Age becomes you.
Thanks. You should try it.
I don't know. I think I'll just keep
drinking my shake every morning.
- Comes in chocolate now.
- Ah. Yum.
Hello, Athena.
I started to think you
were never coming home.
Where, oh, where have you been?
Doing my job.
Your job?
I'm sorry. Were we not clear
when we suspended your
recruitment protocols?
I got that sense when you
called me "bloody obsolete"
and tried to disassemble me.
Well, you've certainly
caused quite a commotion
by launching an antique rocket
ship out of the Eiffel Tower.
Under normal circumstances,
we'd be working overtime to convince
everyone it was just an elaborate hoax.
Fortunately, for all of us,
doesn't really
matter now, does it?
[ CASEY ] Why doesn't it matter?
And who might you be?
I'm Casey.
Newton.
And who might you be?
David Nix.
Pleasure.
Well, Frank, it's been
wonderful catching up,
but as we were fairly clear
about the terms of your exile
and the consequences
of violating it,
I have to ask...
what the hell are
you doing here?
I think she can fix it.
I'm sorry.
Her.
I think she can fix it, David.
Wait, what?
I've been pirating your signal.
Every time you turn it on
here, I can see it there.
And it flickered.
The percentage dropped, David.
Impossible.
You don't believe me? Let's
go find out right now.
I'm sorry, what can I fix?
The world, Ms Newton.
He thinks you can fix the world.
Is that like a portal to Earth?
No. It is a bridgeway to Earth.
Welcome back to the
Monitor, Frank.
It's something, isn't it?
Yeah, it's something.
Don't worry about
the light show.
It's perfectly safe.
- Am I supposed to do something?
- Uh-huh.
Okay, could you be a
bit more specific?
Because fixing the world
sounds a little...
Just be yourself.
Gotcha.
[ GOVERNOR NIX ] Flashes
of the future.
What are those?
Flashes of future.
This is us a few
seconds from now.
This whole tower funnels
energy via tachyon,
a particle that moves
significantly faster than light.
We discovered them
almost 40 years ago.
Your physicists are still arguing
over whether they exist.
[ GOVERNOR NIX ] Oh, dear.
Too late.
Oh, dear.
[ GOVERNOR NIX ] So,
on with the show.
We've enhanced the
interface significantly
but it still functions on
your original algorithm.
You have something
to show me, Frank?
Show me.
Pick a place.
- What?
- A location anywhere in the world.
Pick one.
Canaveral.
Cape Canaveral.
Easy, easy...
The interface is oriented from your
hands to the centre of the Earth.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. I got it.
You trained her obviously.
I just met her yesterday.
She knows how things work.
You told me this story my entire
life and now I'm telling you.
[ CASEY ] How is this possible?
[ GOVERNOR NIX ] We are millions
of exponential deviances
away from the dimension
you call home.
Frank had the novel idea
of building this machine
so that we could keep in touch.
This is three days ago.
Relatively.
That's space/time humour.
Because tachyons travel
faster than light,
once we harness them...
You can see backwards in time.
Not just backwards.
You're kidding.
No.
What happened?
[ GOVERNOR NIX ] Keep going.
Just a little further.
[ EXPLOSION ]
[ INDISTINCT CLAMOURING ]
That's enough.
That's enough, kid.
[ GASPS ]
That's my house.
[ GOVERNOR NIX ] It would have been nice
if Frank had prepared you for this...
but I'm afraid the
world is ending.
It is certain, it
is unavoidable...
and it is coming.
When?
This is 58 days from now.
58 days?
But whatever caused this could happen
any time after the static starts.
It could be a month.
It could be sooner.
Still looking for
your flicker, Frank?
I know what I saw.
So why aren't you
telling anyone?
The whole planet is gonna die
and you're just sitting here?
We're not gonna die.
This is your world, not ours.
We'll be perfectly fine here.
Then why don't you
let people in?
Tell her, David.
Oh, Frank.
All those years in exile, and
you still don't understand.
These people are
driven by savagery.
If we told them about this place
then that would
happen here to us.
Then nothing would survive.
But it hasn't happened yet!
Actually, it has happened. You
just haven't accepted it.
Well, I don't accept it!
Did you see that?
David, I know that you saw that.
That means that there is a chance.
There's at least a chance...
[ SCREAMS ]
That went quite well,
don't you think?
What happened?
You're being deported.
Again.
Well, that's Nix for you.
No new ideas.
Apparently, your 1/10,000
variable in the inevitability
wasn't convincing enough
to change his mind.
[ SIGHS ]
Be gentle.
You Okay?
You know, you'd think
somewhere in the zillions
of questions that
I was asking you,
you could have said,
"Oh, Casey, that stuff's
not really the issue"
"because our future-predicting
machine says we're all gonna die."
We did sort of hint at it.
This place has nothing
to do with hope.
It's the opposite of hope.
- Come on. Don't say that.
- Why not?
You said it.
No wonder you gave up.
That's before I knew about you.
I mean, you really...
You really are special.
Why do you people keep
saying that to me?
I'm not!
Why'd you even
give me this, hmm?
You showed me a place that
was amazing and incredible
and it was a lie.
If you're gonna zap an
idea into people's heads,
you should really make
sure that it's the truth.
Because you can't do that.
You can't just zap...
[ RADIO FREQUENCIES TUNING ]
What?
Zap an idea into people's heads.
You were pirating the signal.
- How?
- What?
At your house. All your
TVs, your doomsday room.
You were boosting the feed
from that Monitor thing.
- How did you do that?
- No big deal.
They're running so much
power through it now,
a ham radio could pick it up.
It's just a matter of finding
the right frequency...
You grabbed a signal
from another dimension.
From a machine here.
That means it's
transmitting there.
What if it's not just
predicting the future?
It's broadcasting it.
When I touched this thing
for a few minutes it felt
like anything was possible.
So then why can't the
opposite happen?
What if the Monitor
is just a giant pin?
But instead of making
you think positive,
it makes you think
negative and it...
And it's convincing the whole
world to feed the wrong wolf.
We need to turn that thing off.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
It's time to go home.
[ FRANK ] David. David.
- Ah, it's uninhabited and uncharted.
- Listen to me.
But it looks like a lovely
place to spend your last days.
David... The Monitor is
acting as an antenna.
It isn't just
receiving tachyons.
It is taking a
possible future and...
And amplifying it, transmitting
it, like a feedback loop.
It's a self-fulfilling prophecy
that's coming from right there.
But it's not just showing
people the end of the world,
it's giving them the idea over and
over again until they just accept it!
It's a ticking time bomb, and
we're the ones that lit the fuse.
We still have 58 days to
try and change things.
But nothing will work as long
as that thing is still on.
Young lady, I'm gonna assume
that your knowledge of tachyonic
fusion is a little sketchy.
Shutting it down is impossible.
There is no off.
[ CASEY ] I'm telling
you what it's doing.
Why don't you care?
Because he's the one
that's doing it.
Right?
Let's imagine.
If you glimpsed the future
and were frightened
by what you saw,
what would you do with that
information? You would go to...
Who? Politicians?
Captains of industry?
And how would you convince
them? With data? Facts?
Good luck.
The only facts they
won't challenge
are the ones that keep the wheels
greased and the dollars rolling in.
But what if...
What if there was a way
of skipping the middleman
and putting the critical news
directly into everyone's head?
The probability of widespread
annihilation kept going up.
The only way to stop
it was to show it.
To scare people straight.
Because what reasonable human
being wouldn't be galvanised
by the potential destruction of
everything they have ever known or loved?
To save civilization,
I would show its collapse.
But how do you think this
vision was received?
How do you think
people responded
to the prospect
of imminent doom?
They gobbled it up, like
a chocolate éclair.
They didn't fear their
demise, they repackaged it.
It can be enjoyed as video games,
as TV shows, books, movies.
The entire world wholeheartedly
embraced the apocalypse
and sprinted towards it
with gleeful abandon.
Meanwhile, your Earth was
crumbling all around you.
You've got simultaneous epidemics
of obesity and starvation.
Explain that one.
Bees and butterflies
start to disappear.
The glaciers melt.
Algae blooms all around you.
The coal mine canaries
are dropping dead,
and you won't take the hint!
In every moment,
there is the possibility
of a better future.
But you people won't believe it.
And because you
won't believe it,
you won't do what is necessary
to make it a reality.
So you dwell on this
terrible future,
and you resign yourselves to it.
For one reason,
because that future doesn't
ask anything of you today.
So, yes,
we saw the iceberg, we
warned the Titanic.
But you all just steered for
it anyway, full steam ahead.
Why?
Because you want to sink.
You gave up.
That's not the Monitor's fault.
That's yours.
Put them through.
Thanks for visiting, Frank.
It was genuinely nice
to see you again.
Hmm.
[ BEEPS ]
- What are you doing?
- Not giving up.
[ GRUNTS ]
[ YELPS ]
Oh!
[ BRACELET BEEPS ]
Look out!
[ GRUNTS ]
- Get the thing!
- What thing?
The thing I gave you
when we first got here!
Arm it! Get on the platform!
Ah!
Casey!
The bomb!
Get on the platform!
- Now what?
- Arm it!
How?
[ WHIMPERING ]
- [ BEEPING ]
- [ GASPS ]
[ POWERING DOWN ]
[ ROBOT BEEPS ]
[ BOTH GRUNTING ]
[ BOMB BEEPING ]
[ SCREAMS ]
Casey!
The bomb!
Where is the bomb?
[ EXCLAIMS ]
[ BOMB BEEPING ]
FEMALE AUTOMATED VOICE:
One minute to detonation.
- 45 seconds.
- [ YELLS ]
Athena! The bomb.
What do I do? How
do I turn it off?
30 seconds.
You can't.
[ LAUGHING ]
This is not funny!
[ CASEY ] Frank, get out of
there! It's gonna blow!
Frank, get out!
Ah!
Get out of there!
FEMALE AUTOMATED
VOICE: Four. Three.
[ CASEY ] Close the portal!
- Two. One.
- Close the portal!
[ EXPLOSION ]
[ SCREAMING ]
[ FRANK ] Are you all right?
[ CASEY ] The bomb's gone.
- Can you stand?
- Yeah.
- [ GOVERNOR NIX ] Frank!
- [ LASER POWERING UP ]
[ GASPS ]
No.
[ CASEY ] The bomb's gone.
- [ FRANK ] Can you stand?
- [ CASEY ] Yeah.
- Frank!
- [ LASER POWERING UP ]
[ SCREAMS ]
What happened? Ls she okay?
I need to get her
to a repair module.
Frank!
No one's going to repair me.
Not in time.
I need to tell you
something now.
Oh, darn.
I'm shutting down.
[ DISTORTED ] I'm shutting down.
I'm going to lose sync.
Don't look at me like that.
If I lose sync it's not failure.
I know.
There are things I need to
tell you before the final...
Before the automated
program kicks in.
I'm a machine.
I never thought that was bad
until I saw your face
when you found out I was.
I always knew.
No, you didn't.
FEMALE AUTOMATED VOICE:
Systems failing.
Activating last thoughts
saved for Frank Walker.
[ ATHENA ] Log 15; September...
1965.
Frank Walker is looking at me in a
manner that is difficult to recognise.
It seems imperative
to explain to him
that I am an
Audio-Animatronic...
Athena...
But I am concerned that he
may be adversely affected
when he finds out
that I am not human.
He has potential.
I don't want to damage it.
He needs someone
to believe in him.
And I am fulfilling that need.
He is my top recruit.
Log 24; October, 1965.
I'm having unusual thoughts
towards Frank Walker.
I suspect a flaw in
my empathy interface.
I am thinking I
should report it.
But I haven't.
I cannot explain why.
Log 78; April...
1984.
Frank Walker has been
banished by Governor Nix.
He says he has lost hope
and he holds me responsible for having
given it to him in the first place.
I do not understand this.
He says I never will
because I do not feel
anger or disappointment.
Or love.
FEMALE AUTOMATED
VOICE: End recording.
I was designed to find dreamers.
I found you.
And lost you.
Till I found her.
Casey.
Dreamers need to stick together.
It's not programming.
It's personal.
[ SYSTEM BEEPING ]
The Monitor.
The bomb is gone.
But I'm not, yet.
There isn't much time.
My self-destruct, use it.
You know what to do, Frank.
Help get it right this time.
[ SIGHS ]
I thought you can't have ideas.
Well, what do you know?
What do you know.
[ BEEPING SPEEDS UP ]
Systems failing.
- Frank?
- Yeah?
Do you want to know why you
could never make me laugh?
Why?
Because you're not funny.
[ BOTH CHUCKLE ]
You can let me go now.
Goodbye, Frank.
[ BEEPING RAPIDLY ]
Goodbye, Athena.
[ EXPLOSION ]
Oh, bollocks.
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLING ]
[ GRUNTS ]
[ GRUNTING ]
[ PANTING ]
[ FRANK ] Now what?
You're asking me?
This was your idea, kid.
Yeah.
You think it Will work?
I guess we have to make it work.
[ SIGHS ]
[ FRANK ] So, we're making it work.
[ CASEY ] First order of business,
get the door back open.
Couldn't hurt to get a few
experienced engineers over here.
Next...
[ FRANK ] Put the party back on.
And print out some
new invitations.
Which brings us to why
we're here today.
A year ago, it was all
supposed to be over.
We shouldn't even be here.
But we are.
It isn't hard to knock
down a big, evil building
that's telling everybody
that the world's gonna end.
What is hard
is figuring out what
to build in its place.
And if we're gonna do that,
we can't do it alone.
We're gonna need all of you.
- Frank Walker, may I ask a question?
- Sure.
The search parameters
you've given us,
while mathematically
sound, are a bit...
undefined.
Could you be more
specific, please?
Well, Miss Newton,
you wanna tell our new recruiters
what they're looking for?
Dreamers.
We are looking for dreamers.
Anyone who will feed
the right wolf.
So, I once told your predecessor
that she was nothing but a
combination of ones and zeroes.
I was wrong.
She was much more than that.
You are much more
than that, too.
So, go out there and do
what she would have done.
Find the ones who
haven't given up.
They're the future.
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLING ]
[ ALL APPLAUDING ]