what do you think,
theodore?
he looks like a real live one.
come on!
all right!
get him
with the rope!
huh?
rope him!
well, throw it!
maybe we could head him off
at the pass. mm-hmm.
maybe we can do a little better
this time.
two of diamonds.
jack of diamonds.
three of diamonds.
queen of diamonds.
ace of diamonds.
ten of hearts.
well, how proud are you
of that ace, leonard?
ace bets a dollar.
a dollar.
there was a time around here when
a jack high was worth a poke of gold.
i'm in.
me too.
i'm folding.
well, i'm in.
did the mines dry up?
quake of '65 pinched off the veins,
but the quake we had two years ago
finished us off for good.
hasn't been ten cents' worth of gold taken
out of quake city since.
ace, ten still high,
leonard.
bet a dollar. i was wondering about
that name, quake city.
when you build a town on top
of the calaveras fault,
you can figure to get shook up
once in a while.
ten. me too.
ain't that bad, homer.
we've still got two fine saloons,
our own theater...
and the only hook and ladder
this side of chicago.
you planning to settle down here,
mr. donavan?
no, no, no. i'm working my way
to new orleans.
soon as i get a big enough stake,
i'm gonna open up my own place.
first class too--
red carpets,
crystal chandeliers from europe,
two roulette tables.
good evening, gents.
homer.
if you need a haircut, wintle,
my barbershop's closed.
if you're lookin' to sue somebody,
my court's open every second tuesday.
if you want the sheriff,
i'm playin' poker.
deuces bet a dollar.
no, judge.
it's just that i'm leaving
for san francisco tonight.
san francisco's loss
is quake city's gain.
leonard?
the trouble is...
that i'm expecting
some valuables
on tomorrow's stage,
and i can't be here
to pick them up.
me neither.
oh. yes.
hmm.
mayor sharpe?
got a council meeting
tomorrow.
i'm in.
what kind
of valuables, john?
well, bless
my suspender buttons.
donavan! i haven't
seen you since, uh--
- santa fe?
- right.
when you sold me
the marshal's horse?
- right.
i was just funnin', donavan.
- the marshal wasn't amused.
well, now, old friend,
maybe i can make it up to you.
two pairs bets two dollars.
like i say, i'm expecting
valuables on the stage.
i'm in. like what?
oh, things a person wouldn't
leave lying around without
somebody responsible--
like yourself--
to keep an eye on it.
there's a game
going on, wintle.
there's your two,
and raise you five.
you couldn't have hit
an inside straight again.
i'll call ya.
if you'll claim them for me,
i'll make it worth your while,
besides repaying
what i charged you
for the marshal's horse.
the mayor
raised five.
it's just till
i come back, governor.
are you in or not?
uh--
here's five on account,
if you can use it.
i don't know how you
came by five dollars,
but i'll apply it
to your loan
at the bank.
it's a deal?
it's a deal.
i'm in.
thanks, donavan.
thanks.
- you won't forget?
- i won't forget.
thanks.
all right,
let's see 'em.
- hit it again!
- i don't
believe that.
welcome to quake city,
mr. donavan. looks like
luck's against you.
well, there's one good thing
about luck. it always changes,
and i've got a feeling
that mine is just
around the corner.
again?
whoa!
well, they saddled up
in boston, still wet
behind the ears??
and they made their way
across the wild frontier??
as they sought
their fame and fortune??
their legend
up and sprang??
and they soon became
the apple dumpling gang??
and they called them
it wasn't long
they'd been gone??
from the eastern shore??
people knew their name
from far and near??
they sure shook up quake city
some folks was out to hang??
all the riders of
the apple dumpling gang??
and they called them
it wasn't jesse james
or old black bart??
for whom
the posses rode??
even though there was
a price upon their heads??
it was celia
bobby and clovis??
the town folks
up and sang??
'bout the threesome called
the apple dumpling gang??
and they called them
the apple dumpling gang????
well, here it is,
folks, quake city.
much obliged, ralph.
hotel's across the street.
you can get somethin'
to eat there...
or at the hard times cafe.
and take your stuff with you.
there's two bits charged for
packages stored overnight.
you got anything broken
in transit,
report it
to the ticket office
tomorrow mornin' at 5:00.
excuse me.
mornin', dusty.
my weeklies come?
mornin', sheriff.
yeah, they're
in the mail pouch.
excuse me, but do you
have something
for john wintle?
right in front
of you.
oh, thank you.
not there in front of you.
therein front of you.
sign here.
for what?
ain't you claimin' them
for wintle?
i am not.
last night
you said you was.
took five dollars
in advance,
as i recall.
yes, but, uh,
but that was to pick up
some valuables,
but not a bunch
of runny-nosed kids.
they're in good shape,
mister, just as good
as when i got 'em.
now sign here.
uh, pardon me.
may i speak to anyone
in authority?
how about the founder
and president of the line?
perfect.
pa? you wanna hear
this feller out?
colonel t.r. clydesdale,
at your service, sir.
well, uh,
colonel clydesdale, sir,
uh, there appears to be...
an unfortunate
misunderstanding
about the children.
you see, i didn't--
to cut through the fat,
this saddle blanket tinhorn
agreed to pick up these kids
for john wintle,
and now he's tryin'
to weasel out of it.
- magnolia!
- "magnolia"?
and where are...
the legal guardians
of these waifs?
their folks passed away
back east is what i get
from 'em.
they've been shipped
out here to john wintle.
he's their second uncle,
or something.
and where
is john wintle?
halfway to san francisco,
i'd say.
all i know is,
the stage made delivery...
to the consignee
or his agent, and that
seems to be you, mister.
what youdowith them
is your business.
that argument wouldn't
hold up in any court of law,
and you know it.
it would in my court,
and i'm the law
around here.
but, sheriff, look.
sheriff,
i didn't know
they were children.
now, i'm not
a family man.
mister,
i gotta go.
yeah, just as soon
as we get this
straightened out.
now, sheriff, i--
i have no--
i have no place to keep them.
wintle's got a shack
on the edge of town.
- mister, i gotta go bad!
- she can't wait too long,
mister.
- take my word for that.
- it might be prudent
to resolve...
the more imminent problem,
uh, forthwith.
all right. fine.
come on. let's go.
oh, where did you say
wintle's shack was?
well, you go
to the edge of town,
turn left,
and just beyond
that old pile
of shoring timbers--
well, i'll--
i'll show you.
hey!
oh, uh, i'll be right back.
just hold on.
what?
right here.
oh.
magnolia.
meanwhile, rest assured
that the butterfly stage
and freight company...
will make every endeavor
to satisfy...
uh, the problem
to the ultimate,
uh, satisfaction...
of all
concerned parties.
uh--
"unfortunately, mr. bradley's
lingering illness
left him destitute,
"and there are
no monies left
in the estate.
"however, mr. bradley felt
that revenues from his share
of the commodore mine...
would more than provide
for the care and well-being
of his children."
i guess when wintle got this,
he didn't want to be saddled
with the kids,
so he decided
on a change of scenery.
anything would be
an improvement.
yeah. well, now,
the way that i see it,
until we know
one way or the other,
uh, exactly what
wintle had in mind,
the children are wards
of this town, right?
wrong. there is no funds
nor facilities for orphans
in quake city.
well, you don't expect me
to be able to take care--
donavan, this is just
a half-portion
of a town,
but we do have certain
what you might call
rules to live by.
well, i--
you don't jump
another man's claim.
you don't steal his wife,
woman or whiskey.
you don't
strike a bargain...
and then entertain
second thoughts
about the matter.
any one of these offenses
can make you...
the exalted guest of honor
at a hemp party.
uh--
no, i'd say
you'd best...
keep these youngsters
or provide...
for their safekeeping.
well, it's time
i was getting back
to my barbershop.
oh, and, uh, donavan,
i wouldn't go
on no long rides
if i was you.
no. no.
- when are we gonna eat?
- uh, just--
just a little while now.
oh!
clovis don't like
to be touched.
don't he?
nope.
- now what?
- clovis, now put it back!
come on, you two.
clovis,
give it to me.
i mean it! no more
playing around the fire.
gimme it!
will you stop?
now listen to me.
i don't want any more--
- clovis don't like to be--
- i know. clovis don't
like to be touched.
gimme it, clovis.
will you stop?
give me that.
let me see what the fuss
is about.
"commodore mine,
december 3, 1871."
- commodore's our mine now.
- well, it's just
an old ore sample.
- is it valuable?
- if it was,
it wouldn't be here.
our dad said
there's gold
in the commodore mine.
everyone says
there's gold in their mine.
what's that?
it's salt pork--
i think.
- it looks like fat.
- well, whatever it is,
it's dinner.
- that's dinner?
- that's dinner.
couldn't you make us
apple dumplings instead?
no.
why not?
because even if i could
make apple dumplings,
i wouldn't make them
for you or anybody else.
bobby?
it's raining
on celia again.
then move celia
again!
there's no more
dry places to move her.
bobby, w--
oh, no,
not my salt pork.
what have i done
to deserve this?
who are you talking to?
it doesn't matter.
i don't think he's
listening to me anyway.
evenin'. had some extra
son-of-a-gun stew.
was either throw it out
or bring it up here.
huh. stopped raining.
you know,
it's really amazing.
what is?
the way those kids
settled right down
for you.
well, when you're dead
on your feet and you get your
belly full, you get sleepy.
- what's amazing about that?
- oh, you underestimate yourself.
i think i can say
without hesitation...
that was the best
son-of-a-gun stew
that i've ever had.
really?
yeah, and you saw the way the
kids polished off their plates.
you know,
i think it's a crime...
that someone
with your culinary talent--
well, i guess
you'd really have
to call it magic--
hasn't a family
to share it with.
you tryin' to dump
those kids on me, or you
workin' on somethin' else?
i am merely trying
to point out...
that you have a natural way
with children.
you're barkin' up
the wrong tree, mister.
my advice to you is,
get yourself a job
and look after your kids.
- they're not my kids!
- yes, they are,
till you find somebody else
to take 'em off your hands.
night.
it's dripping
on me again.
oh.
i, uh, i'm very attached
to the little fellas,
but i'm, uh,
i'm a bachelor, you see,
and i'm really
in no position
to care for them,
not like you and your
attractive wife could.
i'm sure there
must be room here
for three small children.
it would just be
until mr. wintle
gets back.
hey!
ma'am, i can--
oh, get out
of the way!
come on!
get outta there!
get out!
why?
don't get
your feet wet.
i'm really very attached
to the little fellas, you see,
but i'm in no position
to care for them.
howdy, ma'am.
good morning.
but they're all
healthy specimens,
sound of wind and limb.
they don't eat much.
they'd be a lot of help
around here.
- they could-- no!
- ow!
i can explain
about that.
uh, he's the only one that
does that. you see, he's just
a little sensitive, that's all.
uh, no, really!
the other ones--
come on.
get out!
ma'am, that little girl
could help you
in the kitchen.
she could wash your dishes and
scrub your personal clothes!
come on.
good day, sir.
i can see that you're
a man of substance.
i have
an interesting proposition
i thought that might--
- ah. the lady of the house.
kids. yech!
the children are
marvelous about parties.
they love parties themselves.
come on.
if you could just--
one small look at them--
who was that,
mr. donavan?
the president
of the garden club.
all right,
come on.
mr. donavan? look!
get out of there!
- celia!
bein' a family man's
quite a responsibility.
- i'm hungry.
- naturally.
hard times cafe
serves a nice lunch.
thanks.
come on, kids.
come on.
pair of tens
wants the money.
doggone. i guess
that sure beats
ace, queen high.
well, i'm on
my last card too.
all right, you kids
find something to do,
and stay out of trouble.
- where ya goin'?
- i have a few sheep
to fleece.
ace bets a dollar.
two, deuce.
jack. oh, a king.
what's a "millstone"?
i don't know.
why?
mr. donavan said
he doesn't want...
three millstones
hanging around
his neck.
i gotta show you
where we're gonna
put it inside.
then we won't have
to move it again.
you don't want
to move something
as delicate as this twice.
what is it,
bobby?
i don't know.
ow!
go on!
get away from there!
this thing's come
halfway across the country,
and i don't want anything
happening to it now!
get! get! get!
all right, let's
move it in now, fellas.
real careful now.
move it in.
what did he say?
i think he's afraid
we'll get his
laundry dirty.
what's that
up there?
looks like a mine.
a mine?
is it ours?
could be.
let's go see.
pair of jacks.
no improvement.
three of hearts.
five of clubs.
ace of hearts
and king of spades.
kings bet.
kings bet ten dollars.
i'm in for ten.
i'm in.
there's your ten,
and i'll raise you twenty.
twenty?
i don't believe
you got 'em.
cost you 20 to find out.
that's kills me.
i'm in.
now there's a man
from missouri.
i fold.
all right,
let's see 'em.
well, three jacks.
three jacks?
uh, another round
for the gentlemen,
please.
i believe i've
also won the, uh,
the deal.
wow! how much money
you figure that dude's
got in front of him?
'bout 500.
500? wow!
you know,
that'd be, uh--
that's 200 apiece.
i told you he was
a real live one, didn't i?
right.
all right, now,
as soon as he leaves,
we jump him, right?
in broad daylight?
we get him
when the time is right.
let's get out of here
before he starts
gettin' suspicious.
two dollars.
okay. i'm in
for two dollars.
okay. and the pot
is right.
a pair of sixes.
four to the deuce.
a pair of ladies.
jack to the three.
ten to the four,
and a jack to the six.
look!
it's a little train.
it's not a train,
celia.
what is it?
it's a cart
to haul dirt.
this isn't our mine at all.
it's the moonridge
number two.
hey!
come on, now.
all aboard!
get out of there.
come on, clovis.
you and celia
get out of there.
put the brake on!
it's stuck!
whoa!
duck!
look out,
bobby!
i can't steer it!
uh-oh!
stop the train, bobby!
- i can't. hang on, celia!
uh-oh!
oh, whoa!
we're coming
to a fence.
get down!
move it, move it,
move it!
get the sheriff!
it's so much fun
and it's no pity??
taking suckers
in quake city??
doo-dah, doo-dah????
that's him!
they're his kids!
don't bother putting
that away, mister.
now, just one minute!
now. one mirror, $300.
what are you talking about?
i was in the--
one melodeon.
i don't own a melodeon.
you do now.
how 'bout
my chickens?
why do we have
to go to bed so early?
because if you're asleep,
you just might stay
out of trouble.
what's that?
that is a cherished token
of a lady's affection.
- i'm sure you'll
understand, belle.
- you're gonna sell it?
i might raise a little
investment capital on it,
should the need arise.
if you'd go get the gold
in the commodore mine,
you could keep
the cherished token
of a lady's affection.
there is no gold
in that hole in the ground.
if there was,
someone would have
found it years ago.
and i don't have
to answer...
to three whelps
who aren't even dry
behind the ears yet.
- mr. donavan?
- what?
- i gotta go.
- you just went.
- i gotta go again.
- that's impossible.
go to sleep.
i'm gonna have
an accident.
all right,
come on.
i like you, mr. donavan.
psst! hey!
what makes you think
that gambler's gonna
come by this way?
well, he come this way
the last time,
didn't he?
well, that don't mean--
amos, will you stop
tryin' to think?
now come on.
get up on top
of that roof.
you know something?
why do i have to go
through this foofaraw of
dropping a bucket on him?
why don't i just throw down
on him and say,
"hand it over"?
and if he just
keeps on walkin',
then what?
well, then i'll call to him,
and then i'll start
throwin' lead.
you know somethin', amos?
the lord poured
your brains in with a teaspoon,
and somebody joggled his arm!
i keep tryin' to tell ya,
we ain't got no lead to throw
and no powder to throw it with!
oh, that's right.
i keep forgettin'.
come on.
this is gonna be easier
than robbin' a bird's nest.
right.
now you get up on that roof
and wait. i'll give you
a hoot-owl call when he comes.
hoo! hoo!
that's good.
i'll tell you what.
i'll answer
with a whippoorwill.
that's good.
good!
all right,
i got it.
here it is.
the hash knife gang
rides again!
i should have heard
from jay gould regarding
my amalgamation proposal.
look into that
first thing in the mornin',
magnolia.
yes, pa.
we'll be needin'
new equipment, of course.
yes, pa.
don't you worry about
finances, little lady.
leave all that
to me.
yes, pa.
now i have to stop in here
and see some people, magnolia.
yes, pa.
good night, pa.
where you off to?
well, after i drop this
at the harness shop,
i'll head back to the barn
and fix the brake pedal
on the stage.
and then when i'm
through with that,
i've got diablo's teeth
to file.
he's not gettin' much
out of his food lately.
and then, when i'm through
with diablo, there's that
cracked singletree to fix.
aside from that,
i got a free evening.
uh-huh.
well, run along
and enjoy yourself,
my dear.
remember, these are
the best years
of your life.
hoo! hoo!
ah!
- hoo! hoo!
- yeah. i'm comin'.
hoo! hoo!
hoo-hoo!
amos!
evenin'.
evening.
well, that's what
i call solid comfort.
yeah. it's very pretty.
where are the children?
fed and in bed.
you know, i'm not sure,
but i think two men
tried to waylay me.
what?
yeah. back there.
probably just
theodore and amos.
- who are theodore and amos?
- used to ride
with the stillwell gang.
the stillwell gang?
really?
till amos accidentally shot
stillwell in the leg.
they call themselves
the hash knife outfit now.
hmm.
they're pretty harmless
for the most part.
mm-hmm. hey.
buy you a drink?
i'm sorry.
i, uh--
i just wasn't thinking
of you as a wo--
i'm sorry.
mr. donavan!
we're going to the mine
to get some gold!
- you want to come with us?
- not so loud, and just
a little bit slower.
where are you going?
to dig some gold
out of our mine.
then we don't have to eat
biscuits and greens
all the time.
mr. purvis
in the assay office says
it's on bald hill.
will you come with us,
mr. donavan, huh?
- no.
- but why?
because my head hurts,
and because there is
no gold in that hole
in the ground.
our pa said
there was.
then you go get it.
and i'm going to go
get some sleep.
you know, leonard,
with the kind of luck
you have,
you ought to play poker
for a living...
and have banking as a hobby,
instead of the other way
around.
thank you, friend.
thank you very much.
hey, mr. donavan,
why does he got...
your cherished token
of a lady's affection?
because three deuces
beats aces over eights,
that's why.
don't get in trouble.
theodore! theodore!
theodore!
go on, clarice.
go hide, quick!
douse that fire!
ah!
what's the matter
with you?
what are you doing?
did you lose your--
come on!
there's a posse
after us! here!
come on!
a posse?
i don't see anybody.
they're down there,
all right.
i saw 'em.
they're all hidin'
in the bushes.
how many?
i don't know.
it was five, six.
maybe 20.
and they're all
loaded for bear too.
got those big,
long buffalo rifles.
you know somethin', amos?
hmm?
we gotta make
a decision.
what?
does the hash knife outfit
throw in its hand, or do we
go out in a blaze of glory?
right! uh, just
what do you mean,
"blaze of glory"?
fightin' till
the last man's killed.
what's it gonna be,
pard?
uh, you know that jail
in santa fe wasn't
all that bad.
remember?
i say we go out
clawin' and fightin'.
make 'em pay
for our hides.
what do you say?
uh, all right.
i'm with you.
you know somethin',
theodore?
this could be the end
of the trail for us.
looks that way, amos.
you know somethin'?
you and me been through
a lot together,
and although i climbed
your hump once in a while,
i-- i just couldn't have
asked for a better partner.
if we meet again
in that big roundup
in the sky sometime,
i'm gonna spread my blanket
'side of yours,
just the same as always.
mister?
we're lookin'
for the commodore mine.
uh, mm, it's, uh--
it's right up the hill there.
just follow the trail.
take you right to it.
thanks.
- bye!
- bye.
amos, that is the most
humiliating thing that's
ever happened to me.
i know.
three bitty kids
with shovels...
walk right into our hideout
and get the drop on us.
i know.
and you burnt
my hand, amos.
i'm sorry about that.
and you scorched a hole
in my best shirt!
well, i can fix that.
why did you tell me those
three bitty kids was a posse?
well, i thought i saw 'em
down there in the bushes.
oh, you couldn't see through
a barbed wired fence.
theodore?
that head of yours
wouldn't hold straw.
theodore?
you couldn't sell
hacksaws in a jail.
what about that big
roundup in the sky?
i don't want to talk about it!
i said i--
said you were gonna
spread your blanket
next to mine.
w- why don't we
dig here?
because somebody
already did dig here.
you scared?
no. no more
than you are.
i'm not scared.
neither am i.
i am.
bobby?
come on.
a little mouse
can't hurt you.
it was just an owl.
this looks like
a pretty good place
to dig.
you start over there,
and i'll dig here.
find any gold yet?
nope. did you?
no.
maybe there ain't any gold,
like mr. donavan said.
pa said there was.
stop shaking it, celia!
i'm not shaking it!
it won't stand still!
it's an earthquake!
let's get out of here!
bobby?
i gotta go.
are we trapped?
there must be
another way out.
come on.
bobby, what's that?
well, we base
our evaluation...
on what the price
of the gold was
when we checked last,
but the price may have
gone up in the meantime,
in which case the nugget
could be worth more.
the san francisco mint
will give us a receipt
for the nugget,
and the cash deposit will remain
in the children's name
in the quake city bank.
i'll leave that end
of it to you. i just
want to make sure...
that the children's
interests are
well protected.
ah, donavan, don't worry
about a thing.
we'll see that that nugget
is well taken care of.
can we touch it?
i'm sorry, ma'am.
that's as close as
we can let you get to it.
it's a piece of cake.
you mean
it ain't gold?
course it's gold,
stupid.
i mean getting that nugget out
of that bank's gonna be easier
than fallin' off a log.
oh, boy!
act natural.
don't do nothin'
to attract attention.
hey, uh, theodore,
how we gonna--
theodore?
how, uh--
how we gonna get it
outta that bank?
all right, first
we gotta get ourselves
a long ladder,
and we're gonna go in
through the skylight,
through the roof.
then we gotta get
that nugget outta town,
and i figure
if it's worth $87,000,
it ought to--
oh, i'd say
it'd weigh close to--
let's see.
gold is $15 an ounce.
how many ounces
in a pound?
are you listening
to me, amos?
yeah, but--
yeah, but what?
your rear end's
on fire, theodore.
oh, thank you.
ah! ow!
why didn't you tell me
my rear end
was on fire?
well, you told me
not to do anything
to attract attention.
you got a match?
i've got--
excuse me.
ah! ah!
hello.
nice day.
mabel, stanley,
donavan.
hello.
hi, sheriff.
well, now,
this is what i call
havin' a party.
mr. donavan said
we can have all
the apple dumplings we want.
did he? did he?
well, that's very generous
of mr. donavan.
and he bought me
a new dress, see?
oh, i think that's
the most beautiful dress
i ever saw.
awful nice kids.
yes, they are.
you still bound
for new orleans?
oh, yes. yes.
well, nothing's happened
to change that.
of course, uh, i have
a few things i have
to clear up here in town,
and i've gotta
make arrangements
for the kids.
seems a lot
of people...
are anxious to take
the youngsters
to their bosoms.
they're sayin' the kids
ought to be made
wards of the court...
and for me to give 'em
to some respectable family
around here,
people of substance.
'course, that'd fit
right into your plans.
you'd be free
to go on your way.
unencumbered. unfettered.
yeah. yeah.
fine, fine.
who wants 'em?
oh, there's no shortage
of applicants.
- there's the little darlin'!
- here, let me have
the sweet little thing!
what do you know
about children? you don't
know nothin' about the child.
let go!
all right, ladies. ladies,
this is a private party!
but he said i could have her!
you're all gonna wind up
in the calaboose
if you don't get out of here.
that'll all be
decided later on
at the hearing.
out! out!
see what i mean?
they ripped
my beautiful dress.
i know,
but we'll fix it.
hey. we'll fix it.
there'sgotto be
better people in this town.
there's always
miss clydesdale.
who's miss clydesdale?
dusty?
mm-hmm.
- but she's not married.
- that's easy to fix.
well, who can you get?
you're not suggesting--
i'm only suggesting it
for the kids.
i know, but dusty's--
dusty's a fine specimen
of womanhood!
i seen her get caught
in a cloudburst once,
and i wanna tell you!
yes, mr. donavan.
please marry dusty.
no two people
ever got married...
for a more honorable
or worthy cause,
donavan.
think that over.
hearing's not till
the day after tomorrow.
marry dusty?
if they give us
to mrs. stockley, she won't
hit us with a stick, will she?
why would she hit you
with a stick?
she hits mr. stockley
with a stick,
and she might get mad
if we track mud in the house
or something.
or forget
to comb our hair.
well, i'm sure
she wouldn't do that.
when mr. stockley
gets mad, he uses words
i never heard before.
he's not as mean
as mr. leach.
mr. leach'll put you in a sack
and throw you in the river
if you even talk too much.
nobody's gonna throw you
in the river.
if rowdy joe dover got us,
i bet we'd have to sleep
in his shed.
don't worry, clovis.
if celia gets pneumonia,
i can take care of her.
we picked these
for you,
mr. donavan.
so you won't forget us
when you get to new orleans.
you can press them in a book
and they'll keep forever.
then every time you see one,
you'll remember us
three "widdle" kids.
that you gave away.
come on, clovis.
we better do the dishes
and not bother mr. donavan
anymore.
all right!
i'll ask her.
"three 'widdle' kids"?
three little swindlers,
you mean.
bobby?
what?
what's "swindlers"?
i don't know.
okay, come on.
come on!
soon as we get the ladder out
of here, we head straight
for the bank.
amos! amos!
yeah?
ahh!
this one's
too small.
get the one
on the other side.
mmmm--
i'll go open the door.
it's too long.
we can't get it out this way.
push it together.
aah! you idiot!
you get on that end,
and i'll get on the other...
and then we'll
push it together.
on the count of three.
get in there
and get it out!
it went through
the other window. i'm gonna
pull it all the way through.
someone's comin'!
howdy.
evening.
don't worry. as soon as
we get across here,
it's gonna be all downhill.
get back, you cabbage head.
you're gonna bust it.
don't worry.
aah! mmm!
it's a long way
down there, theodore.
well, don't look down.
it's startin' to shake!
hoo!
don't do that.
move it!
my spur's caught.
get up there!
i am. i d--
aah-ha!
get off!
if i didn't think
you'd freeze to death
come this winter,
i'd rob this bank myself
and leave you here.
comin' through.
watch it!
uh--
maybe you ought to check and
see if the front door's open.
will you shut up?
perfect. it's a great scheme.
only when it's over,
i'm the deserted wife left
with three kids to mother...
while i watch your south end
disappearing over a hill.
but you'll be compensated
for any inconvenience, any--
i don't want their money.
it's theirs. they found it.
agreed. the only reason
i suggested it is that i knew...
that you would provide them
with a good home.
what do you get
out of this "arrangement"?
a chance to get to new orleans
before winter sets in.
- that all?
- well, i would appreciate it
if you'd square my debts.
i will repay you
in due time.
- and that's all?
- yes!
oh, now wait a minute.
uh, do you mean...
might i exercise
my husbandly prerogatives?
that's exactly what i mean.
miss clydesdale, nothing
could be further from my mind.
this marriage
would ensure a good home
for those children.
nothing more.
i give my word
as a gentleman.
it's not the best guarantee
i've ever had.
well, maybe not,
but it's the best
i have to offer.
so what's it gonna be,
miss clydesdale?
you calling or folding?
all right,
i'll go along with it.
but it's not for you.
it's for the kids.
and the sooner
you light a shuck out
of this town, the better.
it's gonna be daylight
before we even
get in that bank.
boy, once we get our hands
on that gold, we're gonna be
livin' like kings.
we'll be shooin' those
senoritas off like flies.
never mind about that now.
just make sure this mule
of yours don't get frisky.
don't you worry about clarice.
she'll get you up there
all right.
now you wait for my signal.
all right. you gonna use
that hooty-owl again? now
i answer with a whippoorwill.
no, no. don't you
remember nothin'?
when i give that rope a tug,
then you haul me up.
that's a new one. right.
tug and haul. right.
okay. no hooty-owl.
okay!
now this time,
it's just gonna be
a tug and haul. you got that?
well, that's it.
come on, clarice.
come on!
hold it. stay right there.
shh! you're gonna
wake somebody up!
come over here!
uh! i'll help you.
stay right there.
whoa.
you all right?
i told you
to wait for my signal!
right.
shh-shh.
yeah.
go ahead!
shh-shh.
yeah. uh,
come on, clarice.
come on.
get up, clarice.
come on, you--
come on.
get up, clarice.
you can rest on your patio
when we get to mexico.
come on. gotta get up now.
come on.
come on!
mr. donavan said he doesn't
want us wandering around--
somebody's coming!
we're not wandering around.
we're looking for him.
- maybe we should stay home
till he gets back.
- he should've been back by now.
unless he forgot.
hi.
who are you talkin' to?
oh. hey, you're the man
that showed us how to get
to the mine, aren't ya?
that's right.
you kids run along now.
we're looking
for mr. donavan.
well, i think he went that way.
why are you standing
on your toes like that?
'cause i wanna
stand on my toes.
now get outta here.
well, you kids go ahead now.
i'm real busy.
- where's your friend?
- he'd better be
in another county.
how'd you get up there?
never mind how i got up here.
you kids should be in bed now.
get outta here.
ah! bite me,
you ungrateful
fleabag you.
how'd you do that?
anyway, i got here early
this morning to draw up
the certification papers...
for the nugget
for the san francisco mint,
and when i opened up the place,
when i opened up the place,
i got the shock
of my life!
morning.
you two couldn't take candy
away from a baby without
comin' out on the short end.
well, it's not gonna go
so easy on ya this time.
get outta that silly rope,
and stand up.
this court is now in session,
the honorable homer mccoy
presiding.
theodore ogelvie,
amos tucker,
you're charged with
attempted bank robbery.
how do you plead?
guilty or not guilty?
- not guilty?
- guilty!
- the wrong one.
- this court sentences you...
to be hung by the neck
until dead, and i'm fining you
an extra ten bucks for perjury.
let 'em out, leonard.
nice goin'.
unh.
be down to the oak tree
near boot hill at 12:00 sharp
for your hanging.
thank you, your honor.
12:00 sharp on that.
you don't thank a man
for hanging you, you
leather-brained ignoramus.
and bring
your own rope.
right.
i'll get it.
where you goin'?
that's the only rope
we got.
get outta here.
well, the hardware's closed.
come on, you dummy.
well, how you
gonna hang yourself
without a rope?
you know, those dummies
are liable to show up.
well, if they do,
they deserve to be hung.
i just want to get 'em
out of this town
once and for all.
sooner that gold's
out of this bank and in the
san francisco mint, the better.
a lot of people
are out to get that nugget.
stillwell, we've been sittin' on
this mountain for two days now.
starin' at a bank
through a spyglass...
ain't gonna get us
no richer.
you worried
about that sheriff?
any time you got one of them
down-home sheriffs, you always
got a town full of vigilantes.
we could be
walkin' into
a real hornet's nest.
we got to get the gold
sometime.
oh, we're gonna get it.
i never rode no 200 miles...
just to look
at the scenery.
dang.
your leg
cutting up again?
yeah, it always
acts up on me every time
the weather changes.
i'll tell you
one thing sure.
if i ever get
in shootin' distance
of that doggone amos tucker,
he's gonna have windows
where his ears was.
uh, homer?
can we, uh,
talk with you?
as barber, sheriff
or justice of the peace?
justice of the peace.
that's two bits.
but i only got
half a shave!
a whole shave's four bits.
now git before i fine you
for loitering.
git, git, git, git.
all right,
all right.
i'll see you
next tuesday.
dusty, you a willin' party
to this union?
just wanna make sure
they get a square deal
and a good home.
i never teamed two more unlikely
prospects. you go together
like ice cream and whiskey,
but i guess
you'd be man and wife,
same as regular people,
and nobody
could say different.
now you kids just
make yourselves comfortable.
did you want it complete
with the trimmings-- love,
honor and cherish and all that?
kind of like
to hear it anyway.
well, fine.
uh, well, let's
just get it over with.
you got a ring?
no.
more legal with a ring.
you hold this till i tell ya.
was you gonna keep
your hats on?
you take her, donavan?
yes!
do you take him, dusty?
i do.
uh, the ring.
give it to mr. donavan.
powers invested in me,
the state of california,
county of tulare,
i pronounce you hitched.
it ain't necessary
for you to kiss
if you don't want to,
but you ought to
at least shake on it.
well, that's it.
i generally get two dollars
about this point.
pay you back.
ah.
since you two don't seem
to have no immediate plans,
i'm buyin'.
oh, good, good!
oh, dusty, would you mind
just keeping an eye
on the kids for awhile?
might as well
get used to it.
come on. let's have
our own celebration.
how come mr. donavan's
goin' that way,
and we're goin' this way?
it's kind of hard to explain.
that all then,
miss cole?
all right.
$4.62.
i'll put it right here
on your bill.
you can each have
a licorice whip
and one jelly bean--
but just one.
mornin', dusty.
mr. purvey.
if you're here
for those grain bags,
they didn't come in yet.
i have to get boots and jackets
for the kids.
oh, well, here.
we'll look 'em up
in the catalogue.
i see somebody bought the bed.
yep.
sure is pretty.
yeah, sure is.
who'd you sell it to?
donavan.
- who?
- mr. donavan.
he picked it out
this morning.
did he really?
donavan!
yes, you, you snake oil
salesman. are you comin' out
here, or am i comin' in there?
- what's the matter?
is there some trouble?
- yes, there's trouble all right,
and you're in it.
"all i want
is a chance to be on my way,
unencumbered and unfettered."
- that's right.
that's all i wanted.
- don't slick-talk me!
dusty!
wait a minute, dusty.
hold it.
wait a minute!
wait--
dusty--
wait, dusty.
wait, wait, dusty.
now wait a minute!
dusty, will you just
let me say one word?
one!
dusty--
that's it.
no!
"nothing could be further
from my mind, miss clydesdale.
you have my word
as a gentleman."
i meant--
gentleman?
yeah!
aah!
no!
get off of him.
coward.
aha!
no!
no, dusty.
back! back!
give me that!
don't!
now wait a minute, dusty.
now wait.
dusty--
no, no!
wait!
now this is ridiculous.
when you, uh, get rational,
we'll discuss this.
oh!
we'll discuss it
right now.
ohh!
sorry, ralph.
dusty, you're being hysterical.
we can't accomplish anything
this way!
what happened
with them two?
they got married.
dusty, be reasonable.
shut up, you liar.
i don't know what's happened,
but i can explain.
you're not gettin'
out of it that easy,
you pasteboard slinger.
pay you back, homer.
dusty! dusty! now look.
what's bothering you?
that bed!
that great, big brass bed!
if you had no intention
of exercising
your husbandly prerogatives,
why'd you buy that bed?
that's it?
the bed?
yes!
the bed...
happens to be
for the kids, dusty.
with the nights getting colder,
they need a warmer place
to sleep,
so the brass bed
is for the boys,
and the smaller bed
is for celia!
well, why didn't you say so
in the first place?
we could have avoided
this little misunderstanding.
pardon me.
ahem. excuse me, please.
come along, celia.
this is no place
for a lady.
order in the court!
order, order!
quiet now!
everybody, sit down
and shut up.
edgar, you get back
in your seat.
i think we've heard
about all the testimony
this building can take.
now i'm gonna decide who gets
these sprouts of wintle's,
and that decision
is gonna be final.
this court appreciates
the generosity...
and the kindness
of all you good people...
who have offered to provide
homes for these kids...
and to safeguard
their assets.
proves this town's got
a heart after all.
but after due deliberation
and a consideration
of all the facts...
and the merits
of the applicants,
this court awards bobby,
clovis
and celia bradley...
to mr. and mrs. russel donavan.
that's the order of this court.
i don't want to hear
a lot of argument about it,
and i don't want
a half a dozen people
comin' up here--
homer. i heard you were
about to gavel off my kin.
that won't be necessary now
since i'm here to claim them.
donavan,
thank you for taking
such good care of them.
my lawyer.
he will explain
all the "whereas's"
and "wherefore's."
tell them.
tell them, uh, why
the kids are mine,
with no maybe's.
may it please the court,
i have an order--
what would please this court...
is to see both of you
rode out of this town
on a rail!
your honor,
the law--
i don't need
no checkered-pants lawyer
to tell me the law.
give me that!
all right,
they're yours, wintle.
get yourself and that jackleg
outta here before i show you how
contemptuous this court can be.
yes, sir, reverend.
that gold's the most valuable
shipment ever entrusted
to the butterfly line.
oh, my goodness gracious.
the most valuable shipment.
my word.
and exactly how much
does this nugget weigh?
three hundred and fifty-six
pounds, without the crating.
now, uh, that's not quite
as large as the one they found
in breckenridge.
still, that's
a whole lot of gold
all in one piece.
oh, i assume you have
a goodly portion of men
protectin' it.
we're bringin' in
extra guards from
marysville tomorrow.
i see.
then you won't be
making your regular
noon passenger run.
well, now--
oh, fear not,
dear brother.
you're speaking to
a servant of the lord.
well, bein' a man of the cloth,
it can do no harm.
ahem.
they're takin' it out
as soon as the, uh,
bank closes
at 4:00 tomorrow,
but they won't be goin'
by the regular route.
they'll be goin'
over china grade.
splendid.
splendid idea. why,
i shouldn't imagine...
that they would encounter
so much as a horned frog
on that old slag road.
my thinkin' precisely.
uh, reverend, could i
buy you a drink?
oh, thank you, no, sir.
i never imbibe.
however, i would be happy
to accept this as
a contribution for the poor.
bless you, brother.
bless you.
well, charlie.
charlie, i seem
to have, uh,
left my purse
at the office.
i was, uh-- ah.
would you set 'em up
for charlie and me there?
hi, dusty.
howdy.
annulment papers.
homer says you can drop 'em off
at the marysville courthouse,
but it'll take two, three days.
we must have set
some kind of record.
yes.
well, you're
finally rid of 'em.
what now?
well, i guess
i'll work my way east.
change of scenery,
change of luck, you know.
uh, dusty?
thanks for what you did.
we tried somethin'.
it didn't work, that's all.
well, good-bye.
bye.
donavan?
you were a good father
to those kids. they
couldn't have asked for better.
we got along.
well--
- and, donavan?
- yeah?
i'm sorry
i hit you in the head
with the spittoon.
a perfectly logical
misunderstanding.
and i'm sorry that i
offered you a drink
in the saloon too.
well, it's a perfectly logical
misunderstanding.
well, i wouldn't make
that mistake again.
you wouldn't?
good luck, dusty.
how you expect to get warm
sittin' in front of a fire
that's been out for two days?
aw, i don't know.
i always used to sit here
for breakfast.
couldn't we build just one
little itty-bitty fire?
it don't seem like home no more.
no! amos, i tell you.
we got big trouble.
we go in town to get food,
we get strung up.
if we stay here,
we starve to death, if we
don't freeze to death first.
so what's it gonna be?
well-- well,
what if we went down
and told sheriff mccoy...
that we was real sorry
and we wasn't gonna
rob banks anymore?
ever.
right. and we'd even
cross our heart.
well, that's worth
thinkin' about.
we wouldn't want to take
any ropes with us,
would we?
hey, mister.
what do you kids
want now?
you tell him, bobby.
we want you to have
our gold nugget.
- what gold nugget?
- the one you tried to steal.
- oh, that gold nugget.
- all you gotta do is
take it out of the bank.
you kids come all the way
up here just to tell us
to rob the bank again?
we're already sentenced
to be hung for robbin' it
the first time.
say, uh, maybe it's a fix
to smoke us out, theodore.
this isn't any trick.
judge mccoy said mr. wintle
really doesn't want us.
he just wants the gold.
so if you take the gold,
then mr. wintle
will go away again.
and mr. donavan
will be stuck with us again.
mr. donavan buys us
all the apple dumplings
we can eat.
it ain't like it's really
stealin'. it's our gold,
and we're givin' it to ya.
all you have to do
is pick it up.
we'll help you.
pardon me
just a minute, ma'am.
what do you think,
theodore?
oh, i don't know about
the hash knife throwin' in
with a bunch of kids.
how's that gonna look
in the history books?
we wouldn't have to call it
"hash knife." we could call
them the apple dumpling gang.
who's gonna know
the difference?
it's like the kid says.
- it ain't actually stealin'.
- and you better hurry...
'cause we're
leavin' at 4:00,
when the bank closes.
theodore?
all right.
all right! come on.
now, here's the bank.
now we're gonna need some
dynamite to blow the safe.
we gotta get
some kind of a wagon
to haul off the gold.
you got that, gang?
now i think we'll go in
the side door.
you remember that side door.
yeah. now when we
were hangin' in there--
let's see--
that would be
just off to the right.
you told me to get you
a wagon, didn't ya?
not that wagon.
well, what's wrong with--
look. these are
the fastest horses in town.
we'll be halfway to mexico
before they find out.
it's too late to change now.
let's get the thing headed
in the other direction.
right.
you kids keep a lookout
for the sheriff.
i'm sorry.
we're closed.
eh?
i say we're--
i'm sorry, reverend.
we're closed for the day.
you'll--
open that safe.
clovis!
somebody else
is already robbing the bank.
come on!
oh, no.
get on in there.
hurry up!
where'd they come from?
they was outside
lookin' in.
get 'em over yonder
out of the way.
and you keep quiet.
you hear?
ox, keep an eye on 'em.
get out of the room.
ain't that
the most beautiful sight
you ever saw?
- boy, oh, boy.
- ay-yi-yi. it's heavy.
- where's the wagon?
- it's right outside.
easy, boys.
let me catch up with you.
this blasted thing
weighs a ton, dang it.
sure does.
my leg don't work too good
goin' round this turn.
now, that's got it.
now we got her.
hey, don't nobody move!
this is a holdup!
we're gonna rob the bank,
and we mean business.
you're a day late
and a dollar short.
like he said right here--
did you say it?
aah!
who in blazes are you?
well?
ahem. uh, mr. stillwell
asked you a question, theodore.
uh, uh--
- theodore.
- hi, frank.
- amos.
- uh, still aren't mad...
'cause i shot you
in the leg, are you, frank?
i guess you are.
please, gentlemen,
no shooting.
that dynamite is old
and is sweating.
- if he drops it, there won't
be a bit of this bank left.
- that makes sense.
all right,
you two, get over here
and out of the way.
all right.
move.
get these kids out of here
where we can watch 'em.
all right, you. come on.
you're gonna walk right
out of here ahead of us,
straight to the wagon.
one peep outta you and
i'll blow a hole in you that
you can throw a mule through.
you understand?
all right, get to walkin',
and keep smilin'.
hurry up!
hooks, get ahold of this.
come on.
easy does it.
that's our gold!
we said they could have it!
outta my way. all right,
now we're gonna walk--
watch out
for that dynamite!
whoa, whoa.
it's the law!
looks like we're gonna have to
blast our way outta here.
- you idiot.
what's all the firing?
- they're tryin'
to get the nugget.
get this thing
off of me!
hold this.
must be 50 of 'em
in there.
i'll go get old betsy.
somebody
get him a drink.
take more than that
to get the sting out.
get down!
my knees!
get down.
don't do that
anymore.
get down.
aah! i'm sittin'
on my spurs!
dusty!
ha! ha!
are you tryin'
to get yourself killed?
i am trying to stop
a bank robbery.
well, do it from a safe place,
not the middle of the street!
get it inside!
come on!
whoa!
aah!
does anyone know where
alvin keeps his corkscrew?
grab these kids,
and let's get out of here.
what about the gold?
forget about the gold.
we'll be lucky to escape
with our hides. hurry up.
frank, are you sure
you don't want your gold?
it's all yours, partner.
don't spend it all
in one place.
i'm gonna buy
some new toes.
you can't take
those children.
let's go this way.
frank, our horses
are around front.
well, so is
half the town.
come on.
i ain't never gonna rob
no bank-- ever, ever, ever.
that's it!
aah! aah!
i can't move!
i can walk.
my back!
go!
i can't move!
we gotta
get out of here.
i can't move! my back!
all right.
aah! the dynamite!
i can't move.
just cover me, mildred.
mr. donavan!
they got celia.
hyah! hyah, hyah!
hyah!
clyde!
ha!
howdy.
shh! listen.
they stopped firing.
aah!
there's two more
in there.
get this team to movin'!
hurry!
hyah! hyah!
celia!
dusty!
hey!
donavan!
what?
whoa!
my.
you always
kiss like that?
i've been savin' up.
oh, yeah?
get stillwell,
wring him out
and lock him up.
donavan?
dusty?
you're gonna drown in there.
i guess
they don't mind.
well, we better get back
to town and see what's
happened to that nugget.
gold!
it's a gold nugget, lily!
gold! gold!
gold!
get out of here.
this is my claim. anyone who
looks for gold around here...
is gonna fight me.
i wandered today
to the hill, maggie??
to watch the scenes below??
the brook and the creaking
old mill, maggie????
my bank.
my beautiful bank.
oh, a man that can fill an
inside straight like you can
don't need a bank.
leonard, you can work
out of my barbershop
till you rebuild--
at no charge.
i want you to know
that i hold your bank
and this town responsible...
for the loss of my gold.
and you! you can be
jolly well responsible
for those three brats too.
mr. donavan!
theodore and amos--
they were in the bank.
there you are, donavan:
5,000 for the capture
of frank stillwell.
it's no more
than you deserve,
donavan.
and here is the deed
of the benson place.
there it is.
the roulette tables,
crystal chandeliers,
the red carpets.
everything.
well,
you don't have to go through
with it if you don't want to,
donavan.
someone else
will buy the benson place.
it's in fine shape.
it shouldn't be so bad.
i'll be going into town one or
two nights a week to play poker.
wanna bet?
look.
it's a holdup.
whoa.
- hi.
- i thought you promised sheriff
mccoy you were gonna stop that.
oh, we are stoppin',
mr. donavan. fact,
me and amos talked it over,
and we've decided we've been
the scourge of the west
long enough...
and we're hangin'
our firearms up for good.
and, uh-- ahem.
well, we was just wonderin'
if, uh, uh--
climb on.
you mean i'll be livin'
under the same roof with
these two lawless profligates?
just till you hear
from mr. gould, pa.
that horse
got a name?
lucius.
oh, yeah?
lucius, clarice.
clarice, lucius.
so they settled down together
their troubles all behind??
now that donavan and dusty
tied the knot??
and their friends
wished them happiness
as all the church bells rang?
for that family called
the apple dumpling gang??
mr. donavan?
i gotta go.
and they called them??
the apple dumpling gang????