You there,
which way to Pepperinge Eye?
Couldn't say, sir.
It said on the wireless to paint out
the signposts in case the Nazis drop in.
I'm not a Nazi. I'm a British officer.
That's what you'd say
if you was a Nazi, isn't it, sir?
Drive on, Corporal.
Sorry to give you so many,
but you do have six bedrooms.
Oh, no trouble, my dear.
Anything to get the poor things away
from those terrible bombings in London.
Come along, love. Let's go.
Hey, what about us?
Oh, yes. What is your name, please?
Rawlins, ma'am.
Rawlins? Rawlins?
Oh, yes. Here we are.
Carrie, Charles, Paul.
Well, you're for Miss Price.
I'm expecting' her in.
I won't be a moment.
Please, don't touch anything.
Call out the tanks
From the Cliffs of Dover
call up the Gauls
And don't forget the loyal territorials
Who's digging in here?
Who will defend
every inch of England
no matter what they send?
Who's standing firm
in our own front yard?
The soldiers of
the old home guard
That's who
The soldiers of
the old home guard
For we wrote the story
of the old brigade
We know the glory
of yesterday's parades
Who's standing firm
in our own front yard?
The soldiers of
the old home guard
That's who
The soldiers of
the old home guard
Parade, halt.
Carry on, Sergeant.
Captain Greer, sir,
from headquarters at Tidbury,
here to check military preparations
in the area.
Tell them Pepperinge Eye
has matters well in hand.
But nevertheless, I...
What on earth is that?
Good morning, General.
I received your message, Mrs. Hobday.
I assume that my parcel has arrived.
It's in the office.
Ah, lovely.
Who is that?
Miss Price, splendid woman.
Her late father served
with me at Vimy Ridge.
What's she burn in this thing?
It smells a bit like sulfur.
Ridiculous. One can't make
motor fuel out of sulfur.
Here we are.
Another object from
Professor Emelius Browne in London.
Thank you.
Is it what you expected?
I imagine so.
Professor Browne sent you a cat
last time, did he not?
Yes.
Professor Browne is well?
I haven't the faintest idea.
Are we to have
the pleasure of meeting him?
I very much doubt it. I don't know
Professor Browne personally.
- Was there something else?
- As a matter of fact, there is.
Would you come this way, Miss Price?
Well, I'm very anxious
to get home, you know.
Come along, please.
Get down, Charlie. I want to ride.
Stop it this instant!
Children, this is Miss Price.
Carrie, Charles, and Paul Rawlins.
All the way from London.
- How do you do?
- How are you, miss?
The government's trying to evacuate
as many children as possible
into the country.
Very sensible.
Today they sent us 45.
And I've had to find homes
for all of them at very short notice.
These are the last three.
All right, children, pick up your things.
You're not suggesting that I should
take these children into my house?
Exactly.
Oh, I'm sorry,
but that's quite out of the question.
Children and I don't get on.
I believe you, miss.
Come on, back to London.
Hurray!
Be quiet.
Besides, I have work to do,
very important work.
Miss Price, you do have
that entire house to yourself.
And according to the order
of the Ministry of Civil Defense,
you have no choice.
I see.
Very well, if that is the case,
I shall take them into my house
with the understanding
that you find a more suitable home
as soon as possible.
Fine, come along.
Ah! Good morning, Miss Price.
There they are. Oh, Miss Price.
What a charitable thing you are doing,
taking in these poor
unfortunates from the city.
Hold this very carefully.
I wonder, Miss Price,
if I may drop by later this afternoon.
Why?
Ah, well, we have their spiritual
needs to consider now. Do we not?
That won't be necessary.
They won't be with me for long.
Oh!
My parcel, please.
Bring your things inside.
A bit murky, ain't it?
Yeah.
Not another house
around here for miles.
Wipe your feet.
Big place, this.
Who else lives here?
I live alone.
It suits my purpose.
All right. Come along, everybody.
A cat!
Sorry, miss. The cat startled us.
No need for alarm.
You just frightened him, that's all.
Yes, scared to death. You can see that.
What do you call your cat?
I don't believe in giving
animals ridiculous names.
I call him Cosmic Creepers,
because that's the name he came with.
You will sleep in here.
This was my father's bedroom.
And I want you
to be very careful of everything in it.
You boys take the bed, there.
All right, miss.
- What was your name?
- It's Carrie, miss.
Carrie, you sleep on the sofa in there.
Thank you, miss.
Is that all you brought?
We ain't exactly burdened
down with frillies.
Travel light, that's us.
Well, I don't think this
arrangement is going to work,
but it seems that I have no alternative.
We'll do our best, miss. Really we will.
Thank you, Carrie.
The bathroom is along the landing.
Supper is at 6:00.
You will wash thoroughly...
- Wash?
- You will wash yourselves,
otherwise there will be no supper.
Is that clear?
A house of horror,
that's what we've come to.
Please don't bother to whisper.
I'm exceptionally keen of hearing.
You are planning to run back to London.
If you've any plotting to do,
please do it elsewhere
where I shan't have to listen to it.
I'm afraid I don't know much
about what children eat.
You'll have to make do as I do.
Is there anything particular
that you fancy?
Sausage and mash,
bubble and squeak, toad in the hole.
Fried fish. Oh, anything at all.
I'm afraid you
won't find any fried foods in this house.
- No fried food?
- No.
How do you keep your health?
Cabbage buds, rose hips,
glyssop seed, elm bark,
whortle yeast and stewed nettles.
"Dear madam, with this shipment,
"the Emelius Browne
Correspondence College of Witchcraft
"sends you its heartiest congratulations
"on qualifying for the first
degree of your chosen calling.
"You may now call yourself
apprentice witch.
"Yours faithfully, Emelius Browne."
My first broom.
Time to go. Everybody up.
Wake up, Paul.
We're going back to London.
Now, let's see how we fly this thing.
Here we are.
"Clasp the broom with both hands."
Yes, of course.
"No, never astride the broom."
"Technically, a witch is always a lady
"except when circumstances
dictate otherwise.
"Take an easy,
graceful, sideways position."
Of course, that's much better.
An easy, graceful, sideways position.
There we are. How's that?
"To start up the broom,
your basic formula."
I wasn't ready!
Now, watch this.
Here we go.
It's going to be a little
different this time.
All right, I know it's not ladylike.
- Cor!
- What's the matter?
- How does she do that?
- 'Cause she's a witch.
- That's the sort of thing witches do.
- Oh.
She don't fly good, do she?
She's crashed!
Come on, now's our chance to hop it.
Suppose she's hurt?
Go on. You can't hurt a witch.
Look out!
She's proper cross, now.
Let's get away from here.
Hang on. I'm having a bit of a think.
"A witch she is," says you.
"Then let's use the old loaf," says I.
Let's get back to London.
What we have here is an opportunity.
She don't want anyone
to know she's a witch, does she?
Not ruddy likely.
That's the opportunity.
And I intend to make the most of it.
Come on.
Bran porridge.
Thank you, miss.
Very healthful, I'm sure.
Hurt your foot, Miss Price?
Oh, just twisted my ankle.
Sorry to hear that.
Thank you. It's nothing serious.
Lovely weather for flying last night.
Why did you say that, Charles?
Game's up, Miss Price.
We know what you are.
I see.
Don't worry, Miss Price.
No one's gonna peach on you.
Thank you. I should be most grateful
if you didn't tell anyone in the village.
'Course, there'll have to be one or two
little changes made around here.
I mean, I'd like to see an occasional
sausage on the table here.
A bit of strawberry jam.
Charlie!
Let me handle this.
And another thing, Miss Price,
there'll be no more of this
wash, wash, wash, mornin' and night.
Anything else?
Now you mention it,
I could do with a bit of lolly.
Lolly?
Cash, cold hard cash.
You must have buckets of it.
For your information,
the most accomplished of witches
can't make money out of thin air.
Have you ever heard of a rich witch?
Be that as it may,
you don't want us to blab, do you?
Have you considered
what danger you might be in?
I am a witch, you know.
What will you do? Turn me into a toad?
Lovely, a toad with pink eyes.
I might just do that.
Go on, then. I dare you.
Very well, Charles.
You shouldn't have said that to her.
She don't frighten me.
She can't even ride a proper broom.
Excuse me, Charles.
Oh, Charlie!
That's better than a toad.
That's a rabbit.
Bother! I never seem
to be able to manage toads.
Stop! Leave him alone!
Don't let Charlie get hurt.
Oh, not to worry.
My spells don't last very long.
I'm just an apprentice witch, you know.
Look out, Charlie!
You flamin' brute!
I'll teach you to do that to me!
Let Cosmic Creepus alone.
Weren't his fault.
I'm afraid it's my fault.
Bad enough not being
able to manage a broom,
I can't perform a simple, basic spell.
You dared her to do it.
I don't see why we can't all be friends.
Maybe she's not a wicked witch.
Of course I'm not.
- See?
- If only I could trust you.
You see, the work I'm doing
is so important to the war effort.
How do you mean?
I mean, exceptionally important.
Most secret.
What do you say, Charlie.
We can keep a secret.
Yeah, if someone made
it worth our while.
I don't follow.
Simple, you give us something
valuable to seal the pact.
Oh, Charlie,
don't try to be clever again.
It's for her own protection, ain't it?
If we broke the pact,
we'd have to give back
the valuable object.
I think it's an excellent idea.
I wonder what I could give you?
Would you settle for one of my spells?
I bet that's not worth much.
Come with me.
I liked you better as a rabbit, Charlie.
Shut up, you.
Well, I never had a rabbit.
Careful what you touch in here.
Rum sort of place, ain't it?
When I signed for my witchcraft course,
there was a free bonus,
a certain marvelous traveling spell,
if you paid promptly in advance.
I think I'll give you that one.
- Is it valuable?
- Certainly!
Poisoned dragon's liver!
Poisoned dragon liver.
You mean you poison the dragon
or just the liver?
Well, it comes prepared.
It's part of the school equipment.
Ah, here we are. "The traveling spell."
All right, everybody gather around.
All right, now let's see.
Does anyone have a bracelet or a ring?
Something that you can twist.
No, Miss Price.
What about you, Paul?
I always carry a few things
around with me.
You never know when
they might come in useful.
A piece of blue glass.
A lovely bit of string.
Horseshoe nail.
What's that?
A knob, come from the bed upstairs.
It twists, don't it?
Yeah, twisted right off.
Yes, I think that will be all right.
Carrie, turn the light down a little bit,
will you?
There.
Isn't that pretty!
Is that all we get?
This knob will now work
the famous traveling spell.
And what's the famous traveling spell?
How does it work?
Well, you take this knob
and put it back on the bed upstairs.
Then, turn it smartly
a quarter turn to the left.
Then, in a firm, clear voice,
tell it where you want to go,
and the bed will take you there.
- Go on!
- Miss Price, will it really?
Well, I see no reason to think otherwise.
Oh, thank you for the lovely gift.
Oh, I'm sorry, but it does belong to Paul.
He's the only one
who can work the spell.
Me?
Yes.
That's right. Mine, now wasn't it.
That's the way the spell works.
Nice mess he'll make of things.
Oh, bother.
You children run upstairs,
but mind you, don't try anything
with the bedknob till I get back.
"Dear madam,
it grieves me to inform you,
"that due to the war,
we have been forced
"to close down
our college of witchcraft.
"This means that we shall
not be sending you
"the final lesson in which
you expressed so much interest."
We were wondering
what was keeping you.
I've had some very bad news.
Is there anything we can do?
No, no, thank you.
Yes, yes, there is
something that Paul can do.
- Me?
- Paul, I need the bedknob back.
I must get to London immediately.
No, I want to go to the jungle.
Come with me, Paul.
Now, Paul, ridiculous as it may seem
to have to explain this
to a six-year-old child,
but I do need your help.
Go ahead.
I was expecting a very
important spell in the mail
from my teacher,
Professor Emelius Browne,
and it hasn't come.
What's that got to do with my knob?
I must go to London immediately
and see Professor Browne.
With his help, we may be able
to bring this war to a successful end.
That is why I need the knob.
What is your decision?
Thank you, Paul.
I brought this for your hair, Carrie.
It may be windy.
Thank you. Oh, it's ever so nice.
Paul, have you been to the bathroom?
- Twice.
- Good.
Charles, you'd better
put on something warmer.
The bed may travel quite fast.
I'm not going. I'm staying right here.
But why, Charlie?
All that rubbish about a traveling bed.
It won't work, that's why.
Carrie, help me to pull the bed out.
We don't want to scratch
the wall when we take off, do we?
How's a ruddy big bed, like that,
going to get out of this room,
with those little windows?
I don't know, Charles.
There's a great many things
about magic that I don't know.
We'll just have to find out.
Lovely. Just so's you leave me out of it.
I don't fancy making a fool of myself.
What's come over you lately, Charlie?
You're no fun, anymore.
Help me to tidy up the bed, Carrie.
We don't want to go to London
with an unmade bed.
How old is Charles?
Eleven, going on twelve.
I see. That's what my father used to call
the age of "Not believing."
What's that supposed to be?
When you rush around
in hopeless circles
Searching everywhere
for something true
You're at the age
of not believing
When all the make believe is through
That's Charlie to a T.
When you set aside
your childhood heroes
And your dreams
are lost upon a shelf
You're at the age of not believing
and worst of all you doubt yourself
Throw that into the wastebasket.
You're a castaway
where no one hears you
On a barren isle in a lonely sea
What's that supposed to be? Poetry?
Where did all the happy endings go?
Where can all the good times be?
Everyone on the bed who's going.
You must face the age of not believing
Doubting everything you ever knew
The knob, Paul.
Until at last you start believing
There's something wonderful in you
Lovely sentiment, I'm sure.
- Are you ready, Paul?
- Yes, Miss Price.
Repeat after me.
Take us to Professor Emelius Browne.
Take us to Professor...
Emelius Browne.
Very good.
Headmaster,
Correspondence College of Witchcraft.
Headmaster, Correspondence College.
Of Witchcraft, London.
Now, when I say "go,"
tap the knob three times
and turn it a quarter turn to the left.
- Left.
- That's it.
Now, we better hold on tight.
The behavior of the bed
is something I'm not quite sure of.
Let me breathe a little.
All right, Paul, ready?
Go.
One, two, three.
Is this London?
Course it is.
Can't you smell that lovely, sooty air?
Marvelous, ain't it?
Well, Charles,
are you convinced by now?
Not yet, I ain't.
I don't see no Professor Browne.
Neither do I, in point of fact.
You children look after the bed
while I make inquiries for Mr. Browne.
I told you this flamin' bed wouldn't work.
Oh, Charlie, don't start that again.
It didn't work proper.
- This bed was supposed to take us to...
- Look!
Professor Browne!
Come on!
Ladies and gentlemen!
Gather around, please,
ladies and gentlemen!
Please note the name,
ladies and gentlemen,
Professor Emelius Browne.
I am here to divert, to amuse,
and, yes, even to help you.
There he is!
It is not what things are.
It is what they seem to be.
Is that not so, madam?
That ain't the kind
of professor I expected.
I'm not sure it's the kind of professor
Miss Price expected, either.
What effect a little smoke is
with a dash of hocus pocus
and the scent of burning...
And the scent
of burning sulfur in the air.
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
for my next trick,
may I draw your attention
to this solid piece
of ordinary window glass
framed in an ordinary,
unprepared frame.
May I also draw your attention
to this perfectly ordinary steel nail.
Now, I shall place the framed glass
in this brown, unprepared,
unprepared, mark you,
ladies and gentlemen,
unprepared, brown, paper bag.
I shall now attempt
to drive the steel nail through the glass
without breaking the glass!
"Impossible," I can hear you say.
We shall see.
He ain't very good,
even if he is a professor.
I'll tell you what I'm going to do.
No, ladies, please don't go.
Don't leave now
and regret lost opportunities later.
You, young sir,
would you care to warble
like the storied nightingale?
With this inexpensive device,
you can charm the very birds
down from the trees, like so.
How much?
For you, sir, one penny.
One copper coin of the realm.
Carrie, I'm very surprised at you,
wandering off like this.
We found him for you, miss.
We found Professor Browne.
It don't work. I've been cheated!
Is that Professor Browne?
It is indeed, my dear.
How may I serve you?
Would you be interested
in the mating call
of the Brazilian Matouacan bird?
Known as the bird of love?
Very useful, eh?
You are the headmaster
of the Emelius Browne
Correspondence College of Witchcraft?
The late headmaster.
The college, alas, is now defunct.
Professor Browne,
I am one of your pupils.
My dear lady, you are, indeed,
an ornament to the college.
- Splendid!
- Not at all.
I was shocked and dismayed
when you closed down the college
without that most important last lesson.
I'm sorry, my dear, no refunds.
Look at your contract.
But I must have the spell
that comes with the last lesson!
The matter is closed.
I bid you good day!
I have an appointment
at my club for squash rackets.
The matter is not closed!
Don't let him get away.
Right-o!
Leave go of me!
Would you mind? Would you mind?
Would you mind...
Ah, here we are.
Will you get this child off my leg?
Would you get this child...
Cor!
Now, I trust you'll behave
more like a gentleman.
Look out!
Well, there goes another rabbit.
Oh! What was all that about?
I changed you into a rabbit
with one of your own spells.
My spell? From my school?
Not one of your
best spells, in point of fact.
It doesn't last very long.
Some of your others are much better.
But I don't understand.
My spell?
They were just nonsense
words that I got out of an old book.
Well, they worked perfectly well for me.
They worked for you?
Good woman, some kind of destiny
has brought us together.
You got the words for these spells
out of some old book you say?
Well, more or less.
I changed them 'round a bit.
I gave them a bit
of my own style as it were.
The old sorcerers
did have a bit of a tendency
to waffle on, but dear lady,
I never thought I'd meet
somebody like you.
What a treasure.
Mr. Browne, will you
please stick to the point!
I would like
to see this book, immediately!
Certainly.
It's at my new town house.
Would you care to
join me for luncheon?
We can discuss my ideas
at the same time.
Thank you. We'd be delighted.
We shall all go together.
- On the bed?
- On the bed, Paul.
You go 'round the other side.
I always travel on the left.
Will you give the address
to Paul, please.
May I ask, how we're going
to get there on this bed? Fly?
My dear Professor Browne,
with your own traveling spell,
the one you gave with
the course as a bonus.
My traveling spell?
That works, as well?
Just give the address, please.
Eight Wynchfield road.
Bed, take us to Eight Wynchfield road.
Madam, is this vehicle safe?
Oh, perfectly safe.
Bit theatrical, perhaps,
but then, most good spells are.
Well, we're here.
I would never have believed it.
You must have given us
the wrong address.
You don't live here, do you?
In point of fact, I do.
Temporarily, at any rate.
I found the front door open.
The house was deserted.
Everyone has left the neighborhood.
Now, why should they do that?
This probably
has something to do with it.
Merciful heavens!
I should think you'd be terrified
at the very idea of living here.
You'd have thought so, wouldn't you?
I am by nature, a little bit of a coward.
But then I pondered, as I often do.
In the perverse nature of things,
this diabolical object is probably
the best friend I've ever had.
It enables me for the first time
in my life, to live like a king.
Shall we go in?
Rothschild '26.
Noble, worldly-wise,
but with a charming touch of innocence.
- Wouldn't you say?
- Mr. Browne, the book. Where is it?
Dear lady, you are relentless.
The book is in the library
and we shall proceed there
after finishing our cheese and wine.
Why'd you keep the curtains closed?
So that we may enjoy
the gentle glow of candlelight.
More likely,
so's the coppers don't peek in
and catch you hidin' out here.
Now, why don't you young things
have a look around the house?
I want to have a chat with Miss Price.
- May we?
- Yes, run along, children.
But mind you, don't touch anything.
Remember, this house doesn't
belong to Mr. Browne.
Mr. Browne, where is that book?
I must have that spell
on substitutiary locomotion.
What is it? A toy shop?
No, it's a nursery.
Ain't you ever seen a nursery?
No, and neither have you.
Would you hold this, please?
What do you think of that?
Well, I don't know what to think.
Miss Price, just think
how successful I could be
with an assistant
who can really do magic!
Oh?
Dear lady, have you ever
considered entering,
what some of us call, "Show business?"
The what business?
The theater, pantomimes,
village fairs, the seaside, Brighton,
Blackpool, follies on the prom...
Mr. Browne,
I have very important work to do.
Listen to me. We could make a packet.
Let us strike a bargain
You possess a gift
but I can speak the jargon
That will give your
gift the needed lift
Oh?
You possess the know how
and I command the show how
Oh, how successful
you could be with me
I'm afraid we're wasting valuable time.
- What's your name?
- Miss Price.
No, your first name, my dear.
Eglantine.
Eglantine?
Eglantine
Oh, how you'll shine
Your lot and my lot
have got to combine
Eglantine, Eglantine
Hark to the stars
Destiny calls us
The future is ours
as the shine sells the boot
And the blossoms the fruit
All you need to succeed in your plan
Is the proper ally
upon whom to rely
And I'm your man
For I have an acumen
that's nigh superhuman
I sell things that nobody can
So I humbly suggest
you accept my behest
I'm your man
Eglantine, Eglantine
Mr. Browne!
Oh, how you shine
Mr. Browne, will you please...
Your lot and my lot
Have got to combine
Eglantine, Eglantine
Mr. Browne, do you hear me?
Hark to the stars
Destiny calls us
Mr. Browne, I'm warning you.
The future is ours
What are you reading?
Isle of Naboombu.
Can't be no such place.
There is too such a place.
These pictures proves it, don't it?
A bit weird, ain't it?
Animals wearing hats and things?
I like it.
I warned you, Mr. Browne.
Now, where is the book?
Well? Where is it?
At last, Mr. Browne!
The Spells of Astoroth.
Of course.
Here's the traveling spell.
This is where you got it.
Does one's nose
have to twitch like this?
Oh, you're back, Mr. Browne.
Miss Price, a word about your tactics.
I don't mind being changed
into a hawk or a tiger,
or something with a bit of dash to it,
but always a fluffy, white rabbit?
It's intolerable!
Ah, here we are.
"Substitutiary locomotion."
"The ancient art of...
"The spell which creates this force
is five mystic words.
"These words are..."
But the rest of the book is missing!
Now you see why
I closed down the college.
But where are the other pages?
Oh, I haven't the foggiest.
Listen to me, Mr. Browne.
I'm all ears.
You will be if you don't pay attention.
Where did you get this book?
I bought it from a chap
in the street market.
There was a bit of unpleasantness
as a matter of fact.
He claimed
that I'd given him a dud coin, I ask you.
There was a sort of scuffle.
The book tore.
He got one half and I got the other.
But where's the other half now?
Oh, it's probably been thrown away.
If it still exists,
there's only one place to find it.
Where is that?
Portobello Road
Street where the riches
of ages are stowed
Anything and everything
a chap can unload
Is sold off the barrow
in Portobello Road
You'll find what you want
in the Portobello Road
Rare alabaster
Genuine plaster
A filigreed samovar
owned by the Czars
A pen used by Shelley
a new Botticelli
The snippers that clipped
old King Edward's cigars
Made in Hong Kong?
Two bob a dozen, would you say?
Waterford crystal
Napoleon's pistols
Society heirlooms
with genuine gems
Rembrandts, El Grecos
Toulouse-Lautrecos
Painted last week on
the banks of the Thames
Very interesting,
but where do they sell books?
There's a little place around the corner.
Portobello Road Portobello Road
Street where the riches
of ages are stowed
Anything and everything
a chap can unload
Is sold off the barrow
in Portobello Road
You'll meet all your chums
in the Portobello Road
Lovely to see you, goodbye.
What I want is the other half
of this book.
All in good time, my dear.
Burke's Peerage the bride book
The fishmonger's guide book
I'm looking for the other part of this,
thank you.
A Victorian novel
The Unwanted Son
You don't understand, I'm not...
The history of potting
The yearbook of yachting
The leather-bound
life of Attila, the Hun
Portobello Road Portobello Road
Street where the riches
of ages are stowed
Artifacts to glorify a regal abode
Are hid mid the flotsam
in Portobello Road
Who do you think you are?
The Queen of Sheba?
Tokens and treasures
yesterday's pleasures
Cheap imitations
and heirlooms of old
Dented and tarnished
scarred and unvarnished
In old Portobello...
This good lady is looking
for the other half of this book.
It's called, The Spells of Astoroth.
I don't keep no torn
or damaged books here.
What do you think I am?
A ruddy wastepaper merchant?
You can eat like a king
in the Portobello Road
I think, if I'm right, there's another book
store along here, somewhere.
Grandpa, you don't
expect to sell a piano like that do you?
Let me have a go, my dear fellow.
Portobello Road Portobello Road
Happy things are happening
in Portobello Road
You feel like a ballerina
when you're hopping like a toad
When you kick your heels up
down in Portobello Road
Come on, ducks.
Come on, girls.
Lovely.
Oh!
Closing time. Closing time.
Closing time.
- Bye.
Bye.
Portobello Road
Street where the riches
of ages are stowed
Anything and everything
a chap can unload
Hey, guv'nor,
somethin' for the lady friend? Nylons?
- No, thank you.
- Uh, petrol coupons?
- Chocs for the little ones?
- Nope.
How about one of these?
Fell off the back of a lorry.
Do be a good chap and run away.
Would you fancy this, then?
Ah...
Now you have my undivided attention.
What can I do for you, friend?
You're to get over
to the bookman straightaway.
He wants to see you.
You, too!
Who is the bookman?
And what right has he got
to order me about?
Under the circumstances
I think we better ask questions later.
Excuse me.
Sorry, guv, no one
told me about the stairs.
Why didn't you just bring
Scotland Yard, Swinburne,
and half the household's cavalry,
as well?
What's the bed for?
It's a present for you.
That's what he said.
Nothing of the sort.
The bed belongs to me.
Except for this knob, which is mine.
Be that as it may.
Bookman, there's been
bad blood between us long enough.
Let this glittering gift
begin friendship anew.
Draw the curtains and lock the door.
You'll be snug as a bug.
Mr. Browne,
isn't that the section of the manuscript
that we've been looking for?
Who is this person?
A Miss Eglantine Price,
a charming young woman
of my acquaintance.
Miss Price, I've been looking
for this other bit a long time.
Mr. Swinburne told me you
were in the market making inquiries.
And here we are.
I don't mind saying,
to see it all together at last,
there isn't much I wouldn't do.
Or haven't done, for that matter.
Right, guv?
You'll close your mouth, Swinburne!
Is that clear?
It's all rather like a jolly detective
story, or jigsaw puzzle, isn't it?
We're both after the same spell.
You have one clue. I have the other.
In that case, the sensible thing
seems to be for us to cooperate.
I assume you're looking
for the same thing I am.
May I?
This is quite a moment for both of us.
"Substitutiary locomotion,
the lost miracle of the ancients."
And so on and so forth.
Ah. Here we are.
"The spell which creates this force
is five mystic words.
"These words are..."
"Engraved on the star that was always
worn by the sorcerer, Astoroth."
But where are
the words of the spell?
I assumed they'd
be in your half of the manuscript.
But I thought they'd be in yours.
Once again, a dead end.
I shall never know the secret.
Isn't that old Astoroth?
And there's his star.
It's a pity it's so small
you can't read the writing.
But why the animals?
Towards the end of his life,
Astoroth kept animals in cages
and searched for the spells that would
make them more like humans.
The legend is that finally the animals
rebelled at the experiment,
killed Astoroth,
and stole many of his powers.
Including the star with the spell on it.
Possibly. They found a ship,
sailed away,
and were never heard of again.
However, there's a final notation
in my half of the book,
saying that in the 17th century,
a shipwrecked lascar
was taken from the sea
half-mad with thirst
and exposure to the sun.
Before he died, he swore
he'd seen an island ruled by animals.
Where?
There is, I regret to say,
no such island.
I looked for it in every chart.
The Isle of Naboombu does not exist.
Oh, it does, too!
Got me own...
What is he trying to say?
Nothin'.
When he don't say nothin' he burbles.
I wish the child to speak!
Now you've done it.
There is, too, such a place.
Got me own book. There.
Real pretty letters, ain't it?
Let me see it.
You're not interested, Bookman.
It's just a simple children's book.
I'll be the judge of that.
- Give it to me.
- No!
Please don't annoy me.
Give me the book, boy!
Not likely.
Bit of a stalemate, isn't it?
If it's all the same to you,
I'd rather use me own.
Sentiment, you know.
Come along, Paul,
I believe it's time to go.
Go? How, my dear?
The door is locked.
Observe the fundamental
weakness of the criminal mind.
You'll believe in no one, or in anything.
I understand. The knob, Paul.
- Right.
- Of course you do, my dear.
Do you realize
we can tell them the complete truth?
They will believe nothing!
He's up to something, you know.
Bookman, before your very eyes,
I shall cause this bed
and all the occupants upon it,
to disappear.
Disappear?
I'd like to see a cheapjack,
tenth-rate entertainer
do a trick like that.
Cheapjack entertainer!
Now, that was naughty.
All right, Paul.
Where to?
To the Island of Naboombu.
- I'm very curious about that place.
- Good.
Bed, take us
to the Island of Naboombu.
Enough of this nonsense.
Get the book.
Beastly climate!
I never did fancy the sea.
Where are we?
Naboombu, of course.
I ain't never seen no
island like this before.
I'm afraid we may have
fallen into the lagoon.
That's right!
Here we are, on page three.
Ahoy, Mr. Codfish.
Hello, young fellow.
Welcome to Naboombu Lagoon.
Now I'm hearing things.
Fish don't talk.
Not too bright, is he?
- He's me brother.
- Oh!
Sorry.
Mr. Codfish,
where is the island of Naboombu?
You mean the land part?
Oh, that.
Straight up. You can't miss it.
None of my business, of course,
but I shouldn't go there if I were you.
Having troubles, they are.
Troubles?
He's right, you know,
a lot of trouble.
Well, trouble or not,
we should be getting along.
I wish to see who is in charge.
What's the rush?
It's really rather splendid down here.
For you, my dear.
Oh, thank you.
How pleasant!
Bobbing along
Bobbing along on the bottom
of the beautiful briny sea
What a chance
to get a better peep
At the plants
and creatures of the deep
We glide
Far below the rolling tide
Serene
Through the bubbly
blue and green
It's lovely bobbing along
Bobbing along on the bottom
of the beautiful briny sea
What if the octopus
the flounder and the cod
think we're rather odd?
It's fun to promenade
Bobbing along singing a song
On the bottom of the
beautiful briny sea
Look.
It's lovely bobbing along
Bobbing along on the bottom
of the beautiful briny sea
What a chance to get a better peep
At the plants and creatures of the deep
It's grand
When you're dancing on the sand
Each glance
Bubbles over with romance
It's lovely bobbing along
Bobbing along through the water
where we get along swimmingly
Far from the frenzy
of the frantic world above
Two beneath the blue
Could even fall in love
Bobbing along singing a song
On the bottom of the beautiful briny sea
On the bottom of the beautiful briny
Shimmery shiny
beautiful briny sea
Bravo. Bravo.
Most exciting. Most exciting.
You've won the ruddy cup.
Help! Help!
This time I really got a whopper!
Whew!
People! People!
Oh, no!
What scurvy luck!
- My goodness!
- I'll deal with this, my dear.
Don't you know that...
Good day, Captain.
L used to be a bit
of a seafaring man, myself.
Many's the time
I've shipped out of Portsmouth.
Delighted to meet a fellow mariner.
Huh?
Now, stow it, mate.
Oh, really!
Can't you read readin', huh?
Uh, it says...
"No peopling allowed."
"No peopling allowed." Ridiculous.
Don't antagonize him, Mr. Browne.
That means I gotta throw you all back.
That's what it do.
Wait a minute.
It says here that anybody
can see the King, and that's the law.
Where do it say that?
Here, in me book.
Mmm-hmm.
So it do.
But if you people
knew what was good for ya,
you'd get yourselves all throwed back!
The King don't like people!
Nonetheless, we must see the King
on an urgent, personal matter.
Please lead the way.
Uh-huh.
But just don't say
I didn't warn ya, see?
Follow me.
I'm a peaceable sailor
and that sure ain't all
Blow, blow, blow the man down
Get out of here!
Yes, yes.
What can I do for you?
I, uh, caught some people
down at the sea lagoon.
They want to see the King.
Really?
Well, we can't be bothered
with that sort of thing now, can we?
I don't know that I fancy this.
His Majesty is in a frightful rage.
Excuse me, sir. As an all-around
entertainer of sorts,
I am considered not without talent.
Perhaps I can cheer him up?
No, no, no.
You don't understand.
As everyone knows,
His Majesty is the world's
greatest soccer player.
But, due to a technical problem,
the royal cup match
cannot take place today,
and His Majesty
had so set his heart on it.
Throw these...
Creatures back into the sea.
Aye, aye, sir.
Just a moment. I can help.
Do you really think so?
I'd be most grateful.
Do you know soccer?
Do I know anything about soccer?
Why, I was captain
of Tottenham Hotspurs for two years,
three seasons with Manchester United.
- Yes, yes, yes, you'll do.
- Before that I...
Come this way, please.
Mr. Browne, are you certain
you'll be all right?
Now what?
Not an ideal person in many respects,
but Mr. Browne is a very brave man.
Do you think he's done for?
Do you think so?
I can't tell you how I appreciate this.
For some reason,
we have great difficulty
finding referees 'round here.
If there be one thing we like,
it's volunteers.
Eh, Birdy?
He's a proper king.
Look at his crown.
What's he got 'round his neck?
What a magnificent...
Ornament, sire.
Ah, yes.
Wouldn't be without it.
Been in the family for years.
The star of Astoroth.
You're to sit
in His Majesty's royal box.
No littering, no chewing, no fruit
or wrappers from boiled sweets, please.
Rise, please.
Loyal fans, this is official.
We have a volunteer referee.
Let the match begin!
He's still wearing it.
Right, Dirty Yellows,
let's have a nice, clean game.
Right, True Blues, best foot forward.
Weird sort of game they play here.
Hurry up. Get rid of it.
Gracious.
You're doing fine, matey.
Move it around. Move it around.
Get on with the match!
- Foul! Foul!
- They're only animals.
That's no excuse for dirty football.
Ref, are you blind?
Be quiet, Charles.
Don't forget who the referee is.
- Don't they have no rules?
- 'Course they do.
The King makes them up
as he goes along.
Poor Mr. Browne.
Do you think he's all right?
Well, he's moving.
Steady, matey. Move it around.
Oh, he almost had it then.
Looks like he's done for, this time.
Don't just stand there!
Head it in!
Stop that ball!
Goal.
Game's over. I win.
Ah, let me give you a hand, matey.
That's quite all right, Your Majesty.
Thank you, so much.
Oh, please, let me help you on
with your robe.
Why, yes. Thank you. Thank you. Yes.
- Can't have you cold, Sire. Can we?
- Why, no, no.
Have you ever heard of something
called "the gypsy switch"?
No.
Can't say that I have.
Remind me to tell you
about it sometime.
I can't tell you when
we've had such a good time.
We'll carry the memory of Your Majesty
in our hearts for a long while.
I think it's time to leave.
Aye. Must you go?
We must be dashing.
Marvelous game.
Lovely to see you. Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
- Come, children.
Friendly lot.
Don't mind them visiting.
Wouldn't want them living here!
Come along, children.
Come on, children. Hurry up.
Stop gibbering.
What's the matter with you?
Your royal star!
They've stolen your royal star.
Don't be ridiculous.
What do you think this is?
Why didn't you
say so?
All right, Paul,
put the knob on the bed.
At last, the magic words.
I'll keep it. Women always lose things.
Hurry, Paul, the knob.
It's stuck!
I suppose I should do something.
Please do. Quick!
Got it.
Oh, bother! I do hate shoddy work.
I don't suppose I shall ever
get used to this thing.
Children, will you push the bed
back into place, please.
I think we could all do
with a nice cup of tea.
Oh, no time for that.
I've gone to a lot of trouble
to find this spell.
I'm going to try it immediately.
Mr. Browne, kindly let me
have your shoes, please.
My shoe? Oh, fine.
What's the shoes for?
Really, Charles,
if you had been paying attention,
I should think you'd be aware
that substitutiary locomotion is the art
of causing inanimate objects
to take on a life force of their own.
Obviously, I must have
inanimate objects to experiment with.
Makes sense, don't it?
Stand back, everyone.
I need plenty of room.
I want you all to be absolutely quiet.
Mr. Browne,
- you have the star of Astoroth, I believe.
- Oh, yes.
It's in my nice, clean hanky.
It's all right, Mr. Browne.
I should have realized that it
would be quite impossible
to take an object from
one world into another.
If only I would have had the sense
to remember the words on that star.
I know the words, Miss Price.
Don't bother Miss Price. She's thinking.
Charlie, why don't you and I
nip down to the village
and get something for supper.
And I might conceivably call into
the pub for a pint to steady my nerves.
- Trebonna?
- I do know the words, Miss Price.
Come along.
- How can you know the words?
- Frebunna?
Troop movements,
and massing of barges
in French and Dutch channel ports.
The prime minister
has told the nation
to be on the alert
for signs of a possible invasion.
That was the news...
To think I might have been able
to do something about all this.
It's out of your hands now, my dear.
If only I could have
remembered those words.
It's maddening!
Why don't someone ask me?
Come off it, Paul.
You can't remember
those kind of words.
You mean like...
How do you know that?
Easy.
Says right here in me book.
You mean, it was there in your book
all the time?
Yes, but nobody ever listens to me.
Nothing happened!
Am I doing something wrong?
Well, to tell you the truth,
it does seem a bit old fashioned.
After all, we are in the 20th century.
What do you suggest?
Well, it needs rhythm, tempo, music.
As I always say, "Do it with a flair."
- Do you mind if I have a go?
- Oh, of course not.
Now, come along, you lot.
We need all the help we can get.
Substitutiary locomotion
Mystic power that's far
beyond the wildest notion
It's so weird so feared
And yet wonderful to see
Substitutiary locomotion come to me
Shh!
Now.
Cor!
I don't want
locomotiary substitution
or remote intransitory convolution
Only one precise
solution is the key
Substitutiary locomotion it must be
Treguna, mekoides
and trecorum, satis, dee
Oh!
Substitutiary locomotion
Lovely substitutiary locomotion
You've made substitutiary history
With Treguna, mekoides
and a little help from me
With Treguna, mekoides and
Trecorum, satis, dee
Lummy!
Mr. Browne, what is going on here?
I haven't the foggiest.
How do you do?
Oh, shall we?
That's my nightgown!
Is it really, my dear?
Yes, and I'm not responsible
for its behavior.
Obviously not, my dear.
Paul, what on earth are you doing?
Having a jolly good time, that's what!
- How can we stop all this?
- Must we? It's really most agreeable.
Yes, but we must do something!
Didn't I give you
my all-purpose, cut-off spell?
- Lesson number eight.
- Number eight.
Yes, number eight, I think it was.
Oye! Me Sunday trousers!
Buzz off, old chap.
Find your own dancing partner. Oh!
Ow!
Be careful, Carrie, slow down.
Charles!
Mr. Browne, will you please
control your shoes?
Dear lady, I very much fear
that we have nothing under control.
Do you mind?
Now, who would like some more
of my lovely sausages and mash?
No more for me, thank you.
Oh, Carrie?
It's very good,
but I've already had two helpings.
I'm full.
Me, too.
Well, at least somebody wants some.
Cheer up, my dear.
This should be
something of a celebration.
I'm sorry.
There doesn't seem
to be much to celebrate.
I still haven't mastered that spell.
Of course you have! You just need
a little more practice, that's all.
Do you really think so?
No doubt about it.
Meantime, there's nothing
to liven the spirits
like a little masterjuggling.
Right, Charlie?
Go on, then, guv.
Give us some juggling.
Very few better than me at this.
All you need is 20 years practice,
and a touch of genius.
Never happened to me before.
I don't usually juggle
with cats under my feet.
Look, she's laughing.
Oh!
Oh, Mrs. Hobday, do come in.
Oh, I can't stop, my dear.
I just come by
to bring you the good news.
- Good news?
- Yes, yes. Mr. Bisselthwaite,
who brings the milk, you know?
Well, he's promised
to take the children in.
He and his wife have got that farm,
just the place for growing children.
Put a bit of color back in their cheeks.
Why? What's the matter?
I thought you'd be pleased.
You told me yourself
that you were much too busy.
You have no time
to take care of children.
Circumstances have changed,
somewhat.
That's right.
We got a dad now, Mr. Browne.
Paul.
Miss Price, is this true?
Of course.
You do want him to stay with us,
don't you, Miss Price?
I suppose I hadn't really
thought about it.
What about him?
What do you say
about it, Mr. Browne?
Well...
It's all rather sudden.
I don't quite know what to say.
Then I'll leave you two to talk it over.
Oh, I'll come back in the morning.
Yes. Good night.
- Good night.
It is true, Mr. Browne,
you are going to be
our father now, aren't you?
Well, we...
We are rather rushing
things, aren't we?
Perhaps Mr. Browne has other things
besides you children to think about?
Yes, as a matter of fact,
I should have left ages ago.
I... I must get a train
back to London tonight.
It's rather an important matter,
as a matter of fact.
I'd like to tell you about it,
but it's a little bit hush-hush, you know.
Sort of a secret.
Well, uh, if...
If I've been any sort of help to you,
I'm pleased.
You've been immensely kind.
Thank you.
I've enjoyed being with you.
Perhaps it's been good for all of us.
Will you be coming back?
Someday, my dear.
I, uh, certainly hope
that we shall meet again.
Someday, when all
this war business is over.
I see.
And then, perhaps,
I shall realize my fondest dream,
"Eglantine and Emelius,
illusionists extraordinary."
Just think how
that will look on the poster, huh?
The children are going to miss you.
Do you really think they will?
Yes.
Well, I shall miss you, all of you.
If I don't go now,
you might never get rid of me.
Goodbye, Carrie.
Must you really go?
I think it's best for everybody.
Goodbye, Paul.
I still think you should be our father.
Goodbye, Charlie.
Do you want me
to come down to the station with you?
No. No.
No, you stay here
and look after everybody.
Goodbye, Miss Price.
Goodbye, Mr. Browne.
When is the next train
to London, please?
Lord bless you, sir.
There ain't no train.
Nothing till milk job,
4:00 a.m. tomorrow morning.
Do you mind if I wait in here?
You suit yourself. Good night, sir.
Good night.
Out you go, Cosmic.
Hello? Hello?
Hello!
Emelius Browne.
Do you know
you could be warm and cozy
in that house at this very moment?
For once in your useless life
you really seem to have been needed.
You're a failure, Emelius Browne.
And a coward.
No, Fraulein, this is not the invasion,
just a little exercise,
a minor raid to induce panic,
and to spread a little mischief.
When you English
get it through you head,
that the German forces can land at will
wherever and whenever we please,
perhaps you will consider
a reasonable peace.
Not bloody likely!
Go on, Miss Price. Do it to him.
I must say, it's very tempting.
Colonel, how would you feel
about being turned
into a nice, white rabbit?
I said, "How would you feel
about being turned
"into a nice, white rabbit?"
Be quiet, please!
Not again?
Your memory, Miss Price.
Charles, would you kindly fetch my
notebook from the workroom, please.
Right-o.
Let him go!
Silence!
Fraulein, we have work to do.
I am sorry, but I must send
all of you someplace
where you will no longer be a nuisance.
As the words tell the tune
and the moonbeams the moon
all I need to succeed in my plan
is a champion rare
with a flourish and a flair
Eglantine.
Where is the spell for rabbits?
"Easiest of all," she says.
Confound it! Can't women ever learn
to file things properly?
There it is.
That's it!
Uh...
Now, come along, my boy.
Just for once in your life,
you've got to believe in something.
That's it.
Good lad.
Now what's the use
of putting the children and me
in that drafty castle?
It's quite chilly.
Because, Fraulein,
the colonel believes
when the British female
decides to become a nuisance,
she can become the greatest
nuisance in the world.
And I'm inclined to agree with him.
You need a lesson
in manners, Sergeant.
If I only had my notebook,
I'd make certain you'd learn a few.
Jumping Jehoshaphat, more Jerries.
Take it easy, can't you?
Try holding your breath.
I am holding it.
We could strip him down
and grease him with soap.
No, it's no good.
He can't do it.
I could've told you
that in the first place.
If we can't get Paul
out to give the alarm,
we'll just have to think
of something else.
What about that spell
that makes things move about?
Oh, but I need weapons.
How about all these things?
I'm afraid they're a bit ancient.
Where did this come from?
It's Mr. Browne. That's who it is.
He's on his way to London.
Mr. Browne?
If you are Mr. Browne,
would you be kind enough
to get down off my lap?
It is Mr. Browne!
It is you!
You didn't think
that I could do that spell, did you?
I am glad to see you!
What about all these Germans?
Well, as Charlie says,
"What's wrong
with the substitutiary locomotion spell?"
That ought to be useful.
No, but it isn't ready, yet.
You saw what happened this afternoon.
Well, we have to chance it.
We can't let these so-and-sos get away
with their beastly little raid.
Mr. Browne,
won't you get up off the floor,
and we'll go to work.
Herr Oberst!
- Jolly good luck, my dear.
- Thank you, Emelius.
Let's hope you haven't
forgotten the spell, Miss Price.
Oh, not this time, Charlie.
Found this in the castle.
Probably not a magic broom,
but it might make you feel
more at home.
Well, thank you, Carrie.
That was very thoughtful of you.
Come now, children.
Let's get out of Miss Price's way.
Look.
Sound the advance!
Just in time for the kickoff.
Steady on the left.
Victory for England and Saint George!
Like the Lord Mayor's show.
Pikemen, hold your distance.
Fire!
Blimey!
Where's it coming from, Sergeant?
Sounds like the sea road, sir.
- Come on, lads. After me!
- Come on.
Good shooting, bowmen!
Well caught, sir! Very good.
Knock his block off! That's it!
Mr. Browne, make those children
take cover this instant!
Are you still there, Colonel?
I thought you'd be on your way by now.
You see? Things may not be so easy
for you, after all.
Goodbye, Colonel.
- Eglantine, oh, Eglantine.
- Dear Mr. Browne.
Miss Price,
we thought they'd damaged you.
See? No one can hurt Miss Price.
There they are, lads.
I sensed something was afoot.
All right, drive them into the sea.
Firing positions, you fellas. Both sides.
All right, men, hold your fire.
I think we've taught the Hun a lesson.
He'll think twice
before coming back here again.
It's tragic. All your spells,
your equipment, all gone.
Still, I was able
to perform some small service first.
That mean you ain't going
to be a witch no more?
Never?
No, Paul.
I realized some time ago
that I could never be a proper witch.
When was that?
Was it that first magic moment
when you laid eyes on me?
No, it was the day
my poisoned dragon's liver arrived.
I knew then that anyone
who felt the way I did
about poisoned dragon's liver,
had no business being a witch.
You're certain
you're doing the right thing?
Well, I think so.
The way things are, it's much
too dangerous being a civilian.
Take care of yourself, guv.
I'll do that.
And I'll be back
before you've grown an inch taller.
We'll be together again.
Sounds like you have an escort
to the station.
Parade, halt!
Well, here we go.
Permission to move off, sir!
Carry on, Sergeant.
Parade, by the right, quick!
March! Left, left. Left, right, left.
Suppose that's it.
We ain't going to have no fun no more.
Well, still got this, ain't I?
Call out the navy
Call out the ranks
Call out the air force
Call out the tanks
From the Cliffs of Dover
call up the Gauls
And don't forget the
loyal territorials
Who's digging in here?
Who will defend
every inch of England
no matter what they send?
Who's standing firm
in our own front yard?
The soldiers of
the old home guard
That's who
The soldiers of
the old home guard