¶ I keep busy
takin' life easy ¶
¶ Livin' one day at a time ¶
¶ Ain't it something,
happy with nothing ¶
¶ Livin' one day at a time ¶
¶ Don't worry about tomorrow ¶
¶ 'Cause I don't care ¶
¶ Long as I got
that great big sun ¶
¶ High up there ¶
¶ I'm admittin',
like to be sittin' ¶
¶ Watching
the world go along ¶
¶ Don't need money,
isn't it funny ¶
¶ Give me a smile
and a song ¶
¶ It doesn't matter
if I don't have a dime ¶
¶ I keep busy
takin' life easy ¶
¶ Livin' one day at a time ¶
Dear.
Hmm? What?
Summer's going to be gone
before we know it.
We still haven't decided
what Leonora's going
to do this fall.
Go to college or what?
What do you think, dear?
I think if business
doesn't pick up,
I'm going to have
to put on some kind
of a sale or something.
Charles, are you talking
about the store again?
Of course, I was
talking about the store.
I don't think I had
five customers today.
But what about Leonora?
What about her?
Well, I just
got through sa--
Charles, look.
Look, look.
A shooting star.
Charles.
I see it, Nettie.
It-- It pointed
right at you.
Do you think
that means something?
Oh, come on, Nettie.
Star!
Where's the star?
Well, it's gone now.
It went down over behind
the Methodist church.
It shone right on
your father.
Make a wish, Mom.
Oh, well, uh--
Leonora:
I know what I wish.
I wish that
someday I'll have
a beautiful wedding
with pink flowers.
You didn't see
the star, Leonora.
Pop saw it.
So what do you wish, Pop?
[buzzing]
I wish these mosquitoes
would let me alone.
Go on, Mom,
make a wish.
I wish...
No, I'm not gonna tell.
Come on, Ma.
Just tell us.
Please.
I wish...
we could all
go to Chicago
and see the World's Fair.
What an idea!
- Yeah, Dad, how about it?
- Dad, please?
- Come on.
- Could we, please?
How I'd love to see that.
Oh, Charles,
do you think we--
No, I guess not.
Daddy, why are you
so dead set against
taking Mom on a nice trip?
Leonora, if there's one thing
that's a bigger waste
of time and money than a fair,
I haven't heard of it.
Besides, there's
a depression on, you know.
Don't these wishes
ever come true, Pop?
Rupert, there's only
one way to get things
in this world,
and that's
to work for them.
I think we ought to go in
before these mosquitoes
eat us alive.
What do you think
you're doing, nutty?
I'm wishing for
Mom's wish to come true.
Didn't you hear
what Pops said about
that wishing junk?
Well, I don't care.
Maybe he doesn't think
about such things.
All he knows is work.
Good night, boys.
Good night, Pop.
Good morning, ladies.
Yoo-hoo, Mr. Appleby.
Oh, good morning,
Miss Partridge.
Good morning.
Now, Pierre,
you be a gentleman.
I don't ever recall
you having a sale
before, Mr. Appleby.
Well, that's true,
Miss Partridge.
But we've never had times
like these before, either.
Oh, so true.
So very true.
Now, let me see
if I understand
this sale correctly.
I could buy this little
green tea pot for, uh--
For the regular price:
$2.00.
And then I would
get the orange one
for just a penny?
That's right.
$2.00 for the green one
and just one cent
for the orange one.
Oh, that's very good.
That is a very
ingenious sale.
That's $2.00,
and one cent.
Oh, dear.
Something wrong,
Miss Partridge?
Uh, the green one
is chipped.
Do you see that,
Mr. Appleby?
Oh, it is a little
chipped, isn't it?
Maybe I can
find another one.
Oh, no, no.
Please don't bother.
I'll just
take the orange one.
And here's your penny.
Good day, Mr. Appleby.
Come along, Pierre.
Miss Partridge.
That isn't exactly
the way it works.
- Miss Pa--
- [telephone rings]
Come on, Rupe.
It's time for it right now.
Come on!
Radio Announcer:
"The Romance
of Helen Trent."
The woman who proves
that romance can come
even after 35.
[changes stations]
Second Radio Announcer:
Ha ha ha!
Yes, sir.
We ready, boys and girls?
We don't have much time.
Today, Captain Bob
was gonna tell you
how to finish
your Captain Bob kite.
Yesterday, we fastened
our sticks together
and tied our string
all around the frame.
Now then,
how many of you
have your flour
and water paste all mixed?
Neatly, of course.
Put your hand down, Rupert.
That's fine.
Now spread your paper
out on a table.
Table, table.
Any old table
will do, of course.
Or the floor
would do even better.
I hope you remembered
to take my advice
about using tissue paper,
and not wrapping paper.
Darn it.
Come on, go, Rupe.
Go find
some tissue paper.
I don't know
where any is at.
Just find some!
However, if some of you
don't happen to have
any tissue paper
around the house,
I would suggest
you go right ahead
and use ordinary
wrapping paper.
Don't eat that, Jigs.
That's glue.
Now take a good,
sharp pencil,
and then lay your frame
on the tissue paper
or wrapping paper...
Pencil, where's
the pencil?
...and draw a line
all around it...
Hurry, come on.
The pencil. Get it.
Have you got that done?
No!
Good.
[laughs]
Now take
your little scissors,
but be very careful
not to cut yourself.
- Pencil.
- Here.
I said pencil!
- Well, he said scissors.
- Forget it.
Captain Bob
wouldn't like that.
So take your scissors,
and cut along the lines,
keeping a good straight edge.
Busted.
Take your time so you
do a nice, neat job
like Captain Bob
wants you to do. Yes, sir.
Are you finished cutting?
No!
Wonderful. And now
it's time to paste.
Wait, we haven't
finished cutting!
Oh, my, that's
the most fun of all.
You're getting it
all over me!
Well, he said paste.
...or Mother will be
mad at Captain Bob,
and we don't want that, do we?
No, sir. Oh, brother.
Rupert!
Now spread a thin layer
of your paste
along the edges
very carefully.
That's it.
Now fold the edges
over the strings,
press firmly, and kazaam!
There's your Captain Bob
kite all finished.
Now, wasn't that easy?
[laughs]
Okay, now, boys and girls,
let's get to those birthdays.
Jigs, no!
Happy birthday
to Randy Feckstetter...
Boy, are we in trouble.
...Timmy Grossman,
Eloise Ludwig...
Jigs!
What are we gonna do?
Boy, are we gonna get it
when Mom gets back.
Let's clean up this place.
Hurry up.
My stars.
What are you doing?
Making a kite, Mom.
A kite?
It looks like a tornado.
Jigs. Jigs,
get off there.
Get off there.
Get off!
Look at your father's chair.
Oh, thank goodness
he's not coming home
this evening.
You, get this mess
cleaned up. Jump!
Well, this
wouldn't have happened
if Pop would help us
build a kite
like Frankie Gosset's
dad did for him.
Don't blame it
on someone else.
[telephone rings]
- What a mess.
- I'll get it.
[rings]
Hello?
Oh, Leonora?
Just a minute,
I'll check and see
if she's here.
- Mom, I'm here.
- Shh. It's Ray Ferris.
You don't want
to talk to him.
How do you
know I don't?
Your father
doesn't like him.
When did Daddy say that?
He doesn't even know Ray.
Well, if he did,
he wouldn't like him.
Mother.
Hello, Ray?
Well, this evening?
Oh, nothing much.
Why don't you come over?
Leonora, shh-shh.
No, no.
Just a sec.
What's the matter now?
- Derwood.
- What?
Derwood is coming over
to see you this evening.
That doesn't matter.
Ray, listen.
You don't mind
if Derwood's coming over
tonight, do you?
Oh, you do.
Oh, don't be silly, Ray.
Don't be silly.
That's silly.
Silly is right.
Okay, cookie.
See you later. Bye-bye.
What's so wrong with Ray?
I think he's cute.
I went with a boy
who was cute once.
So, what happened?
I married him.
[horn honks]
Why don't you learn to drive!
Think they own the road.
[horn honks]
What are you,
some kind of a cat
with nine lives?
What?
You are number 476-9W-14,
aren't you?
I don't know who you are
or what you're talking about,
so will you just
get off my car?
I've had enough
trouble today.
Now will you please
get off my car?
What's the matter
with you, you loony bird?
What's the idea
of blocking the alley?
Don't ask me, ask him.
Ask, uh--
Oh, you better
go sober up, buddy,
or they're gonna slap you
in the booby hatch.
You'd better
get off of there
because I have to go
to a lodge meeting.
Oh, no.
You have to come with me.
You'd better hang on.
[whistles]
Sorry you're gonna
have to miss lodge, Charley.
How do you know my name?
No big deal.
Your basic facts
are all here.
Meerschaum, hey?
I had one like this.
You mind if I try it?
Got a match, Charley?
- Well, uh--
- Never mind.
[horn honks]
Hey!
Look at that.
Will you cut out
this bunk?
Who are you anyway?
Don't you know?
I'm your angel.
Oh, come on.
You expect me
to believe that?
Frankly, no.
It looks like
the only thing
you believe in
is your cash register.
If your life actually
has been as dull as this,
you're probably glad
it's over.
What do you mean, over?
Your number is up, Chum.
What?
I'm perfectly healthy.
We get lots
of healthy ones.
In fact, if you had been
standing an inch closer,
that sledgehammer
would have worked.
The sle--
Did you do that?
Oh, no.
My job is just
to deliver you.
Well, now, wait a minute.
You can't deliver me.
I'm not dead yet.
You got a point there, kid.
Look, I don't believe
my number's up.
And I don't believe
you're an angel.
You don't even
look like one.
Oh, Charley.
You're such a pain.
All right,
look over there.
Satisfied?
Now then, let's get down
to cases, Charley.
We know your number
is up, so--
Look, I can't
go with you now.
I'm not ready.
You birds never are.
Well, I've got to have
more time.
More time?
Are you kidding?
You never learned how to use
the time you've already had.
What do you mean?
I've always made a good
living for my family.
You call that living?
Well, I couldn't afford
to do all those
exciting things.
How expensive is it
to go out and play
ball with the kids?
Would a 50 cent
bottle of cologne
for your wife break you?
That's all
well and good--
As far as I know,
there's no charge at all
for a good sunset.
All you have to do
is take time to look at it.
Uh, wait a minute.
Where are you going?
This thing is so fouled up,
I gotta go back
and find out when and how
they're gonna take you.
They've already
tried three times.
Isn't that enough?
Look, kid, when
your number's up, it's up.
I've got to have more time.
There's so many things
I have to do.
Well, you've got
one thing in your favor.
You're still here.
Wait. What do I do
in the meantime?
If I were you,
I'd drive
more carefully.
Hello, dear.
[gasps]
Charles.
What are you
doing home?
I thought I'd
surprise you, honey.
Oh, you scared me
half out of my wits.
The lodge hall burn down?
Not that I know of.
Here.
Oh, where did you
find those?
I didn't find them,
I bought them.
For you.
For me?
Why, what have you done?
I haven't done
anything, Nettie.
Is it against the law
for a man to buy his wife
a few flowers?
No, no.
Of course not.
They're lovely.
Thank you.
All right, Charles.
What happened?
Why aren't you
at the lodge?
I decided not to go.
I'd rather spend the time
here with my family.
Nettie, have you seen
the sunset out there?
- The sunset?
- It's really something.
Come on out on the porch
and look at it with me.
Charles--
Would you look
at that sky, Nettie?
What colors, huh?
Makes you feel like, well,
like there's something
important going on
up there, doesn't it?
Yes.
A man should take the time
to appreciate things like this.
Before it's too late.
What do you mean,
too late?
Oh, nothing.
But we just never know
what might be around
the corner for us
in this great scheme
of life.
Charles...
let me smell your breath.
Come on, Nettie.
You know me better than that.
Well, let's go in.
I'm hungry.
We better get a man to fix
that screen door tomorrow.
You've been saying
that for months.
But this time I mean it.
No more putting it off.
In fact, I'm going
to have the whole place
fixed up for you.
I'll go and get washed up.
Just a minute, Rupert.
I don't think
we've said grace yet.
Grace? You, Daddy?
Well, of course.
Dear God, thank you
for this food and all.
Take care of us
in the days ahead.
And speaking of
the days ahead,
if you could
see your way clear
to stretching them
out a little, I'd sure--
We'd sure appreciate it.
Amen.
Well, now, what
did you boys do today?
We didn't
do anything. Honest.
Well, I wasn't accusing you.
I was just interested,
that's all.
It was really Jigs' fault
that the paste--
Everything was just fine.
Today, just fine.
Eat your
vegetables, Rupert.
How would you all like
to go to the movies tonight?
The whole family?
How does that sound?
Tonight?
I don't know what's playing,
but I know it's bank night,
so maybe we can
pick up a little money.
Oh, well, maybe
tomorrow night, huh?
Well, I might not be able
to make it tomorrow night.
Oh, well, I sort of
have a date with
Derwood tonight.
- Oh.
- And Ray, also.
You have a date
with two boys?
You'll never get a husband
that way, Leonora.
Who said I was
looking for one?
[car horn honks]
Oh, that must
be Derwood.
Sorry, Daddy.
Maybe some other time.
Well, you haven't
finished your dinner.
I'll be late.
[honks]
I know Derwood, but who's
the other fellow she mentioned?
Oh, Ray.
Ferris.
Who's Ray Ferris?
[other car horn honks]
[honks]
That'll give you an idea
of who he is.
- You ready to go?
- Uh...
Great.
See you later, Derwood.
[engine doesn't start]
Well, that doesn't mean
the rest of us
can't go, right boys?
Um...
to the movies,
did you say, Pop?
Weren't you
listening, Willie?
Boy: Willie, Rupert,
come on, let's go!
Go?
Go where?
Oh, no place, really.
We sort of promised
Frankie Gosset
that we'd go
along with him.
You're going
no place with Frankie?
Frankie:
Hurry up, guys!
Dad's waiting to take
us to the movies!
Okay, Frankie.
We'll be right there.
You're--
You're going to the movies
with Frankie's dad?
Yeah, he takes us
lots of places.
He's a keen guy.
Excuse us.
See you later, Pop.
Yeah.
Well, Nettie, old girl,
I guess it looks like
it's down to
just the two of us, huh?
Dear, maybe
you could still get
to part of
your lodge meeting.
You mean you have
some place to go, too?
Only to Clara's.
Well, can't you
go to your sister's
some other night?
Uh, not really.
On Thursday nights,
I'm always a fourth.
A fourth what?
A fourth.
At bridge.
- Oh.
- Just leave everything, dear.
I'll do the dishes
as soon as I get home.
I'm running a little
behind schedule.
Bye-bye.
[whines]
Hello, Jigs.
Well, we have a few
leftovers for you.
By the way,
are you busy tonight?
The first thing
I want you to do, Pete,
is fix that
back screen door.
I want the whole place
put in top shape.
You think you can
handle that?
More than likely.
And I may want
the house painted.
Can you paint a house?
What color?
What difference
does that make?
Could make a lot.
Say I painted it orange,
and you wanted it purple.
I want it the way it is.
Then why paint it?
I mean, I want it
the color it is.
Well, it's your house.
This is wild.
After all these years,
he's actually
fixing the place up.
What's come over Daddy, Mom?
I wish I knew.
Oh, Pete, it seems to me
I've heard some rumors.
Tell me,
are you a drinker?
Thanks, but not now.
It's too early.
I don't want to catch you
drinking on the job.
Oh, you won't.
If I feel like drinking,
I stop working.
All this to catch
a poor little fish.
Zowie.
Whoops.
Sorry, Charley.
So, it's you,
the pipe filcher.
Tell me,
what did you find out?
What are they
going to do with me?
I don't know.
Boy, they're sure
making better reels
than back in my day.
You don't know?
What kind of an outfit
are they running up there?
Right now,
a confused one, kid.
Why? What's the jam-up?
They don't
tell me anything,
but near as I can figure,
someone up there thinks
you're worth salvaging.
Yeah?
Why, I don't know.
But at least that's why
you're still alive.
Then I do have
a chance for more time?
I wouldn't bank on it, kid.
Not with your record.
Look, if you're
really my angel, help me.
I mean, tell me what I can
do to improve my chances.
That's for you to learn,
but whatever you do,
I'd sure do it
in a hurry.
Would I have time
to take Nettie
and the kids
to the World's Fair?
Oh, come on.
You know you don't
really intend to do that.
How do you
know I don't?
I suppose
the minute I'm gone,
you're gonna march
right over to the bank
and draw out money
for the trip.
Well, I can't
very well leave
the store right now.
Oh, of course not.
I'll be seeing you.
Now, wait
a minute, angel.
Look, I feel kind of silly
calling you "angel".
What's your name?
Oh, I wouldn't remember that.
You don't remember
your own name?
No, you see,
those earthly things
sort of fade away.
Oh, sometimes you get
flashes of the old life.
A tennis game
with a strawberry blond.
A line from an old song.
How old
are you anyway?
Well, maybe this
will give you some idea.
[plays like a ukulele]
¶ Hello, my baby,
hello, my honey ¶
¶ Hello, my ragtime gal ¶
¶ Send me a kiss by wire ¶
¶ Baby, my hearts on fire ¶
¶ If you refuse me,
honey, you-- ¶
Oh, Roy Zerney.
- What?
- That was my name.
Roy Zerney.
Sort of popped in.
Sounds kind of
silly now.
¶ Hello, Roy Zerney ¶
¶ Let's go,
my ragtime gal ¶
[pots chime like bells]
¶ Send me a kiss by wire ¶
¶ If you refuse me,
honey, you lose me ¶
¶ Then you'll be
left alone ¶
¶ Oh, baby, telephone ¶
¶ And tell me
I'm your own ¶
¶ Tell me, tell me,
dumpty-dum ¶
Roy: I suppose
the minute I'm gone,
you're gonna march
right over to the bank
and draw out money
for the trip.
[people shouting]
Hey, give us
our money!
- Robbers!
- Crooks!
- The bank's busted!
- I want my money!
They won't
give us our money!
[shouting]
What's happened?
What's going on here?
- Bank's closed!
- The bank's busted!
All my savings
are gone!
We can't
get our money!
Give us our money!
Ernie, open up.
It's Appleby.
I've got to
talk to you.
[knocking]
Ernie,
it's important!
I can't talk
to you now, Charley.
Ernie. Ernie, I've got
to have some of my money.
There's nothing I can--
Look, you're putting me
in an awful spot.
Do you think I'm having
a picnic in here?
Now, look, Ernie,
if you hadn't talked me
out of putting
my money in bonds--
I'm sorry about that.
You knew this was
going to happen.
Charley, I am going
to try and get
the bank open again
just as soon as I can.
Well, how soon?
Well, I don't know.
It'll be a few weeks
or months.
A month?
I can't wait a month.
You'll have to,
just like everybody else.
But, Ernie,
you don't understand.
I-- I may not be
around here too long.
From the sound
of that crowd out there,
I may not be around
too long, either.
Ernie--
Watch out
for the string, Pop.
What are you trying to do,
set a booby trap for me?
No, we're making
a telephone with Frankie.
- Oh.
- His pop showed us how.
Oh, he did, huh?
Yeah, he teaches us
lots of things.
Oh.
I wish you fellas
would keep your bicycles
out of the driveway.
Yoo-hoo, Charles!
Don't walk under the ladder.
You might have bad luck.
I might?
That's a hot one.
Boy.
Nettie:
Oh, did you notice?
Pete started painting
the house today.
Looks more like
he's painting the windows.
I guess I'm going
to have to let him go.
Oh, no, no.
You can't do that.
Nettie, didn't you hear about
the bank closing today?
Well, that's exactly why
you can't let him go.
What kind of logic is that?
Well, I had to loan
poor Pete $100.
You what?
Well, he needed it
because he said
his cash was all
tied up at the bank.
His cash?
I'll bet he's never
had a bank account
in his life.
Well, anyhow,
the only way
he can pay it back
is to work it off.
Nettie, when you
have to start handling
your own finances--
No, I don't intend to.
Well, you may have to.
Sooner than you think.
Testing.
Good evening.
I'll do the talking.
You just hold it.
Testing.
Good evening, Mister
and Missus America,
and all
the ships at sea.
Let's go to press.
Frankie, could
you hear me?
Frankie:
No! Talk louder!
What?
When I'm ready for the song,
I'll signal you like this.
You're supposed
to hold it.
And don't forget the money.
Okay, Frankie,
we won't forget.
Hey, listen,
when Pop comes in,
you gotta ask him.
Why don't you ask him?
Because you're littler.
All right, Willie,
what did you
want to ask me?
Oh, uh, we need
two bucks, Papa.
Two bucks?
When I was your age,
I had to work
a week for that.
What do you
want it for?
Uh...
It's for a surprise.
Oh. I'm glad you brought up
the subject of money,
because it's something
I've been wanting
to talk to you about.
Come over here
and sit down,
will you?
Pop, we gotta practice
a song that we're gonna
sing on a telephone.
Well, that
will wait, Willie.
Just sit down.
You know, boys, I'm--
Well, I'm not always
going to be around for you
to run to whenever
you need money.
So I think you should
start earning your own,
learning the value
of a dollar.
[doorbell rings]
Now, don't go away.
I'm not through.
[rings]
Mr. Appleby?
- Yes?
- I'm Ray Ferris.
Oh, you're--
Is Leonora in?
No, I'm afraid not.
She's, uh--
Well, she's gone out
with Derwood.
Oh. Where'd they go,
that miniature golf place?
Well, it's pretty hard
to keep track
of where young people
go these days.
Yeah.
Well, thanks.
Ray?
I think you should know,
Leonora's going steady
with a substantial young man,
and I think we should
leave it that way.
I can't say as Leonora
gave me that impression.
- Well, she wouldn't.
- In fact, she told me--
Do you have a job?
Well, no, sir.
Not at the moment.
Well, there, you see?
Things are kind of tough
right now,
but I'm willing to work
at anything I can get.
Uh-huh. Well, good luck
at it, Ray.
It's been
nice knowing you.
Mr. Appleby?
I don't
give up easily.
Now, let's see.
We were talking about
getting jobs, weren't we?
Yes, sir.
Here, Pop.
What's this?
It's for you.
"To our Dad,
Happy Father's Day."
Well, that's right.
Sunday is Father's Day,
isn't it?
We just thought we'd
give it to you today.
You made this yourself, huh?
Yeah, we made it
at school.
Thanks, boys.
Thanks very much.
Hey, kids.
You guys get ready.
I'll give you
the signal when to start.
Okay, Frankie.
Pop, we promise
that we'll look for jobs,
but right now, we gotta
practice this song.
Come on, Rupert.
He's ready.
¶ Happy Father's Day to you ¶
¶ Happy Father's Day,
Mr. Gosset ¶
¶ Happy Father's Day to you ¶
Oh, about that money, Pop.
Oh, yeah.
I guess I can
see my way clear to--
We're chipping in
with Frankie for his dad.
Because he's been
so nice to us.
Uh-huh.
Well...
- Thanks, Pop.
- Yeah, thanks.
Happy Father's Day,
Mr. Gosset.
[rooster crows]
Leonora, I really
ought to go home.
You can't go until
I put something
on your poor eye.
It'll be okay.
That big bully Derwood.
I never knew he had
a temper like that.
Let's not talk
about him, all right?
I never want
to see him again.
Ray:
Shh.
Just don't talk.
[Charley mumbles]
[gasps]
It's Daddy!
You better go.
Wait, wait, wait.
Ray?
What are you doing here?
I just brought
Leonora home.
What time is it?
It's 5 o'clock
in the morning.
- 5 o'clock?
- 5 o'clock.
How did you
get the shiner?
Oh, Derwood and I just
had a little scuffle.
That took all night?
Oh, no, no, no.
Leonora and I just
stopped off
at this little place
on the way home.
What little place?
Sadie's Place.
Sadie's? That's a roadhouse.
A bootleg joint.
Well, it's the only
place in town
where you can dance.
Ray, if that's
the kind of a place
you're going
to take my daughter,
I don't want you going out
with her anymore.
Mr. Appleby, we weren't
doing anything wrong.
We just enjoy
being together.
Well, don't you remember
when you were young,
how important
it was to, well,
to have someone
care for you,
and to be with them?
You think that's only
important to the young, huh?
Well...
Maybe when people
get older, they just
don't think about
such things.
I guess I better go now.
Mr. Appleby,
I love your daughter.
Nettie:
Charles, aren't you
ever coming to bed?
I'll be up
in a minute, Nettie.
Good morning, Charlie.
Roy.
Now where did you go?
[whistling]
What are you doing
in there, Roy?
Taking a bath.
First tub I ever saw
with a faucet way up there.
That's a shower.
You just stand
in front of it,
let it squirt on you.
Well, what did they
decide up about me, Roy?
They're still arguing.
A couple of 'em
are on the fence,
but most of them think
you're getting nowhere fast.
Well, they can
say that again.
The more I try,
the worse I mess things up.
My wife suspects
everything I do,
my daughter's
ruining her chances
for a good marriage,
and the boys
have thrown me over
for a substitute father.
Yeah, it's tough.
I wish to heck
you could get more time.
I'd like to see you
win this thing, kid.
You would?
I didn't know
you were on my side.
I wasn't at first,
with your record and all,
but I don't know,
I guess I always was
for the underdog,
and right now I'd say
you're the underest dog I know.
Yeah.
Then you'll really
get in there
and pitch for me,
huh, Roy?
I need help
from somewhere.
[knocking]
Charles?
Yes, Nettie?
Is someone
in there with you?
What kind of a ridiculous
question is that, Nettie?
It sounded like you were
talking to somebody.
It did?
I guess I must've been
talking to myself.
Oh?
When did you
start doing that?
Uh, Nettie,
would you mind
if I finished shaving?
I've got to get
to work, you know.
Oh, yes. Yes, dear.
Of course.
Charles.
What?
Charles, Charles.
Will you ever learn
to pick up your things?
It seems to me
I've just been picking up
after you all my life.
You kids
want to work, huh?
Well, first thing
I want you to do
is clear all this
junk out of here.
Just stack it off
to the sides.
I want room
so I can move cars
in and out of here.
You got that?
Move all this?
You said you wanted a job.
Take it or leave it.
Pays ten cents an hour.
We'll take it.
Okay.
I'll keep track
of your time.
Let's have an honest
day's work now, huh?
How are we supposed to learn
the value of a dollar
if we only make ten cents?
Work overtime,
I guess.
Come on, we better
get this started.
Rupe, grab
the other end.
One, two, three.
Boy, I'm pooped.
Let's rest up
a few minutes, okay?
Somewhere in the shade.
Come on, Rupe.
The car.
[both sigh]
How much money do you
think we earned by now?
Ah, at least
20 cents.
[groans]
I wonder if this
clunker still runs.
Hey, look what I found.
Huh.
Hey, I wonder if Felix
will let me have this.
Don't ask him now.
He'll see that
we're not working.
Okay, okay,
keep your shirt on,
will you, Sadie?
Look, I told you.
Bugs should be there
any minute with the stuff.
[car engine starts]
Say, look,
I gotta go, Sadie.
Yeah, business.
Hey!
Hey, cut that out,
you kids!
Stop playing around
with the car!
I'm planning on
selling this one.
I'm sorry.
I didn't think
it would start.
Yeah.
Can I please
have this, sir?
Yeah, who cares?
Just leave the car alone.
And what are you
doing in here anyway?
You're supposed to be working.
Now get out and get to work.
Hey, hey, hey!
Hey, Bugs, what
are you doing?
I'm getting rid of
this load of booze,
that's what I'm doing.
Not here, you idiot.
The cops have been tailing me.
They got the truck spotted.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
But first,
deliver this load
to Sadie's Place.
They've been calling
for it every two minutes.
You deliver it.
Oh, sure. Smart.
If I get caught,
you lose your front
in this town.
[chuckles]
If I get caught,
the big boss will kill me.
Okay, okay.
Don't let's panic.
Just call Sadie
on the phone and tell her.
Shut up, shut up.
I'm thinking.
I got it.
What?
They're gonna
deliver it.
Who?
Them? Come on,
they're just kids.
Hey, boys.
Come here!
Hey, look, Felix,
I don't understand.
I mean--
Nobody would suspect
a couple of kids
of running a load
of hooch, right?
No, but still--
Do me a favor.
Relax.
Let me handle this.
We were working.
Honest!
Yeah, yeah.
Tell me, how good
can you drive a car?
Pretty good.
My pal's father
let me drive with him
a few times.
Would you like to make
a little extra money?
Doing what?
Delivering a couple cases
of cooking oil for Bugs.
This is Bugs.
Poor fellow's truck
broke down here.
Yeah, but we don't
have a car.
I'll tell you what.
You can use that car
that you were playing
around in back there.
Yeah? Where do you want
the stuff delivered?
Sadie's Place.
You know where that is?
- Sure.
- Good.
You bring the car up here,
and we'll load it for you.
Okay.
Shorty. Listen.
This dame Sadie's
gonna give you
an envelope with
some money in it.
For the cooking oil.
Yeah. Now, when you
get this envelope,
you bring it
right back to me.
You got that?
- Yes, sir.
- Okay.
[car engine shakily starts]
[car horn]
Aren't you going to
shift into second?
That darn clutch
is so far away.
All right.
Can just barely reach it.
[horn honking]
- Look out!
- Help!
[tires screeching]
You try shifting.
You've got a better
angle on it.
Now.
[gears grind]
Attaboy, Rupe.
Wanna try for high?
Not now,
I'm settling for this.
Stick your arm out.
We're gonna make a right
at the next corner.
[honks horn]
[brakes screech]
[screams]
Sorry, ma'am!
Well, I never!
Hello.
Coming.
Are you Sadie?
Run along, kid.
We're busy.
Wait, don't you want
your cooking oil?
Cooking oil?
You?
We're delivering it
for Mr. Bugs.
Wait here a minute.
Mack.
Look what Bugsy's
pulled now.
Mack:
Well, what are
we gonna do?
What can we do?
Unload.
Hey, Bart.
How long ago they leave?
Okay.
Thanks, Mack.
Half an hour ago,
he said.
A half an hour ago?
I knew we never should've
trusted those kids
with all that loot.
I knew it.
If I go back to Chicago
and tell the big boss
that I was hijacked
by a couple of kids--
Hold it.
[car engine approaching]
Okay, kid.
Where is it?
Where's the envelope?
Oh, yeah.
Gee, I hope
I didn't lose it.
What do you mean,
lose it?
Oh, here it is.
Thanks.
Everything go okay?
Nobody followed you?
Like, maybe cops?
Why would cops follow us?
Well, uh,
you're underage.
Oh, yeah.
No, nobody followed us.
Good.
We gotta get home.
We're late for supper.
So could we get paid
that extra money, Mr. Felix?
Oh, yeah.
Hey, wait a minute.
What is this?
Fives?
You got any more
jobs like this?
No, no,
we got no more.
Possibly.
Very possibly, boys.
Thanks.
We'll see you later.
- Come on, Rupe.
- Bye.
What's with you, Felix?
Come on.
You mean, the two of you
made $10 for one day's work?
Yep.
But that can't be.
There's something wrong here.
What in the world
kind of work
is Felix having
you do anyway?
Whatever it is,
it's dirty work.
look at you.
You go upstairs
and wash,
and I'll warm up
your supper.
Go on.
Come on.
Here, Mom.
Put this toward
the World's Fair trip.
Oh, no, no.
That's yours, honey.
You earned it.
Mom, we want you
to have it.
That's what
we're earning it for.
For heaven's sake.
Can you
imagine that?
Isn't that something?
Too bad we're not going.
I was hoping I could
take you and the boys.
I still might make it
if I can get a good
price for the store,
and if something else
works out.
What did you say?
I've put the store
up for sale, Nettie.
You what?
I'm selling the store.
Ed Jones is handling it.
How would we live?
What would we do?
Now, Nettie, believe me.
This is something that
has to be done.
I'm doing this
for your own good.
Cutting off our
means of livelihood
is for my own good?
Charles, you'd better
go see the doctor, dear.
Nettie, I do not need
to see the doctor.
Well, getting notions,
these peculiar notions--
I'm sorry I told you.
How would you
plan for our--
Wait, come back.
Where are you going?
I'm going to bed.
Oh.
My goodness.
Well, Roy, why don't
you help me?
How about it, Roy?
Can you hear me?
Are you up there?
Who are you
looking for out there?
Huh? Oh, I was
looking for you?
Roy, I want to know
right now what's going
to happen to me.
I wouldn't push my luck
if I were you, kid.
But I just can't stand
this not knowing.
Now, now,
take it easy, Charley.
I want to wind this up
as much as you do,
because I should be moving on
to other assignments.
I thought you were
going to help me.
I am. I put in a pretty good
pitch for you today.
Well, did it
do any good?
I don't know.
Oh, fine.
But I can tell you this.
I think they're close
to a decision.
They are?
Boy, they're sure
making these springier
than when I was a kid.
Roy, will you stop that?
All right, so they're
close to a decision.
How close?
I don't know.
Well, what do you
think it'll be?
I don't know.
That's all I get from you
is "I don't know."
This thing
is driving me
batty, Roy.
Roy, again.
How can I make any
plans if I'm sitting
on a trap door
that's gonna
spring any minute?
Now, I want you to go
up there and tell them--
Charles.
Relax, kid,
she can't see
or hear me.
Charles, dear,
would you like for me
to get you some hot milk?
Hot milk?
It might make you
sleep better.
Oh, no.
No, thanks, Nettie.
I'm fine.
I just thought if--
Nettie, what
are you doing?
- I'm getting undressed.
- Well, don't do that.
Charles,
I've had a hard day.
Charles, I'm going to bed.
Don't get undressed
in here in front of--
You never know
who's looking.
What are you
talking about?
Why don't you get
undressed in the closet?
In the closet?
I never, Charles.
Charles.
Charles,
that's enough.
That does it.
Tomorrow, you're
going to the doctor.
Nettie, there's nothing
wrong with me.
- Oh, no?
- No.
Then tell me,
who is Roy?
Roy?
Now, look, I don't
expect you to believe this,
but Roy is an--
An angel.
An angel?
That's right.
Oh, Charles.
Really.
It's true, Nettie.
I swear it.
His name is Roy Zerney.
An angel?
Named Roy Zerney.
That's right.
Now, you can't see him,
but he's right over there
on the bed, watching.
Oh, he's done it again.
Roy?
Roy, where did
you go now?
Roy, do something
to prove to her
that you're here,
will you? Roy?
Are you under the bed?
Roy?
Oh.
Roy? Roy, will you give
a sign or something?
He was right here
in this room.
I swear it, Nettie.
Roy?
Don't do this to me!
I don't know why I went
through all this rigmarole.
There's nothing wrong with me.
Well, you seem to
check out all right.
The only reason
I came in to see you
is so you could
convince Nettie I'm okay.
Then why do you
want to upset her
with all this
nonsense about angels?
Oh, she told you
about that, huh?
Doc, I'm going
to level with you.
There really is an angel.
Named Roy Zerney.
It's all true.
I swear it.
Come on, now, Charley.
What are you trying to pull?
I'm not trying
to pull anything.
You see, doc,
my number's up,
and this angel--
Well, you wouldn't understand.
Sure, I would.
Tell me
all about him, Charley.
Nah, forget it.
You're all alike.
If I could just
prove to somebody
I'm telling the truth.
Where do you
see this angel?
Anywhere.
He popped up in my shower
the other morning.
He could be right here
in this office.
Roy, where are you
when I need you?
Charley, sit down.
I'm not through with you.
No, you've got nothing
that can help me, doc.
Please, Charley.
Look, there's
a very good psychiatrist
right down the hall.
Fine.
Give him my regards.
Zerney.
Ed? Doc Sprague.
Listen, I understand Charley
asked you to sell his store.
Don't do it, Ed.
Well, stall him.
He's a--
He's a very sick man.
Six cases
go to Sadie's Place,
and the rest goes
to the Red Rooster.
You got that?
- Sure.
- Good.
How come they use
so much cooking oil?
Well, uh, it's the new
high grade thin oil.
Yeah, they
use it up faster.
You guys better
get going.
Oh, yeah. Sure.
And don't forget
to bring back the envelopes!
I don't like this, Felix.
And I'll tell you
somebody else
who don't like it.
The big boss.
You tell the big boss
I'm running this end
of the operation, eh?
But not for long,
unless you find some way
to cool the local cops.
You know, he's talking
about sending Frankie Zuto
in here to take over.
Frankie Zuto?
I don't want that gangster
coming in here.
Maybe you don't have
a whole lot to say about it.
[humming]
Oh.
[chuckles]
Rupe:
Willie, watch out!
Turn, turn!
[screams]
Hello, Nettie.
Where have you been?
I've been talking
to Ed Jones.
Now all of a sudden,
for some idiotic reason,
he thinks he can't
sell the store.
Dear, I talked
to Dr. Sprague,
and he thinks
you really ought to
see that psychiatrist.
Now, Nettie, let's not
get into that again.
Oh, that Leonora.
I told her to take this,
especially if she's
going to be out late.
Where did she go?
Well, I believe Ray
said something
about dancing.
Dancing? With Ray?
That can
mean only one thing.
He's taken her
to Sadie's Place.
I told that lounge lizard
not to take her there again.
Charles, where
are you going?
I'm going to bring
my daughter home.
Follow me.
Mr. Appleby? Hi.
Oh, hello, Suzie.
Have you seen Leonora?
Well, not tonight. No.
Thanks.
What'll you
have to drink?
Oh, nothing, thank you.
Well, you have to
pay for it anyway.
We have a minimum.
What would you like?
The lemonade
or the iced tea?
Oh, lemonade will be fine.
Look, the only reason
I'm here is to try
to find a certain girl.
Got you, sport.
[laughs]
Hi.
I understand
you're looking for
a little company.
No.
I think you have
the wrong idea.
I don't care.
I'm no bargain.
I just happen to be here
looking for my daughter.
Oh, does she
work here, too?
No, she doesn't work here.
You see, she has this
boyfriend--
Oh, she's lucky.
[coughs]
What do they put in there?
Yeah, it is pretty
cheap booze.
You know, they got
a couple of kids
that are
delivering it now?
I just don't know
what kind of parents
that would allow kids
to do things like that.
[whistle blows]
Run! It's a raid!
Let's get out of here!
[shouting]
Hey, that's Pop.
Willie, look.
Pop's on the front page.
Oh, my gosh.
It is Pop.
Let me see this.
What's he doing
with the cops?
Sadie's place,
raided for selling...
bootleg whiskey?
No wonder they could
afford all that
cooking oil.
"After staking out
the roadhouse for
two nights,
the officers
crashed the doors
and rounded up the"--
All right,
that's enough of that.
Pop is in the hoosegow.
Rupert, where do you
pick up such language?
Didn't you read
where it says--
All right, now listen.
Your father is--
Well, he's not exactly
himself right now.
When he comes down,
the less said the better.
Understand?
Who's that girl?
Uh, sit down, boys.
I'll get your breakfast.
And don't say anything
to make him feel worse than--
[door closes]
Shh-shh.
Good morning.
- Good morning, Pop.
Sure was a nice
picture of you, Pop.
Picture?
What picture?
Girl's kind of
pretty, too.
Who is she, Pop?
Willie, you boys
run up and tell Leonora
that breakfast is on.
Doesn't take
two of us to
do that, Mom.
I said go.
Now go on. Go. Go.
What's it like
in the clink, Pop?
Rupert!
Clara has already
called about it.
Naturally.
Too bad you have to
spread it all over
the front page.
Nettie, I don't
print the newspapers.
By the way,
who is that girl?
I don't know who she is.
Is that the angel
you've been hobnobbing
around with?
Nettie, I explained
the whole thing
to you last night.
Now, if you want to make
something different out of it.
Mom, Pop.
She's not upstairs.
I found this
on her bed.
Where in the world
could she be?
Oh, no.
She's eloped.
My baby.
Eloped?
Well, I'll be darned.
- With Ray.
- Ray!
Well, don't
just sit there.
Go after them.
Well, Nettie, I don't know
where they've gone.
Besides, what good
would that do?
Well, we have to find them
before something happens.
What do you mean,
before something happens?
What she means is--
Never mind what
she means, Rupert.
What are you two
doing in the house
on a day
like this anyway?
Why don't you go out
and play?
We haven't
finished our breakfast.
[telephone rings]
I'll get it.
Oh, if that's Clara,
don't tell her
about poor Leonora.
Don't worry, Mom.
Ray's a keen guy.
Nobody asked
your opinion, Willie.
Hello?
Yes, I'll accept
the charges.
It's Leonora.
Oh, it's Leonora.
Hello. Hello, Leonora.
Are you all right, honey?
Let me talk to her.
Let me talk.
Mad? Of course we're
not mad, sweetheart.
Where are you?
East Plankton?
They've had an accident!
No, no, they haven't.
They wouldn't be
in East Plankton on purpose.
Do you have
a place to stay, honey?
Do you need any money?
Well, we have
a very lovely room,
and Ray is getting a job,
so we don't really
need any money.
Except for maybe
the first month's rent.
But only until
he gets his first check.
How much is it?
I'll send it right away.
Fine. Now hang on.
I think maybe
your mother wants
to talk to you, Leonora.
Now, Nettie,
don't carry on and cry.
Act as though
you're happy for them.
I know what to do.
For heaven's sakes.
Hello, Leonora.
This is your mother.
And I'm so happy for you.
[sobbing]
Boy, do these
take me back.
I wonder
if I could still--
I've been waiting
half the morning
for you, Charley.
Where have you been?
I've been out trying
to raise some money.
Roy, what's
the decision?
- Well--
- Hey, you're taller today.
Roller skates?
Boy, you're fooling
around while I--
Roy, what about
the decision?
Have they reached one yet?
Well, Charley,
the situation is--
[telephone rings]
Your phone's ringing.
Roy, let me have it.
Your phone's ringing, Charley.
I hear it.
All right, don't
you go away, now.
Appleby Hardware.
Yeah, what is it, Harry?
I'm in kind of a rush right now.
Well, Charley,
we got some
Chicago bootleggers
running loose around town.
They even took a shot
at one of my men.
And we're checking out
every lead we got
to see if we can trap 'em.
Yeah, but why
are you calling me
about that, Harry?
Well, uh,
to tell you the truth,
we got a tip that
a couple of local kids
have been making deliveries
for these same bootleggers.
And, Charley,
the descriptions
fit your boys.
My boys?
Harry, that's the most
preposterous thing
I've ever heard.
Don't leave, Roy.
How could they make a delivery?
They don't even have a car.
I'm sorry
I bothered you, Charley.
Okay, Harry.
Okay, Roy, let me
have the bad news,
if that's why
you've been stalling.
Roy:
Well, Charley,
it's like this--
Mr. Appleby.
- You've got a customer.
- I know.
If it's about
the one cent sale,
Miss Partridge,
it's off.
Never mind that.
I'm here to inform you
that I intend to sue you.
Sue me? What for?
Don't play innocent
with me, Mr. Appleby.
Excuse me, Roy.
And don't go away.
Miss Partridge, I don't know
what you're talking about.
I'm talking about
a broken lamp.
It was a very
valuable antique lamp,
and your boys broke it.
My boys broke it?
Miss Partridge,
just when did they do this?
When they tried
to run over me,
in that old wreck
of a car they drive.
- [dog barking]
- A car they drive?
- [arf]
- Pierre.
Miss Partridge,
are you positive
it was my boys?
Well, I'd know
them anywhere.
What is that noise?
Pierre, be quiet!
No wonder Felix
paid them all that money.
Pierre!
What kind of a car
were they--
I've got to find them.
Okay.
Okay, keep your
shirt on, Sadie.
Hey! Hey, Bugs!
Bugs, you crazy
or something?
Get that car
out of here!
Felix, we got trouble.
We got trouble.
Frankie shot
a local flatfoot.
I know, I know,
it's all over the radio.
Frankie, ain't you
smarter than to take
a shot at a cop?
Button that big mouth
of yours and get your car.
You're driving us
out of town.
You're not mixing me
up in this.
Oh, no?
Hey, Frankie,
we got a break.
Remember them two kids
I told you about?
They're here.
Now, they could
drive us out of town.
Nobody suspects them.
Hey, leave them alone.
They're good kids,
and I don't want
them shot up.
You s--
Hey, kids.
Come here.
How you doing?
Did you hear about
the raid at Sadie's Place
last night?
Yeah, I heard. Too bad.
Let's get going.
By the way, this is Frankie.
He's gonna go with us,
all right?
We don't want to make
any more deliveries
to Sadie's Place.
You don't have to. We're
gonna take a little ride.
- Let's go
- Where to?
You're just gonna
drive us somewhere.
Don't worry about it.
Come on, let's go.
Okay, here we are.
Let's go.
What's he doing
down there?
Just shut up
and drive us out of town.
You see any cops,
you let me know.
Now get going.
Yes, sir.
Come on, come on.
Let's go.
[Felix groans]
Felix? Good Lord,
what happened to you?
Your boys.
They took your boys.
Who took 'em?
Frankie Zuto.
Chicago gangster.
Trying to get out of town.
They'll never make it
in that old car.
Don't take that car.
You'll have every cop
in town on your tail.
Uh-oh.
Frankie:
All right, hold it, kids.
Slow down.
Pull in behind that car
before they spot us.
Hey, what's
with you, kid.
What are we gonna do, Frankie?
Just sit here all day or what?
No, we ain't gonna
just sit here.
We're gonna pull out
and go back the other way.
But we're gonna do it
nice and easy
so that we don't
attract no attention.
Now move.
[tires screech]
- Easy! Easy!
- Where you going?
Hey, our roof's come off!
You got it?
Yeah, yeah,
I got it!
Hey.
Hey, we're
being followed.
Yeah? Who by?
Our own car.
Must be Felix.
Couldn't be,
not in his shape.
Aah!
Hey!
Shake 'em.
Cut through that alley.
Bugs, take the wheel.
This kid'll kill us.
Yeah.
Don't let go
of the wheel,
you idiot!
[horn honking]
[yelling]
[horns honking]
Won't nothing
stop that jerk?
Must be something here.
Don't stand out there.
Get in.
I'm hot on their trail, Roy.
Listen, Charley.
There's something I gotta--
Yeah, but don't
bug me now, huh?
[horn honking]
Charley, you all right, kid?
Help me, Roy.
My boys.
Radio:
Calling all cars.
Suspect's black Packard sedan
has been reported
driving in vicinity
of 21st street
in a highly erratic manner.
That's it,
the bootlegger's car!
Let's go!
[siren wailing]
There's nobody
driving that car.
What do you mean,
there's nobody
driving that c--
Well, what
are we gonna do?
Tell him to pull over.
Tell who to pull over?
I don't know,
shoot out the tires.
Do something.
No wonder
he wasn't driving.
He was ducking bullets.
Look at that windshield.
What happened?
Where am I?
Hey, it's the hardware man
we picked up
in the raid last night.
Appleby.
Well, what do you know?
Who'd think a square like him
would be running booze?
Packing a Tommy gun.
Here.
Okay, Appleby, let's go.
It's all over.
Wait a minute.
My hat.
Thanks, Roy.
I'll see you.
Radio:
We interrupt this program
to bring you a late bulletin.
The police department
reports it has apprehended
the gunman's car,
and a suspect is in custody.
Good.
Keep him there.
We now return you
to Harry Horlick
and the A&P Gypsies.
[snoring]
Roy.
Buck up, Charley.
You won't have to
suffer much longer.
Get me out of here, Roy.
I can't get you out.
I can only get me out.
But I've got
to go to my boys.
Simmer down, Charley.
There's something
more important I--
Well, I just
have to tell you.
Roy, I know now,
nothing is more important
than those boys.
I'm glad to hear you
say that, but...
Well, here it is, kid.
Your time is up tonight.
Tonight?
You're kidding.
Sorry, Charley.
I know how you feel.
Wait a minute.
There must be something--
See you tonight, kid.
Now the whole
town's surrounded.
Every road.
Where'd they get
all those cops?
Run for it.
Come on, let's go.
Yeah, but we ain't got it.
Besides, it's gonna
be dark soon.
Hey!
- Rupe!
- Wait!
Grab the little one!
Okay, hold it, kid.
I wouldn't
try that again, pal.
I don't like stoolies
that could rat on us.
Yeah, there's already
a reward out for--
Shut up, Bugs.
Now, I want you two guys
to find us a place
where we can hide out
for a couple of hours.
We don't
know any place.
I just wanna go home.
Hey.
That's it.
The kid's got it.
Where is your home?
Over that way.
But my pop would
never let you.
Don't worry
about it, kid.
We'll take care
of your old man.
Let's go.
Come on, here.
You're getting to be
my best customer, Charley.
Listen, Harry.
My boys--
I mean,
it's one thing
to get picked up
in a raid,
but what were you doing
driving a bootleg car?
Never mind that.
The real bootleggers
have kidnapped my boys.
- How you do you know that?
- Because I followed them.
- I almost caught 'em.
- How'd you get the car?
Would you just
get some men on this
so those hoodlums
don't get out of town?
Don't worry.
Nobody's gonna get
out of town tonight.
Anything happens
to Willie or Rupert--
I know, I know,
we'll find them.
I promise you.
Come on,
I'll take you home.
Just drop me off
at the store.
One more thing.
Don't get any more
foolish notions
about chasing gangsters.
Leave that for us, okay?
Okay.
This it?
Willie:
Yeah, this is it.
Well, come on, let's go--
[loud bang]
Come on.
That ladder leads up to
my sister's old room.
She doesn't use it now,
so you could use it
as a hideout.
Who's that?
My mother.
Hey, shorty.
Go in and keep her occupied
so she don't get nosey.
Remember, we got your brother
upstairs with us,
so don't go getting
any big ideas about
tipping anybody off.
You got that?
Yes, sir.
Well, thank goodness.
Somebody's finally here.
I've warmed the liver up
so many times,
it's like shoe leather.
Where's Willie?
Oh, he'll be in.
Hear about
the big excitement?
A shooting,
police chasing bootleggers,
I don't know what all.
Yeah, I believe I heard
something about that.
I wish your father were here.
I worry about him now.
Go upstairs
and wash, Rupert.
I'd rather
do it down here.
Sit down, kid.
You ain't going nowhere.
Come on.
What in the world
is Willie doing out there?
I better call him.
Where have you been?
Nettie, don't
get excited, but--
Rupert, you're safe!
How did you get away
from the bootleggers?
- Bootleggers?
- How'd you know about that?
- I was chasing you.
- That was you, Pop?
- Yeah.
- What in the world--
Where's Willie?
Have they still got him?
No, he's--
He's upstairs, I think.
Upstairs? You said--
He must've gone in
the front way.
Well, come on, Rupert.
We better call the police
and give them all the
information you've got.
I don't think
we oughta do that, Pop.
We have to, Rupert.
I wish somebody would
tell me what's going on.
Come on downstairs, Willie.
And hurry it up.
You, come here.
All right, go on down.
But don't try anything, pal.
You send
your brother up here.
If he's not here
in five seconds,
we're coming down.
Will you please
tell me what
this is all about?
Not now, Nettie. Oh, Willie.
I'm calling the police.
I want you and Rupert
to tell them everything--
Rupert,
where are you going?
- Uh--
- The bathroom.
- Yeah, bathroom.
- Well, hurry it up.
I want you to tell them
everything you know
about these birds.
Do you know
where they are now?
I think they're
hiding out some place.
Where were you when
you got away from them?
[doorbell rings]
Do you remember that?
Mama!
My baby!
Leonora!
Daddy, hi.
Oh, hello, Ray.
We're so pleased
to see you.
Hi, Ray.
Well, then,
this is a surprise.
Is everything all right?
Isn't it wonderful
to have them
come for a visit
so soon?
Well, it's not exactly
a visit, Mama.
Oh?
All right,
what's happened?
Well, Daddy, you're not
gonna believe this.
I think I'd better
tell it.
Yes, Ray will tell.
Well, what
happened was--
He got cheated.
He got cheated right out
of that good job.
That big crook
hired his own stupid
brother-in-law instead.
And there we were.
Ray, take
the bags up, dear.
No!
What do
you mean, "no"?
He's right.
The room's a mess.
Let me run up
and tidy it.
No, Ma. I'll do it.
Just let me do it, okay?
- What's wrong with you?
- Let me go, Willie.
We have to make that
phone call, you know?
Believe it or not,
we're trying to run down
a couple of crooks.
Hey, yeah.
We had a dickens
of a time
coming through
a police blockade.
What's going on?
Well, you see, these two
crooks from Chicago--
[Nettie screams]
Charles!
Charles, call the police!
Call the police!
All right,
put the phone down.
Close the door.
All right, now get in here.
Come on, come on.
Charles.
Well, looks like a nice
little family reunion.
I'd sure hate
to spoil that.
How'd you get up
in Leonora's room?
Shut up, lady.
One thing I can't stand,
it's a yakking broad.
Why, you're terrible.
That's right, lady.
Coming in to
a nice home--
Nettie, take it easy.
- Bugs?
- Yeah?
Take the ol' lady
in the kitchen,
have her sack up
some food.
Sure, sure.
Come here.
Don't you touch me.
Wait a minute.
Go ahead, Nettie.
Get 'em some food.
I'm not an old lady.
Hey, sweater.
You look like a hotshot
with a hard-running car,
right?
What's it to you?
Oh, we got a smart one, huh?
Let's see if you're
smart enough to hand me
your car keys.
You may be smart,
but your hearing's
not too good.
I said toss me
the car keys.
Do it, Ray.
Give 'em to him, Ray.
Catch on quick, pal.
Where's it parked,
out front?
Yeah.
Here.
You hang on to it, lady.
Bugs?
Put your hat and coat on.
We're leaving.
And bring that
other kid down here.
I'd like to keep
the family together.
Here, take it.
No, you hang on to it
'cause you're
coming with us.
What do you mean,
she's coming with you?
You're not taking
my wife anywhere.
I ain't got time to debate
it out with you, Dad.
Well, you'll take her
over my dead body.
Okay, just remember.
You laid down
the conditions, not me.
[screaming]
Aah!
Charles!
Wait a minute, Nettie.
Wait a minute.
I'm not shot.
Howdy, folks. Anybody--
Attaboy, Pop!
Bugs, get him off me!
Okay, hold it, Pop!
Hold it!
Hold him, Ray!
Get off me, kid!
Nettie:
Now, don't get hurt!
Willie:
Come on, Ray!
Frankie!
[yelling]
Well, aren't you
gonna help them?
They're doing just fine.
Oh!
Come on, Leonora!
[yelling]
Charles:
Attaboy, Ray.
Now, wait a minute!
Wait a minute!
[screaming]
Ray! Ray!
Willie:
Get 'em, Pop!
[shouting]
Charles:
The gun!
- Get the gun!
- The gun.
All right, mister.
Hold it right there.
Ung!
Hey, Rupe, you missed
all the fun.
All right, boys,
take charge of these hoods
and get 'em out of here.
Oh. Oh.
Come on, Nettie.
There you go.
Thank you.
Oh, Charley.
Charley, you are a tiger.
You won't give up,
will you?
You know, Pop did it.
Pop whupped Frankie?
Gun and all.
You should've seen him.
Did it to save Mom.
I tell ya, Rupe,
we've got some pop.
Well, I, uh--
I had a little
help, you know.
Okay, now hold that.
I think you moved.
Good. Now, what do you
plan on doing with the money?
- Money?
- What money?
You don't know?
For capturing Frankie Zuto.
Right, Chief?
Right, Chicago has
a standing reward
of 5,000 bucks on him.
$5,000?
[shouting]
Miss Nettie?
- Uh, Miss Nettie?
- Yes, Pete.
Speaking of money, the reason
I dropped by tonight--
Pete, we haven't
got the money yet.
Besides, you haven't
paid back the last loan.
Oh, Charles.
What do you think
I'm trying to do?
Here you are.
There's $100.
And there's
your interest.
Thank you, Pete.
Charlie, the town
has a little something
for you, too.
Arnie?
This is the best
I could do
on such short
notice, Charlie,
but you'll find
your hotel reservations
right in there.
And when you get there,
just ask the clerk
for your tickets
to the World's Fair.
The World's Fair!
Oh, Charles!
And if you need any cash,
the bank examiner's
gonna let me open up
tomorrow morning.
How about that?
Fine.
All right, now, look.
Let's get out of here
and let these people
get some rest.
They've had a hard day.
Good night, Charlie, Nettie.
Nettie:
Good night, Chief.
Goodbye!
Bye.
I knew it, Pop.
I knew we'd go.
Yes, you were
the believer, Rupert.
We wished on a star,
didn't we?
Pop made it happen,
not the wishing.
I wonder.
Well, Leonora's wish
for that big wedding
never came true.
Who said it didn't?
I wished for
a beautiful wedding,
not a big one.
And mine was
the most beautiful wedding.
Well, I cried all the way
through it, didn't I, Ray?
Yeah, she sure did.
You know, we had better
get some sleep
'cause we gotta get up early
and go house hunting.
That's right.
Good night.
Good night, Leonora.
Good night, Ray.
Hey, we gotta
go up and pack.
Oh, yeah.
Hey, listen, we gotta
pack those baseball gloves.
You know, in case
a foul ball comes our way
when we go to see the Cubs.
Yeah!
You boys get
right to bed now.
It's late.
You can pack
in the morning.
Oh, Charles.
This is all
so wonderful.
I can hardly
believe it.
Charles?
Hmm?
What's the matter?
I, uh, I just remembered
something, Nettie.
I don't know how
I could've forgotten it,
but with all
this excitement, I did.
You forgot what?
Come over here
and sit down, Nettie.
Honey, I, uh,
I have to go down
to the store.
Well, tonight?
- Yes, I--
- Oh.
I have an appointment
with a fellow.
You're not still
thinking of selling
the store, are you?
Oh, no, no. I'm saving that
for Ray and Leonora.
Good.
Nettie,
promise me something:
that no matter what,
you and the boys will
go to the fair, hmm?
But, Charles,
we're all going.
Would you like
for me to pick you up
one of those
seersucker suits
for the trip?
No, no.
Nettie, I just want you
to know one thing.
I think you're
a fine woman.
Oh, what brought that on?
If I had my life
to live over again,
I'd do a lot
of things differently.
But one thing I know,
I'd want
to live it with you.
Don't stop.
I think I'll go up
and see the kids
for a minute before I go.
Think about
that seersucker, Charles.
You'd look nice in it.
[Leonora and Ray laugh]
Boys?
[sighs]
Well, Nettie,
I guess I'd better go.
I wish you didn't
have to go right now.
So do I, Nettie.
So do I.
You haven't kissed me
like that since...
since that night after
the Air Force league picnic.
I know. I should have
done it more often.
I love you, Nettie.
[whines]
Oh, there you are.
Boy, you sure picked
a fine time for this.
Yeah.
Pull over to the curb.
Charley, why do you
have to be so difficult?
I don't know what
you're talking about, Roy.
So let's get this
over with, huh?
Where's it gonna happen?
It's already happened.
It has?
Who do you think
that gunshot was meant for?
That was it.
It was?
Roy, I don't understand.
He shot right at me,
but there was no bullet.
Oh, yes there was.
You mean, you--
How did you do that?
Well, I had to
move pretty fast.
But why?
Because I'm
a soft-hearted boob.
As long as I can remember,
that's always
been my trouble.
What do I do now?
If I were you,
first thing I'd do
is pick me up
a seersucker suit.
Roy, wait a minute.
How will I know
when my number's up?
You won't.
You'll have to go on
like everyone else,
not knowing.
Except maybe you've
learned how to live now.
So long, Charley.
[cows mooing]
Oh, Charles.
You do look handsome
in your seersucker suit.
Yeah, Pop,
you sure look snazzy.
I guess it doesn't
look too bad, does it?
Oh! Charles, my hat!
It's coming back.
Boy, that must
be some wind.
Oh!
For heaven's sake.
How could it
do that, Pop?
Uh, well,
as you said, Willie,
it must be some wind.
Who are you
waving at, Pop?
Oh, I was just waving
goodbye to summer, Rupert.
I'll bet this is one
we'll never forget.
¶ I keep busy
taking life easy ¶
¶ Living one day at a time ¶
¶ It doesn't matter
if I don't have a dime ¶
¶ I keep busy
takin' life easy ¶
¶ Livin' one day at a time ¶