Umph.
What a location.
Ah, Si. The mighty Coliseum.
The glory of Rome.
Doesn't it stir your imagination?
You bet it does, baby.
Do you people realise
what a shopping centre
we could put up there?
Plenty of parking too.
Here it is, ladies and gentlemen,
the world's highest
office building.
Hawk Plaza... 130 stories
of man-made glory.
In just a few hours,
Hawk Enterprises
will break ground on
this incredible project.
How did it happen,
you ask? I give you
now the man that made
it all possible.
Thank you, friends. Thank you.
My heart is too full to speak.
Ah, you see.
You've brought a tear to
this flinty, old eye.
So, all I can say is thank you.
Thank you for allowing me to share
a moment of your precious time.
Get those deadheads out of here.
What, are they gonna stand around
all day and drink my booze?
All right, ladies and
gentlemen, down to my office...
where a scroll awaits you.
Hello.
Mr. Barnsdorf, sir.
Hello, Barnsdorf.
When are you going to be ready
for us to start digging?
What are you talking about?
That building site's
as clean as a...
What's that?
I thought we got
rid of that crummy
little firehouse months ago.
There's just one
hold-up. We couldn't get
old lady Steinmetz
to sign the papers.
Just one, beat-up old
lady makes monkeys
out of the most overpaid
lawyers in the country.
Come on, boys. I expect a little
action, and I better
get it or else.
For some reason, she
doesn't seem to trust us.
Of course she doesn't. Have
you looked at yourselves?
Your own mothers
wouldn't trust ya.
What we need is somebody
so nauseatingly innocent,
and so stomach-turningly helpful
and so incredibly dumb
anybody would trust him.
What is it?
Mr. Willoughby
Whitfield to see you.
He says he's your nephew.
Whoever he is, throw him out.
Don't bother me again.
Say, wait a minute.
Is that that dumb-looking kid
of my sister's from back east?
He was going to law
school or something?
He just finished law school. He
says he's a full-fledged lawyer.
He's a full-fledged
lawyer. Send him in.
Mr. Hawk will see you now.
Oh.
Thank you.
Come in, boy. Come in.
Isn't he beautiful?
Uncle Alonzo, I hereby present you
with the first law college
Humanitarian-of-the-Year Award.
Here.
Oh, well, well.
Humanitarian of the Year?
That's right, Uncle.
Award committees give
out humanitarian
awards to a lot of strange ducks,
but why me?
I was the award committee.
You put in the fix.
You figured to take care
of your Uncle Alonzo.
You're a smart boy.
If there's one thing I admire,
it's somebody who knows how
to use juice properly.
Juice?
Yes, juice. How to use
muscle, influence,
how to bend things his own way.
Oh, no. My goodness, no.
It wasn't done dishonestly.
I thought it over,
and I couldn't think of anyone
any more deserving than you.
How come?
From the day I was born, my
mother never tired of telling me
what a great man her brother was,
getting rid of dirty old buildings
and building shiny new ones,
sending us California fruit at
Christmas. You were her idol.
You clowns get out of here.
I'm trying to have a nice talk
with my favourite nephew.
When I look into your eyes
and see the shining light
of idealism aglow there,
it makes me young again
and ready for battle.
Battle?
Yes, battle.
It has never been easy
for us idealists.
Now, I'm going to
give you a chance
to put that idealism into play
on your very first job.
Oh.
Picture if you will, a
tough, little old lady,
living in a rundown,
rat-infested firehouse,
standing right in the way of
our latest civic benefaction.
There may be city builders who
might find it in their heart
to be vindictive to this old lady.
They might say that
she feeds on the
misery of the poor
in that forsaken neighbourhood,
that she rolls drunks, that she
teaches small children to steal
and make them bring most
of the take to her.
Would I, Alonzo Hawk,
Humanitarian of the Year,
stoop to such tactics?
On the contrary.
I would do everything in my power
to help that tough,
no-good, little old lady.
I would give her a large sum
for that worthless property,
and I would provide a
special price to her alone
a lifetime lease in
Eternity Towers,
that beautiful new haven for
helpless old people
such as herself.
It has a gymnasium, a sauna,
an old Rudolph Valentino
Sessue Hayakawa movie.
It has a beauty
parlour, hobby centre,
and instead of cooking her
heart out over a hot stove,
there would be automatic
machines in every hall
to lavish her with everything
from pizza to hot chilli.
Now wouldn't it make
just your whole
being happy to be
part of all that?
When can I start, Uncle?
Here's the address. Get moving.
- Here.
- Thanks, pal.
Ah, isn't it breathtaking?
It's a mess, all right.
That guy, Hawk, oughta be hung.
What?
I'm coming.
Mrs. Steinmetz? Good morning. My
name is Willoughby Whitfield.
I'd like to discuss
business with you.
Come in, won't you?
I can't.
You see this car has
rolled onto my foot.
Oh, dear.
I guess somebody forgot to
set the brake or something.
Herbie, aren't you
ashamed of yourself?
Get off Mr. Whitfield's foot.
Herbie's always
trying to protect me.
Herbie?
I'm quite capable of
taking care of myself.
I was about to make
a nice cup of tea.
Come in. You must
have one with me.
Oh, thank you.
Of course, I have
to humour Herbie.
He used to be a famous racing car,
but his driver went to Europe
to drive foreign cars,
so he's a little sensitive.
You can understand that.
Yes. Now, to get down to
business, Mrs. Steinmetz.
People have been worrying about
you living in this old firetrap.
I've been asked to
come over and...
Firehouse, not firetrap.
Firehouse, yes. Be that as it may,
the least we can do...
Stop that. That's downright rude.
Do you know what he was playing?
Do Not Trust Him, Gentle
Maiden. Nothing personal.
No.
He's a friend of
Herbie's, of course.
Friend of Herbie's?
So is old 22.
You may as well meet all the
family while you're here.
Number 22 used to be on
the old Clay Street line.
Herbie found him in a vacant lot.
Someone had used him
as a chicken house.
He's much happier here, of course.
I can understand that you may have
some emotional attachment
to this old building...
Indeed, I have.
I was married here
to my late husband,
Captain Steinmetz, of the San
Francisco Fire Department.
Oh?
One of the heroes
of the great fire.
We understand your
position. That's
why Mr. Hawk has authorised...
Don't tell me you're
from Alonzo Hawk?
Yes.
Oh, you have such a nice face.
Thank you.
Not at all like those
ruffians he usually sends.
If you would just look at
the size of this check.
I don't know anything about money.
My nephew, Tennessee Steinmetz,
usually takes care of me.
He used to live here.
He had to rush off to Tibet
because his guru got sick.
If you would just look at
this... What's a guru?
His teacher. My nephew is a
student of Oriental Philosophy.
That's how he learned that
things have an inner life.
Like wind, rain, traffic lights,
can openers, flowers...
And little cars.
That's how Herbie and Tennessee
became such great friends.
Mrs. Steinmetz, this
sum of money could
take care of you for
the rest of your life.
I didn't have to study Oriental
Philosophy the way Tennessee did.
I could talk to Herbie right off.
Oh?
I guess it's in the blood.
See ya tomorrow.
I don't like to press,
but believe me,
Mr. Hawk has your
interest at heart.
I have an agreement here.
If you would just glance...
Oh, Nicole.
I want you to meet a
gentleman from Mr. Hawk's.
- How do you do?
- Agh.
Poor Mr. Whitfield.
Such a nice young man.
They're bothering us again?
You've hurt your hand.
On the contrary, it
feels marvellous.
Are you all right, Mr. Whitfield?
What was that?
Nicole Harris, a very brave young
lady. She works for the airline.
Last week she knocked
out a hijacker
with a bottle of California wine.
Now, get out. If you or any more
of Hawk's stooges come around,
you'll get worse than that.
Please. Mr. Whitfield and I were
having a nice conversation.
I'll bet. But...
Isn't it time for your nap?
Mr. Whitfield is just going.
Well, very well.
Goodbye, Mr. Whitfield.
I hope I'll see you
again when I come down.
Mrs. Steinmetz...
- Out. Out.
- What?
Please, have a heart.
This is my first
assignment. I can't
afford to fail.
I said, out.
All right, all right.
Miss, you look like
a sensible person.
You must know living all alone
in this crummy neighbourhood
is no place for an elderly woman.
What do you mean
"alone"? She's got me...
And she's got Herbie.
That's another thing.
That goofy story about this car,
that's a sure sign
she's coming apart.
So you think it's goofy?
Of course, don't you?
How would you like to
go for a little ride?
I thought you didn't like me?
I'd like to take you for a ride in
Herbie. I'd like that very much.
That's very nice of you.
I'll be ready in a minute.
All right, Herbie.
Let's get going.
Miss Harris, you're obviously
an intelligent young woman.
Why do you pretend to talk to
this car? People might wonder.
Don't listen to him,
Herbie. Just move it.
I can understand Mrs. Steinmetz
thinking of this car as a person.
Old age has many
fantasies. It only
proves that she needs
Mr. Hawk's help.
Remember, Alonzo Hawk sent him.
You and I know better, don't we?
You stubborn bucket of bolts.
You always have to do
everything your way.
Let's stop kidding ourselves. This
is just an ordinary little car,
like a million other ordinary,
rather unattractive... Whoa.
I don't think you
should have said that.
Herbie's very sensitive
about his appearance.
All right, you've had your
laugh. You ought to stop now.
You won't get Herbie to stop
until you say you're sorry.
The thing that upsets
me most about this
thing is you trying to
maintain the fiction
about this... Whoa.
Please, tell Herbie you're sorry.
All right.
Herbie, I'm sorry.
What do you think now?
I think you're a skilful driver,
but I don't know if I'd like
to have you drive me again.
You think it's a trick?
Yes. I would say the
whole thing is a trick.
Would you like to drive?
Yes.
Good.
There, you see,
this car is just your ordinary,
rather stupid-looking... Whoa.
What do I do now?
It's too late now.
You're on your own.
I just hope Herbie hasn't
lost his sense of humour.
"Chicken tournament
jousting today."
What? What's it up to now?
I don't know. It's hard to
figure Herbie out sometimes.
The gallant and
chivalrous contenders
are now taking their places
on the field of honour.
At the north end of the list,
the undefeated champion
of the tournament,
earless, brutal, unforgiving,
the Red Knight.
Yeah.
At the south end, his
stout-hearted adversary,
the ever-popular Sir Lancelot.
I don't know what
Herbie's up to, but
I hope it's not
what I think it is.
Let the joust begin.
Give the signal, Your Majesty.
What are they doing?
Seems dangerous to me.
Hey, what are they doing?
I think this is where I get out.
Good idea. I'll join you.
The victor, thus far, has
demolished all who oppose him.
The surviving champion,
your favourite and mine,
the Red Knight.
At the other end,
we have a mysterious
new contender,
but the name doesn't matter.
No one lasts for long
against the Red Knight.
Let the joust begin.
No, Herbie. Wait.
I take everything back.
I apologise. I believe, Herbie.
I believe.
My brave champion,
you have won me.
Take me to your kingdom.
You win the bread, man. $3.
I'm beginning to think
that I owe you an apology.
Oh, no, I can't stand
men who apologise.
Oh, well, may I take you to lunch?
All right.
I used to live in a
little apartment
building opposite the firehouse.
I loved it. Then Alonzo Hawk came
along to tear the place down.
And kicked me out.
I'm sure he didn't
mean it personally.
Now you know why I
go crazy every time
I hear the name Hawk.
How's your jaw?
It's all right. It's... Ooh.
I'm sorry. How was I supposed to
know it was your first assignment?
You couldn't possibly know
what a no-good he is.
Miss, there's something
I should tell you...
Anyway, Mrs. Steinmetz
took me in until
I could find another
place to live.
When I found out what Hawk was up
to, I stayed on to protect her.
I wasn't gonna let
rats from Alonzo
Hawk talk her out of her home.
I don't think you're
being quite fair.
Fair? To Alonzo Hawk?
Yes.
Don't tell me he's conned you the
way he's conned everybody else.
I think I should tell you that...
Did you know...
He put a parking garage
on the lot where
the DiMaggios learned
to play baseball?
Please, I...
His factories are polluting
all the fish in the Bay.
Look, you...
His skyscraper casts
a cold, grey shadow
on the children's
playground all day long.
Let me tell you...
He kicked 30 old-time
Chinese families
off Grand Avenue to make
room for his skyscraper.
Please, Miss Harris.
I can't believe Uncle Alonzo
would do things like that.
Wait a minute. Uncle.
He's your uncle?
Yes...
You rotten spy.
Here's your warm milk, Grandma.
Be sure and drink it. You
know how good it is for you.
Yes, dear. I still
can't understand
why you hit him with
a boiled lobster.
Grandma, I wish I could stop
doing things like that.
I really sort of like him.
I'm glad to hear that.
After all, brilliant, eligible
lawyers don't grow on trees.
What are you leading up to?
Nothing, dear.
I just thought that
perhaps you could talk
things over with that
nice Mr. Whitfield.
Nice try, Grandma.
But if I want a young man,
I'll have to get him my way.
I suppose so, dear.
Stop hatching plots
and go to sleep.
Yes, dear.
Good night, Grandma.
Good night, dear.
Good night, Herbie.
Pleasant dreams.
He used to be a famous racing car.
Uncle Alonzo,
I dropped by to talk
to you man-to-man,
so I could look you
squarely in the eye.
No, I'm wearing make-up
because of a black eye.
A girl hit me in the face
with a boiled lobster
the moment I mentioned your name.
This same wonderful, intelligent,
clear-sighted girl
was able to convince me what
kind of a person you really are.
I do not hold with your scheme of
cheating Mrs. Steinmetz
out of her home
so that you may build
your concrete anthill
on the spot where she has
known so much happiness.
I think you are despicable,
greedy, grasping
and wholly without
principle or pity.
I also believe you are
not a nice person.
If you write my mother, who
is also your sister, Frieda,
please do not tell her that I
wear make-up as a general rule.
I'm going back to Missouri now,
so you may no longer
use me as a cat's paw.
I bid you farewell, more
in sorrow than in anger.
Please do not send us any
more fruit for Christmas.
Goodbye, Grandma.
Hi, everybody.
Hi, Herb.
No hard feelings, okay?
I'm so glad you and Herbie
decided to make up.
Oh.
I'm just going for
my morning walk.
Come with me. We could
have a nice chat.
I just came to say goodbye. I'm
going home to Hawk City, Missouri.
Oh, what a pity. Nicole was
hoping to see you again.
She's a wonderful
girl, even though
you don't seem to agree with her.
I do agree with her now.
As a matter of fact, I'm
going straight to my uncle
to tell him exactly
what I think of him.
That's splendid.
He might be an
important man but it's
time somebody told
him the real truth.
Nicole will be thrilled. Please
wait 'til she comes back.
To be honest, I'm more afraid
of her than I am of my uncle.
Nonsense. Nicole is just a
high-spirited young lady.
Oh, that's for sure.
Goodbye, Mrs. Steinmetz.
Don't weaken about the firehouse.
Don't you worry.
Call my nephew
wherever he's staying
and tell him to get
right over here.
Yes, sir. And Mr. Barnsdorf
is on the phone for you.
Yeah, what do you want?
You ready for us to dig yet?
My boys are getting itchy.
I'll tell you when
to start digging.
Thought I'd remind you I got some
high-priced digging equipment
and crew sitting around
playing gin rummy,
waiting for you to
make up your mind.
It's costing you 80 grand a day.
Stop bugging me, Barnsdorf.
I'll give you the order to
start digging any moment now.
What do you want?
I'm sorry, Mr. Hawk. I called the
motel but your nephew checked out.
What do you mean he's checked out?
When? Where? Who told
him he could check out?
How dare he disappear when
he knows I'm worried sick.
I'll tear his chicken-livered
gizzard to pieces.
I'll stomp him silly. I'll
take this letter knife
and I'll stab that kid in
his ungrateful breastbone.
You know me, Millicent.
Normally I'm a kindly fellow.
But when I get
crossed, I go bananas.
Yes? Oh.
It's your nephew.
Willoughby?
Where are you?
Oh, hi, Uncle.
I thought I'd save time
and phone you the news.
That's marvellous, great.
You're a smart boy.
That Hawk blood will
tell in the end.
All ashore that's going ashore.
What's all that
noise? And what news?
The news I was leaving town.
Leaving town?
I'm on the ship-to-shore phone...
From the deck of the Swedish
freighter, the Gustav Gustaffson,
bound for Helsinki.
Helsinki.
I'm glad you're taking
it like this, Uncle.
You know, you really should
leave Mrs. Steinmetz alone.
Haaa.
Don't worry. You'll feel
better in the morning.
Stop talking like an idiot.
I feel better right now.
Alonzo Hawk may be betrayed,
but he is never defeated.
Outta my Way.
Since none of you pitiful excuses
for men have enough muscle
to move a feeble old
lady off her property,
I'll go and do it myself,
like I have to do
everything around here
that's important.
- Now, Mr. Hawk.
- Oh, shut up.
We'll start on number
one, harassment.
And I wrote the
book on harassment.
We'll shut off her phone,
turn off her water.
We'll sic the health and
building inspectors on her.
Steal her dog.
She doesn't have a dog.
What do you mean? A little old
lady living in a place like that?
Who looks out for her?
How does she get around?
She has a little car she
goes everywhere in.
You fellows go and pick it up.
Yes, Mr. Hawk.
A bunch of lamebrains.
Hold it, hold it.
You fellows'll
probably even foul up
on a simple assignment like this.
The first team is on the job.
I'll go pick the car up myself.
Overeducated pinheads.
All right, gentlemen, start taking
notes. Learn how the
grown-ups do it.
You gentlemen are
probably unaware of it,
but I began my fabulous career
as a repossessor of motorcars.
At the tender age of 19,
I was the best-known repossessor
of cars west of the Mississippi.
Hot-wire Hawk, they called
me. Observe, gentlemen.
Screwdriver, pliers
and a piece of wire.
Check your watches,
and you will see
that I will return
with the object of my mission
in 15 minutes or less.
All right, let's go.
Madam is not at home, sir.
Thank you, Maxwell.
I won't be needing you any more.
Very well, sir.
Once you learn
something when you're
young, you just never forget it.
Except a six-year-old kid could
steal this one-cylinder
hair dryer.
Quiet.
All right, buddy, let's get this
thing outta here before I...
Oh, hello, Mr. Hawk. What are
you doing in this little car?
Just shut up and push.
Certainly, Mr. Hawk. One tiny
thing, is the car out of gear?
Of course it's out of gear,
you nitwit. Just push.
All right, Mr. Hawk.
Okay, push.
Hey, wait a minute. What are
you gonna do about that cab?
Are we trying to get tough?
Don't you dare to threaten me.
All right, Mr. Hawk.
Well?
Three minutes to go.
Oh, hello, Commissioner.
Got a little problem.
We gotta tow him outta here.
Mr. Hawk, just sit
quietly this time.
Don't touch the pedals or
the gears, understood?
Don't order me around.
I will do as I please.
The traffic commissioner
shall hear about this.
I am the commissioner.
Then what are you doing
in that monkey suit?
The traffic commissioner would
dress in dignified clothes.
This happens to be
my dress uniform.
I was on my way to the ceremonies
for "I am a Policeman" day.
Okay, let's go.
Commissioner, call your office.
There's been an accident.
See the man. See the man.
One minute to go.
He'll never make it.
Oh, if Mr. Hawk says he'll
do something, he'll...
Here he is.
Get that car, dead or alive.
Right away, sir.
Mr. Hawk?
If you'll sign a few
of these citations.
Compliments of the commissioner.
Well, he's got more
stuff than I thought.
Yeah, I'm sorry he's going too.
All right, I'll see
you later. Bye-bye.
Flight 38 for Las Vegas...
I tell you, Mother, you've never
seen Uncle Alonzo in such a rage.
He's probably having this
airport watched right now.
But he won't find me. I'm wearing
a disguise. A disguise...
A beard and a moustache.
Yes, I know, Mother. I promised I
wouldn't grow a beard when I left.
Don't you understand?
It isn't real.
No, I will not go back and
apologise to Uncle Alonzo.
He is a greedy,
unscrupulous, no-good,
thieving,
coyote. Yes, thank you, miss. Oh.
No, Mother, my asthma
is not coming back.
No, nothing's the matter with me.
Everything is just fine now.
This is the turning
point of my life.
Uncle Alonzo used
to push me around
and you were always
telling me what to do.
Then I met this perfectly
wonderful girl.
I was even afraid of her 'til now.
I've just decided something.
I am not going to be
a rabbit any more.
Goodbye, Mother.
- Ooh.
Come along, Herbie. Off to market.
Thank you, Herbie.
Let me see now. Half
a dozen tomatoes.
The broccoli looked
very nice yesterday.
What else was there?
We've sighted the car, Mr. Hawk.
We're moving in for the kill now.
They're moving in
for the kill now.
Ooh.
What happened? You said you
were moving in for the kill.
Negative. A little
premature, I'm afraid, sir.
She's obviously a
very desperate woman.
But don't worry. She
won't make it this time.
Another of your shortcuts, Herbie?
Where is she now?
She's still going up and up.
It's incredible. She's
driving like a madman.
Oh, Herbie, behave yourself.
You knocked my glasses off.
Where on Earth is she?
Don't answer it. It'll be Hawk.
Look.
No, Mr. Hawk, the phone
didn't ring before.
Were you trying to reach us?
Did you grab the car?
Any moment now.
There it goes, into the
Sheraton-Palace Hotel.
The Sheraton-Palace Hotel?
May I draw your attention
to the superb baby shrimp?
All right, Herbie,
but you'll never convince me this
is a shortcut to Vern's Market.
Gentlemen, do you
have a reservation?
There it is.
After her. Somebody stop her.
Don't let her get away.
Come on, let's go.
There's only one
thing gives me the
creeps, that's that
weird little car...
What's the matter with you?
There it is.
Pull yourself together.
You're getting hysterical.
Take two aspirins and lie down.
One of us has to keep our nerve.
Come on, come on. Move it.
Now we've got him.
Stop wool gathering, Herbie.
We really must get to the market.
Oh, oh. Wait a minute.
Look out. He's coming back.
Ooh.
Look out. Look out.
Grandma, I was worried about
you. Is everything all right?
Wonderful. Herbie took me for
a nice drive on the bridge.
Let me help you.
It's Mr. Whitfield. So
nice to see you again.
This morning you were on
your way to Missouri.
Nicole spoke to me.
Grandma, Mr. Whitfield's agreed
to help us fight his uncle.
Wonderful. Stay for dinner.
I've already invited him.
Why don't you take those
out to the kitchen?
Yeah. Thank you.
What a fine young man.
You look so right together.
Oh.
Now, if there's
anything I can do...
There is one thing, Grandma.
Just let nature take its course.
Oh, yes, dear. Oh, I
wouldn't want to interfere,
not for anything.
Oh.
By the way, we're going to
want more broccoli for dinner.
Will you and Willoughby
pick me up some, please?
Sure.
Incidentally, you ought to
drive down to the beach.
Grandma.
It's the most beautiful day.
We'll just go get some broccoli.
Yes, dear, of course.
I'm not gonna say
another word, Herbie.
There's nothing I can do.
Of course, I can't help it if you
happen to have a mind of your own.
Can I?
I guess I should have told Mrs.
Steinmetz I don't like broccoli.
Herbie, where are you going?
The young lady and gentleman
have turned towards the north.
It would appear that they're not
immediately returning
to the firehouse.
See that they don't. Do
anything you have to,
but don't let them return to
that firehouse until after dark.
Do you read me?
Perfectly, sir.
Oh, Grandma put him up to this.
Where's he taking us?
I don't know, but I
could make a guess.
Pardon me, sir. Is this the
only road from the beach?
Yep.
Would you care, sir, to earn $50?
Don't mind.
We wish you to obstruct the road
from the beach for two hours.
My employer is preparing
a surprise party...
Don't explain. Just
give me the money.
It's very romantic
here, don't you think?
Do you know that's the
first time I've ever heard
anyone use the word "romantic"
in a real conversation?
I hope I wasn't being too
forward, but it is romantic.
I think that's what
Grandma had in mind.
She always thought the Pacific
Ocean was very romantic.
Captain Steinmetz proposed to her
on the beach near the
Cliff House 50 years ago.
I'm sorry I punched you
the first time I met you.
That's okay.
It wasn't very ladylike to hit
you with a boiled lobster.
It's okay.
You can hit me back if you want.
That isn't exactly
what I had in mind.
Oh.
Herbie. Oh.
Oh, it's time we
were getting back.
Herbie, come on.
Leave that sea gull alone.
Herbie.
I wish that car would
learn to mind.
Herbie, please.
Herbie.
Heel, Herbie.
See? Just needs a firm hand.
You know, Willoughby, sometimes
you really surprise me.
Hey, what's happening?
Sorry, sir. My rear axle's frozen.
But, how're we...
Sorry.
No, Herbie.
Ooh.
Whoa.
Oh.
Oh, well, here we are.
Ah.
Nicole?
Very quietly and quickly, pull
your hand back inside the car.
Why?
We've got company.
That's ridiculous. Why would
a shark follow a Volkswagen?
Because he thinks the
same thing I do.
We're going to sink.
Excuse me.
Can you tell me the
way to San Francisco?
Yeah, man. Straight up the beach
road, first left, second right.
Thank you.
Whoa...
Old number 22, it's gone.
What?
They came with a big truck.
Everything's gone.
Who did it?
It said on the truck,
"Alonzo Hawk Van & Storage."
Haven't you ever
jimmied a lock before?
Of course not.
It isn't a hobby of mine.
Hurry. We can't just stand here.
Good for Herbie.
Halt.
You have been detected by
electronic surveillance.
You are about to be surrounded
by agents of the Alonzo
Hawk Security Service.
Touch nothing in this warehouse
or you will be prosecuted to
the full extent of the law.
Don't you dare talk to
me like that, Mr. Hawk.
I want my things back and
I'm going to have them.
I think that's a recording.
I don't care what it is.
Halt. You have been...
Let's find your things
before somebody gets here.
By agents of the Alonzo
Hawk Security Service.
Touch nothing in this warehouse
or you will be prosecuted to
the full extent of the law.
Your things aren't here.
Maybe we better...
All right, hold it.
Okay, get your hands up.
Don't you get fresh
with me, young man.
Watch it, Smitty. She's
the ring leader.
Come on, grandma. Move it.
Keep your hands up.
I most certainly will not.
If you say please, I
might consider it.
All right, please.
There now, you see, that
wasn't so difficult after all.
If you'd mind your manners,
life would be easier
for all of us.
Now, would you be good
enough to tell me exactly
what you are doing
with my furniture?
How do we know, lady?
All I can tell you is that nothing
goes out without Mr. Hawk's okay.
Look out, Smitty. Run.
There goes some more.
Out of the way.
Hey, we're out off. How're
we gonna get out of here?
You know, Smitty,
I don't think Mr.
Hawk's gonna be happy about this.
Whew.
Oh, evening, mother.
Ain't you a might old
to be a stewardess?
There've been a lot of changes
since I come to visit this town.
Barnsdorf, will you stop worrying
about your digging equipment?
You're paying me 80 grand a day.
Will you stop bothering me?
I have broken the old
lady's spirit. Yeah.
I've taken every
stick of furniture.
She's sitting in an
empty firehouse,
ready to listen to reason.
Barnsdorf, I guarantee you
you can start digging first
thing Monday morning.
Yeah.
What?
That's right, sir. Yes, they
got away with everything.
Call out every unit of the
mobile security force.
We'll nail 'em to the wall.
Stop at the top so
we can figure out
how to get down the other side.
Right.
Like I was saying, little lady,
I was doing fine
'til I got into that
sheep-dip you call
liquor in this town.
My name is Judson.
Got a little cow ranch a couple
hundred miles north of here.
Been alone with those cows for
over 40 years, so I thought
I'd get into town and stir
up a little excitement.
Might be my last opportunity.
I better get a piece
of rope and tie
us all up together, nice and snug.
Oh, no. It looks
like Uncle Alonzo.
No, Herbie. Don't do it.
Oooh.
After him.
Faster. Faster.
Oh, Herbie, now you
have got us in a mess.
Now, Herbie, stop this minute.
Hey, watch out. What
are you trying to do.
You busted my machine. Look,
here comes another one.
That's not nice. Look what you've
done to my "pretzellette".
Mrs. Steinmetz.
Mrs. Steinmetz, put on the brake.
You're a fine looking woman.
Did you say you was married?
No, the Captain's been
gone these many years.
There he is, Captain Steinmetz,
hook and ladder,
number 27, city of
San Francisco, a fine gentleman.
Nice picture.
You carry it around
with you everywhere?
Mrs. Steinmetz, use
the hand brake.
- Oh. You okay?
- Yeah.
I declare, little lady,
you're a sight to
make this country
boy's heart flutter.
Oh, don't be silly.
I'm much too old.
Oh-oho. The way I
figure it, you're
just about coming into your prime.
Can't that thing play something
with a little more pep?
How nice to see people
dressing up for parties again.
Was that anyone we know?
Looks like these
cars go a lot faster
than when I was a young fella.
Well, you can't stop progress.
Look at that.
Herbie, you gotta help us.
Steady, Herbie.
Come on. Come on. Move closer.
Hurry up. We're running
out of street.
Closer. A little more.
Go On, Jump.
Whoa.
Oh.
Well, here's where I get off.
Thanks for the ride, little
lady. Appreciate it.
Sure like to cross trails
with ya again sometime.
Are you all right, Grandma?
Of course.
I just met the most
interesting man.
Good morning, Grandma. Sleep
well after being up so late?
Not a wink, my dear.
I suddenly realised
what an enormous amount of trouble
Alonzo Hawk is giving me.
I'm going straight
down to his office
to give him a piece of my mind.
Oh, no, you don't.
Oh, I have to go.
Bye-bye, Grandma.
Please, don't do anything foolish.
Willoughby, I know Grandma and
I think she's up to something.
Don't worry, I'll keep
her out of mischief.
You better or else
I'll get tough again.
Bye.
Where are you going,
Mrs. Steinmetz?
To see Mr. Hawk.
Oh, no, you can't do that.
You heard what Nicole said.
Nicole is a very sweet
girl. But at her age
she shouldn't start
ordering me around.
Do you mind if I go with you?
That won't be necessary.
No, but I think Nicole
would prefer it.
Hey, come back. Mrs.
Steinmetz. Come back.
This certainly is a nasty
whiplash, Mr. Hawk.
I'm afraid you're
trying to do too much.
I know, Millicent.
But except for you,
who can I depend on?
I have to do every...
Who are those clowns?
Your new lawyers. You fired
the others yesterday.
Oh, now look, fellas, I'm gonna
tear down the Steinmetz firehouse.
Just a moment. You have
the necessary permit?
Of course I don't have a permit.
I don't even own the land yet.
Sorry, Mr. Hawk, such an
action would jeopardise
the legal status of
your new building.
We can't permit you...
Will you get outta here?
I didn't hire you to
tell me what I can't do.
I hired ya to tell
me how I can do it.
Go.
You see, everybody lets me
down. You know me, Millicent.
I'm enthusiastic, boyishly eager.
All I get is cheap lawyer talk.
Poor Mr. Hawk. It isn't fair.
Nevertheless, I shall not falter.
I am like a sensitive,
finely-tuned violin.
All I need to restore me is a
few moments of peace and quiet.
Hey. Hey.
Hey, you out there.
Hey.
Hey, turn it off.
You idiot. What do you
think you're doing?
Washing the windows, every
Wednesday, Mr. Hawk's orders.
I am Mr. Hawk. Get out of here.
Okay, cancel the windows.
And you better shut the window.
Runs up the air conditioning bill.
You're fired, get your money...
Mr. Hawk's orders.
They may harass me,
but don't let them ever
think they have me beaten.
That is when Alonzo Hawk
is at his most dangerous.
Yes, sir.
Millicent.
This is what I want you to do.
I want you to try and get
Fred Loostgarten on
the phone for me.
He used to work with our wrecking
company before I fired him.
I understand he has a little
one-horse operation
of his own now.
Yes, I think that's how Captain
Steinmetz would
handle the situation.
Excuse me, could you tell me
where Mr. Hawk's office is?
Yes, ma'am, the old
buzzard hangs out
28 stories up, six
windows to the left.
You can't miss it.
I'm sorry. I don't hear
so good from this side.
28th floor. You can't miss it.
Thank you so much.
No. Mrs. Steinmetz. Stop.
Mrs. Steinmetz. Come back. Stop.
Mrs. Steinmetz. Help.
Grandma. Mrs. Steinmetz.
Help.
Missus... Grandma.
Help. Mrs. Steinmetz.
Grandma. Help. Mrs.
Steinmetz. Help.
Grandma.
Is that you, Mr. Whitfield?
Where are you?
Down here.
Help me.
Oh, there you are.
Just a minute. I'm coming.
No, no, stay where you are.
Just take us down.
Of course, Mr. Whitfield.
But first you must promise
to let me see Mr. Hawk.
Anything. I'll do
anything you say.
Very well, Mr. Whitfield.
Hey, Loostgarten, old
buddy, how are ya?
I know things haven't
been going too
well for ya, but that's
the way life is.
Yeah, right, Mr. Hawk.
I got to thinking...
I've got to find a job for my
old friend, and here it is.
You know that crummy old firehouse
on the site where I'm
building Hawk's Plaza?
Yeah?
I want you to get your
wrecking ball and smash it.
I want nothing left but
itsy-bitsy splinters.
Don't worry, Willoughby. I shall
be perfectly polite... But firm.
What do you mean, "send
you over a permit"?
I don't get one 'til
tomorrow morning.
Yeah, but, Mr. Hawk, I...
Loostgarten.
The job has gotta be done tonight.
Take it or leave it.
Millicent, my dear, will you put a
check in the mail to Loostgarten?
That's Loostgarten Wrecking
Company, a thousand on account.
Tonight he's gonna smash that
crummy firehouse to matchwood.
That'll teach that old
battle axe a lesson.
No, no, Grandma, he
won't like that.
I don't care what he doesn't like.
Knock down my home, will he?
Oh, no. Uncle Alonzo, I don't
believe you've met Mrs. Steinmetz.
How do you do?
Don't worry, Uncle.
Everything's under control.
Yeah, just dandy.
Now you've done it, Mr. Hawk.
You've made Herbie very angry.
No. No. Get out. Get out. Get out.
No. No. No. Go away.
No. Herbie. Stop.
Ooh. Wrong way.
Stay away from me.
Somebody come in here
and stop this thing.
Don't you think we ought to see
what all those noises are?
When Mr. Hawk says he doesn't
want to be disturbed, that's it.
Herbie.
Uncle?
Now's a good time to explain.
You.
Help.
Herbie, stop it.
Will you be going out
for a while, Mr. Hawk?
Herbie.
Gotta get away from that thing.
- Good morning, Miss Millicent.
- Good morning.
Mrs. Steinmetz?
I told you Mr. Hawk was busy.
Aw, shut up. And get
off my building.
There must be some way
to make this car behave.
I don't like to threaten Herbie.
He has been trying to help us.
But there's one thing
Herbie is afraid of.
Whoa.
Now stop, Herbie.
Don't make me do it.
Please, do it, Grandma.
Very well, Herbie.
It so happens that I know
this nice used car lot.
I'd certainly hate to call Mr.
Honest Al, the used car man.
Of course, you know I
never would do it.
And between you and
me, I don't think
Herbie believes I would either.
But it always works.
What a lovely morning.
I thoroughly enjoyed it.
Did we get the name
of the gentleman
who thinks he's going to
knock down my firehouse?
It was Loostgarten,
of the Loostgarten
Wrecking Company.
I'm going to write that down.
We're going to need it.
Well, thanks anyway for
trying Millie. Bye.
Millie's one of the stews who
works for Hawk's airline.
She can't find his address either.
May I say something?
No, I'm still mad at you for
not taking care of Grandma.
If we can't find out where he
lives, my idea won't work.
We'll just have to think
of something else.
I am going to say something.
I've sent Uncle Alonzo
a card every Christmas
since I was seven years old,
and here's his address.
Willoughby, oh. You're wonderful.
Right.
Loostgarten speaking.
This is Alonzo Hawk.
Right, Mr. Hawk.
Loostgarten, there's been
a slight change of plan.
I don't want you to knock
down that firehouse tonight.
Instead I want you to knock
down 343 Oleander Heights.
You got that? 343
Oleander Heights.
Right.
Write it down.
I don't want to see
you blackballed
in the wrecking ball business,
If you get what I mean.
You were wonderful.
Oh.
Yes... I know it's 3:00 in the
morning, but I can't sleep.
Well, you're my doctor, aren't ya?
Sometimes the
old-fashioned remedies
seem to work best, Mr. Hawk.
Have you ever tried
counting sheep?
Sheep.
Picture in your mind's eye
a grassy green meadow,
a whitewashed, three-rail fence,
a flock of sweet little sheep.
They begin to jump over
the fence. One sheep...
Six sheep, seven sheep,
eight sheep, nine sheep,
ten...
Yeah, what is it?
Sorry to disturb ya at this
time of night, Mr. Hawk.
But a guy in my job can't
afford to make mistakes.
What are you talking about?
That address you gave
me on the phone.
What about it?
343 Oleander Heights.
Are you sure that's
the right address?
Of course I'm sure, you idiot.
I know it as well as I
know my own address.
Wait a minute. It
is my own address.
Loostgarten. No. Not
this. This is my house.
You dumb jerk.
Loostgarten. This time
you're really through. Help.
You...
We beat him.
I knew he'd cave in. He just
couldn't stand the heat.
Hello? Oh, good morning, Mr. Hawk.
Well, now that it's all over, I
just had to phone you and tell you
how much I admire the
plucky fight you
put up for that sweet
little firehouse.
Oh, thank you, Mr. Hawk.
Well, what brought about
my change of heart
was an accident to
my own little house.
It only brought home
to me how terrible
it is to lose something
you really love.
What happened, Mr. Hawk?
Well, a very confused
man came along
and knocked down the
whole side of it,
smashed it to rubble.
Someone knocked down
Mr. Hawk's house.
Aw, what a rotten shame.
But it...
It did serve a purpose.
It made me realise I can't
knock down any more
of San Francisco's
beautiful old buildings.
So I don't want you
to worry that sweet,
little, grey head
of yours about it.
Is that clear?
Yes, Mr. Hawk. Thank
you, Mr. Hawk.
All right, Mrs. Steinmetz, and
I'll drop by one of these days
and have a cup of tea with you.
Bye.
I always said you'd do the
finer thing, Mr. Hawk.
What are you talking
about, fathead?
Giving up Hawk Plaza.
Are you fooled by
this phony story?
But, Mr. Hawk, you
can't go back on this.
Oh yes, I can. I can
say I was misquoted.
I can say they printed
the story purposefully
to discredit me in the
eyes of the public.
Well, it's an old gag. It's
out of my bag of tricks.
You mean we're still going
after the old lady?
Right for the jugular vein, baby,
right for the old jugular.
I wish Grandma would
hurry up and get here.
Can't start a celebration
party without her.
It gives us a chance
to have a quiet
talk. We never had one before.
Something always
happened. Oh, thank you.
Nicole, there's something
I've been wanting to say.
What's that, Willoughby?
Did I ever tell you that my
great-grandfather Whitfield
was one of the first men to go
over Niagara Falls in a barrel?
Oh, well, was he all
right afterwards?
I don't know. They
never found him.
I think I'll call Grandma.
The giant lobster is
very good tonight, sir.
Of course, no lobster.
I did mean to call,
dear. But I was
just sitting here
thinking to myself
what a fine time those
two young people
must be having without
me in the way.
Now listen, Grandma, I
love you very much,
but I've had enough
of your matchmaking.
Now you get over here
like you promised.
If I do marry Willoughby,
I'd like the
satisfaction of
nailing him myself.
Do go ahead without
me, dear. I think
I'll just have a quiet
evening at home.
Goodbye, dear.
Now, do go on with your wonderful
story about the cows, Mr. Judson.
I swear I never seen a
handsome woman like yourself
who had so much an
interest in cows.
That's quite natural, Mr. Judson.
After all, a cow is
not only useful,
but an extremely
decorative animal.
Ain't it just.
As I was saying, I got this
nice little 200-acre
spread up in Oregon.
What in tarnation
you doing that for?
I'm not quite sure. I think
I saw this once in a movie.
Oh, no.
Just let me get my hands on the
brute responsible for this.
Now. Horse whipping's
too good for him.
What on Earth?
It's Mr. Hawk.
Herbie. Don't you dare.
Oh. Every man for himself.
Herbie must have gone for help.
Hope he makes it through to
the fort. We must be cut off.
Okay, Steinmetz. We
know you're in there.
We've got you surrounded.
We'll give you 10 minutes to get
your stuff together and get out
before I grind this
dump to powder.
Now you hold on there, Mister.
This little lady's
under my personal
protection and she stays here.
Ten minutes, Steinmetz.
To get back to my
great-grandfather
at Niagara Falls,
I don't think I put it quite
right. What I wanted to say was,
though we Whitfield men
look like rabbits,
we have always liked challenge,
the scent of danger
in our nostrils,
the high road to adventure.
Yes, Willoughby?
That's why I want to
go on seeing you.
Not to deprecate your physical
attributes, certainly,
but because there is this
feeling of danger about you,
of something about to happen.
You're right, Willoughby.
Looks like we've just
picked up a friend.
Three minutes to go, Steinmetz.
This is your last chance.
Make your play, Hawk.
We're standing pat.
I think Captain Steinmetz would
have liked you, Mr. Judson.
You're his kind of man.
Thank you, ma'am.
Hey.
Attention. One minute to zero.
Gentlemen, start your engines.
Here come the hostiles.
We're ready for 'em.
I think Captain Steinmetz would
have liked you to wear this.
Why, I'd be proud to, little lady.
Mighty proud.
Power shovel number one, ready?
Ready, Mr. Hawk.
Full speed ahead. Go.
Fire.
Hey. Hey.
Stop. Help.
Cease fire.
Good shooting, Mr. Judson.
Thank you. That one won't
bother us for a while.
Hurry. Move in with the crawler.
All right, Mr. Hawk.
Fire.
Please, stop it. No.
Ceasefire.
There goes another one. We got
the devils on the run. Fire.
Oh, no.
Are you all right?
Don't worry about me, ma'am.
What we gotta worry about,
we're plumb outta ammunition.
This time we all go in together.
We got nothing to
regret, little lady.
We done our best.
Ready.
Drive. Drive. Let's get
going. Get outta here.
Hi, Grandma. Hi, there.
Why, that rascal. She's
got a man with her.
No wonder she wouldn't
come to our party.
Faster. Faster. Faster.
Wait a minute. Back.
Why don't ya look
where you're going?
How dare you raise your voice
to me, you myopic oaf.
Hey. What do you think
you're... Whoa.
All right, Herbie.
That's enough now.
You think you're gonna
make him stop? Fat chance.
Herbie, if you don't stop, you
won't be invited to the wedding.
Ah, it's you again, Mr. Hawk.
Save me. Save me. They're
after me. They're after me.
Who's after you?
Those little cars...
Hundreds of 'em.
Can't you see them, you idiot?
Mr. Hawk, I wonder, would you mind
coming down to my
place of business?
I would be happy to.
I would... Ooh. Ooh.
Ooh. Ooh.
And what happened then?
Willoughby told Herbie that
if he didn't stop, he wouldn't
be invited to the wedding.
Wait a minute. What wedding?