♪ Digga-digga-dog ♪
♪ Digga-digga-dog digga-digga-dog ♪
♪ Bow-wow-wow ♪
♪ Digga-digga-dog ♪
♪ Digga-digga-dog, dog, dog ♪
- You dog, you!
♪ Bow-wow-wow ♪
♪ Digga-digga-dog ♪
♪ Digga-digga-dog digga-digga-dog ♪
♪ Bow-wow-wow ♪
♪ Digga-digga-dog ♪
♪ Digga-digga-dog, dog, dog ♪
- You dog, you!
♪ Bow-wow-wow ♪
♪ yippee-yo, yippee-yay ♪
♪ Ain't that ♪
♪ the man in the moon ♪
♪ Dancin' over our heads ♪
♪ Atomic Dog ♪
♪ Yeah, while all good dogs
are asleep in their beds ♪
♪ Atomic dog ♪
♪ ohh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Smiling in their dreams ♪
♪ At the crazy things ♪
♪ people do ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ And when you think ♪
♪ you've fooled them ♪
♪ Who'll make a fool ♪
♪ out of who ♪
♪ Whoa-ohh-ohh ♪
You dog, you!
♪ Don't be believin' ♪
♪ Bow-wow-wow ♪
♪ Looks are deceivin' ♪
- You dog, you!
♪ Bow-wow-wow ♪
♪ Don't be believin' ♪
♪ Looks are deceivin' ♪
You dog, you!
♪ Bow-wow-wow ♪
♪ Yippee-yo, yippee-yay ♪
♪ You think ♪
♪ you're on top of the game ♪
♪ You got a lot to learn ♪
♪ Atomic Dog ♪
♪ yeah, you do ♪
Woof!
♪ When life hangs tough ♪
♪ Take a dog-legged turn ♪
♪ Atomic Dog ♪
♪ yeah, uh-huh-huh ♪
♪ People, they think ♪
♪ they're so cool ♪
♪ If they throw you a bone ♪
♪ Hey ♪
♪ Arf Arf! ♪
♪ Wait till they discover ♪
♪ You've got some tricks ♪
♪ of your own ♪
♪ Ah, hey, hey-ey-ey ♪
You dog, you!
♪ Don't be believin' ♪
♪ Bow-wow-wow ♪
♪ Looks are deceivin' ♪
♪ You dog, you! ♪
♪ Bow-wow-wow ♪
♪ Don't be believin' ♪
♪ Looks are deceivin' ♪
You dog, you!
♪ Bow-wow-wow ♪
♪ A-bow-wow-wow ♪
♪ Spotted dog spotted dog ♪
♪ Where have you been ♪
♪ I've been to London ♪
♪ to look at the queen ♪
♪ Can you tell ♪
♪ a spotted story ♪
♪ Yes, I can ♪
♪ I saw a dog ♪
♪ who was walkin' a man ♪
Oww!
You dog, you!
♪ Bow-wow-wow ♪
♪ Don't be believin' ♪
♪ Oh-ohh-ohh ♪
♪ Bow-wow-wow ♪
♪ Looks are deceivin' ♪
♪ Hey, you dog, you ♪
♪ Bow-wow-wow ♪
♪ Digga-digga-dog ♪
♪ Don't give me no more rules ♪
♪ Digga-digga-dog digga-digga-dog ♪
♪ Digga-digga-dog ♪
♪ Dog, dog ♪
You dog, you!
My client is not a laboratory
animal, Dr. Pavlov.
Your client wants out of prison, Mr.
Torte,
and with my behavior
control therapy,
freedom is…
Mmm!
I have patented
a humane cocktail…
Of electric shock treatment,
Aversion therapy, hypnosis,
drugs…
And plenty of green vegetables.
But, of course, the
real challenge remains.
I mean, this is a
prison, not a pet shop.
And I don't
represent animals in court.
Dr. Pavlov, my client…
is cured.
Oooh!
Oooh-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Brush up your Swedish,
Dr. Pavlov.
This could be your nobel prize!
Cruella De Vil.
Do call me Ella.
Cruella sounds so…
Cruel.
Ms. De vil, I am releasing you into
the custody of the probation office.
You will perform 500 hours
of community service.
Mr. Torte, your client is,
I believe, a wealthy woman.
After my exorbitant fees,
milord,
her assets stand
at a mere â£8 million.
Then you will be bound over to keep
the peace to the sum of â£8 million.
If forfeited,
the money will be donated…
To the dogs' homes
of the borough of westminster.
Which means,
if you repeat the offense,
your entire fortune
will go to the dogs.
Alonzo.
My ever-loyal valet.
My only visitor,
stuttering sweetly on the far, far
side of the bulletproof glass.
Oh, miss De vil, I've
w-waited for this d-day.
I hope it's not too presumptuous,
but I've brought you a g-g-gift.
Oh, Alonzo, how considerate.
Oh!
I think I'll call him fluffy.
Oh, he's smiling at me.
Oh, what a sweet voice.
Wrong side, Alonzo.
Come, fluffy.
Mummy will drive.
I told you
you wouldn't believe the truth.
The dog ate your pay stubs.
Ewan, can't you do
a little better than that?
I was abducted by aliens.
- Put me out at piccadilly, they did.
- It was a…
How can you work here? I can't
even keep me own story straight.
Listen.
I won't say it again.
No pay stub, no probation.
Dog shelter suits me.
I-I think I found meself.
Mm-hmm.
Here's a snap of me
with the dogs.
Uh, that's the boss.
He's a top bloke.
You'd love him.
Ah. Told ya.
Drooler got ahold of it.
Ewan,
this is an I.O.U.
- Well, we're a bit tight on funds at the moment.
- Chloe, this is…
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
Ewan was just off.
All right.
Thanks, miss.
Uh, next week, then?
Yes. With pay stubs.
Am I being clear?
Uh, supremely.
Keep the photo.
You do put the
fear of god into them, Chloe.
Which is why I've chosen
you to…
Is it… line three!
Hello?
Is it… yes! Stay there!
Keep breathing, and I'll be
there in a second.
Oh! Ah.
Oh! Goodness.
Hurry!
See you soon!
Chloe! Chloe!
You forgot this.
W-what… ah.
Oh, for Pete's sake.
Are you two at it again?
Kevin, how many times
have I had to tell you…
It's pointless for you humans to
play tug-of-war against us dogs.
Come on, drooler!
Hit him with both barrels!
Yes! You got it!
He's ours! He's down!
He's… he's getting up!
Well, I always say, if you
can't stand the heat, cheat!
Hurry, boys!
Get in there!
We dogs need to stick together.
All right, chomp,
sock it to him!
Can you dig it, digger?
Let's get ready to tumble!
Hey! Hey!
That's not fair!
Yes, it is! All's
fair in tug-of-war!
I took you misfits in out of the goodness
of my heart, and this is how you repay me?
That's pathetic, kev. How many
times you gonna fall for that one?
I managed to get another week out
of my probation officer, boss.
Think she quite fancies me.
Come on, boys.
It's grub time.
Where'd you get that dog food?
Didn't pinch it, did you?
No. I'm done
with all that.
There you go.
Fill your belly.
Come on.
Good girl.
Okay, who's next?
Hey.
Fill 'er up, kev.
I'm a very hungry dog.
Oh, thank you.
Hey! Hey, wait!
Come back with my grub!
Come on, waddlesworth.
Today's the day.
Fly up to your house, and then I'll
feed you. Come on, waddlesworth, fly!
No, I've told you once, I've told you
a hundred times: We dogs can't fly!
See? Now stand
aside, birdbrain.
Save some for tomorrow. I don't know
where our next meal's coming from.
Me mum always said, "when the heart
hopes, hope comes knocking."
"'Eart 'opes"?
Hope comes knocking.
What? Evicted?
But you said…
you shouldn't believe what people say.
I don't.
You can't turn all these
dogs loose in the city.
Give us another chance. I'm not
the one running a charity here.
- Maybe you can get
away with this…
You and your mangy pack
are out of here tomorrow!
You'd better not leave
any of this junk about!
Next time I'll bite
your bum, you smelly little git.
Don't worry.
Everything'll be all right.
Oh, Dottie, they're
absolutely beautiful.
Aren't they, dipstick?
You must be very proud.
You are an odd one, aren't you?
There you go.
Now you should get some rest.
Come on, dipstick.
It's smaller than I remember.
I k-kept everything
just as you l-left it.
Oh, come, fluffy.
We'll share a bath.
An interminable soak…
Scented with lavender…
And a drop of sumatran…
Tsk-tsk-tsk.
Never mind.
I think I'll enjoy
doing a little dusting.
Oh, fluffy, a bath,
Followed by a nap…
Submerged in feather pillows and satin…
Alonzo!
Fur! It's everywhere!
Lock them away! Bury them
beyond sight and memory!
- Even the Mongolian pony skin trousers and the…
- Now!
And this!
Is it safe?
Yes, it's s-safe.
I do not believe it.
How could they release
that… that…
I pity the poor probation
officer that has to look af…
oh, no.
No, it's not possible.
Oh!
Well, I refuse.
I'm not doing it.
What?
You remember her, don't you?
You remember what she
almost did to you.
Dipstick.
Okay.
I'll do it for you.
And for the family.
Miss De vil.
Yes?
You're five minutes late.
It's a good start.
Well, perhaps your clock's fast.
I'm your probation officer,
Chloe Simon.
Yes, of course you are.
And we're going to be
such friends.
Mmm. Friends.
You are going to help me be a useful
member of society, aren't you?
Find me
a little niche somewhere?
Could you manage something
with puppy dogs?
I see you as a coal miner,
or something
in the sewers, perhaps.
Ah, I see.
Oh!
You have doggies?
Yes, and I don't want you
looking at them.
I'm sorry. I…
listen, can we just be
sensible about this?
Yes! Let's.
Well, must dash.
Bye.
This is your last chance,
Mr. Button.
When the press sees what you're
doing to these poor dogs,
you'll be the most
hated man in London.
I don't see any press,
but I can guarantee
the bailiff is on his way.
Right!
That's it, Mr. Buttocks!
That one's vicious, he is!
They're here!
Everyone on your best behavior.
Pick up your signs.
Come on.
Here! Here we are outside
the second chance…
you're just in time. Excuse me.
I'm trying to…
no, the dogs are over here. These
rescued dogs are being evicted…
just one moment!
This man has no right…
here she comes!
Who she comes?
- Cruella De Vil?
- Cruella! Cruella!
Cruella!
Please!
Call me Ella.
Ella! Ella!
Well.
This place and I
were made for each other.
Is it yours?
No, it's mine.
And he… Alonzo.
Buy the dump.
And give him a little extra
for a tie.
So, could you tell us how Cruella
De Vil became plain Ella?
Well, I certainly can. It was all
thanks to Dr. Pavlov and his therapy.
Do you really think
that you, a convicted dognapper,
are the right person
to run this establishment?
Second chance
dog shelter says it all.
And I think I deserve a
second chance too. Don't you?
No, I do not.
She tricked me!
It's
the red baron, king of the sky!
Stop playing
and give me a hand here.
Look. Another volunteer.
See, Ewan? There are
good-hearted people everywhere.
Beautiful good-hearted people.
That's my probation officer!
What, that's
your probation officer?
- Are you Kevin Shepherd?
- Yes. Yes, I'm Kevin…
and you call yourself
a dog lover?
Well, yes, I do. I am.
He does. He is.
I'll get to you, Ewan.
I'm Chloe Simon.
Cruella De Vil's
probation officer.
Oh!
She's in the back.
Is there some problem?
I mean, uh…
excuse us, chomp.
I mean, miss De vil, she seems
devoted to…
Nice bird!
You are a nice bird.
I'm not a bird.
He means you.
Where are your manners?
Buried in the yard with my bone.
This is…
um… Chloe. Chloe Simon.
Chloe, meet waddlesworth.
He's a rottweiler.
Hello.
That's funny, because he looks
like a macaw.
Trust me.
He's a rottweiler.
I don't think I trust anyone who knowingly
puts Cruella anywhere near dogs.
Well, yes, but she's changed.
- People like Cruella don't change.
- Of course they do.
That's why I started second chance. I
knew what it was like to need one.
And the same goes
for dogs. Eh?
Take chomp here, for example.
He chewed through three postmen before I
rescued him. Now he wouldn't hurt a flea.
And digger, he was banned from every
park in London as a menace to roses.
And drooler…
well, drooler hasn't
really changed much.
- Those are dogs.
- Oh, but dogs are people too.
- But Cruella is…
- changed.
Who's washing who, Alonzo?
Now, hair must be a statement,
a reflection of our inner life.
Color is important, of course,
but texture is vital.
Voila!
Oh, darling, darling.
It's you.
Do you like it? I'll be
keeping my eye on her.
I hope so.
♪ Cruella De Vil ♪
Three!
♪ Just hearing her name ♪
♪ used to make you feel ill ♪
♪ Now suddenly she's ♪
♪ drippin' with good will ♪
♪ Can this be ♪
♪ Cruella De Vil ♪
♪ A heartwarmin' laugh ♪
♪ Instead of a scream ♪
♪ She's practically human ♪
♪ Or so it would seem ♪
♪ As playful ♪
♪ as a puppy in the snow ♪
♪ That's not ♪
♪ the Cruella we know ♪
♪ Oh, remember ♪
♪ when she lived ♪
♪ Just to be rotten ♪ ♪
♪ How she loved to frighten ♪
♪ the little tots ♪
♪ Who thought ♪
♪ she could be kind ♪
♪ Respectful and refined ♪
♪ Has the lady ♪
♪ really changed her spots ♪
♪ Oh, lord ♪
♪ Oooh-ooh, oooh-ooh ♪
♪ oooh-ooh, oooh-ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Cruella De Vil ♪
♪ Now check this out ♪
♪ you know what ♪
♪ She gave up her bark ♪
♪ but will she still bite ♪
♪ What's wrong ♪
♪ with this picture ♪
♪ It doesn't look right ♪
♪ Unfortunately ♪
♪ only time will tell ♪
♪ If Cruella ♪
♪ I mean, Ella ♪
♪ Is from heaven or hell ♪
♪ ooh, yeah ♪
And now BBC 2
is proud to present…
The third part in our series,
What makes Big Ben tick?
Turn down the television, quick!
What a unique sound pattern.
Very loud.
That would be Ben on the telly.
Yes.
It must have jolted their
brain waves back into…
this mustn't get out.
Do you hear me?
It never happened.
What are you doing?
You're… yes.
And this is domino.
Little Dipper's easy because his
tail is exactly like his daddy's.
And I know oddball
because she doesn't have any…
shh!
I don't want her to be sensitive
about her lack of, um,
s-p-o-t-s.
Oh. Is that normal
at her age?
Well, like everything else
about her,
it is a bit…
Odd.
Hello? Is that you, Nigel?
I know you're there.
I can hear you breathing.
Will you take them up to
your office for a while?
'Cause I just keep
staring at them,
and I'm falling dreadfully behind
with my paperwork, as you can see.
Yes, I can see.
It's probably just as well
with miss De vil coming in.
- Cruella?
- Y-yes.
She asked to change her appointment.
I thought you knew.
Come on, oddball,
little Dipper, dipstick.
Quick, quick, quick, quick!
Cruella De Vil, that wretched…
philanthropist? Cruella,
I didn't realize…
oh, please, please call me Ella.
Now, Chloe, you can't stop me.
It's my duty to demonstrate
against a fur fashion show.
And it's my duty to inform you
that if you go anywhere near fur,
I'll put you
straight back in prison.
Won't you even let me heckle
that monstrous LePelt?
- No.
- Just a teensy-weensy heckle?
You know… murderer!
Round two!
Knockout!
Body blow! Body blow!
Bonus fall.
Round three!
I have so much to atone for.
I'm seeing spots.
Dr. Pavlov!
Oddball!
Grab my legs! Grab my legs!
What… oh!
Oddball! Aah!
Aaah!
Ohh!
How did you get out?
Are these your lovely dogs?
Yes. Are you all right?
Dipstick, shh, please!
I remember you…
As a puppy.
Aah!
Why don't I come back later.
I'm feeling a little…
Chilly.
Aaah!
Aah! Aah!
Um, wouldn't you be more
c-comfortable in the c-car?
Aaah!
Ella?
Not Ella.
Ella's gone.
And Cruella's back!
Pull! Pull!
Stand aside, worm.
Aaah!
Oh, mummy's home, and I'll
never leave you again!
Oh, yes!
Oh, hello!
Oh!
Why do I feel incomplete?
What could be missing
from my life?
Cruella De Vil, who has it all!
The softest, the rarest,
the whitest, the blackest,
the stripiest,
the sportiest, the…
- hmm?
- Of course.
Where is it?
Where?
Oh, there it is.
My dalmatian puppy coat.
The coat of dreams.
The ultimate fur coat…
That was denied me
by that canine cabal…
For which I have lost
three years of my life!
Alonzo!
- We are going to make them pay.
- Oh, yes! How much?
Dipstick, she called him.
Ah, what fiendish justice.
He escaped me, but I shall wreak my
vengeance on the next generation.
S-sounds w-wonderful.
Alonzo, I need you.
I'm yours.
Furnish yourself with a torch,
a large sack
and rubber-soled shoes.
Meanwhile, I need a furrier.
And I know
just where to find him.
♪ Freak out ♪
♪ Le freak, c'est chic ♪
♪ Aww, freak out ♪
♪ Freak out ♪
♪ le freak, c'est chic ♪
♪ Aww, freak out ♪
♪ look at me in this big spotlight ♪
♪ I'll make this ♪
♪ one magical night ♪
♪ I am fierce ♪
♪ And we are fabulous ♪
♪ Freak out, so fabulous ♪
♪ so fierce ♪
♪ Freak out ♪
♪ so beautiful ♪
♪ So beautiful ♪
♪ so freaky ♪
♪ Freak out ♪
♪ so fabulous ♪
♪ So fabulous ♪
♪ so hip ♪
♪ Freak out ♪
♪ so beautiful ♪
♪ So beautiful ♪
♪ so freaky ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Some kind of love ♪
♪ Ah, freak out ♪
Murderer! Murderer!
Killers!
- Come on, you.
- You're nicked!
No! No!
Monsieur LePelt! Monsieur LePelt!
Get out!
Animals!
They are all animals!
They have no class! Ooh!
But, monsieur…
Leave me alone!
No… no…
aaah!
Not here!
Forgive me.
My idiots didn't recognize you.
Only two minions to abuse?
Oh, Jean-Pierre,
the world is so unfair.
Get out! You are unfit to look
upon this goddess of fashion!
Out! Out!
Cruella De Vil,
my idol, my inspiration,
at my show.
I am so sorry
for the demonstrators.
Demonstrators?
I thought they were critics.
Go away!
Jean-Pierre,
you've come such a long way
from poaching weasels.
And you, out of prison at last.
Yes.
Terrible experience, prison.
Who are you, little man? And what
are you doing in my trailer?
You shouldn't have brought them
in here, you idiot! But I…
he's with you!
Aah!
What is this?
Your salvation, Jean-Pierre.
Monsieur LePelt
has clearly run out of ideas.
I propose…
An alliance…
Mmm?
Between monsieur LePelt…
And the house of De vil.
You have an idea in the bag?
Oh, Jean-Pierre.
Together,
you and I will make a coat…
So soft, so luxurious,
so practical in any weather,
so bad that we'll rip the veils
off the eyes of fashion…
And write our names
in the pantheon of stars.
Of course.
From "poopies."
Ah, not just any "poopies."
"Poopies" with…
Spots.
Hey, wait for me!
Enjoy the show.
One adult, three dogs
and one bird, please.
Oy, I'm a dog, mate.
Four dogs.
Well, look who's here.
Blimey!
I'm seein' spots!
Hello, Kevin.
Chloe! Are you,
uh… yeah, I'm going.
- And are these your dalmatians?
- Yeah.
This is digger, chomp and drooler.
You call that a bark?
This is a bark.
That's right.
Go hide behind mummy.
And… oddball.
He's not gonna hurt you.
Your change, sir.
Oh. Thank you.
- Don't you count your change?
- Well, why should I?
Now it all makes sense.
What?
How you could actually believe
that Cruella De Vil had changed.
She h changed.
Shh! The show's gonna start.
Let's just enjoy the show.
Let's.
- Hello, everybody!
- Hello, Mr. Punch!
Hello, everybody!
Hello, Judy!
Give us a kiss. Aaah!
Everybody would laugh at us!
- Wouldn't you, everyone?
- No!
All right, one kiss.
Ready? Eeeek!
Oh, you are awful!
There's a dog around here today.
Ohh!
- If you see a dog, will you tell us, please?
- Yes!
- I won't be long then. Bye-bye!
- Bye!
I don't see any dog. Where is it?
Oh, dear.
What is it?
Oddball's obsessed with…
S-p-o-t-s.
- Spots?
- Shh!
What? What'd I do?
I just said "spots."
Help! Help!
Help! Help! Oh!
Oh, no!
Help, help!
Help! Help!
Ohh!
Oddball!
Oddball, no!
Follow that dog!
Ooh! Oh!
What's that?
Oy!
They've got balloons!
Oddball! Stop!
Get 'em back here!
Where is that dog?
Hold on! We're coming!
Waddlesworth.
Oddball!
Now's your chance. You fly up
there and just cut a few strings.
- Not all of them!
- Right, just a few! Come on, waddlesworth!
You can do it! Fly! No! Owww!
Let go of my paw, you twit! I
told you I couldn't fly! Ohh!
Honestly!
Don't worry. I'll go.
Hey, hey, what you doing?
Hey, get off… oww!
Got her.
Oddball.
Oh.
Oh, Kevin, I don't know
how to thank you. Oops.
Uh, how about dinner?
Sorry?
I was inviting you to dinner.
Dinner would be nice.
A coat
to make the world "shuvver."
"Shudder."
"shutter"?
Shudder?
Sh…
shiver?
Exactement.
Genius!
Yes, but…
I need…
A special something…
For three special puppies.
Too dressy?
Too dressy.
Too stuffy.
Too small. Too blue.
Dottie, I've got nothing to wear.
Please help me.
What's that?
Dottie, are you sure?
It's completely
see-through. Look.
Oddball.
Yeah, that's a sweater.
But…
what a fantastic idea!
Thank you!
Thanks, oddball.
My brilliance astounds me.
No. No.
We should add the "poopies" to the hem.
Oh, you wouldn't dare.
But this is last year's length!
If Cruella De Vil draws it,
it defies length.
No. No!
No…
What?
Forty dalmatian puppies…
Sh-shipped off to Paris…
To h-his shop.
Not enough.
We need 102.
This time I want
a hooded spotted puppy coat.
- Hooded spotted p-puppy coat?
- "Hooded spotted poopie coat?"
But 99 puppies
would make a lovely coat.
- It's not that easy to steal…
- Steal? Who said anything about steal?
What did you think, LePelt, that
we'd have time to breed them?
Skinning is one thing,
but stealing…
oh, stop whining.
I have a perfectly good idiot…
To take the fall.
Not you, Alonzo.
Another idiot.
On, dasher, on,
dancer, on, digger, on, drooler!
Look at me! I'm Rudolph, the red-nosed
rein-dog with a present for miss oddball.
Hello?
I'll be right out, Kevin.
Take your time.
Oh, right.
Chomp's brought his favorite video.
Is that all right?
Is it suitable for the children?
Yes, it's absolutely fine.
Is everything all right?
Yes. Beautiful.
Um, waddlesworth, he's brought
a present for oddball.
Yeah, about time. This thing was
gettin' heavy. Hang on, pup.
Keep your spots on…
sorry. You don't have any.
Here you go. There.
Come on, show us.
Mr. Puppeteer and I
came to an agreement.
Oh, Kevin, thank you.
It's brilliant.
Come here, you.
Well, I think it's a success.
Looking good, girl!
Looking… oh, no!
Oddball's got no underwear!
Look away, children!
Turn a blind eye!
Excuse me, young lady.
Is this spot taken?
I can see we're not needed.
As soon as the video's over,
straight to bed for the children.
No more telly.
Bye.
Be good.
Anybody wanna order takeout?
So, where was I?
Oh, yes.
I started the shelter,
and we were going down for the third
time when Cruella stepped in.
Her again.
Yes.
But did you know that if she
ever goes back to dognapping,
all her millions will go straight into the
dogs' homes of the borough of westminster?
Yes, I did.
It's in her file.
Thank you.
How did you know that?
She told me.
And did you know…
That second chance is the only
dog shelter in the borough?
You're joking.
Mmm!
Can you imagine what drooler
would do with â£8 million?
Now, tell-a me,
what's-a you pleasure?
A la carte?
Dinner?
Aha. Okay.
Hey, Joe!
Butch, he says he wants
two spaghetti speciale,
heavy on the meats-a-ball.
Tony, dogs-a don't-a talk!
He's-a talk-a to me! Okay, he's-a
talk-a to you. You the boss.
Mama Mia.
Now here you are.
The best-a spaghetti in-a town.
♪ Oh, this is the night ♪
♪ It's a beautiful night ♪
♪ And we call it Bella notte ♪
♪ Look at the skies ♪
♪ They have stars ♪
♪ in their eyes ♪
♪ On this lovely ♪
♪ Bella notte ♪
♪ Side by side ♪
♪ With your loved one ♪
♪ You'll find ♪
♪ enchantment here ♪
♪ The night will weave ♪
♪ its magic spell ♪
♪ When the one ♪
♪ you love is near ♪
♪ For this is the night ♪
♪ And the heavens ♪
♪ are right ♪
♪ On this lovely ♪
♪ Bella notte ♪
Aaah!
Ohh!
Shh, shh, shh!
Get in the sack!
Come on…
Go. Get in.
Oh, Lassie… Oh.
Oh!
It was a dream.
Darn it.
I, uh, had a great time.
So… so did I.
Oh, kiss her, for heaven's
sake, while we're still young.
Look, I, uh,
know you don't believe
in second chances,
but, uh,
do you believe in second dates?
I do, a-actually.
Good.
Great.
Good night.
Well, at least
he's good-looking.
Dogs.
Mm-hmm.
♪ This is the night ♪
♪ It's a beautiful night ♪
♪ bye. ♪
♪ And they call it ♪
♪ Bella notte ♪
♪ Look at the skies ♪
♪ They have stars ♪
♪ in their eyes ♪
You know, dipstick,
he's a lot like you.
Sweet and solid,
funny without meaning to be.
Hello? There
are "poopies."
"Poopies"? At second
chance "poop" shelter.
What? Poor little
dalmatian "poopies."
Dalmatians? Oui. Second
chance "poopie" shelter.
- Hello? Who is this?
- Hello?
Hello? Hello?
"Poopies"?
Oui! "Poopies"!
Oh, puppies. Mm-hmm. Oui. Voila.
You will find them by the river
at the foot of the bridge.
We'll pick them up right away, monsieur.
Bye.
Box of abandoned puppies
just around the corner.
Abandoned no more.
Oh, blimey!
The coppers!
Forensics
is on its way. Over.
Don't panic, Kevin.
Let me handle this.
Kevin Shepherd?
Yes, hello, guv.
I'm Kevin Shepherd.
Waddlesworth!
Sorry. How can I
help you, officer?
A warrant
to search the premises.
You have expensive taste, sir.
Don't admit to anything.
What's all this about?
Sixteen dalmatian puppies were
reported stolen last night.
Sir.
You'll never guess.
Oh, no!
Busted!
Oh, miss De vil.
Ooh, I suppose I must.
Disgusting creature!
Oh! Ohh!
Chloe, that helmet. I'd
rather have my skull crushed.
Cruella De Vil, you're under arrest.
- Kevin Shepherd, you're under arrest.
- Kevin!
Chloe.
Hello, miss Simon.
Is he one of your charges?
No, he's not the one.
She is! Why suspect Kevin?
Caught him red-handed.
And he's got a record
for dognapping.
- Mmm.
- I can explain.
- You can explain where you were last night.
- He was home kissing her. Oh!
I was out. Out?
- Out.
- I think we've established he was out.
- Right, let's discuss this at the station.
- He was out… with me.
Found this, sir…
list of addresses.
All the houses that have
had dalmatians stolen.
Chloe, you can't possibly
believe… this is crazy!
I'm being set up. Here's the box
of puppies you asked us to…
whatever it is, I didn't do it.
No.
I sent Ewan to pick up those.
There was a phone call and…
oops.
This is crazy. Why would
I steal dalmatians?
Hmm? What possible motive
could I have to want to…
- the judge's order.
- What?
Oh, Kevin, how could you?
- All this for money?
- What?
Just like you said
at the restaurant.
Would somebody kindly
acquaint me with the facts?
If I'm caught stealing puppies,
my entire fortune goes to him.
Would that be a motive?
I'm innocent, I tell you!
Innocent!
Couldn't tear them apart, sir.
Ah, never mind.
Just goes to show,
a dog will love anyone.
Inspector Armstrong!
Oh, inspector, thank you.
You and your men
do such a wonderful job…
Protecting the weak
and the innocent.
Oh, thank you very much. And
I must say, miss De vil,
you are the most remarkable case of rehabilitation
I've known in all my years on the force.
Thank you so much.
Bye-bye.
Good-bye.
Don't be hard on yourself, dear.
We were both fooled.
I'm sorry, miss De vil.
I had no idea that Kevin was a…
that I let myself trust him.
Oh, this is all so dreadful.
You need distraction, darling.
I'm having a few friends 'round for
dinner tonight with their dogs.
Why don't you and yours join us?
Adults only, of course.
Oh, do come.
Remember, darling, we have
the doggies to live for.
Smashing.
A party?
I was hoping we would
dine alone tonight.
- I can't be seen dining with a furrier, you fool.
- You fool!
Grr! In fact, you shouldn't
even be here at all.
Why do you keep that "job
odd" man about the place?
Are you jealous, Jean-Pierre?
Jealous? Of him?
Poo!
What can he do for you?
Steal puppies.
Poo!
Like taking the baby from the candy.
Oh, just like.
Well, now's your chance
to impress me.
I've saved the last three for you.
Me?
Three very special puppies.
The owner will be out.
But, cherie… faint heart never
won fair lady, Jean-Pierre.
The keys, my little c-cabbage.
Dipstick.
Chloe, darling!
How kind of you to come.
Oh!
We're not still holding
a grudge, are we?
Dipstick, be polite.
I'm so pleased
you're here, darling.
Come with me.
Now, tell me.
Your little spotted puppies…
Are snug and safe at home?
Yes, they're with Dottie.
Oh, with mummy!
Yes.
How dear.
It's such a relief to
have the bad man in jail.
If puppies can't be
safe in this world, who can?
Dinner is served.
Alonzo?
Take our guests of honor
to their places.
I've a special surprise
planned for you, my dear.
Tonight our dogs
join us at table…
So we can show our appreciation
to a magnificent species.
My past…
Has been riddled with mistakes.
I pray someday to be forgiven.
Shh.
But tonight I will begin
to set things right.
From tonight…
We'll be closer than ever.
- To the dogs.
- To the dogs!
"Bone" appetit!
Please eat! Eat!
Dipstick.
Do you want mine?
Ugh!
Whee!
Oh, my… oh!
Everyone, eat!
Where's dipstick?
Dipstick!
Oh!
Oh. Oh.
Ahh, bonsoir, my little ones.
I am the great LePelt,
and you are… how do
you say… dog meat.
Oh!
Nice. Nice, doggy.
Dog nice!
Aaaah! Nice!
Quiet!
Shh. Nice doggy.
Be quiet!
Be nice.
Naah!
Hee-hee! Hee-hee!
Three puppies, she said, hmm?
Yaah!
Well.
Aaah! Aaaah!
Oh!
Surprise!
Earlier than I planned,
but c'est la vie.
- I hereby revoke your probation.
- And I hereby lock you up.
With St. Kevin of assisi in the
clink, it just wouldn't do…
If three more puppies
were reported missing.
- Three more?
- Good-bye, my dear.
No!
I'll think of you every time I
wear your sweet little doggies!
No!
Stop!
Ooh, not bad.
The english can do the knitwear.
Shh! Be quiet!
Ooh!
Hey, what's that?
Listen. Hey.
Do you hear that?
What? What is it?
Uh, best I can make out, they're
all yappin' about "tubble."
Tubble? Oh, trouble.
Must be puppies talking.
Listen. Hey, wait.
There's more.
Uh, "widdle ones"?
"Bad man gwab widdle ones.
Twee potted doggies."
Potted?
Twee widdle potted…
bad man grabs three
little spotted doggies.
Oh, my gosh.
Chloe's dogs.
Aah!
Aaaah!
Oh! Aah! Aah!
Aah! Aah!
The puppies!
Thank you, fluffy!
♪ Go to sleep ♪
♪ little guardie ♪
Dog, James dog.
Aah!
♪ Go back to sleep ♪
♪ stupid guardie ♪
Taxi!
St. John's mews, please. You know,
I could get five to ten for this.
That's 35 to 70 in dog years.
Ow!
They've gone.
Where are they? Calm
down, calm down.
- Whoa!
- Aah!
Hoo! Aaah!
I'm so sorry.
I should have trusted you.
No, I should never
have trusted Cruella.
With my police record…
it doesn't matter.
Yes, it does matter.
Look,
I broke into the lab
and freed those dogs.
They were being used
for experiments.
That was your
dognapping conviction?
Yes.
That's all?
What's this?
"The orient-express."
Paris.
They're going to Paris!
Come on!
Oh, Jean-Pierre,
you've outdone yourself.
I am the Napoleon of the fur,
and you are my…
Waterloo? My Josephine.
Together we'll…
aaah! A rat!
I need spotted puppies,
you idiot!
But it is not a rat.
I know rats!
It's a "poopie."
Alonzo!
Yes. Find the rat and kill it.
- Lepelt and I will be on the orient-express.
- K-kill?
The last time I underestimated a
puppy, I wound up in the pokey!
Go! Go!
Why not him?
Oh! Yes, I see.
Thank you.
Ahh.
There.
Yaah!
Oh, oh. Ohh!
Ohh-ohh-ohh-ohh!
Excuse me. The orient-express?
Platform nine.
Paris! City of I'amour!
Of la mode!
Of LePelt!
Lepelt, with his
slippery frenchman ways.
She'll see. She'll see
that I'm the loyal one.
Alonzo. Oh, joy. Le petit homme.
You took care of the rat?
You will never…
See it… again.
This isn't the orient-express.
We're on the wrong platform!
There she is!
Come on.
Oddball!
Oh, no, I can't look!
She'll be killed!
Somebody do something!
Oh, what am I doing?
Help! Help!
Your wings!
Flap your wings!
Flap wings? Oh!
Where did these come from?
Blimey, they work!
I can fly!
Dogs can fly!
Whee-yah!
I just realized I'm not
a rottweiler at all!
I'm a retriever.
Where are we going?
Paris!
We've missed the train! Then
we'll catch the next one!
You think he saw us?
We better… we better hide.
But where?
What? Bad wady's cow?
Oh, good idea, spotty.
Vive la Paris!
Careful now.
Careful. Careful.
Uh, careful!
Mustn't harm the
"poopies."
The p-poopieman
gets to ride in the c-car.
Is Alonzo keeping up?
The little man is too slow.
This traffic is too slow. The French
are useless behind the wheel!
Aah! You're
going the wrong way!
They're going the wrong way!
We're going to die!
Shut up, Jean-Pierre!
Jean-Pierre, our next challenge:
Reinventing the poodle skirt.
Nothing. Nobody saw anything.
Oh!
I didn't know you spoke French.
Come on! Come on!
Taxi, stop!
So what did they say?
Follow les chiens.
It's spooky, all right,
but you'd have to be a sniveling,
whimpering, cowardly little chihuahua…
Not to barge right in there and
take charge of the situation…
With no hesitation at all.
After you, then.
Ohh, I'm gonna regret this.
What do you look at?
Work! Work!
Illegal immigrants?
Of course.
Hmm. How much?
Fifty francs a week.
Oh.
That's not much.
It's all they can afford.
Sure hope you know
where you're going, pup.
Bingo.
Don't worry, oddball. I'll
have 'em out in a jiffy.
Hmm. Tastes like chicken.
Ooh.
It's no good looking
at me like that.
It won't do any good, you know.
Sorry.
Okay.
Go right through.
Did you hear something?
It's just your little man
outside.
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh!
Hey, I thought I told you
to wait outside. Hey.
I know, but they
were worried. Oh!
Hello!
Hi!
Okay, let's get them
out of here.
Come on.
Well, miss Houdini.
Aren't you in a tight spot?
Ooh, what fun
to get away with murder!
Ta-ta!
I'm really beginning
to dislike that woman.
There's got to be a way
out of here.
Hello, nice bird. Aah! Aah!
Waddlesworth!
Is oddball with you?
You bet she's here.
She's commando leader.
- Now, pass up the pups, quick.
- Okay.
One. Have a seat.
Two. Good, good.
Join the other one.
Come on, hurry up, hurry up.
One hundred. In a bunch.
Come on, in a bunch.
One hundred and…
are you 100 or 101?
Great. Now we have to start
all over again. That's it.
Bring me the "poopies"!
Come on!
This is my favorite part.
The skinning?
Not the strangling?
Ah, I like the strangling also.
The Mark of a great furrier, Alonzo,
is that he does his own strangling.
Remember that.
Thank you.
Shh.
Wha…
Aaah!
It's the little rat!
You lied to me.
M-m-me? Why should I… ugh!
Does she look dead to you?
Does she?
You worm!
I'll kill her myself.
You are a wormy little man.
Oh!
Aaah!
Whoa!
Oh! You're both idiots!
Aah! Excuse me!
Work!
Now I crush you, little man!
Aaah!
Who's the little man now?
I'll wear you on my sleeve.
Here, puppy, puppy.
Puppy.
Sweet puppy.
Uhh!
Oh! Oh!
Oh, oh!
No!
Aah!
Aaaah! Ugh.
Oh! Oh!
Oh. Aah!
Oh! Aah, aah!
Ohh! Aah! Aah!
Aaah! Aaah!
Quickly! To the bakery!
But can we trust him?
Now is not the time to count
your change, Kevin. Come on!
She's after the puppies!
I've got you now,
you little rat!
Oh.
Without spots, you're just
not worth the trouble.
Chop, chop.
And now to my coat!
Domino! Little Dipper!
Oddball!
Oddball?
Where are you? Come out,
come out, wherever you are!
Ahh!
Aaah-aah!
Oh!
And now for the topper.
You may now kick the bride.
I'm ruined! This is the
fall of Maison LePelt.
How do we get out
from this mess?
Piece of cake.
Look out, everybody!
It's the bad lady's cow.
Oh, no.
Hello, all.
I've come from miss De vil's
solicitor, Mr. Torte.
I asked if I might have the
pleasure of delivering this.
- Eight million pounds?
- Yes!
It's the judge's orders.
Eight million quid?
Eight million pounds!
Eight million quid.
It's for the dogs, of course.
That's eight million.
And for the best, unless…
unless she's rehabilitated.
No, Alonzo.
Cruella will always be Cruella.
Hope Springs eternal.
What's that puppy
doing up there?
No, oddball!
Oddball!
Oh, oddball!
Ohh!
What have you been up to now?
What have you been doing?
Hey! Hey.
Ohh!
Dirt.
Kevin. Look.
These won't come off.
She's got her spots.
Oddball's got her spots!
Look!
S-p-o-t-s!
♪ Digga-digga-dog ♪
♪ Digga-digga-dog digga-digga-dog ♪
♪ Bow-wow-wow ♪
♪ Digga-digga-dog digga-digga-dog, dog, dog ♪
♪ you dog, you! ♪
♪ Bow-wow-wow ♪
♪ yippee-yo, yippee-yay ♪
♪ Can you keep that excitation ♪
♪ down to a roar ♪
♪ Atomic Dog ♪
♪ When fate comes a-knockin' ♪
♪ Better open the door ♪
♪ Atomic Dog ♪
♪ Rise to the occasion ♪
♪ Yeah, enter the cause ♪
♪ Hey ♪
♪ If they're pitchin' ♪
♪ second chances ♪
♪ Don't you fumble the ball ♪
♪ Oh, no, no ♪
♪ you dog, you! ♪
♪ Digga-digga-dog digga-digga-dog ♪
♪ don't be believin' ♪
♪ Looks are deceivin' ♪
♪ you dog, you! ♪
♪ Don't be believin' ♪
♪ Digga-digga-dog ♪
♪ Looks are deceivin' ♪
♪ you dog, you! ♪
♪ Bow-wow-wow ♪
♪ yippee-yo, yippee-yay ♪
♪ Sometimes you gotta dream ♪
♪ with eyes wide open ♪
♪ Atomic Dog ♪
♪ yeah, you do ♪
♪ You can't earn your spots ♪
♪ just wishin' and hopin' ♪
♪ Atomic Dog ♪
♪ no, you can't ♪
♪ Goin' out on a limb ♪
♪ for a cause ♪
♪ The heart must be brave ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ And a miracle's a gift ♪
♪ Of keeping the faith ♪
♪ Gotta keep the faith ♪
♪ you dog, you! ♪
♪ Don't be believin' ♪
♪ Digga-digga-bow-wow ♪
♪ Looks are deceivin' ♪
♪ you dog, you! ♪
♪ Don't be believin' ♪
♪ Digga-digga-bow-wow ♪
♪ Looks are deceivin' ♪
♪ you dog, you! ♪
♪ Bow-wow-wow ♪
♪ Bow, bow ♪
♪ Spotted dog, spotted dog ♪
♪ where have you been ♪
♪ I've been to London ♪
♪ to look at the queen ♪
♪ Can you tell a spotted story ♪
♪ Yes, I can ♪
♪ I saw a dog ♪
♪ who was walkin' a man ♪
Oww, you dog, you!
♪ What you gonna do ♪
And I think I deserve
a second chance too.
Don't you?
♪ What you gonna do ♪
♪ You let me think ♪
♪ that I knew you ♪
♪ I was right ♪
♪ I only saw ♪
♪ what you wanted me to ♪
♪ You caught me ♪
♪ in your web of lies ♪
♪ Now you tell me ♪
♪ that it's gonna be different ♪
♪ And just how much ♪
♪ you've changed ♪
♪ What you gonna do ♪
♪ with your second chance ♪
♪ What I wouldn't give ♪
♪ to read your mind ♪
♪ What you gonna do ♪
♪ with your second chance ♪
♪ Will you throw it away ♪
♪ Or get it right this time ♪
♪ What you gonna do ♪
♪ what you gonna do ♪
♪ I'm watchin' you ♪
♪ It's so easy to say it ♪
♪ For a while ♪
♪ you can put on a show ♪
♪ If what you're saying ♪
♪ is more than words ♪
♪ Time will tell me so ♪
♪ Now I'm willing ♪
♪ to let you show me ♪
♪ You've turned it all around ♪
♪ What you gonna do ♪
♪ with your second chance ♪
♪ What I wouldn't give ♪
♪ to read your mind ♪
♪ What you gonna do ♪
♪ with your second chance ♪
♪ Will you throw it away ♪
♪ Or get it right this time ♪
♪ I'm watchin' you ♪
♪ what you gonna do ♪
♪ I, I, I want to believe ♪
♪ You're shooting straight ♪
♪ with me ♪
♪ Tell me what's it gonna be
♪ tell me what's it gonna be ♪
♪ Baby, baby, yeah ♪
♪ oh, no ♪
And I think I deserve
a second chance too.
Don't you?
♪ Okay ♪
♪ here's your second chance ♪
♪ What you gonna do ♪
♪ with your second chance ♪
♪ What I wouldn't give ♪
♪ to read your mind ♪
♪ What you gonna do ♪
♪ with your second chance ♪
♪ Will you throw it away ♪
♪ or get it right ♪
♪ What you gonna do ♪
♪ with your second chance ♪
♪ What I wouldn't give ♪
♪ to read your mind ♪
♪ What you gonna do ♪
♪ with your second chance ♪
♪ Will you throw it away ♪
♪ Or get it right this time ♪