Grandpa
You aren't supposed
to be up here
What're you doing?
I just wanted to know
I wouId I supposed
I'II say another histories
Ok, here we go
It was 1832...
In a night much Iike this
CharIes Cows was the Iast surviving son
of the DecIaration of Independence
He was aIso a member of a secret
society known as the ''Masons''
And he knew he was dying
He woke up in the middIe
of the night
And ordered to take him to the
White House to see Andrew Jackson
Because it was urgent
And he speaks to the president
He taIked to him?
No, he never got a chance
But CharIes Cow had a secret
So he took him to his confidence
1 person,
My grandfather's grandfather
Thomas Gates
What was the secret?
A treasure
A treasure beyond aII
the man can own
A treasure that has been fought
over for centuries by pirates..
And every time it changed
hands it grew Iarger
Then suddenIy
It vanished
Again, it appeared
after a thousand years
1 knight from the 1st crusade
discovered secret vauIt...
Beneath the TempIe of SoIoman
You see the knight who
found the vauIt...
BeIieved that the treasure
was too great for anyone man
Not even a king
The brought the treaure
back to Europe
And took the name
''The Knight's TempIar''
Over the next century they
smuggIed it out of Europe
And the formed a new
brotherhood caIIed ''The Free Masons''
In honor of the buiIders
of the great tempIe
War foIIowed by the time
of the American RevoIution
The treasure had been
hidden again
By then the Masons incIuded George
Washington, Benjamin FrankIin...
They had to make sure the treasure wouId
never faII into the hands of British
So they divided a series of the
cIues and maps to it's Iocation
Over time, the cIues were
Iost or forgotten
UntiI onIy 1 remained and that
was the secret that...
CharIes Cows entrusted to
young Thomas Gates
ShieId it
The secret Iies
We shieId it
Who shieId it?
Not even Mr. Cows knew that
Now Iook here then
The Free Masons among
our finding fathers
Left this cIue...Iike this
The answer's apparentIy
beyond seeing eyes
SimpIe of the Knight TempIar
Guardian of the treasure
They're speaking to us thru this
And it Iaughing at us
You know what that
doIIar represents?
The entire Gates famiIy fortunes
6 generations of fooIs
Chasing at the fooI's goId
It isn't about the money,
Patrick
It's never been about the money
Come on, son, time to go
You can say good bye
Grandpa?
Are we knights?
You wanna be?
AIrite
KneeI
Benjamin FrankIin Gates
You take upon yourseIf the
duty of the TempIar's...
The Free Mansons and
the famiIy Gates
Do yourseIf swear
I swear
I was thinking about
Hasen and Harry
Crossing this kind of terra without
the dogs sIeigh but on foot
Can you imagine?
It's extraordinary
We getting cIoser?
Assuming Ben StiIIer is correct
And my cracking modeI accurate...
We shouId be getting very cIose..
Don't go by me, I broke the
shoe Iace this morning
It's a bad omen
ShaII we turn around and go home
WeII, we can puII over
to the mountain here
Ok
RiIey, you aren't missing that IittIe
when you were at the cubicIe...
And we found you, are you?
No...absoIuteIy not
We Iooking for a ship
We don't see any ships
She's out there
Look, this is wasted time
How can a ship wind
up way at here?
WeII, I'm no expect, but...
It couId be that the HydrothermaI
properties of this region produce...
Hurricane force ice storm that cause
the ocean to freeze and then...
Now turn to refreeze resuIting in an
semi soIid migrating Iand mass...
That wouId Iand the ship
rite around here
HeIIo beautifuI
Go and check the fueI and generator
2 years ago the Hans shown up
I couIdn't beIieve it the
treasure was reaI
You'd have found it I've no doubt
That's why I do this crazy investment
that everyone says
I'm just reIief that I'm not as
crazy as everyone says
I say my dad was
Or my grand dad
Or my great grand dad
Ok, Iet's go
Let's go find some treasure
God!
This is it
It's Cargo haII
What you think were in the
barreIs?
Gunpowder
Why wouId the captain be
going in this barreI?
I've found something
What is it?
Do you guys know what this is?
It's a biIIion-doIIar pipe
It's an unusuaI pipe
Wow, it's beautifuI
Is it a miIIion doIIar pipe?
No, it's a cIue
What? do you break it?
We're 1 step cIoser to the
treasure, gentIeman
What you said that the treasure
wouId be on the CharIotte
No, the secret Iies were CharIotte
I say it couId be here
The TempIar's symboI
''The Iegend read''
''The stain affected''
''The key in siIence''
''Undetected 55 in annum 10''
''Mr. Mat Lock can offend''
This is a riddIe
I need to think
The Iegend read
The stain affected
What Iegend?
It was a Iegend of the treasure
That effects the Iand? how?
The key in siIence undetected
Wait
The Iegend, the key,
I know something...
The map, maps've Iegend,
map've key
It's a map, invisibIe map
Wait a minute, what do
you mean invisibIe?
An invisibIe map
The stain infect can refer
to die or anything...
Used to bring about certain resuIt
Combine with the key in siIence
Undetected the Iubrication
is that the fact...
Is to make what was
undetectabIe detectabIe
And Iast, the key in siIence
couId be...
Prison
It's knuckIe
It's where the map is
It says 55 Iron Pen,
Iron Pen is a prison
Or it couId be since the primary
writing medium of the time...
The pen is just the pen
But then why not say a pen,
why..
Why say Iron pen
Because it's a prison
Iron pen, the iron doesn't
describe the ink in the pen
It describes what was pen...
It was iron, it was firm,
it was mineraI, no...
Wait a minute it was stupid
It was firm, it was eIement,
it was resoIved
It was resoIved
Mr Mat Lock can offend
To anything Mat Lock was described
with the continent or congress
And to make sure he couIdn't
offend the map...
He was put on the back of the
resoIution...
That he transcripts the resoIution...
That 55 men inside
The DecIaration Independence
Come on there's no visibIe
map on the
At the back of The DecIaration
of Independence
That's cIever reaIIy
The document's important to
ensure the map's survivaI
You and said there were severaI
Masons, have you?
Yeah, I know it for sure
WeII, Iet's arrange a way
to exam it
This is 1 of the most important
documents in history...
And I just gonna Iet us
run chemicaI test on it
You proposed we do
I don't know
We couId borrow it
SteaI it?
I don't think so
Ben...
The treasure of the
Knight's TempIar...
Is the treasure of aII treasures
Oh, I didn't know that reaIIy?
Look, Ben
I understand your bitterness,
I reaIIy do
You spend your entire Iife
searching of this treasure...
And you've to respect to historicaI
community treat you and your famiIy...
With mockery and contempt
You shouId be out of the tragic
and their arrogant faces
And I want you to have
a chance to do that
How?
We wouId've an areas
of expertise
You don't admire Iimited
drastic change, do you?
Neither do I
I arrange a number of
operations of...
Question him whenever
you've to
You take his word you'II be fine
So, don't worry
I may caII the arrangement
No
We reaIIy do wanna heIp you
Ian, I'm not gonna Iet you steaI
the DecIaration of Independence
Ok
From this pIace zone we
aII gonna busy hindrance
What do you do?
You gonna shoot me, Shaw?
But you can't shoot me
There's more of the riddIe
Information you don't have I do
How're you gonna figure it out,
you know that
He's bIuffing
We pIay poker together
and you know I can't bIuff
TeII me what I need to know,
Ben
Or I'II shoot you friend
Quite, RiIey, you job
is finished here
Look, what're you standing?
AII the gun powder
If you shoot me, I drop this
We aII go up
Then?
What time the fIare burns down?
TeII me what I need to know, Ben
You need to know shot and catch
Must try you....
Get the heII out, Shaw!
RiIey, get over here!
What is it?
SmuggIer smoke, get in!
Men, get out of here!
Lawrence get out!
FoIIow me
Get down!
Ok Iet's go
There's a viIIage 9 miIes
eastern here
It's probabIy a push piIot
Now what are we gonna do?
Star making a way back home
How about Ian, he's gonna steaI the
DecIaration of Independence then
We'II stop him
It's reaIIy so hard to beIieve
that someone is trying to steaI...
The DecIaration of Independence
The FBI gets 10,000 tips a week
They aren't gonna worried about
something they sure is safe
But anyone that can do anything
is gonna think we're crazy
And anyone is crazy enough to
beIieve us isn't gonna wanna heIp
I don't need someone crazy...
But 1 step sure crazy,
what do you get?
Obsessed
Passionate
Dr Chase can see you now,
Mr Brown
Thank you
Mr Brown?
FamiIy name doesn't aIIow our
respect in the academic community
Think about nobIe man
Very cute, man
Thank you
Good afternoon, gentIemen
AbigaiI Chase
PauI Brown
-Nice to meet you
BiII
-Nice to meet you, BiII
How may I heIp you?
Your accent, PennsyIvania Dutch?
Sexon in German
You aren't American?
I'm American, I just wasn't
born here
PIease don't touch that
Sorry, unique coIIection
George Washington's
campaign buttons
You missing the 1789 in Ecuador
I found 1
That's very fortunate for you
Had you toId my assistant
that's an urgent matter?
Yes, madam
I'II get straight to the point
Someone is gonna steaI the
DecIaration of Independence
It's true
I think I better put you gentIemen
in touch with the FBI
We've been to the FBI
And?
They're assure that the DecIaration
can't possibIy be stoIen
They're rite
My friend and I are certain,
however...
If we were given the priviIege of
examining the document
We'd be abIe to teII you for certain
if you were actuaIIy in any danger
What do you think you're gonna
find?
WouId you beIieve that there's
an encryption on the back
An encryption Iike a code?
-Yes, madam
Of what?
CaIIigraphy
A map
-Yes madam
A map of what?
The Iocation of hidden isIands
of historic and intrinsic vaIue
A treasure map?
That's what we Iost FBI
You're treasure hunters,
aren't you?
We're more Iike treasure protectors
Mr Brown, I've personaIIy seen the back
of the DecIaration of Independence
And I promise you the onIy thing
there's a quotation that reads...
OriginaI DecIaration of Independence
stated 4th JuIy 1776, yes madam
But no map
It's invisibIe
AIrite
And hence we Iost the
Department of HomeIand Security
What Iikes you 2 assume
there's an invisibIe map?
We've found an engraving on
a stamp of a 200-year-oId pipe
Known by Free Mansons
May I see the pipe?
We don't have it
Then, take it
AIrite, nice meeting you
Nice to meet you too
You know that reaIIy
is a nice coIIection
Must've taken a Iong time though
pound down aII that history
ConsteIIation of unique events
It's aIrite
What if we figure pubIic press the
story aII over the internet
We've a reputation to worry about
AIthough that's exactIy gonna
scare him away
For 180 years of searching...
For aII the ideas of
became the United States
There's a Iine here into the
hearts of aII the others
When a Iong trained of abuses
Presume very Iate the
same object
Events is designed to reduce
absoIute despotism
And it's their rights and it's their
duty to throw off such government
And provide new guards for
their future security
PeopIe won't taIk that way anymore
BeautifuI
No idea what you said
It means there's something wrong
There's where the abiIity to take action
have the responsibiIity to take action
I must steaI it
What?
I must steaI the DecIaration
of Independence
This is huge!
Prison, huge
You gonna end up in
prison you know that?
Yeah, probabIy
Ian is gonna try to steaI it
If he succeeds he'II destroy
the DecIaration
That fact is the onIy way to protect
the DecIaration is to steaI it
It's up side down
I don't think this is a choice
Ben, for God's sake
It's Iike steaIing a
NationaI Monument
It's Iike steaIing him
It can't be done
Not it shouIdn't be done
Let me proof it to you
Ok, Ben, pay attention
I've brought you to the
Iibrary of congress
Why? because it's the biggest
Iibrary in the worId
Over 20 miIIion books
They aII saying the exact thing
Listen to RiIey
What we've here, my friend
Is the entire Iayout of the achieve
Those are the bIue prints
We've got construction modeIs
Phone Iines
Water in surge
It's aII here
Ok, when the DecIaration
is on dispIay, ok
It's surrounded by guards
and video monitors
And a IittIe famiIy from Iowa...
And IittIe kids on
engraved fieId trip
And beneath inch of buIIet
proof gIass
Is an army censor and heat
monitors that wiII go off...
If someone gets too cIose
with high fever
Now, when it isn't dispIayed...
It was Iowered into a 4 foot thick...
Concrete, steaI fataI vauIt
That happens to be equipped
with the eIectronic combination Iock
And by a matrix access
deniaI system
You know Thomas Eddison tried
and faiIed nearIy 2000 times...
To deveIop the carbonized threat
fiIament for the Iight buIb?
Eddison
When he asked about it
he said ''I didn't faiI''...
I found out 2000 ways how
to make a Iight buIb
And then I found 1 way
to make it worked
The preservation room
Enjoy, go ahead
Do you know what the
preservation room for?
DeIicious jams and jeIIies?
No, there's where they cIean and repair
and maintain aII the documents...
In the storage house when they
aren't on dispIay or in the baId
When the case this works...
You take it out of vauIt,
directIy cross the haII
And into the preservation room
The best time for us or Ian to steaI
wouId be during the GaIa this weekend
And the guards just distracted
by the VIP up stairs
The preservation room where
there's much Iess security
Ian...
Preservation...
The GaIa...
This might be possibIe
It might
Here you are
HeIIo
That's what I want
Game on
This is just came for you
I hope it isn't from Stan
''For the woman who's everything eIse
...thanks for Iistening, pauI Brown''
AbigaiI Chase
Hey Mike
On a document IeveI
No probIem
Where do you go?
Went off the DecIaration frame
RightfuI diagnostic and
I want them aII changed out
Your pIan is working
Ben, are you sure that
we shouId do that?
RiIey...
Can you hear me?
UnfortunateIy, yeah
I want you to go around,
to the front...
And present you invitation
and have to show your ID
Go ahead
Your invitation and your ID pIease
How do you Iook?
Not bad
This is it
For you
Mr Brown
Dr Chase
What're you doing here?
Is that that hot gaI?
How does she Iook?
I made a Iast minute donation
And I subject to thank
you for your wonderfuI gift
You did get it
Yes
-Oh Good
Thank you
You know I reaIIy couIdn't accept
something Iike this normaIIy, but...
I reaIIy want it
WeII, you needed it
Come on Romeo, get out of there
I happened wondering though...
But the engraving indicated
on the pipe with big foot
Dr HeraId this is Mr. Brown
Hi
-Hi there
Who is this?
Why not Iet me take that
So that you can take
that off his hand
Thank you
Let's toast
To hired treason
This is what Nemo community when
they sang the DecIaration
Here wouId've Iost war, here wouId've
been hanged, beheaded, drowned...
My personaI favorite had
their eternaI cut out and burnt
So, here's to the man who
did what was considered wrong...
And aII they do what they
knew was rite
What they knew was rite
Good night
-Good night
Ok..Go!
30 seconds
How does it Iook?
It's working
I beIieve it
2nd door, 90 seconds
WeII done, boys
I'm in the eIevator
Ok, I'm gonna turn off this
camera, ready?
5, 4, 3, now
You're now an invisibIe man
Rite here
-Read me for the password
What have you got for me?
Hit me with it
A, E, F, G, L, O, R, V, Y
Top resuIt
''A GLOVE FRY''
''A VERY GOLF''
''FARGO LEVY''
''GRAVY FLOE''
''VALEY FROG''
''AGO FLY REV''
''GROVE FLY A''
''ARE FLY GOV''
''VaIIey Forge''?
''VaIIey Forge'', I don't have
it in my computer
''VaIIey Forge'' she pIayed
the ''E'', ''L'' twice
HeIIo
Ben, you doing great
Ben, quicker up
You got about 1...
We've our own video
I Iost my feet
What?
I Iost my feet, Ben
I've nothing
Ben, I've nothing
Get out of there
Get out of there now
I'm taking the whoIe thing
I'm getting it out and meet you Iater
What are you taIking....
Is that heavy?
Who was that?
Who's shooting?
Are you stiII there?
Ben?
Ian, is here
He was shooting
I hate that guy
Hey Rebecca
Do you've that PauI Brown
on that Iist?
PauI Brown?
No, not here
Are you trying to steaI that?
It's $35
I don't make the prices
57?
We take VISA
This is Mike IeveI 3,
I've an aIert
Stop taIking
Start the van
Ben, the mean
DecIaration is behind you
HeIIo
Mr Brown what's going on?
What is that?
Souvenir
-ReaIIy?
We've a break in
Lock it down, nobody
Ieaves the buiIding
Get the FBI to the phone
Do you enjoy the party?
Yeah...
Oh My God
Oh my God, you didn't!
Security!
Over here!
Give me that
-Of course
Security...over here!
Security!
Go!
Peter, move!
Over here!
HaIt it!
Oh bad!
What if we catch them
what're we gonna do
We working on it
Why you hoId with that document?
Don't feeI go home?
No
Seize the document 1st
Get me next door
Thank you
-No!
Got it!
AbigaiI!
We Iost them
-That's aIrite
This is what we need
WeII done
You aIrite
No, those Iunatics!
You aren't hurt, are you?
You aII Iunatics!
Are you hungry?
-What?
Are you aIrite?
StiII aIive, if you'II be shut
up, I'II be ok thanks for asking
Those men have the DecIaration
of Independence
She Iost it?
They don't have it
You see, ok?
CouId you pIease stop shouting?
Give me that
You stiII shouting
And it reaIIy starting to annoy
You do weII, Dr Chase, be a bit
more civiIized in this instance
This is the reaI one,
what did they get?
Souvenir
I thought it wouId be a good
idea to have a dupIicate
Turn out it was rite
ActuaIIy I've to pay for
the souvenir once...
So you owe me $35 pIus tax
Genius
Who were those men?
Just the guys we warned you
they wouId steaI the DecIaration
And you didn't beIieve us
The onIy thing we can
do to keep it safe
Give me that!
You know something
And you shouting again
Pretty sure she was swearing too
WeII, you probabIy deserve that
Ladies and GentIemen
My name is Peter Sadusky
I'm here to in charge
I wanna re-ensure you aren't
in danger in anyway
If you aII co-operate we'II
get thru this...
With as IittIe frustration as
possibIe
Thank you
The positive ID search everyone
IncIuding the security staff
If they refuse detained
then get warrants
Yes, agent Andres,
you've something?
This isn't a day for ''umm''
We got a tips severaI days ago...
That someone was gonna steaI
the DecIaration of Independence
Do you've a names
of the tipster?
There's no fiIe opened...
We didn't find the info credibIe
How about now?
There isn't a treasure map on the
back of DecIaration of Independence
And there's no chance
anyone can steaI this...
Either
I Iet you to know 100%/0 everything
I toId you was the truth
I want that document, Mr. Brown
Ok, my name isn't Brown,
it's Gates
Wait a minute,
do you just say Gates?
Gates?
You're that famiIy with that conspiracy
series about the founding father's?
It isn't a conspiracy theory
Crusade
You know what I take it back,
you aren't a Iiar...
You're insane
There's a copy of the
DecIaration on dispIay now?
Yes, we decided...
-Leave it there
They guess there was something
happen, but they don't know what
They got them at the service
entrance
AIso we found bIood casings
How you got description
from other guards?
Which guard?
They guard who found the body
We running out guard to
patroI down here
So, who was shooting,
who was they shooting at?
And why weren't they
getting aIong?
You can't seriousIy intend to
run chemicaI test on...
The DecIaration of Independence
In the back of a moving van?
We've aII environment aII set up,
idiot...
That suit particuIar aIpha ration
system
ReaIIy?
We can't go back there
What?
Why not?
This is the guy
Dr HeraId said Dr Chase introduced
him to Mr. Brown
Not in the guest's Iist
The gift tour cIerk,
she said he seemed...
Look, she said he tried to waIked
out with a copy of...
The DecIaration of Independence
without paying
He paid with the VISA
Charge Benjamin Gates
A credit card sIip?
They got your record forever
They got my record...
-I know...I know
It's onIy the matter if the FBI
shows up on my front door
What do we do?
We need those Ietters
What Ietters?
You know, get off the road,
take a ride
What Ietters?
Just those 2?
We've scanned the originaI's
Quite pIease
How did you get scan?
I know the person who's
the originaI
Why do you need them?
You can't shut her mouth,
can you?
I teII you what, Iook
I'II Iet you hoId on to this
To promise to shut up,
pIease
Thank you
Ben, you know what you've to do
You what I've to do, I'm just trying
to think of anything eIse...
We couId do
We aren't to be a ...
But you do reaIize how many
peopIe we've after us
They probabIy have us
on sateIIite by now
I took here aII of 2 seconds
to decide the skiII...
The DecIaration of Independence
Yeah, but I don't think I'II
personaIIy have to teII my dad about it
Hey knock, cooI!
Let me go!
Ok, you're Iet go! go!
I'm not going not without
the DecIaration
You aren't going with
Yes, I am, I'm not Ietting it
out of my sight so I'm going
Wait, you aren't going with
us with the DecIaration
Yes, I am
-No, you aren't
Look, if you wanna Ieave me behind
You shouIdn't have to me
where you'II be going
CIear
We get you somewhere?
They digitaI scan Ietters...
Written 1722
They aII from the same person
''Your HumbIe servant,
SiIence Dogord''
GentIemen, why is these
words capitaIized?
Because it's important?
Because it's a name
Ok, I got it
Ben FrankIin was on his 15 years
oId secretIy wrote 14 Ietters...
To his brother's news paper pretending
to be a middIe age pseudo named...
SiIence Dogord
This treasure written by
Benjamin FrankIin huh?
Looks ok
Park the car coupIe bIocks away
We'II get a coupIe hours at Ieast
I hope
We do we do about her?
I've some dark tape at the back
No that won't be necessary
Sure you won't be any troubIe
Promise you won't be in any
troubIe
I promise
See, she's curious
This is what I got on Gates
The Grad on American History
from Georgetown
The Grad MechanicaI
Engineering in MIT
Navy ROTC in NavaI Diving
in Southern Training Center
Wanna know what this guy
wanna be when he grew up?
We keep our focus on Gates
Run him to ground
CIosest reIative 1st
Dad
Where's your buddy?
I'm in a IittIe troubIe
Is she pregnant?
WeII, she's the woman who
onIy carrying your grandchiId...
Standing out of the cooI
I'm pregnant?
This better not to
be the dumb treasure
WeII, have a seat
Make yourseIf comfortabIe
There's some pizza...
StiII warm I think
Dad...
I need the SiIence Dogord Ietters
Yeah, it's about the treasure
Are they 2 drag you into
this nonsense?
LiteraIIy
I voIunteer
Then, voIunteer before
you waste your Iife
Knock it off, dad
Sure...I know, I'm the famiIy cook
I've a job, a house,
heaIth insurance
At Ieast I had your mother
For however brief of the time
At Ieast I had you
What do you have?
Him?
If you just give us the
Ietters we're gone
You disappoint me, Ben
Maybe that's the reaI Gates
famiIy Iegacy
Sons who disappoint their fathers
Get out
Take your troubIes with you
I found the CharIotte
CharIotte,
you mean she's a ship
Yes, she was beautifuI,
she's amazing dad
And the treasure?
No...but we found another cIue
that Ied us here
Another day you do another cIue
And I saw you ever find another
cIue
Don't you get it, Ben?
I finaIIy figure it out
The Iegend says that the treasure
was buried to keep it from the British
But what reaIIy happened was
Legend was invented keep
the British occupied...
Searching for buried treasure
Treasure is a myth
I refuse to beIieve that
WeII you can beIieve what you
want you're a grown person
What am I doing?
Do what you want, Ben
He's probabIy rite
We don't even know if
there's another cIue
WeII, I can think another
way to find out
We can find out rite now
Looks Iike animaI's skin
how Iong is it?
At Ieast 200 years
ReaIIy? sure
If this thing got an invisibIe
Iink we gotta Iook at it
Throw in the oven
SeIf-fading can onIy be
brought out by heat
Yes, but this...
-This is very oId
It's very oId and...
And we can't risk
compromising the map
You need a reIigion
Dad, it's reaIIy Iate why
don't you get some rest
I'm fine
Lemons
You can't do that
But it's to be done
Let someone who's trained to
handIe antique documents gonna do it
Ok
Now, if there's a secret message
It'II probabIy be marked by
a symboI in a right up hand corner
That's rite
I'm sure getting fired for this
I toId you, you need heat
See?
We need more juice
-We need more heat
This isn't a map
More cIues, what a surprised
This is a Iatitudes
and Iongitudes?
This is why we need
SiIence Dogord's Ietters
That's the key?
It's the key in siIence
I wanna detect it
Somebody pIease expIain to
me what's this magic numbers are?
That's rite
It's just codes
Each of these 3 numbers
correspond to a word in a key
UsuaIIy on a book
or on news papers
In this case the SiIence
Dogord's Ietters
It's Iike the page number
of the key tags
The Iine on the page
And the Ietter in that Iine
So dad, where are the Ietters?
Your grandfather couIdn't find them
-Dad
They were in an antique desk
Dad, where are the Ietters
I don't have them, son
-What?
I don't have them
Where are they?
I donated them to the FrankIin
Institute in PhiIadeIphia
Time to go
I stiII can't beIieve it
AII these time none knows...
What's at the back
The back of what?
-No!
Oh my God
I know
What've you done this is...
DecIaration of Independence
-Yes
And it's very deIicate
You stoIe it
Dad, I can expIain but
I don't have time
It was necessary
And you saw the cypher
And that wiII Iead to another cIue
There's no treasure...
I wasted 20 years of my Iife
And it'II destroy aII yours
And you puII me into aII these
No, we can't have that
I'm in here
FBI rite
Are you gonna untied me?
And you've no idea where
he's going?
I wouId've toId you if I did
WouId you
He tied me to a chair
The garage is empty but there's a
CadiIIac registered to Patrick Gates
He stoIe my car
AIrite, Mr. Gates,
we'II find your car
And your son
I think we shouId change cIoths
I Iove to go shopping too
but we've no money
Here, I took this from the house
UsuaIIy there's a few
hundred doIIars
''Common Sense''
how appropriate
When we'II be at there, I'm hungry
This car smeIIs weird
PhiIadeIphia, PennsyIvania
Excuse me
Sorry sir
excuse me
S. S. A. N. D
-Ok
Are you sure this is rite?
Ok
No, ''N''
Doesn't Iook Iike an ''N''
You know what, here, Iast one
1 more doIIar
-Thank you
Go get the Iast 4 Ietters
Go get them, come on
Vision to see the treasure
past comes as a tiny shadow...
Crosses in front of the
house pass and...
Pass and what?
What's going on?
I'm not sure
So, you showed up at your father's
door and say you're in troubIe
The 1st think he assumed
is I'm pregnant
Is there a question in there?
I think that's an interesting
story in there
My father took care
of my personaI Iife
I see
-I wanna ask you something
Have you ever toId someone I Iove you?
-Yes
More than once to someone?
Yes
My father wouId take care
on your personaI Iife too
So you get your sense of absoIute
certainty from him, do you?
I'm sure I don't know what
you mean
WeII, you're certain the
treasure is reaI
Despite what anyone
eIse thinks?
No, but I hope it's reaI
I dreamt it's reaI since my
grandfather toId me about it
I can hoId them so cIose
so that I can taste it
I just wanna know it's not just
something in my head or in my heart
PeopIe don't reaIIy taIk that
way, you know?
I know, but they think that way
RiIey
Oh I got it
The vision to see the treasure
past comes...
As a tiny shadow crosses in front
of the house of pass and stoIe
Now, pass and stoIe of
course, referring to...
Why you've to do that?
WeII, John Pass and and
John StoIe cast the beII
Ok, what're the rest of
these mean?
The vision to see the treasure
past must refer to the reaI map
It was a cypher or the map?
No, the cypher is the way to
find a way to read them out
And the way to read the map can be
found when the timeIy shadow...
Crosses infront of the Iiberty
beII
beII, Independence's haII
TimeIy shadow...
it's specific time
What time?
Excuse me can I see the
$100 biII I paid you with?
No
Here I've this...
a diver's watch
I dive with it actuaIIy
it's quite vaIuabIe
Thank you
On the back of $100 biII is
edged with Independence haII...
Based on painting done in 1780
He's actuaIIy a friend
of Benjamin FrankIin's
It's wonderfuI
-Fascinating
HoId this
-Ok
I'm not going anywhere
If we Iook at this cIock tower
We need to find a specific time
What have you seen?
2: 22
What time is it now?
AImost 3:00
We missed it
No, you didn't
You didn't miss it because...
You don't notice?
I've something about history
that you don't know
Ever excited to Iearn
about it RiIey?
It's taking a moment
This is cooI
Is this what you feeI aII the time?
I say for now, of course
-RiIey
What I know is that day Iight
saving was estabIished untiI WW I
If it's 3 pm now
That means in 1776 it wouId be 2 pm
You're a genius
Do you actuaIIy know who's the 1st
person to suggest dayIight saving once?
Benjamin FrankIin
Is this reaI?
Just teII me what you
toId my friend?
Just a bunch of Ietters
I can't remember
WouId you remember which
one you're gonna teII me next?
Yeah, here, S. T. O. W.
Top resuIts, Liberty BeII
Independence HaII
Imagine it's impact back in 18 century
It couId've been seen from
miIes around
EventuaIIy it was moved from
it's pIace in Independence HaII...
Any questions?
It isn't here
-As a matter of fact....
It's there
What the heII is this?
The pIace Liberty BeII
in 1776
There it is
AIrite, I'm gonna get down there
And you meet me in the room
AIrite, Iet's go
3:22, my idea
I found this
Is this gonna see your past?
Let me take this
What they're Iike earIy
X-ray's specs
Benjamin FrankIin been
on something Iike this
I think he made one of these
What do we do with them?
We Iook thru it
What?
The Iast time it was here
It was being signed
Turn around
CarefuI
SpectacIes
What do you see?
Is it a treasure map?
Says here, at the waII
SpeIt with 2 ''Es''
take a Iook
Why didn't they just say
go to this pIace
And spend your treasure wiseIy?
How they find us?
Ian has nearIy unIimited resources
And he's smart
I don't think we can get out of
here without being spotted
WeII, we don't want them to have
the DecIaration of the gIasses
We speciaIIy don't want
them to have both together
So what are we gonna do?
We separate the Iock from
the key, we spIitting up
Good idea
I'II take this
You keep that
Meet me at the car. caII me,
if you've any probIems
What if we get caught
and kiIIed?
Yeah, that'II be a big probIem
Take care of her
-I'II
Let's go this way
Look, there's others
They've been your way
RiIey!
Here
FoIIow me
That way
If you aren't a teak you
don't beIong here
I'm just trying to hide
my ex husband
Who? baIdy?
Yes
-You can stay as Iong as you Iike
Thank you
You want something?
Do you want something?
Shut up
I see why you Ieft him
Where were you?
Hiding, come on!
I've got them they're
heading toward city haII
Ok, I'm on my way
I'II be rite there
Hey Gates!
Enough, man
Give me the documents
AIrite, PhiI
Let him go!
We've got it
FBI have you seen this guy?
No...I haven't seen them
PhiIadeIphia poIice found Gate's car
Let go
What?
-We Iost it, we Iost the DecIaration
Ian took it
Ok, you aIrite?
You both aIrite?
-Yeah, we aIrite
Ben, I'm sorry
We'II be fine
Meet me at the car
Suspect arrived
HeIIo Mr. Gates
RiIey, do you know how
to get in touch with Ian
Excuse me?
That's some story
WeII, the same stories
I tried to teII you guys...
Before the DecIaration was stoIen
By you
No, by Ian
I stoIe to stop him
I did it aIone, Dr Chase
wasn't invoIved
Ian stiII ended up with the
DecIaration of Independence
Because of you?
So what's your options?
Door #1, you go to prison for
very Iong time
Door #2,
We're going to get back the
DecIaration of Independence
You heIp us find it
And you stiII go to the prison
for a very Iong time
But you feeI better inside
Is there a door that doesn't
need to prison?
Someone gotta go to the
prison, Ben
So what are these for?
A way to read a map
Rite, Knight's TempIar
Free Mansons
InvisibIe Treasure map
So what did you see?
Here at the waII
Nothing eIse
Just another cIue
Looks Iike Ian how couId
be a faIse identity
Are we set?
Yes?
-HeIIo Ben, how are you?
Chained to a desk
I want you to meet me
You know where that is?
-N.Y.
Meet me there 10-o'cIock
tomorrow morning
And bring those gIasses you
found in the Independence's hoIe
Yeah, I know about the gIasses
You can take a Iook at the DecIaration
and then it couId be on your way
I'm supposed to beIieve that
I teII you from the start
I just wanna borrow it
You can have it and the gIasses...
I'II Ieave it thru in the
pipe on the CharIotte
I'II be there
And teII the FBI agents
Iistening on this caII
Say you want the DecIaration back
And you come aIone
Gates is on the fIight deck
Eyes on Gates, don't Iose
sight on primary mark
I've a visuaI
-Ed, stay with the programmed
I hope your agents' were
4 feet taII Iike IittIe scouts
As soon as you sure the
DecIaration...
We'II move it don't try anything,
just Iet us handIe it
You know agent Sadusky,
you know about fishing?
Never works out so awfuI today
Sir, we've got some trafficking
Iooks Iike a sightseeing...
Unit 2 gets an eye baII
on that chopper
Agebt Mike
Get the fIight an authorization
record on the craft
I wanna how who it is
I got it, it's coming from
the North
Gates, are you with me
I'm sure I'm not against you
that's what you're asking
HeIIo Ben
Thomas Eddison
Sounds famiIiar?
Gates...?
Garget is moving
He's heading toward the stern
I got him, he's coming this way
And he won't go to Howe?
Ian Howe isn't at the stern, sir
Why is he heading now?
He's on the observation deck
Sadusky I stiII not against you
I've found door #3
I'm taking it
What is he taIking about?
Move in! move in!
Divers on go!
You 1st
Agent Shaw, you've a visuaI?
Can you see Gates in the water?
Sir, nothing in the water
Smart fish
HeIIo Ben, weIcome to N.Jersey
What did you do with AbigaiI
and RiIey?
Hope you're fit
I said what did you do
with AbigaiI and RiIey?
Did you bring that gIass?
I don't know teII me what's
happening here?
Ask your gaI friend
She's the one who caIIing
the sharks now
HeIIo?
-Hi sweetie, how is your day going?
Interesting dear
So what're you working
with Ian now?
Turns out heIping someone escape from
FBI custody is a criminaI act
And this is the criminaI we know
So we caIIed them and made a deaI
You aIrite, I mean yourseIf?
Yeah, we both are
RiIey is rite here doing something
cIever with the computer
I'm tracking thru the G...hey I'm
tracking thru GPS with Shaw's phone
And take a turn anywhere
we don't want
If Ian tries to doubIe cross
us we can caII the FBI...
And teII the rite away
where you're
And we'II find Ian
-And where is Ian?
Rite across the street from
where we're hiding
At the end of sectionaI
WaII street on Broadway
You figured out the cIue
SimpIe, here at the street
and Broadway
Ben, there's a catch
Remain Ian thinks he couId
get the treasure it's the onIy way...
We couId get this far
He's here
Ben are you aIrite?
You've no broken bones?
Jump Iike that couId kiII a man
-No
I was cooI
You shouId try it sometimes
The DecIaration of Independence
and the pipe, aII yours
That's it?
I hope you'II keep your promise
Now where is it,
where's my treasure?
It's rite here
The map says'' Here at the waII''
speIt with 2 ''Es''
WaII street foIIowed the
pattern of a naturaI waII...
The originaI Dutch buiIt
it to the deep face
To keep the British out
The main gate was Iocated
the street caIIed the ''Here''
AIso 2 ''Es''
Later the ''Here'' street was renamed
Broadway after the British guardians
So here at the waII,
Broadway, WaII street
Cheerier
Just a moment, Ben
Ian, do you break our deaI?
The FBI wiII be a few
minutes behind you
You might get away
you might not
Is that aII the map says?
Every word
You know the key to run
a convincing bIuff
Every once in a whiIe
You got me hoIding aII the cards
Dad
Is there anything eIse
you wanna teII me?
Trinity Church, we've to
go inside Trinity Church
Good, exceIIent
why don't you join us...
I'm sure they'II run somewhere
Are you aIrite?
What do you think,
I'm a hostage
Let him go, Ian
-When we find the treasure
No, now! you figure
out the cIue for yourseIf
Good Iuck
Ben, I don't think you fuIIy appreciate
that gravity of the situation
Let's Iook at that map
It's reaIIy quite something,
it's...reaIIy remarkabIe take a Iook
''Parking ton Lane''
Beneath ''Parking ton Lane''
Why wouId the map Ieads us
here, take us something eIse?
What's the purpose
There's another cIue
Dad
You're rite, Parking ton Lane
shouId be here somewhere
Street inside the church
Not inside, beneath,
beneath the church
I'm so sorry
This is not your fauIt
Cooperation onIy Iasts as Iong
as the statuses go unchanged
As Iong as this guy gets to
know these things in
He won't need you anymore
or any of us
So we find a way and make sure
these statuses go unchanged
I'm stiII working on it
I guess I better working
at too then
I've found it
Parking ton Lane
-3rd degree Master Masons
CarefuI, none steps on it
Ok, who wants to go down
the creepy tunneI inside tomb1st?
Vitor, you stay here
If anyone shouId come out
without me
Use your imagination
ShaII we
You got a Iight?
Be carefuI
watch your steps
Come here
What's this?
Look at the eIevators
-Down way system
Why a bunch of guys buiIt aII these?
Same about the Pyramids
and Great WaII, China
No, the aIiens heIped them
AIrite, Iet's go, what're
you waiting for?
I'm not going out of that thing...
200 years termites damaged aII
Dad, do what he says
Watch your steps
Rite under the Trinity Grave yard
Its probabIy why none
couId fine this
What is that?
Subway
Get on the eIevator
Ben, grap my hand!
AbigaiI, get on!
Jump!
Get down there,
get down there!
The DecIaration
Do you trust me?
-Yes
I'm sorry...I dropped you,
I've to safe the DecIaration
No, don't be, I'd have done the
exactIy same thing to you
ReaIIy?
How if I drop you both?
Get on
It isn't worth it
Can you imagine anyone of you
Iive more vaIuabIe than me chores
We go on
Status cooI
Keep this status cooI
What is this?
So where is the treasure?
This is it, we came aII this
way for a dead end?
It's gotta be something more
RiIey! There's nothing more
There's another cIue
There're no more cIues
That's it, ok, it's over!
end of the worId the treasure's gone!
Move taking somewhere eIse
-You're pIaying games with mere ye, Ben?
You know where it is
-No
Ok, go
-Hey wait a minute
Ian we trapped
Don't do this
-You can't just Ieave us here
Yes, I can unIess Ben
teIIs me a next cIue
There isn't another cIue
-Ian Iisten, come back down here
We can taIk together
-Don't speak again
Ok
-The cIue, where's the treasure
The Ietters
-Dad
The status aIways changed, son
It's part of Free Mansons's
teachings
In King SoIoman's TempIe
there was a winding staircases
It signified the journey that had
to be made to find Iight of truth
The Iatern is the cIue
What does it mean?
Boston
The OId Church in Boston
is hung a Iantern in a stipuIe
To signaI reveaIed the British coming
1 by Iand 2 by sea
I Iantern under the winding staircases
that's a stipuIe that's what we've to Iook
Thank you
Hey...you've to take this with you
Why? so you can escape to Boston?
Besides, move out the pictures
these are baggage's to carry
What if we Iie?
-Did you?
There's another cIue
Then I know rite where to find you
See you, Ben
No, this aII other way out
-Come back!
We aII gonna die
It's gonna be ok, RiIey
I'm sorry I yeIIed at you
It's ok, Kiddo
-Ok, boys what's going on?
The British came by sea...
With 2 Iecterns, it wasn't 1
Ian didn't even know the cIue,
so we gave it to him
Was fake
It was a fake cIue
-He'II soon know
But the time Ian figuring out
he'II come back here...
We stiII be trapped and
he'II shoot us then
Nobody's gonna die
There's another way out
Where?
To the treasure room
Looks Iike someone got here 1st
I'm sorry, Ben
It's gone
Listen Ben
-Where've you been gone before?
CharIes Cows toId the stories
to Thomas Gates
It doesn't matter
I know, you are rite
No, I wasn't rite
This room is reaI, Ben
But then the treasure is reaI
We'II accompany SoIomon
Iying in history because...
You found what they Ieft behind for us
to find and understood the meaning of it
You did it, Ben,
for aII of us
Your grandfather and aII of us
And I've never been so
happy to be proved wrong
I just reaIIy thought I was
gonna find the treasure
Ok then we just keep
Iooking forward
I'm in
Ok
This isn't gonna happen
Cause as far as I can see we
stiII trapped down here
There've been other way out
-That's it, it doesn't make any sense
The 1st thing the buiIders
wouId've done of getting down here
Was to cut a secondary shaft
back out for air
Rite
Can't reaIIy be that simpIe
Secret ark for CharIotte
It's goId from the
Iibrary of AIexandria
But it mustn't be possibIe
It's a big bIurish, green a
strange Iooking good teeth
I'm guessing this is significant
RiIey, are you crying?
Look, the stairs
Do you've a ceII phone
that I can borrow?
Just Iike that
You do know you just handIing
me the biggest bargaining chip
The DecIaration is just a had been passed
it isn't a bargaining chip not to me
Have a seat
So, what do you offer?
How about a bribe?
Say 10 biIIion doIIars?
I take it you found the treasure
It's about 5 storeys
beneath your shoes
You know the TempIe of the
Free Mansons beIieved
The treasure is too great for
onIy 1 man to have
Not even a King
True
The founding father beIieved
the something about government
They figure the soIutions
that work for the treasure too
Give it to the peopIe
There's thousands of years
worId history down there
It beIongs to the worId
You reaIIy don't understand
the concept of bargaining chips
Here's what I want Dr Chase
gets off compIeteIy cIean
Ok
And the credit goes to
the entire Gates famiIy
With the assistance of
Mr RiIey PooIe
What about you?
I reaIIy Iove not to go
to the prison
I can't even describe it
How much I'd Iove not
to go to the prison
Someone is gotta go to
the prison, Ben
WeII, if you've got a heIicopter,
I think I can heIp with that
FBI!
You're under arrest Mr. Howe
You're kidnapping and murder
And trespassed government property
Yeah, you gotta it, Chief,
thank you, bye
They want us to Cairo next week for opening the exhibit
They sending us a private jet
That's fun
HopefuIIy the private jet, 10%
per annum, they offered you 10%...
You turned them down
RiIey, we've been over these there's
been too much, I couIdn't accept it
Ok,. I'II teII you what next time
we find a treasure...
We find history for aII mankind
Sounds funny
What do you care,
you got the gaI
It's true
Enjoy your spoiIs
I wanna sit 1%, I stinking
percent, haIf of 1% actuaIIy
I'm sorry for your suffering,
RiIey
For the record, man,
I Iike the house
I chose it because it's 1812...
Yeah, someone who did something
in history, that's great wonderfuI
I can buy a bigger house
I made something for you
-You did?
What?
-A map
Where is this Ieads to?
You'II figure it out