NARRATOR: Since the very
beginning of our world,
there have been
wonderful stories about
how life began.
There are tales of how
the Bright Circle gave birth
to the lesser lights
of the dark time,
which watch over us
as we sleep.
And many ways
of explaining
(RUMBLING)
how our world itself
was formed.
(THUNDER CRACKING)
And how the first strange,
incredible creatures
came to walk upon the land.
(SCREECHING)
Which of the stories
are really true, Grandpa?
(LAUGHS) No one
knows, Littlefoot.
That is
one of the great
mysteries of life.
Yeah, but...
CERA: Shh! Littlefoot!
Please! Do not
interrupt!
Yeah! Petrie not like it
when you erupt neither!
(GRANDPA CLEARS THROAT)
GRANDPA: As I was saying,
after many crossings
of the Bright Circle,
great herds began
to appear on the land...
The Longnecks,
the Spiketails,
the Threehorns.
(GROANS)
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
Oh, Dana, Dinah. Hiya!
Threebie hornas!
Hush you two,
or Auntie Cera's
gonna be upset!
Ooh! "Auntie Cera!"
Well! (GIGGLES)
Mmm!
(CHUCKLES)
All right, children.
What happened then,
Grandpa?
Some of these herds,
in their migrations
across the land,
found the most fertile,
beautiful place
in the world.
CHILDREN: The Great Valley!
GRANDPA: Yes. And life
in the Great Valley was good,
(EERILY) until one day,
(DISTANT ROARING)
the Sharptooth came!
(ROARING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(FOOTSTEPS THUDDING)
GRANDPA: And not
just any Sharptooth,
but the biggest,
meanest, most ferocious
Sharptooth ever!
(ROARING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(GASPS)
(STRAINING)
YOUNG LONGNECK: Mama!
(GASPS)
(SCREAMS)
(SHARPTOOTH GROWLING)
GRANDPA: But then,
just when the Longnecks
thought all was lost,
(THUDS)
the Lone Dinosaur
appeared on the horizon!
PETRIE: The who?
The what?
The Lone Dinosaur!
But what is a lone...
Shh!
(GASPS)
GRANDPA: The battle
seemed to last for hours.
It was a spectacle
no one had ever seen before!
(GROWLING)
A lone leaf-eater
taking on a Sharptooth!
(ROARS)
(THUDS)
(YELPS)
GRANDPA: But then...
(GROANS)
(ROARS)
(CRASHING)
(YELPS)
(BRANCHES CRACKING)
(THUDDING)
(ALL SHOUTING EXCITEDLY)
YOUNG LONGNECK: Wait!
Come back. Come back!
(THUDDING)
GRANDPA: And just as suddenly
as he had appeared,
the Lone Dinosaur went away.
ALL: Oh!
That's it?
He just leave?
Nobody ever
saw him again?
Well, legend has it
that not long
after the defeat
of the Sharptooth...
(RUMBLING)
Earthshake!
(GASPS)
(PANTING)
(THUDS)
(SCREAMS)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(CRACKING)
(SPARKING)
ALL: Ooh!
GRANDPA: So they
called it "Saurus Rock."
And it's there
to this very day.
Sometimes, when the wind
is just right and blows
away the mists,
you can see it,
watching over
the Great Valley
just like the Lone Dinosaur
did so many years ago.
They say if you look
very closely
you can see
the circle of teeth
around its neck.
Real teeth?
The story goes
that they came
from the very Sharptooth
the Lone Dinosaur defeated.
ALL: Whoa!
(BOTH WHIMPERING)
They say that
some nights,
you can see the ghost
of that Sharptooth
wandering around,
looking for his teeth!
(BOTH GASP)
(ROARS)
(BOTH YELP)
(ALL LAUGH)
Scary Dana...
Dinah no no!
BOTH: Uh-uh.
(CHUCKLES) Well,
I've never heard
that part of the legend.
But they do say that
if anything ever happens
to Saurus Rock,
(EERILY) bad luck
will descend upon
the Great Valley.
Is it all true, Grandpa?
Well, (CHUCKLES)
it's a grand adventure,
and a really good story.
And it is nice to think
that somewhere out there
is a Lone Dinosaur
watching over us all.
GRANDMA: Grandpa Longneck!
Are you filling
these children's heads
full of nonsense,
and just
before bedtime?
(STUTTERS) Why,
uh, no, I was just...
Yes, I know.
But it's late.
Time for little ones
to be in the nest,
(BOTH YAWN)
resting for another day.
(YAWNS) She right.
Me pooped.
Night, Littlefoot.
Night, Petrie!
Now, Spike,
do not be scared
to walk home
in the dark.
The Lone Dinosaur
will protect us.
He will!
(MUMBLES)
But just in case,
you go first.
Come on, you two.
(SLEEPILY)
No uppies.
Dinah Dana,
sleepy.
(BOTH YAWN)
(BOTH SIGH)
Oh, all right.
Hop on.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(GROANS) Ow!
Don't yank my horns!
They're attached,
you know!
(LAUGHS)
And now
it's your turn,
Littlefoot.
(YAWNS)
Yes, Grandma.
I'm the Lone Dinosaur.
I can find my way
home in the dark
all alone!
(ANIMAL YELPING)
Um, you coming?
(SCREAMS)
(ROARS)
(GASPS) There he is!
The Lone Dinosaur!
(GASPS)
LITTLEFOOT:
(SWISHING) Hiya!
(GROANS)
(THUDDING)
(SCOFFS)
(ALL CHEERING)
I wonder
if it's really all true.
(THUDDING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
BOTH: More tree stars!
(GRUNTS)
(THUDS)
Look, over here!
Over here!
(ALL CHEERING)
What are you children doing?
Oh! Hi, Daddy.
Hello, sir.
We were just, uh...
Don't you kids realize
this is the Time of
the Changing Tree Stars?
We can't waste those
that haven't fallen yet!
They must be eaten
before they dry up.
Do you want us
to run out of food entirely?
GRANDPA: Now, now.
There's no need to frighten
the young ones.
(SCOFFS)
Anyways, Cera,
you should be
watching the twins!
Daddy, I am
watching them!
Oh, really?
Then where are they?
(BOTH SCREAM)
(ALL GRUNT)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Right here. See?
Oh! I knew those Longnecks
should've been watching!
Way to go!
You almost got me
in big trouble.
Oh, Dana no no!
Boohoo Dinah!
(BOTH CRY)
What we
gonna do now?
We do not
want Cera's dad
mad at us again!
No, no, no!
Hey, I got it!
We can play
"Lone Dinosaur"!
Huh?
How do you play?
Well, one of us
is the Lone Dinosaur,
one of us
is the Sharptooth,
and the rest are
the ones who get
chased and saved!
Who gets to be
the Lone Dinosaur?
Well, it was my idea.
Then who's the Sharptooth?
Well, it should
be somebody
who's pretty big
and can act
pretty mean.
Me?
BOTH: Cerrie!
Cerrie! Cerrie!
How come
I have to be
the bad guy?
Well, you, uh,
you're so good
at pretend.
'Member how you
scare twins
last night?
It scared me!
It scared Spike, too!
Right, Spike?
(YAWNS)
(MUMBLES)
Then it's settled!
(ROARS)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
(CERA ROARS)
(KIDS SCREAM)
Never... (CLEARS THROAT)
(DEEPLY) Never fear!
I'm coming!
Mmm. Gotta make
a big entrance.
(GASPS)
Perfect!
(ALL SHOUTING CHEERFULLY)
(CERA ROARING)
Now I have you!
No! Please,
do not eat us,
mean old Sharptooth!
Oh, no, no, no!
Yeah! (GIGGLES)
Me too young
to get ate.
(DEEPLY) Stand back,
big bad Sharptooth!
Never fear!
The Lone Dinosaur is...
(SCREAMS)
(ALL SCREAM)
(GRUNTS) Whoa!
Gee! Thanks!
For a second there
I thought I was...
(GASPS)
(STUTTERS) It's you.
I mean, you're here!
I mean,
who are you?
Name's Doc.
What's going on here?
Who is this?
Are you
bothering our kids?
Daddy! No!
Him save Littlefoot!
Saved Littlefoot?
Goodness!
Are you all right,
little one?
Yes, Grandma.
I was climbing
on that rotten log,
and I fell.
Me see him!
He fall very fast,
'cause he not flyer
like me!
And then this
very big and very nice
Longneck is there!
And he caught him!
Of course,
we probably would've
caught him, too.
Well, wherever you
came from,
you have my thanks
for saving my grandson.
Welcome to
the Great Valley!
Welcome!
Just passing through.
Well, stay just
as long as you want.
Hold on there!
We don't know anything
about this fellow!
Who is he? Where's his herd?
Kind of a loner.
CERA'S DAD:
Mighty suspicious,
if you ask me.
I say send him
on his way!
You sure you feel
up to it, friend?
(STUTTERS) Well,
I... That is...
Uh, our life here
is a sheltered one.
Uh, perhaps we've
forgotten how to greet
unexpected guests.
As Grandma said,
you are welcome here.
What's ours is yours.
What?
But it's the Time
of the Changing
Tree Stars!
Every day,
there's less food
to go around.
And Longnecks
eat a lot!
There's still
plenty for all.
(SCOFFS) Longnecks!
Always stick together!
(CERA'S DAD MUMBLES)
(LAUGHS)
Don't mind him.
He's a good sort,
once you get
to know him.
Don't know
as I want to stay
that long.
(ALL SNICKERING)
All right, children,
run and play.
Let's give our guest
some peace.
Littlefoot, come on!
Hello, kid.
Hi.
Shouldn't you be
with your little pals?
I, uh, I just wanted
to say thanks again
for saving my life.
Hmm, lucky catch.
Um, hey!
If you like tree stars,
there's a big grove
of them down...
By the watering hole,
past the tall grass.
How'd you know?
Been here before.
(GASPS)
Where'd you get
that scar?
Cut myself.
On what?
Something sharp.
Like a tooth?
A sharp tooth?
Kid.
I think I hear
your friends calling.
(STUTTERS)
Yeah, me, too.
Nice talking
to you.
Yup.
Oh boy!
(BUBBLING)
(KIDS LAUGHING)
(GASPS)
Yuck!
Hey! My skin feel
softer already!
Come on! Last one across
is Sharptooth bait!
(BOTH SNICKER)
BOTH: Cerrie!
(LAUGHING)
Whoa! Watch out.
Don't push Auntie...
Uh-oh, Dinah! Uh-oh!
Dana no no! Uh-oh!
(ECHOING) Let me
outta here! Help! Help!
Help!
(GASPS)
Me coming!
(POPS)
(GASPS)
(BOTH SNICKER)
(CHUCKLES)
(GRUNTS)
(MUTTERS)
(GROANS)
(CHUCKLES) Hey!
(HUMMING)
(GASPS)
DANA: Cerrie mad us?
Smiley Cerrie?
(GRUNTS)
BOTH: Whoa!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Leave me alone,
you little pests.
Get lost!
(BOTH SOBBING)
Cera!
What? What?
(BOTH GRUNT)
Hey, guys,
guess what?
CERA: What?
What?
I just figured out
who Doc is!
What's the big mystery?
He's a squinty-eyed
old Longneck
with no friends.
Me could
have tell you that.
No! He's the Lone Dinosaur!
That is what Cera said,
he is a lone dinosaur.
Not a lone dinosaur,
the Lone Dinosaur!
CERA: Are you crazy?
You should talk to him!
He's been to
the Great Valley before,
he's got this
mysterious scar,
he can do fancy tricks
with his tail,
and we know he's a hero,
'cause he saved me!
Well, I've saved you
lots of times.
Does that make me
the Lone Threehorn?
(ALL LAUGH)
Guys, I'm serious!
Listen!
(SINGING)
(SINGING CONTINUES)
(ALL LAUGHING)
(SINGING STOPS)
ALL: Yee-haw!
(ALL SNICKERING)
Well, hmm.
Wow, the Lone Dinosaur!
Right here!
Wait a second!
Your grandma said
all that stuff
about the Lone Dinosaur
is just a story.
That right. Me hear her.
Well, I think
it really happened!
Even if it did,
it couldn't have been Doc!
That was a long,
long, long time ago!
The real Lone Dinosaur
wouldn't still be alive.
Would he?
Me no know.
I do not know, either.
I do not.
Well, I think
he is alive,
and he's right here
in the Great Valley!
I'll bet if you
ever got a good look
at Saurus Rock,
you'd see it looks
just like Doc!
Dana... Rocky,
go, go!
Dinah!
BOTH: Now!
GRANDPA: Oh, Littlefoot!
I've got to go.
Listen, don't say
anything about this
to the grown-ups,
okay? (WHISPERS)
(SCOFFS) Don't worry.
We don't want them
to know you're nuts, too.
GRANDPA: Littlefoot!
Well, bye!
Saurus Rock! (SCOFFS)
(BOTH MUTTERING)
(BOTH SNICKERING)
(MIMICS DOC)
You talking to me?
Well, who are you talking to?
You sure you feel
up to it, friend?
(SWISHING) Ow!
(CHUCKLES) Time
to settle down,
Littlefoot.
Uh, Grandpa,
I was just, uh...
I know.
It's exciting
to meet someone
new and different.
And you'll have
plenty of time to get
to know him better.
But for now,
it's time for some rest.
Yes, Grandpa. (YAWNS)
Night.
Mmm. (CHUCKLES)
Huh? What? Cera?
Have you seen them?
Are they here?
Please say they're here!
Huh? Who?
The twins!
Mmm. No,
they're not here.
Oh, no!
They've disappeared!
Dinah! Dana!
(ECHOES) Kids!
(GRUNTS) Yoo-hoo!
Ah!
(CRACKING)
(SNORING)
Hello, twins,
are you in there?
(GRUNTING)
Uh-oh.
(STUTTERS) Sorry,
Mrs. Maia. I...
Whoa!
(GRUNTS) Oh!
Now I am really sorry.
Yep, yep, yep.
This is terrible!
I'm gonna be
in so much trouble!
I was in charge of them!
(GRUNTING)
Cera, calm down!
We'll find them!
Yes, they cannot be
too far away.
Let's think about this.
When was the last time
you saw them?
Let's see.
Yesterday by
the bubbling goo.
They pushed me in,
I got mad.
I told them
to get lost!
Huh! That right!
She said that!
Me heard her!
Who knew they even knew
what that means?
Then what happened?
Then you showed up,
and started talking
about Doc and
the Lone Dinosaur,
and what Saurus Rock
must look like, and...
ALL: Saurus Rock!
(TWINS CHUCKLING)
Sorry Rocky!
Go, go, us!
(BOTH STRAIN)
(GASPS)
(WEAKLY) And I remember
the day Dinah said
her first words.
Or was it Dana? (SNIFFS)
"Shiny peep-eye no no."
Whatever that means.
It is simple.
That means,
"The Bright Circle
is shining in my eyes
"and it hurts."
How'd you know that?
I am also a twin.
Thirteen of us hatched
at the same time.
Thirteen twins!
Come on,
you guys. We've got
a long way to go.
CERA: So then what does
"No no Grampy Threebie
grr" mean?
DUCKY: That means
"Never make Grandpa
Threehorn mad!"
CERA: Are you sure
about that one?
DUCKY: No. But it is
good advice, just the same.
(WIND WHOOSHING)
BOTH: Ooh!
(ECHOING) Ah!
(LAUGHING)
(GRUNTS)
(GASPING)
(GIGGLES)
(ALL GRUNTING)
They're out there
somewhere.
So little,
and tired,
and scared.
Whoo!
(BOTH GIGGLING)
(THUDDING)
(SNIFFING)
(GROWLING)
(GROANS)
Oh, no! The twins
could never get
across there.
Wait! Remember
the bubbling brown goo?
Whoa!
Maybe they hopped
across the big ditch.
Yep, yep, yep!
(GRUNTS)
It's not hard.
Come on, Cera!
(GROANS)
The things I do for family.
(GRUNTS)
(SHAKILY) Whoa!
Hey, this is kind of fun!
Let's go, Spike.
Me right there with you!
(GASPS)
(MUMBLING)
You can do it.
Just no look down.
(STRAINS)
Spike! No! (GRUNTS)
(GRUNTS)
No look down,
but look at something!
(GASPS)
(WHIMPERS)
(GRUNTS)
Not bad for first try.
You can do it, Spike!
Come on, Spike!
Wait for Petrie!
(THUDDING)
(RUMBLING)
Oh.
Me guess we take
the long way home.
LITTLEFOOT: Whoa!
Not even Grandpa
could reach
those tree stars!
My dad could.
How?
The Threehorn way.
He'd just knock it
right over.
One of these trees?
I don't think so!
Oh, yeah?
Watch this!
(GRUNTS)
Uh, nice one.
Me convinced.
That sure didn't feel
like a tree trunk.
It no look like
tree trunk either.
(GROWLING)
And it does not sound
like a tree trunk. No, no...
No!
(ALL SCREAMING)
It is not
a tree trunk!
(ALLOSAURUS ROARS)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(GROWLING)
(THUDS)
(ALL PANTING)
I think
we lost him.
(GASPS)
(ALL GASP)
Saurus Rock
does look like Doc!
Sort of.
Maybe.
A little.
(GASPS) And there's the twins!
(ECHOING) Dinah! Dana!
Thank goodness
you're okay!
BOTH: Huh? Huh?
Cerrie! Looka whee!
Us uppie!
BOTH: Uppie!
What'd they say?
They say look at them,
they are high up
on the top.
Yeah! So be careful!
(BOTH GIGGLING)
CERA: Look out!
Hold on! We're coming!
(ALL STRAINING)
Roll other way.
Roll other way!
(STRAINS) Hang on, twins,
I'm almost there!
(GASPS)
(BOTH GIGGLING)
(BOTH SCREAM)
(STRAINS)
(CRACKING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(THUDDING)
(MUMBLING)
(RUMBLING)
Uh-oh. Oops!
Oops!
(SOBBING) Sad us, Cerrie.
Dana, Dinah, no no.
It's okay. It's not
your fault Saurus Rock
got broken.
It's yours!
(GASPS) Me!
What'd I do?
If you hadn't been
talking about Saurus Rock,
Dinah and Dana
wouldn't have run away
in the first place!
Cerrie say so. Bye.
We bye-bye.
What did
the little dears say?
They said you are the one
who told them to get lost.
(ALL LAUGHING)
I'm also the one
who won't come
and save you the next time,
if you run
away again! Got it?
Uh-huh.
Yeah.
And not a word about this
to Grandpa Threehorn.
BOTH: Uh-uh! No!
'Cause you don't want
to see Grandpa Threehorn
when he's mad!
When Grandpa Threehorn
gets mad, it's even
scarier than... Than...
A Sharptooth!
No, I think a Sharptooth's
a little bit scarier.
Maybe.
(WEAKLY) No, no, Cera!
Really, behind you!
Oh, Come on.
Don't try that
old gag on me.
(MUTTERS)
(GROWLING)
Okay, Ducky,
nice try!
You almost sound
like a Sharptooth!
Hey, is it
starting to rain?
Argh! Sharptooth drool!
(ALL SCREAMING)
(ROARS)
(PANTING) Yuck!
It spit on me!
(WHIMPERS) It pick
its teeth with you
if you no hurry!
(ALL SCREAMING)
This way!
(THUDDING)
Hey, everybody,
in here!
DUCKY: Cera, it is
a good thing that Sharpteeth
are not very smart.
PETRIE: It dark in here.
DUCKY: (GRUNTS) Spike,
do not poke me!
LITTLEFOOT: Shh! Quiet!
DUCKY: Hey, what is this?
(SCREAMS)
(ROARS)
(ALL SCREAMING)
Whoa!
CERA: Oh, great.
Where are we now?
PETRIE: Me no know,
but it sure still
dark in here.
DUCKY: Maybe we are
in his tummy.
TWINS: (MIMIC VOMITING)
Yuckie!
(STRAINS)
(GRUNTS)
It no look
like tummy. Me no see
Sharptooth at all.
Hey!
No problem!
You guys can walk
right 'cross big ditch!
(STRAINS)
He's right.
Let's go!
Dinah, Dana,
come on!
(STRAINS)
BOTH: Whoa!
Pay attention!
We're going that way!
(BOTH GIGGLING)
CERA: Move it!
(SCREAMS)
I do not like this,
no, no, no.
No worry!
You swimmer, right?
Mmm-hmm.
If you fall, there a skinny
little river way down there
that you might land in!
Maybe.
Oh, thank you.
I feel much better now.
(STRAINS)
Okay, Spike,
let's go!
(STRAINS)
LITTLEFOOT: That's it.
Atta boy. What's the matter?
You're not stuck, are you?
(STRETCHING)
(GROWLING)
(ROARS)
You don't know
how sorry I am
to hear that.
Come on, Spike!
Move!
(STRAINS)
(BOTH STRAIN)
(GASPS)
(ROARS)
(ALL SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
Come on!
(ROARS)
(SCREAMING)
(ALLOSAURUS ROARING)
(THUDDING)
Whoa!
CERA: (SIGHS) What a day!
I thought we'd never get home.
Hey, we got
the twins back.
And your dad
never even knew
they ran away.
Ran away?
(STUTTERS)
Hi, Daddy.
What did he mean, Cera?
Did the twins really run away?
Well, sort of,
for a little while,
but they didn't go far.
Ussie go, go.
Sorry Rocky!
They said they went
to Saurus Rock.
Saurus Rock? Cera!
It was your duty
to watch the twins
and you failed.
Yes, Daddy.
I am very
disappointed in you!
Now march yourself
right home!
Apparently, you still need
to be watched yourself!
Losing the twins!
I never heard of such
a thing! It's absurd!
Me and my big mouth.
Do not feel bad,
Littlefoot.
It not your fault.
Just bad luck.
DUCKY: Just like
your Grandpa said
it would be,
if anything happened
to Saurus Rock.
First we have bad luck.
Then the whole
Great Valley will
have bad luck.
Then maybe
the whole dinosaur world
will have bad luck.
Then maybe even
the whole universe
will have bad luck.
Gosh! She's right.
Bad luck.
(STRAINS)
(SCREAMS)
(GASPS)
(PANTING)
Littlefoot, are you
all right?
Just a bad dream.
Well, it's all
over now. Try to get
back to sleep.
Grandpa?
Mmm?
What if something
happened to Saurus Rock?
What do you mean?
Something bad.
Like, it broke, or somebody
broke it or something.
As I told you,
the legend says
bad luck would
descend upon
the Great Valley.
(CHUCKLES)
But no time
for stories tonight.
Sleep now, little one.
PETRIE: Just bad luck.
DUCKY: Like your
Grandpa said,
(ECHOING) the whole
Great Valley.
GRANDPA: Bad luck!
DUCKY: Then
the whole dinosaur world!
PETRIE: (EERILY) Bad luck!
GRANDPA: (EERILY) Bad luck!
Bad luck?
Yeah. Just like you said.
Ever since we came back
from Saurus Rock.
(LAUGHING) Me just say that.
Me no believe in bad luck!
Huh?
Ducky! What happened
to your beak?
I got it stuck in a hive
of buzzing stingers.
What about
Spike's tail?
Same thing.
You don't call
that bad luck?
Nah. Could happen
to anybody.
Whoa! (GROANS)
Huh?
(BEES BUZZING)
(SCREAMS)
Do not worry, Littlefoot.
What is a little bad luck?
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(SINGING)
(ALL SCREAM)
(SINGING CONTINUES)
(SINGING STOPS)
What do you think, Cera?
The only bad luck
I ever had
was having to watch
those crazy twins.
And now my dad
treats me like a baby.
Cerrie!
Grampy Threebie! Now!
Yoohoo go, go! Now!
Uh, your dad
wants you home.
See what I mean?
They're in charge
of me!
Whoa!
(GIGGLES)
It's just like
Grandpa said,
if something happens
to Saurus Rock,
bad luck descends
on the Valley.
Maybe. But so far
we the only ones
having bad luck.
Yeah, but what
if it starts happening
to everybody?
It'll be our fault!
This is serious, Longneck.
What could make
the watering place
dry up like this?
Hmm. Perhaps the last
earthshake moved it
under the ground.
This is horrible.
Oh!
(ALL TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Please, Please, everyone.
Calm down.
There is still
plenty of water
in the Great Valley.
Yes, but this watering place
was the coolest
and the clearest.
Oh, why did it have to be
the one that dried up?
Very bad luck,
if you ask me.
(ALL TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(GASPING)
(RUSTLING)
Hi, Doc.
Mind if I hang around?
Suit yourself.
(MUNCHING)
Hey, Doc.
You believe
in bad luck?
Seen too much of it
not to.
Say you're having
a lot of bad luck...
What can you do
about it?
Change what you can,
accept what you can't.
You can change luck?
Really? How?
If there's a problem,
try to fix it.
If you can't,
sometimes you just
have to move on.
Oh. But what if...
What if you
don't want to move on?
Then you're asking
the wrong Longneck, kid.
I'm a loner.
That's the way
I've always lived.
This valley's nice.
But there are others
just as nice
out there somewhere.
I've always done it my way...
Moving on, looking for
someplace a little better.
Don't you ever
get lonesome?
Sometimes.
Sometimes I feel
a bit crowded too.
My footsteps were
planted on the wandering
trail long ago.
I'm too old
to change now.
(MOANS)
(CHUCKLING)
(SQUEALING)
Whoa! Whoa!
(CHUCKLING)
What's going on?
I don't know.
We should
find our folks.
Oh, dear...
I don't like
the looks of this.
The children.
Find the children.
GRANDPA: Littlefoot!
Littlefoot!
Cera! Cera!
Oh, no!
Where are the twins?
(WHIMPERING)
Hurry, little ones.
(WIND WHOOSHING)
Littlefoot!
Where are you, Grandpa?
(STRAINING)
Hang on!
Auntie Cera's here.
Littlefoot! Where are you?
Cera!
CERA: Daddy!
CERA'S DAD: Cera...
(GASPS)
Hang on, kid.
Keep your head down!
Littlefoot! Oh!
It's...
It's over.
Littlefoot.
(RUSTLING)
Grandpa?
Oh, Littlefoot.
He saved me!
Doc saved me!
Again!
Then I thank you. Again.
Ah... Lucky break.
Grandpa! Littlefoot!
Thank goodness
you're both safe.
Me never see
swirling wind
like that before.
Oh, no, no, no.
Cerrie ussie blowie no no!
Whoosh!
(CHUCKLING) Yes.
It is good that Cera
didn't let you blow away.
Cera?
I'm very proud of you.
GRANDPA: Oh... Just look
at our beautiful valley.
Well... Looking at it
won't get it cleaned up.
(ALL GROANING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(BOTH SIGHING)
Mighty strange the way
things have been
happening lately.
Take this storm,
for instance.
We've had
whirling winds before.
They're just part of
the circle of life.
I know, but...
It seems to me that we've
suffered more than our share
of misfortunes
since a certain stranger
came to the Valley.
(GROANING)
GRANDPA:
Now, Mr. Threehorn...
I agree
with Threehorn here.
Life was good
in this valley,
just fine.
And then he shows up
and everything falls apart.
That's right!
GROWN-UP: Our luck has turned.
GROWN-UP 2:
It's the stranger's fault.
GROWN-UP 3: He's bad luck.
Please, everyone.
You're being unfair.
Understand me, Longneck.
I'm not saying anything
against the fellow.
He may be quite fine
in his own way.
Apparently he saved
your boy, and...
That's right! He did!
Littlefoot...
Doc did save my life!
He's a real live hero.
The only one I ever met!
Calm down, son.
I merely meant that...
Doc is the bravest and...
And... And the best Longneck
that ever was.
I never said he wasn't,
Littlefoot.
All I said was
that he brought bad luck
to the Valley.
He didn't! He didn't!
All right, Littlefoot.
All right. Shh.
(LITTLEFOOT PANTING)
See here, Longneck.
I, uh, didn't mean
to make the boy...
I know. I know.
We're all a bit upset.
I suggest we discuss
these matters later.
For now, it's best
if we all pitch in.
(ALL TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Littlefoot?
You okay?
Yeah. I'm fine.
All the bad luck...
It's not his fault.
Yes, it is.
No, it isn't.
Well, I agree with my dad.
I think Doc did cause
all the bad luck.
We know who caused
the bad luck, Cera,
and it wasn't Doc.
It was us.
Look, I never liked
the guy much, okay?
And I'm not even sure
I believe in this
bad luck stuff.
But if the grown-ups
want to blame him,
why not let 'em?
'Cause it's not fair!
They're gonna end up
chasing him away.
And I don't want
him to go.
Well, there's nothing
you can do about it, anyway.
Yes, there is.
I can fix it.
(SPITS) What?
I'm not gonna let Doc
take the blame for all this.
If they won't help me,
I'll just have to do
what a lone dinosaur
would do.
Go off by myself
and change what I can.
Maybe I can
change our luck.
Why you say that, Cera?
I didn't mean to make
him mad, but...
Hey, my dad's happy
with me again.
I'd be crazy to let him
find out we caused
all this lousy luck.
I thought you did not
believe in bad luck.
Do you?
I do not know.
Hmm...
(GRUNTS)
(CRASHING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(ALL WHIMPERING)
Petrie believe.
Bad luck real.
Well... Maybe I believe it.
If it is bad luck,
Littlefoot is right.
We did cause it.
Yep, yep, yep.
Well, then, we'll just
have to fix it.
We?
Who needs them, anyway?
I'm a lone dinosaur.
I don't need anybody.
Gee. I wonder if all
the other lone dinosaurs
talk out loud
to themselves like this?
They must.
It would be too quiet.
(SINGING)
(SINGING STOPS)
Littlefoot!
Hey, Littlefoot.
Where'd you go?
Me no find him anywhere.
No see ussie.
Dinah Dana.
BOTH: Huh-uh!
What was it he said,
right before he left?
Littlefoot say
he gonna fix it.
Fix what?
Uh, the bad luck,
I guess.
Yes, but how?
Well...
He said we caused
it when we broke
the Sharptooth's tooth
off Saurus Rock.
(GASPS)
Uh-oh.
You kids better wait
with Grandpa Threehorn.
We've got something
we need to do.
Let's see.
Now where...
There he is!
Right where he landed.
Just one tooth...
(GASPS)
That's all I need. (GROANS)
If I can get it back
on Saurus Rock,
all the bad luck will end.
Whoa!
(PANTING)
And Doc can stay.
So that's it?
You're leaving?
You don't have to go.
Nobody really blames you
for these...
Misfortunes.
Such things are just part
of the circle of life.
I'd be moving on,
anyway.
Now is as good a time
as any.
No need to cause trouble.
Littlefoot will miss you.
He's a good kid.
Well. Better get started
while the Bright
Circle's high.
You're always welcome
if you happen to be
heading this way again.
Much obliged.
KIDS:
Grandpa Longneck!
What is it, children?
Where's Littlefoot?
(GULPS)
(GASPS)
Sure looks dead.
(SNIFFING)
Sure smells dead.
Come on. You can do this.
What's the big deal?
It's just a big,
dead Sharptooth.
Might as well be
a pile of dirt.
A big, smelly
pile of dirt.
With...
Big, sharp teeth inside.
Hmm...
I'm gonna need a stick
or something to get
his mouth open.
(SNARLS)
(GROANING) Oh...
Now which way?
(PANTING)
You mean you don't know
the way to Saurus Rock?
GRANDPA:
To tell you the truth,
I've never gone there.
But you knew so much
about it.
What it looked like,
and how it got there
and everything.
You did, you did.
Yep, yep, yep.
Oh, well...
Those were stories
my grandpa told me
when I was a youngster.
(PANTING) Whew!
Oh...
And right now I wish
I'd never told them
to you kids.
(STRAINING)
Ew...
I better just pick one
and get out of here.
I don't know how long
that stick will hold.
That looks
like a good one.
(STRAINING)
(GRUNTS)
It's stuck in there
pretty tight.
(GRUNTING CONTINUES)
I can do this.
Whew!
Good thing there's
a breeze in here.
Wait a second.
I'm inside a dead Sharptooth.
Why would there be
a breeze?
Unless it's... Breathing.
But if it's breathing,
then that means...
(SCREAMING)
It's alive!
(ROARING)
(GROANS)
(SHARPTOOTH GROWLING)
(GASPS)
(ROARS)
(SCREAMS)
(PANTING)
Gee! I wonder
if I lost...
Help!
I don't want to be a lone
dinosaur anymore!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GROANS)
(GROWLING)
Doc? Grandpa!
Run, Littlefoot!
(PANTING)
You came for me.
Don't we always?
You sure do.
I just hope Grandpa
will be all right.
(ALL CHEERING)
Come on, Grandpa go!
Oh! He doing okay.
Until now...
(ROARING)
(THUDDING)
(GROANS)
Grandpa!
Me no look!
I gotta help him.
LITTLEFOOT: Doc!
(THUDDING)
Oh! You sure have
a habit of showing up
at the right time.
Still just lucky,
I guess.
(CRASHING)
GRANDPA: It's a good thing
Sharpteeth aren't
very smart.
(RUMBLING)
(ALL CHEERING)
Yay, Doc! Hurray!
(GASPS)
(CHEERING CONTINUES)
LITTLEFOOT:
Doc, Doc!
You don't have to leave.
The time of bad luck's
almost over.
It's just time
I was going, kid.
Yeah, but...
This herd life's
not for me.
Too much talking.
Well...
Be seein' ya, kid.
Okay, Doc.
And thanks.
Good luck, kid.
Doc! Don't go too far.
You never know
when we might
need... A hero.
You already got
a hero, kid.
How's that look, Grandpa?
(CHUCKLING)
It looks wonderful,
Littlefoot.
LITTLEFOOT: Now maybe
the time of bad luck
will finally be over.
GRANDPA:
Oh, Littlefoot, I told you.
That was all just
a bedtime story.
There's no...
I know, I know.
There's no such thing
as bad luck.
But there's no harm
in making sure.
I suppose not.
Let's go home.
Grandpa?
Yes, Littlefoot?
Thanks for being my hero.
(CHUCKLING)
CERA: There was
no place to hide.
All seemed lost
for the leaf-eaters.
That terrible Sharptooth
had them cornered.
His massive teeth
dripped blood
as he threw his head back
and roared.
(ROARING)
But then...
Just when there seemed
to be no escape...
Suddenly...
Oh, let me tell this part.
Oh, okay.
Just when there seemed
to be no escape,
suddenly the leaf-eaters
looked on the horizon.
LITTLEFOOT:
And there stood...
The Great Dinosaur!
He stared
at the Sharptooth.
ALL: Whoa!
Then he whipped
his tail forward...
NARRATOR: And so,
another myth was born.
It would change
with each re-telling.
And even now...
Who knows where this one
will end?