NARRATOR: Millions
and millions of years ago,
before there were countries,
or cities, or states,
before there were horses,
or bears, or elephants,
before the first human
ever walked the earth,
the world was filled
with strange and
wonderful creatures.
The greatest
of these creatures
were called dinosaurs.
(ROARS)
But the realm of
the dinosaur was changing.
The weather, the plants,
and the animals
were beginning to transform.
Still, despite the changes
happening in the
outside world,
life in the Great Valley
remained the same.
Grr! Grr!
(GRUNTS)
(LAUGHS)
Cera, you are
a good green
food getter,
you are!
CERA: Let's eat!
(MUNCHING)
ALL: Huh?
ALL: Spike!
(ALL LAUGHING)
Hey, here's Spike.
But where's Littlefoot?
Hello.
(BUZZING IN UPSET)
Wait. Don't go.
(LAUGHS)
(BUZZING)
(LAUGHING)
(GASPS)
Whoa!
(SIGHS)
(FAINT GROWLING IN DISTANCE)
Huh? Wow.
Who are they?
Who's who,
Littlefoot?
Over there, Cera.
Look.
Hey, they're long necks
just like you, Littlefoot.
Yeah.
I wonder where
they came from.
Grandma! Grandpa!
A herd of long necks are
coming into our valley!
Yes. We saw them,
too, Littlefoot.
(GRUNTS) Grandma,
why are you washing
my face?
It's only gonna
get dirty again.
Because we're going
to go and greet our
visitors, Littlefoot.
You want to look nice,
don't you?
Well, I guess.
But who are they?
And where do they
come from?
GRANDPA: They're
our cousins, Littlefoot.
They're a migrating herd.
Migrating?
GRANDPA: That means
they travel and live
in different places.
You mean instead of
living in one place
like us?
That's right.
I wouldn't like that.
I like living in
the Great Valley.
(LAUGHING) Yes.
We do, too, Littlefoot.
Now come. Let's go
welcome our cousins.
(LAUGHS)
Okay!
Hey! Do you think
they have kids?
I'm sure they do.
Oh!
Grandpa!
Are you all right?
Strange. I...
I suddenly felt
so tired.
Perhaps we better
stay here.
Oh, nonsense.
I feel better
already.
Well, Littlefoot,
why don't you
lead the way?
All right!
Everybody follow me.
I'm fine, Grandma.
Really.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Welcome to our valley,
Old One.
Yes.
Now tell me,
how is your climate?
Our climate?
It's... It's fine.
And your land?
Has it changed?
Why, no, it hasn't.
OLD ONE: Good.
Of course,
who knows how long
that will last?
What's that stuffy
old long neck mean by,
"Who knows how long
that will last?"
Shh!
Hmm!
My herd has roamed
far and wide.
And everywhere,
things are changing.
(GASPS)
(ALL GASP)
ALL: Changing?
(FRIGHTENED CHATTERING)
Old one,
are you saying changes
will happen here, too?
I don't know.
All I do know
is that once,
our land was
just like yours.
Then water fell from the sky
for weeks on end.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Our land grew
wet and soggy.
Strange creatures began
to make their home
on what was once dry land.
Other creatures
moved into the trees
that were our source
of food.
(SQUEAKING)
The once green land we had
migrated across for years
had become...
The Land of Mists.
We had no choice
but to leave.
Does this mean that
you and your herd
will be staying
with us, Old One?
We stay in no place
very long.
You and the other
Great Valley long necks
may join us
when we leave.
After all,
there is safety
in numbers.
Um... Grandpa,
we're not going to
migrate, are we?
Of course not,
Littlefoot.
The Great Valley
is our home.
(RELIEVED SIGH)
DUCKY: Oh, Littlefoot,
I'm so glad
you are not leaving.
I am. I am.
The Great Valley
will never change.
Oh, no, no,
no, no, no.
Me glad you not
leaving, too.
Me miss you
whole bunch.
(LAUGHS) I'd miss you,
too, Petrie.
(SLURPS)
(GIGGLING)
Does this mean you'd
miss me, too, Spike?
(SIGHS)
Um, Cera...
Would you miss me?
Well...
I...
Ooh!
Maybe I would and
maybe I wouldn't.
I'm not telling.
Why are you
not telling, Cera?
Is it a secret?
Is it? Huh?
Well,
if you really
want to know,
you have to
catch me first!
Hee!
(DUCKY GIGGLING)
Me catch you, Cera!
You'd better run fast!
(DUCKY LAUGHING)
Wait a minute.
Is that you, Cera?
Ow!
(LAUGHS)
Okay, Cera.
You asked for it.
(ALI GIGGLING)
(GASPS)
(BOTH EXCLAIMING)
(CRASHING)
(LAUGHS)
Hey, you're not Cera.
You're a long neck
like me.
I'm Ali.
What's your name?
Littlefoot.
Um... You want to play
with me, Littlefoot?
Sure.
Great! Not it!
You're it!
(LAUGHS) Maybe!
But not for long!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
All right already!
I'll tell Littlefoot
I'd miss him.
Then will you be happy?
(LITTLEFOOT LAUGHING)
Hey, look!
There are two
Littlefoots.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Feets?
There can't be
two Littlefoots.
It's impossible.
But let's go see
anyway.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(GASPS)
See? She's not
another Littlefoot.
She's a girl.
Yup, yup, yup.
She is a girl.
Hi, everybody.
This is my
new friend, Ali.
Hello, Ali.
Hi, hi, hi.
Hi, Ali.
Me Petrie.
And I'm Ducky.
And this is my
brother, Spike.
Hey.
He cannot talk
like us. Oh, no.
But he still says hello.
And I'm Cera.
A three-horn,
of course.
(GASPS)
What's the matter, Ali?
I'm... I'm afraid.
Are we scary?
Oh, yes!
Petrie very scary!
(INHALING)
(GIGGLING)
(AIR WHOOSHING)
Well, it just so happens
that three-horns
can be very scary.
Grr!
(GASPS)
Cera, you're not helping!
Sorry.
Gee, Ali.
There's nothing scary
about my friends.
Honest. They're really,
really nice.
But Littlefoot, they're
not long necks like us.
I'm sorry, everyone.
I can't play now.
I don't understand
why she's so scared.
Hmm! She's not scared.
She's stuck-up.
Who needs her?
Come on.
Yeah. Hmm!
Who need her?
Are you coming,
Littlefoot?
I... I guess so.
(SIGHS)
ALI: Psst!
Huh?
Psst! Littlefoot,
I'm over here.
Did you change
your mind?
Do you want to play
with me and my friends?
(SIGHS) Ah, gee.
(LITTLEFOOT LAUGHING)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Where Littlefoot?
Over there.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
With her!
If Littlefoot would
rather play with her,
then he's not
our friend!
What?
PETRIE: What?
(CROAKING)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Whoa!
(GRUNTS)
(LAUGHS)
Oops.
Sorry, Littlefoot.
Oh, that's okay.
You're really fun,
Littlefoot.
I hope we're friends.
Of course
we're friends.
And friends share!
(LAUGHS)
(GASPS) Friends?
I ran off and
left them.
I better go make sure
they're not mad at me.
Cera! Ducky!
Petrie! Spike!
I guess they
all went home.
I guess.
Come on.
It's late.
My grandma and grandpa
will be worried.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
(LONG NECK TUTTING)
LONG NECK 1:
It doesn't look good.
LONG NECK 2:
Terrible.
Grandma, what is it?
What's wrong
with Grandpa?
Your Grandpa is
very ill, Littlefoot.
Ill? Well, he'll get better,
won't he?
I don't know,
Littlefoot.
Some dinosaurs do.
And some don't.
I've seen this sickness
many times in my life.
No dinosaur ever
recovers from it unless...
Unless what?
Unless they eat
the golden petals
of the night flower.
The night flower?
LONG NECK 1:
Did you hear that?
The night flower.
Yes. Golden petals.
Sick dinosaurs eat them
and are cured
if they eat them in time.
Grandma, we have to get
the night flower
for Grandpa!
Old One,
where can I find
the night flower?
In the land
we came from.
The Land of Mists.
(GASPS)
(FRIGHTENED MURMURING
IN CROWD)
The Land of Mists.
Cousins,
who will take me
to the night flower?
Not me.
I'm not going
back there.
You'd have to be crazy.
The land has changed
too much.
Long necks are not
welcome there.
But what about
my grandpa?
OLD ONE:
It is too dangerous.
Come, Ali,
it's late.
But, Mother,
isn't there any way
we can help?
I'm sorry, dear.
We can do nothing.
GRANDPA: Littlefoot?
Yes, Grandpa?
Littlefoot,
I want you to promise
that if anything
happens to me...
But, Grandpa,
nothing is going
to happen.
I'm going to
take care of you.
You're still very young.
Grandma isn't as strong
as she once was.
If our valley
does change,
I won't be here
to protect you.
Our cousins are strong.
And the Old One is wise.
I don't think
she's so smart.
Littlefoot,
promise me
that you and Grandma
will go with them
if the time comes.
But, Grandpa, you're
going to get better.
Promise me.
I promise.
It's time to sleep,
Littlefoot.
But I want to help you
watch Grandpa.
You can help me
by getting some rest.
But there has to be
more I can do.
Littlefoot,
we all must learn
to accept
what the great circle
of life hands us.
No.
Please try to understand,
little one.
There is nothing
we can do.
And try not to worry.
The great circle of life
brings us many
good things, too.
Sometimes when
we least expect them.
The circle of life
is simple,
yet profound.
* A quite
straightforward line
* That goes around
and round and round
* It's starts at
the beginning
And it will never end.
* And that to me
must surely be
* Life's secret,
my friend
* For the circle of life
* Continues everyday
* None of us can stop it
* From going on its way
* With each new generation
* One more circle
is complete
* On and on and on
it goes repeating
* Repeating
* It nurtures the young
* Until they're fully grown
* And soon life's
magic circle
* Brings them children
of their own
* The family of nature
* Each husband
* And wife
* Enhances the circle
* The ever widening circle
* The wonderful circle
* Of life
Good night,
my little one.
(GROANS)
There is something
I can do!
I can find
the night flower.
I'll be back!
Please don't worry.
(ALL SNORING)
Ali! Ali, wake up!
Huh?
Littlefoot?
Shh!
What are you
doing here?
I've got to find
the night flower.
What?
Shh.
Will you tell me
where to find it?
I can't,
Littlefoot.
It's too dangerous.
The Land of Mists
is filled with
horrible monsters.
You can't go
by yourself.
I'm not.
I'm going to ask Cera,
Ducky, Petrie and
Spike to go with me.
But what about me?
Well... I...
I didn't think
you'd want to come
because you...
You don't like
my friends.
And besides,
you just said
you didn't want to go.
I'll go. But...
But we can't take
the others.
Huh?
See?
If we take them,
it'll only slow us down.
I don't know.
Hurry, Littlefoot.
I know the way.
The others don't.
We have to go now
or the grown-ups
will try and stop us.
I could not find
Littlefoot anywhere.
Oh... I no find him,
either.
Oh, he's probably
just hiding from us
so he can play with
that dumb old Ali.
(MOCKINGLY)
"Oh, Littlefoot,
I'm afraid!
"Your friends
are so scary!"
(ALL LAUGHING)
"Keep them away!
Keep them away!"
(ALL LAUGHING)
GRANDMA: Littlefoot!
That is Littlefoot's
Grandma.
GRANDMA: Littlefoot,
where are you?
Something is wrong.
It is. It is.
Littlefoot!
I'm afraid he's gone
to find the night flower,
oh, my brave
Littlefoot.
Are you sure you know
where we're going, Ali?
Well, sort of.
Sort of?
See, my herd
has moved so much,
sometimes I lose track
of where I am,
or where I've been.
But don't worry.
I think we go this way.
(SIGHS)
(WATER FLOWING)
Littlefoot!
(GASPS) It's beautiful!
ALI: Oh, Littlefoot,
I remember this waterfall.
We are going
the right way after all.
Come on!
We gotta pass
through this cave.
Wow!
Let's go!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Why are we stopping,
Ali?
Dark water.
It means
it's real deep.
My mother had to
carry me through it.
Is there another way
through the cave?
I don't know.
Well,
we'll just have to
go exploring.
Come on.
Ali, look!
That looks like
the way to go.
Race you!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
I think
we better go back.
(ECHOING) Go back.
Go back. Go back.
What was that?
I don't know.
But I think he
wants us to go.
Who are you?
(ECHOING) Who are you?
(BOTH GULP)
I'm Littlefoot!
(ECHOING) I'm Littlefoot.
I'm Littlefoot.
You can't be down there
if you're up here,
can you?
I don't think so.
(RUMBLING)
(GASPS)
Earthshake!
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Jump!
(SHRIEKING)
(GASPS) Littlefoot?
Littlefoot?
Littlefoot, are you
all right?
(STRAINING)
I can't do this
by myself.
Don't worry, Littlefoot.
I'll be back.
(MOANS)
Ali? Ali?
Can you hear me?
GRANDMA: And then when
Littlefoot's Grandpa
got sick,
the Old One
told us that
only the golden petals
of the night flower
could cure him.
Littlefoot was so worried
about his Grandpa.
That's why I know
he's gone to
the Land of Mists,
to find the night flower.
Oh, no, no,
no, no.
Or maybe he's really
off playing with that
dumb old what's-her-name.
Her name is not
What's-Her-Name,
Cera.
It is Ali.
Remember?
(SIGHS)
Littlefoot wouldn't just
go off and play, Cera.
Not with his
Grandpa so sick.
Besides,
Ali is missing, too.
She probably knows
the way to the
Land of Mists.
I'm sure she
and Littlefoot
are both searching
for the night flower.
Oh, do not worry.
We will go
and get them.
We will.
No, Ducky.
You mustn't.
I can't risk
you young ones, too.
The Land of Mists
is a dangerous place.
You must promise me
you won't go there.
Uh... Okay.
I promise.
Me promise, too.
Oh, the more
I think about it,
the madder I get.
Littlefoot
should've asked us
to go with him.
But no,
he wanted to go along
with his new friend.
Yes, his new friend.
Maybe Littlefoot thought
we would not want to go.
Maybe.
Ha! Well, maybe
I've changed my mind.
Maybe I don't want to go
after Littlefoot after all!
(GASPS) Cera!
Oh, besides!
Who even knows
where that dumb old
Land of Mists is anyway?
I'm sure the grown-ups
aren't gonna tell us.
ALI: Cera!
Ducky! Petrie!
Spike!
(GASPING)
I'm so glad
I found you.
Ali!
You back!
Where's Littlefoot?
Littlefoot?
Well, he's...
See, there was this
terrible earthshake.
And the cave
fell down and...
ALL: And?
You've got to come now!
We coming, Ali.
Well, I'm not!
Why should we
believe her?
She probably made
that story up.
I did not.
What we do now?
What do you think,
Spike?
He thinks
we should go.
Okay.
(GRUMBLES)
Ooh!
(STRAINING)
Ali? Ali?
Are you out there?
I've got to find
another way out.
(SIGHS) At least now
it's not so dark anymore.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING
IN UNISON)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
Grr!
(SCREAMS)
Whoa!
What are you doing
in my cave?
(GASPS)
Well, you see...
(GROWLS)
Hey, you don't have
any teeth.
(GROWLING MEEKLY)
(SIGHS)
Oh, yeah, yeah.
I know.
I couldn't scare anybody
if my life depended on it.
But you can't blame
a guy for trying.
This cave's
a dangerous place,
you know?
I know.
The name's Archie.
What's yours?
Littlefoot.
So tell me,
Littlefoot,
what are you doing
here all alone?
I'm not alone.
I'm with my
friend, Ali.
I mean, if she's
all right, that is.
It's just
around this bend.
Oh, lookie.
Wow...
ALI: Hurry!
Littlefoot's in
the cave ahead.
Ali's on the
other side of this wall.
Hoo-ee.
This was some cave-in.
You're lucky
you weren't hurt.
I hope your friend
was as lucky.
Do you think you can
help me dig out?
Sure. I'll give it a try.
Where there's a will,
there's a way,
you know?
(STRAINING)
Or a pulled muscle.
(SNARLING)
Relax, Dil.
It's me, Ichy.
Ichy? You know
I don't see so good.
Why do you sneak up
on me like that?
Eh, call it
a mean streak.
Well, did you see
anything to eat?
Nah, not a thing since
those baby long necks.
Ichy, I'm hungry.
You're hungry?
What about me?
I do all the
real work around here.
You? I get all the food.
Well, you couldn't
get it without me.
I'm the eyes.
So? I'm the teeth!
(SNARLS)
Aw, who needs you?
And who needs you?
* I need you
like a hole in the head
* And I need you
like a bug in the bed
* You constantly bite
* The claw that feeds you
BOTH:
* Who needs you?
Not me
* I need you
like a pain the gut
* Oh, yeah?
And I need you
* Like a kick in the butt
* You truly disgrace
the race that freed you
BOTH:
* Who needs you?
Not me
* You creepy,
crawly creature
* You're ugly as sin
* Just a scraggly
bag of skin
* And who needs you?
* Your tail's
your finest feature
* You're thick-skinned
and a bore
* Dragging your belly
around the floor
* Oh, I need you
like a rock on my toes
* And I need you
like a sock on the nose
* I'm shocked
and appalled
* By your behavior
* Don't try being nice
* Because that
won't save you
BOTH:
* I'm better off
without you, I can see
* So who needs you?
Not me
* I need you
like a cold in July
* And I need you
like a punch in the eye
* Of all the dumb beasts
* Not one precedes you
BOTH:
* Who needs you?
Not me
* I need you
like I need a disease
* And I need you
like the sun needs
to freeze
* For quickness of mind,
a rock outspeeds you
BOTH:
* Who needs you?
Not me
* Who needs you,
you cross-eyed,
crazy critter
* You twitter and squawk
* And you're knock-kneed
when you walk
* And who needs you
* You flat-foot,
four-foot quitter
* You're bitter and mad
* Because you're
exactly as your dad
* Oh, I need you
like I need
some more teeth
* I lift a rock and find
you underneath
* I'm deeply upset
* By your demeanor
* I know that I'm mean
My sharp teeth, meaner
BOTH:
* No more unlikely pair
could ever be
* The word is
incompatibility
* Not only that,
we don't get on,
you see
BOTH:
* So who needs you?
* Except the race
that breeds you
* Who needs you?
* Not me
BOTH:
Hey, Dil.
Shh! Quiet!
It's one of the
baby long necks.
Something tells me
supper is soon.
(BOTH STRAINING)
(SIGHS)
Hmph!
It's no use.
We'll never be able
to dig through all this.
We need more help.
ALI: Littlefoot!
GROUP: Littlefoot!
Archie!
It's my friends!
We've got to hurry.
He might be hurt.
Me get Littlefoot out!
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMS)
Oh, heavy.
(RUMBLING)
(SCREAMING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
Sounds like
a rock slide.
Don't worry, kid.
I take that back.
Worry.
Straight ahead
till dinner, Dil.
(SNARLING)
Run!
Hide!
(GASPING)
Archie? Archie!
I can't leave the kid
out there alone.
(SNARLING)
Littlefoot.
Archie.
We have to hide.
Follow me.
(SNARLING)
In there, kid.
But what about you?
Don't worry.
Now you see me...
Now you don't.
(SNARLING)
(GASPS)
Where did he go, Ichy?
Where did he go?
There, in that crevice.
(SNARLING)
(SCREAMS)
(GASPS)
Yeah, yeah.
That's using
your tail!
(SQUAWKS) Watch it!
Eee-yah!
Dil, look out!
(SIGHS)
Ow! I hate it
when that happens.
Oh, no. It feels like
another earthshake.
(DIL SNARLING)
And it mad.
Very, very mad.
What we do now?
Littlefoot in big trouble.
CERA: Then what is everyone
standing around for?
ALL: Cera!
Are we gonna save
Littlefoot or not?
ALL: Yay!
(GRUNTING)
ALL: Yay, Cera!
Can I help, Cera?
Sure. Stay out
of my way.
(GASPS)
(SNARLING)
DIL: I know
he's here somewhere.
I see him, Ichy!
I see him!
Congratulations.
Now sic him and remember
to leave me some!
(GROWLS)
Back off,
belly dragger!
Huh?
The kid's a snack.
I'm a meal.
Yeah? Well, I call you
the first course.
Tenderize him, Dil.
(GROWLS)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Grr!
(BOTH EXCLAIMING)
Cera! Petrie!
Ducky! Spike!
You're all right!
Me miss you!
Oh, Littlefoot!
How did you know
where to find me?
Ali came and got us.
She did.
Thanks, Ali.
I was afraid that
maybe something bad
happened to you.
I'm sure glad
you're okay.
Hmph!
(SIGHS)
ARCHIE: Hello.
We got to get moving
before that big-mouthed
belly dragger
and her sharp-beaked
friend wake up.
ALL: Who's he?
I'll explain later.
Now come on.
And then the big-mouthed
belly dragger and
the sharp-beak
were just about
to have Archie
and me for dinner when
you guys
came to the rescue.
You mean I came
to the rescue.
But Ali showed us
the way.
And you no even
come with us at first.
So? I still got here,
didn't I?
(BLOWS)
You should have
asked your real friends
to help you find
the night flower
in the first place.
Night flower?
What's this about
the night flower?
I have to find it
to help my Grandpa
who's sick.
That's why I was
in the cave
in the first place.
I'm going to the
Land of Mists to find
the night flower.
Well, why didn't
you say that
in the first place?
I know a shortcut.
LITTLEFOOT:
Archie, you did it!
Yay!
A way out!
Thanks, Archie.
I was beginning
to think we'd never
get out of that cave.
I want you to take good care
of yourself, Littlefoot.
You and your friends
are awfully young
to be out alone.
I know.
It's just that
I have to help
my Grandpa.
Just do me a favor
and stick together.
You may be little.
But together,
you're strong.
Don't worry, Archie.
We'll stick together.
Yup, yup, yup.
We will.
Hmph!
Good-bye, kids.
Good luck.
ALL: Good-bye, Archie.
Good-bye. Good-bye!
Littlefoot,
come and see.
Wow!
DUCKY: Pretty.
Is...
Is this it, Ali?
ALI: Yes, Littlefoot.
The Valley of Mists.
Stay close. If you get
lost in the mists,
you stay lost.
(TEETH CHATTERING)
Do not be afraid,
Petrie. I am here.
Me not afraid.
Me terrified.
How long until we find
the night flower, Ali?
ALI: Not long now.
(CREATURE HOOTING)
(RATTLING)
(GASPS)
(SCREAMS)
LITTLEFOOT:
What is it, Cera?
Something slimy
touched me.
LITTLEFOOT: Cera!
(CERA SHRIEKING)
She disappeared.
Oh, poor, poor Cera!
We'll find you, Cera!
Don't worry!
Okay! Just hurry.
(EERIE GROWLING
IN DISTANCE)
Please.
There she is!
(ALL SCREAMING)
ALI: Duck!
Look out!
(ROARING)
(GASPS)
(SCREAMING)
(ROARING)
Oh, me get headache
just watching.
Come on!
We've gotta find Cera!
LITTLEFOOT: There's a tree
we can hide under!
I do not like it here.
Oh, no,
no, no, no.
(CREATURES CHITTERING)
(GASPS) What's that?
I think it my teeth.
(TEETH CHATTERING)
Or knees.
(CHITTERING)
(SQUEALS)
(SCREAMS)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(SNIFFING)
PETRIE: This
no time to eat!
(SNIFFING)
(SNEEZES)
(LAUGHS)
He does not look
scary to me.
(GIGGLES)
Oh, no, no,
no, no, no.
He is cute.
He is.
He has tickly fuzzies
all over him.
I'm gonna
call you Tickles.
I am.
(SQUEAKING HAPPILY)
Tickles, have you seen
our friend, Cera?
She's a three-horn.
(CHATTERS)
PETRIE: Petrie take look.
LITTLEFOOT:
I think she sees her!
Me see her, too!
ALI: Over here!
LITTLEFOOT:
Over here, Cera!
DUCKY: Cera!
I see you! Hee!
(SCREAMING)
I can't see! (SCREAMS)
(GASPS)
Help!
Hang on, Cera!
We'll throw you
down a vine!
Hurry!
(GASPS)
Cera, catch this!
(GRUNTS)
(ALL CHATTERING EXCITEDLY)
LITTLEFOOT: Cera, come on!
(GASPS)
(SCREAMS)
Come on!
Let's pull her up!
Pull!
(ALL STRAINING)
Thanks for showing us
that shortcut...
To dinner!
(SCREAMING)
Gotcha! Ya!
(SPITTING)
Ya bumbling belly-dragger.
That wasn't food.
That was a log.
I thought
it tasted funny.
Ow! You hit me!
I didn't.
Though it's not
a bad idea.
(EXCLAIMS) What did
you do that for?
Do what?
That.
Oh, it's those rotten
little edibles.
(GASPS)
(SCREAMING)
You guys keep them busy.
I'll save Cera.
Ali, no.
It's too steep.
You'll fall!
Don't worry! I...
(SCREAMING)
How nice. Dessert.
Head for shore, Dil.
My sweet tooth calls.
But, Ichy,
you know the routine.
Dinner first,
then dessert.
What are you?
My mother?
Come on!
LITTLEFOOT: Ali!
DUCKY: Watch out!
PETRIE: Wake up!
(MOANS)
(GROWLS)
(GASPS)
Ow!
(GIGGLES)
(SPUTTERING INDISTINCTLY)
(GRUNTS)
I'm coming, Cera.
(GROWLING)
Huh?
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(GRUNTS)
Hurry, Cera.
Belly draggers
can't climb.
You let them get away!
Me? It was your fault.
You're dreaming.
Now be quiet!
You be quiet!
Oh, yeah? Well,
you're the one
with the big mouth!
Oh, yeah?
I oughta...
ICHY: La, la, la!
I can't hear you!
(SIGHS)
CERA: Thanks, Ali.
You're welcome.
Hey, guys!
You don't have to
worry anymore!
Ali and me
are friends!
ALL: Yay!
ALI: So you see,
with my herd moving
around so much,
I never got
to know anyone
but other long necks.
Aw...
But after everything
that's happened,
I know now that
it's great to have
all kinds of friends
in all shapes and
sizes, too.
* It takes all sorts
to make a world
* Short and tall sorts
* Large and small sorts
* To fill this pretty planet
* With love and laughter
* To make it
great to live in tomorrow
* Tomorrow
* And the day after
* It takes all types
* Without a doubt
* Dumb and wise types
* Every size types
* To do all the things
* That need to be done
ALL:
* To make our life fun
* Find a place in the sun
* And the brightest way
* The rightest way
* According to reports
* Is simply to take
* All sorts
* It takes all sorts
to make our day
* Smart and slow sorts
* High and low sorts
ALL:
* To make the world we live in
* A place worth being
* To try and
make our future
* A future
* Really worth seeing
* We need all types
* To make our way
* Tried and true types
* Me and you types
ALL:
* To create a world
* That's truly worthwhile
* That knows how to smile
* How to do things in style
* 'Cause the surest
and securest way
* Which everyone
supports is simply to
ALL:
* Take all sorts
Stop your panting,
Dil, and get me
out of here!
Get yourself out!
And ruin my feathers?
Listen, leatherhead,
we've got to
find those kids.
And you can't do
it without me.
Okay!
Oh, Dil! Remember
the good times
we had! (SHRIEKING)
Not so close
next time, lumphead.
(GROWLS)
Now look what you've done.
How are you gonna fix this?
(GROWLING)
No, Dil!
It's all right!
(SCREAMING) No!
DIL: Ichy, we've been
looking for these
kids for hours.
How about resting
the eyes?
(YAWNING)
You're right, Dil.
You keep going while
I take a little snooze.
But, but...
Hey! Hey!
Who is the eyes
around here?
Ichy, you know
I can't see.
Yeah. But if you
keep moving,
we're bound to bump
into something
sooner or later.
Good night.
One of these...
(GRUNTS)
Days, Ichy... (GRUNTS)
One of these... Oh!
Oh, forget it.
(GROANS)
(CRASHING)
When are we
gonna get there?
My feet hurt.
And I'm hungry.
I know, Cera. But we
have to keep going.
We have to find
the night flowers
for my Grandpa.
We are almost there,
aren't we, Ali?
I think so.
See, I've never really
seen the flowers
for myself before.
You haven't?
Oh...
(YAWNING)
I'm very,
very tired. I am.
(YAWNING)
Maybe we should
rest for a while.
(YAWNING)
(SIGHS)
Huh?
I do not need
a bath, Mama.
Hmm.
How pretty.
A golden flower.
Golden flower!
Spike, it is
the night flower!
It is! It is!
Wake up! Wake up!
We were looking
for the night flowers!
But the night
flowers found us!
(GIGGLES)
(ALL GASPING)
We found
'em, Grandpa!
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
(ALL CHEERING)
If we keep
on like this,
we can make
it home by morning.
Surprise!
(GASPS)
You're not going
anywhere but the inside
of our stomachs!
Right, Dil?
(GROWLING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
They're hiding
here somewhere.
And I bet it's
behind that boulder.
What boulder?
Never mind.
Just stay
close to me.
I'll flush them out
and you nab 'em.
(GROWLS)
Shh!
(ALL SCREAMING)
Lookie what
I got, Dil.
(SNARLING)
Hey, what'd you
do that for?
Because this skimpy
snack is barely
enough for me.
(GROWLING)
DIL: You are
so selfish!
(WHISPERING) What
do we do?
(SQUEAKING)
I am not!
ICHY: You're the one
who's selfish.
He's mine.
And that's final!
(CRUNCH)
(GASPS)
(SPUTTERS)
Blech!
Dil, I didn't
mean it!
(DIL GROWLING)
Honest,
it wasn't me.
(CERA CHUCKLING)
Oops!
It's them!
They're over there!
(GROWLING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
LITTLEFOOT:
Stick together,
everybody.
Oh, no!
Come back, flower.
We must stick together.
(GASPS)
(SCREAMING)
Ducky!
(ALL GASPING)
Me save
you, Ducky!
Petrie!
Get away!
Go on! Leave
me alone!
Let go!
(PETRIE STRAINING)
(PETRIE SCREAMING)
(DUCKY SCREAMING)
(ALL GASPING)
No!
Ducky!
Oh, no.
(GASPS)
Put my
friend down!
(LOUD SNARL)
Whoa!
You got her, Dil!
I did?
Then she's mine!
Ducky!
Wake up!
Look out!
Ducky!
ALL: Ducky!
(STRAINING)
Duck... Duck...
Ducky!
(ALL GASPING)
Huh?
(GASPS)
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
Oh...
We gotta
do something!
Come on!
You're next, my
little diet delights.
(CHUCKLING)
(ICHY SHRIEKING)
Oh, no!
Oh, no! Oh, no!
(ICHY SCREAMING)
ICHY: Don't swallow, Dil!
It's me, Ichy.
Ichy?
Open up,
you idiot!
(GASPS) You almost ate me.
But it was
an accident, Ichy.
I didn't see you.
Of course you didn't
see me. You can't
see your own nose
at the end
of your face.
You're useless!
Useless? Without me,
you'd starve!
I would not.
You would too.
Would not.
Would too.
Would not, would not,
would not!
Would too, would too,
would too!
That's it, Dil.
I've had it
with you, Ichy!
From now on...
I'm going it alone!
No!
(SCREAMING)
That'll teach him.
Huh?
Who's there?
(ROARING)
(SCREAMING) Ichy!
Ducky!
Are you all right?
I think so.
But I thought
I heard Spike talk.
He did, Ducky.
Spike talked!
(SIGHS)
Oh, Spike,
I'm so happy!
You talk-ded!
Yup, yup, yup!
You did!
Are you sure you don't want
to come with us, Tickles?
(SQUEAKING)
Do you think we'll ever
see him again, Ali?
I hope so.
The land is changing.
Maybe we'll all live
together someday.
ALL: Bye! Bye!
Good-bye!
ALL: Good-bye, Tickles!
Good-bye! Bye, Tickles! Bye...
We're home.
Yeah. I hope
my Grandpa's still...
Come on, Littlefoot.
We should hurry.
LITTLEFOOT: Grandma?
Littlefoot!
We brought the night
flowers, Grandma.
Oh, Littlefoot.
Is... Is Grandpa... Okay?
He's so weak.
Don't worry, Grandma.
The night flowers will
make him well again.
The Old One said so.
I hope she was right.
And I hope
it's not too late.
Come on! Let's hurry.
(GROWLING WEAKLY)
He ate as much
as he could.
Now, all we
can do is wait.
Littlefoot?
Grandpa?
Well, hello there,
Littlefoot.
Hello yourself,
Grandpa.
GRANDMA: How are
you feeling, dear?
Oh, much better.
I think Littlefoot's golden
flowers are working.
Does that mean Grandma
and I won't be leaving
the Great Valley after all?
That's right.
Littlefoot?
He's all right! My Grandpa's
gonna be all right!
(ALL CHEERING)
PETRIE: Good, Littlefoot!
(GASPS) Me think
me should be going now.
(GASPS) You are right, Petrie.
Our mamas and daddies
are probably very worried.
ALL: Bye! Bye...
OLD ONE: Listen up, everyone.
We will be leaving
in just a few moments.
Good-bye, Littlefoot.
I know we will
meet again someday.
I know we will, too.
Thanks for being
my friend, Cera.
Oh... Hee.
Good-bye, Petrie.
I'm gonna miss you
a whole lot, too.
Aw, gee.
I'll miss you
and Spike, too, Ducky.
And we will miss you very,
very much, we will.
But Spike talks now.
So he can tell you
for himself.
Go on, little brother.
ALL: Yeah, Spike!
Say something! Go on, talk.
Come on, Spike...
(MUNCHING)
Yep, yep, yep!
Spike can talk...
When he wants to.
(CHUCKLES)
(ALL LAUGHING)
Well, good-bye.
ALL: Good-bye!
ALI: (ECHOING) Maybe we'll
all live together someday...
NARRATOR:
And so it came to pass
that the migrating dinosaurs
left the Great Valley
for lands unknown.
And yes, Littlefoot,
and his friends,
Cera, Ducky, Petrie,
and Spike, would indeed
meet Ali again one day.
But that's another story.