(DELIVER US PLAYING)
SLAVES:
Mud
Sand
Water
(SHRIEKS)
Straw
GUARDS:
Faster
SLAVES:
Mud and lift
Sand and pull
Water
And raise up
Straw
Faster!
SLAVES:
With the sting of the whip
on my shoulder
With the salt of my sweat
on my brow
Elohim, God on high
Can you hear your people cry?
Help us now this dark hour
Deliver us
Hear our call, deliver us
Lord of all, remember us
Here in this burning sand
Deliver us
There's a land you promised us
To the Promised Land
(SOLDIERS CHATTERING)
(SINGING IN HEBREW)
My son, I have nothing
I can give
But this chance that you
may live
I pray we'll meet again
If He will deliver us
CHORUS:
Deliver us
Hear our prayer
Deliver us from despair
These years of slavery
Grow too cruel to stand
Deliver us
There's a land you promised us
Out of bondage
And deliver us
To the Promised Land
(RIVER LULLABY PLAYING)
(BABY COOING)
(SINGING)
Hush now, my baby
Be still, love, don't cry
Sleep as you're rocked
by the stream
Sleep and remember
My last lullaby
So I'll be with you
When you dream
(YAWNS)
River, oh, river
Flow gently for me
Such precious cargo you bear
Do you know somewhere
He can live free?
River, deliver him there
(WOMAN VOCALIZING)
(CHATTERING)
(GROWLING)
(GASPS)
(COOING)
(SINGING)
Brother, you're safe now
And safe may you stay
For I have a prayer
just for you
Grow, baby brother
Come back someday
Come and deliver us too
(BABY COOING)
Mommy.
Come, Rameses.
We will show Pharaoh
your new baby brother.
Moses.
CHORUS: (SINGING)
Deliver us
Send a shepherd
to shepherd us
And deliver us
To the Promised Land
Deliver us
WOMAN:
(HOOFBEATS)
MOSES: Ha-ha!
RAMESES: Faster, you beasts!
You run like mules!
Hey, Rameses,
how would you like
your face carved on a wall?
Someday, yes.
How about now?
(MOSES GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
You almost killed me!
Aw, come on.
Where is your sense of fun?
Oh, it's fun you want.
(GRUNTS)
(HORSES NEIGHING)
(SCREAMING)
(SIGHS IN RELIEF)
Moses?
(APPROACHING HOOFBEATS)
(MOSES WHOOPING)
(MOSES LAUGHING)
(MOSES WHOOPING AND LAUGHING)
(RATTLING)
(WHOOPING)
Come on, Moses. Admit it.
You've always looked up to me.
Yes, but it's not
much of a view.
(LAUGHS)
RAMESES: Hyah!
(WHOOPING)
(HORSES NEIGHING)
MAN: Hey!
RAMESES: Second born,
second place.
MOSES: Not for long.
(MOSES AND RAMESES WHOOPING)
(CHANTING)
(MOSES AND RAMESES WHOOPING
AND LAUGHING)
(HORSES NEIGHING)
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMS)
Jump!
(BOTH YELLING)
(BOTH PANTING)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(WOOD CREAKING)
(BOTH YELLING)
(SCREAMING)
(MOSES AND RAMESES WHOOPING)
You don't think
we'll get in trouble
for this, do you?
No, not a chance.
SETI: Why do the gods
torment me
with such reckless,
destructive,
blasphemous sons?
Father,
hear what I...
Be still! Pharaoh speaks.
I seek to build an empire,
and your only thought
is to amuse yourselves
by tearing it down.
Have I taught you nothing?
You mustn't be
so hard on yourself,
Your Majesty.
You're an
excellent teacher.
It's not your fault
your sons learned nothing.
Well, they
learned blasphemy.
True.
Father, the fault is mine.
I goaded Rameses on,
and so I am responsible.
Hmm. "Responsible."
And do you know the meaning
of that word, Rameses?
I understand, Father...
SETI: And do you
understand the task
for which your birth
has destined you?
The ancient traditions.
When I pass into
the next world,
then you will be
the morning and evening star.
One damaged temple
does not destroy
centuries of tradition.
But one weak link
can break the chain
of a mighty dynasty!
(SIGHS)
You have my leave to go.
Father.
Father?
You know it was
really my fault.
Must you be so hard on him?
Moses, you will never
have to carry a burden
like the crown I will pass
to Rameses.
He must not allow himself
to be led astray,
not even by you, my son.
All he cares about
is your approval.
I know he will live up
to your expectations.
He only needs
the opportunity.
Maybe.
Maybe so.
Go now.
I shall see you both tonight.
(WHISTLING)
Well, that went well.
RAMESES:
Just go away.
Could have been worse.
"The weak link
in the chain."
That's what he called me.
(SIGHS)
Well, you are rather pathetic.
Irresponsible,
ignorant of the traditions.
He practically accused me
of bringing down the dynasty.
Yeah, I can see it now.
There go the pyramids!
(CHUCKLES)
You can laugh about it.
Statues cracking
and toppling over,
the Nile drying up.
Single-handedly,
you will manage to bring
the greatest kingdom
on Earth to ruin.
Tell me this, Moses.
Tell me this.
Why is it that every time
you start something,
I'm the one who
ends up in trouble?
(WATER SPLASHING)
(HOTEP AND HUY SCREAMING)
HOTEP: Man! Oh!
It's Rameses.
You're in trouble,
young man.
Rameses, get down here!
I think you owe us
an apology!
Oh!
HOTEP: My new thing!
HUY: I am so upset!
You might as well.
HOTEP: You'll pay for this!
HUY: We're gonna
tell the pharaoh!
HOTEP: We're telling
the pharaoh and that's...
HOTEP AND HUY: Oh!
HOTEP: Look at me.
I'm drenched again.
Hey, I figured it out.
You know what your
problem is, Rameses?
What?
You care too much.
And your problem is
you don't care at all.
Oh, in that case,
I suppose you care
a lot more than I do
that we're late
for the banquet,
for example.
(MOSES AND RAMESES PANTING)
I'm done for.
Father will kill me.
Don't worry.
Nobody will even
notice us coming in.
(CROWD CHEERING)
"Nobody will even notice."
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
Ah, the young princes.
Rameses, you were just named
Prince regent.
You are now responsible
for overseeing
all the temples.
I suggest you get over there,
and thank your father.
Apparently, Moses,
someone thought he just
needed the opportunity.
My lord Pharaoh,
I propose that
the high priests
offer tribute
to their new regent.
SETI: An excellent idea.
Hotep, Huy!
Huy.
Hmm?
The Midian girl.
That's a good idea.
Go get her.
By the power of Ra,
we present for your
delectation and delight
an exotic apparition
stolen from a faraway land.
(CROWD GASPING)
(CROWD APPLAUDING)
(BOTH GASPING)
We offer you
this delicate desert flower.
(CAMEL GRUNTS)
(SHRIEKS)
(CROWD LAUGHING)
(GRUNTS)
Let us inspect
this desert flower.
(GASPS)
(CROWD GASPING)
More like
a desert cobra.
(LAUGHS)
Not much of a snake charmer,
are you?
That's why I give her to you.
No, no, no,
that's generous, but...
I won't be
given to anyone.
Especially an arrogant,
pampered palace brat!
(CHUCKLES) Are you gonna
let her talk to you like that?
(TZIPPORAH GRUNTS)
You will show
the proper respect
for a Prince of Egypt.
But I am showing you
all the respect you deserve.
None!
No. Wait!
Be still.
Untie this rope!
I demand you set me free!
Be still.
Let go!
As you wish.
(SCREAMING)
(CROWD LAUGHING)
(LAUGHS)
(LAUGHING)
You there,
have her dried off
and sent to
Prince Moses' chambers.
(GRUNTING)
If it pleases you, Father,
my first act as regent
is to appoint Moses
as royal chief architect.
(CROWD CHEERING)
(SIGHS)
Uh...
Well. (CLEARS THROAT)
Right.
(GASPS)
(MUFFLED SPEAKING)
(MUFFLED WHIMPERING)
(GASPS)
(CAMEL GRUNTING)
TZIPPORAH: Shh.
(WHISPERS) Come on.
(GRUNTING)
(CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY)
Guards.
BOTH: Prince Moses.
MOSES: Uh...
There is a man
tied up in my room.
Well, look into it.
BOTH: Right away, sire.
(CHUCKLES)
TZIPPORAH: Please,
I need water.
I have a long journey
ahead of me.
MIRIAM: May God protect you.
TZIPPORAH: Thank you.
(CAMEL GRUNTING)
(TZIPPORAH GRUNTS)
(POT SHATTERS)
Oh! Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry. I...
Oh, please forgive me. I...
(CHUCKLING)
I didn't expect
to see you here,
of all places, at our door.
Mmm.
At last!
"At last"?
Didn't I tell you, Aaron?
Didn't I tell you?
I knew he would return to us
when he was ready.
Miriam, do you
want us flogged?
I knew you cared
about our freedom.
(WHISPERS) Miriam.
"Freedom"? Why would I
care about that?
Because you're...
You're our brother.
MOSES: What?
They...
(SIGHS)
They never told you?
Who never told me what?
But you're here.
You must know.
Be careful, slave.
Oh, my good Prince.
Um, she's...
She's exhausted
from the day's work.
Uh, not that it was too much.
We... We quite enjoyed it.
But she's confused,
and knows not
to whom she speaks.
I know to whom I speak, Aaron.
I know who you are.
And you are not
a Prince of Egypt.
AARON: Miriam.
What did you say?
Your Highness,
pay her no heed.
Come, Miriam. May I discuss
something with you?
No, Aaron.
No. Please, Moses,
you must believe.
That's enough.
You were born of
my mother, Yocheved.
Stop it.
You are our brother!
Now, you go too far.
You shall be punished.
No.
Please, uh, Your Highness.
She's ill. She's very ill.
We beg your forgiveness.
Please, Miriam,
let us go.
No, Aaron.
Our mother set you adrift in
a basket to save your life!
Save my life? From who?
Ask the man that
you call Father.
How dare you?
God saved you
to be our deliverer.
MOSES: Enough of this.
And you are, Moses.
You are the deliverer.
I said enough!
(GROANS)
You will regret this night.
(SOBBING SOFTLY)
(SINGING)
Hush now, my baby
Be still, love, don't cry
Sleep as you're rocked
by the stream
Sleep and remember
My last lullaby
So I'll be with you
When you dream
(GRUNTING)
WOMAN 1: Stop him.
(GASPING)
MAN: Did you see him?
It's Moses.
WOMAN 2: Moses.
(PANTING)
(ALL I EVER WANTED PLAYING)
MOSES: (SINGING)
Gleaming in the moonlight
(MOSES PANTING)
Cool and clean
and all I've ever known
All I ever wanted
Sweet perfumes of incense
And graceful rooms
of alabaster stone
All I ever wanted
This is my home
With my father
Mother, brother
Oh, so noble, oh, so strong
Now I am home
Here among my trappings
and belongings I belong
And if anybody doubts it
They couldn't be more wrong
I am a sovereign Prince
of Egypt
A son of the proud history
that's shown
Etched on every wall
Surely this is
all I ever wanted
All I ever wanted
(WOMEN SCREAMING)
(BABIES WAILING)
(GASPING)
(GASPS)
(PANTING)
SETI: The Hebrews grew
too numerous.
They might have
risen against us.
Father, tell me
you didn't do this.
Moses, sometimes,
for the greater good,
sacrifices must be made.
(SIGHS)
"Sacrifices"?
Oh, my son.
They were only slaves.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
THE QUEEN: Moses?
Is this where you found me?
Moses, please try
to understand.
So... So everything I thought,
everything I am, is a lie.
No.
You are our son,
and we love you.
Why did you choose me?
We didn't, Moses.
The gods did.
(ALL I EVER WANTED PLAYING)
(SINGING)
This is your home, my son
Here the river brought you
And it's here the river meant
To be your home
Now you know the truth, love
Now forget and be content
When the gods
send you a blessing
You don't ask
why it was sent
Last night, the gods
granted me a vision.
I'm not merely going to
restore this temple.
I will make it more grand,
more splendid than
any other monument
in upper or lower Egypt.
I'll make you...
(GROANS)
(GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
(GROANING)
(GROANS)
(SIGHS)
Moses. Look,
fate has turned our
little misadventure
into a great opportunity.
GUARD: Get up, old man.
RAMESES: I know Father
will be so pleased
with what you and I...
Put your back into it!
Faster!
RAMESES: And this is
just the beginning.
A gateway will open
to an entire new city
of white limestone,
more dazzling than the sun.
And here, a statue of Hapi...
(WHIP CRACKS, OLD MAN GROANS)
I said, hurry!
...god of the Nile flanked by
two great columned halls.
MIRIAM: Stop it!
AARON: Miriam, no.
Somebody's got to stop this.
There's nothing
that we can do.
(GROANS)
(WHIP CRACKS)
(OLD MAN GROANS)
RAMESES: Let's raise
the roof over here...
(GROANING)
(WHIP CRACKING)
Stop it. Stop.
Stop it. Leave that man alone!
Moses.
(GRUNTS)
Out of my way.
Out of my way. Move!
(CROWD MURMURING)
Who did this?
MAN: Up there.
It's him. Up there.
(CROWD CHATTERING)
(PANTING)
(ALL GASPING)
Moses.
(GRUNTS)
Moses, what's going on?
Moses!
RAMESES: Moses!
Moses.
Let me go!
No, wait.
You saw what happened.
I just killed a man.
We can take care of that.
I will make it so
it never happened.
Nothing you can say
can change what I've done.
I am Egypt,
the morning
and the evening star.
If I say day is night,
it will be written,
and you will be what
I say you are.
I say you are innocent.
What you say does not matter.
You don't understand.
I can't stay here any longer.
Moses...
No! All I've ever known
to be true is a lie.
(PANTING)
I'm not who you think I am.
What are you talking about?
Go ask the man
I once called Father.
Moses?
Please.
Goodbye, brother.
Moses!
(WIND WHISTLING)
No.
(GROANS)
(GRUNTS)
(WIND HOWLING)
(SNIFFS)
(GROANS)
(CAMEL GRUNTS)
(WATER SLOSHING)
(COUGHS AND GRUNTS)
Hey, wait.
Please.
(MOSES GROANS)
(SHEEP BLEATING)
(BLEATS)
(GIRL 1 SCREAMS)
GIRL 2: What are you doing?
GIRL 1: Help! Stop!
GIRL 3: Let our sheep drink!
GIRL 2: Go away!
Leave us alone!
Get away from me!
GIRL 1: Leave us alone!
GIRL 2: Get away!
GIRL 1: (SCREAMS) Stop it!
GIRL 3: Stop it!
MAN 1: We'll do what we want.
GIRL 2: My father's
the high priest of Midian...
MAN 1: Get away!
...and you'll be
in big trouble.
(SHRIEKS)
(GRUNTS)
MOSES: Hey, you.
Aren't these your camels?
Hut-hut.
No, no.
No, no, wait!
No!
MAN 1: Wait, stop!
MAN 2: No!
(GROANING)
(SCREAMING)
(LOUD SPLASH)
(ALL GRUNTING)
What are
you girls doing?
We're trying to
get the funny man
out of the well.
Trying to get the funny man
Well, that's one
I've never heard before.
(MOSES YELLS)
(GASPS)
Oh, my. Oh...
Don't worry down there.
We'll get you out. Hold on.
(GRUNTING)
You.
Huh?
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
(SCREAMING)
(LOUD SPLASH)
Mmm-hmm.
That's why Papa says
she'll never get married.
(GROANING)
You don't have to do this.
Ladies, please, I'm really...
I'm really quite...
No, not there, please.
(LAUGHS)
That tickles.
Ladies, you've cleaned
every inch of me.
Whoa! I... I was wrong.
(GIRLS LAUGHING)
JETHRO: Let me through.
Let me through.
I want to see him.
Ah!
You are most welcome.
(MOSES GRUNTS)
You should not be a stranger
in this land.
You have been sent
as a blessing.
And tonight,
(COUGHS)
you shall be
my honored guest.
(LAUGHS)
(CHUCKLES) My father,
Jethro, High Priest of Midian.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
GIRL 1: Psst.
Sit with me.
All right.
GIRL 2: Psst.
Not yet.
Oh, sorry.
JETHRO: My children,
let us give thanks
for this bountiful food.
And let us also give thanks
for the presence
of this brave young man
whom we honor here tonight.
(CLAPPING)
Please, sir,
I wish you wouldn't.
I've done nothing in my life
worth honoring.
First, you rescue
Tzipporah from Egypt,
then you defend
my younger daughters
from brigands.
(GIRL 1 LAUGHS)
You think that is nothing?
It seems you do not know
what is worthy of honor.
(THROUGH HEAVEN'S EYES
PLAYING)
(SINGING)
A single thread in a tapestry
Though its color
brightly shine
Can never see its purpose
In a pattern of
the grand design
And the stone that sits
on the very top
Of the mountain's mighty face
Does it think
it's more important
Than the stones
that form the base?
So how can you see
What your life is worth
Or where your value lies
You can never see
through the eyes of man
You must look at your life
Look at your life
through heaven's eyes
(PEOPLE VOCALIZING)
Dance with me.
No, I don't know how.
A lake of gold
in the desert sand
Is less than
a cool, fresh spring
And to one lost sheep
a shepherd boy
Is greater
than the richest king
If a man lose
everything he owns
Has he truly lost his worth?
Or is it the beginning
Of a new and brighter birth
So how do you measure
the worth of a man
In wealth or strength
or size
In how much he gained
or how much he gave?
The answer will come
The answer will come to him
who tries
To look at his life
through heaven's eyes
And that's why we share
all we have with you
Though there's little
to be found
When all you've got is nothing
There's a lot to go around
No life can escape
being blown about
By the winds of change
and chance
And though you never know
All the steps
Dance with me.
No, I... No.
You must learn
to join the dance
(CHORUS VOCALIZING)
(INAUDIBLE CONVERSATION)
So how do you judge
what a man is worth
By what he builds or buys
You can never see
with your eyes on Earth
Look through heaven's eyes
Look at your life
through heaven's eyes
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
I love you.
(SHEEP BLEATING)
(INHALES DEEPLY)
(EXHALES)
(BLEATING)
It's too early for this.
(SHEEP BLEATING)
MYSTERIOUS VOICE: Moses.
Moses.
Here I am.
MYSTERIOUS VOICE:
Take the sandals
from your feet,
for the place
on which you stand
is holy ground.
(PEBBLES RATTLING)
Who are you?
I am that I am.
I don't understand.
I am the God
of your ancestors,
Abraham, Isaac and Jacob.
MIRIAM: You were born
of my mother, Yocheved.
You are our brother.
What do you want with me?
GOD: I have seen
the oppression of
my people in Egypt
and have heard their cry.
MOSES: Stop it!
Leave that man alone!
GOD: So I have come down
to deliver them
out of slavery,
and bring them to a good land,
a land flowing with milk
and honey.
And so, unto Pharaoh,
I shall send you.
Me? Who am I to
lead these people?
They'll never believe me.
They won't even listen.
GOD: I shall teach you
what to say.
MOSES: Let my people go!
But I was their enemy.
I was the Prince of Egypt,
the son of the man who
slaughtered their children.
You've... You've chosen
the wrong messenger.
How can I even speak
to these people?
GOD: (LOUDLY)
Who made man's mouth?
Who made the deaf, the mute,
the seeing or the blind?
Did not I?
Now go!
(PANTING)
(QUIETLY) Oh, Moses,
I shall be with you when
you go to the King of Egypt.
But Pharaoh will not listen.
So I will stretch out my hand,
and smite Egypt
with all my wonders.
Take the staff
in your hand, Moses.
With it, you shall
do my wonders.
I shall be with you, Moses.
Moses.
(BLEATING)
(INAUDIBLE CONVERSATION)
But, Moses,
you are just one man.
Tzipporah.
Please.
(SIGHS)
(GIRLS LAUGHING)
(JETHRO LAUGHING)
Look at your family.
They are free.
They have a future.
They have hopes and dreams,
and the promise
of a life with dignity.
That is what I want
for my people.
And that is why
I must do the task
that God has given me.
I'm coming with you.
(ALL GROANING)
(GROANS)
(FESTIVE MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(MUSIC STOPS)
Rameses.
Moses?
Is it really?
(CROWD MURMURING)
(LAUGHS)
Moses, where have you been?
Rameses.
RAMESES: I took you for dead.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Look at you.
Pharaoh.
Well, look at you.
What on Earth
are you dressed as?
(LAUGHS)
Oh, Rameses,
it's so good to see you.
HOTEP: Excuse me, uh,
Your Majesty.
We are compelled to
remind you that this man
committed a serious crime
against the gods.
We are loathe to
bring it up, mind you.
Yet the law
clearly states
the punishment
for such a crime...
Death.
We hesitate to say it.
Be still.
Pharaoh speaks.
I am the morning
and the evening star.
Rameses.
It shall be as I say.
I pardon forever all crimes
of which he stands accused,
and will have it known
that he is
our brother Moses,
the Prince of Egypt.
(CROWD MURMURING)
Rameses.
In my heart,
you are my brother,
but things cannot be
as they were.
I see no reason why not.
You know I am a Hebrew,
and the God of the Hebrews
came to me.
What?
He commands that you
let His people go.
(CROWD MURMURING)
Commands?
Behold,
the power of God.
(STAFF THUDS)
(CROWD GASPING)
(HISSING)
(HISSES LOUDLY)
Well, impressive, but... Mmm.
Very well, Moses.
I'll play along.
(CHUCKLES) Hotep. Huy.
Give this snake charmer
our answer.
(CHUCKLING)
(PLAYING WITH THE BIG BOYS
PLAYING)
BOTH: (SINGING)
By the power of Ra
Mut
Nut
Khnum
Ptah
Nephthys
Nekhbet
Sobek
Sekhmet
Sokar
Selket
Reshpu
Wadjet
Anubis
Anukis
Seshmu
Meshkent
Hemsut
Tefnut
Heket
Mafdet
BOTH:
Ra, Mut, Nut, Ptah
Hemsut, Tefnut, Sokar
Selket, Seshmu
Reshpu, Sobek, Wadjet
Heket, Mafdet, Nephthys
Nekhbet
Ra
So you think you've got
friends in high places
With the power to put us
on the run
Well, forgive us these smiles
on our faces
You'll know what power is
when we are done
Son
You're playing with
the big boys now
Playing with
Oh, that's pretty.
Every spell and gesture
Tells you who's the best
You're playing with
the big boys now
PRIESTS:
By the power of Ra
HOTEP AND HUY:
You're playing with
the big boys now
PRIESTS:
Mut, Nut, Khnum, Ptah
HOTEP AND HUY:
You're playing with
the big boys now
PRIESTS:
Hemsut, Tefnut, Sokar
Selket
Stop this foolish mission
Watch a true magician
BOTH:
Give an exhibition how
HUY:
Pick up your silly twig, boy
BOTH:
You're playing with
the big boys now
(CACKLING)
PRIESTS:
By the power of Ra
Mut, Nut, Khnum, Ptah
Sobek, Sekhmet, Sokar
Selket
Anubis, Anukis, Hemsut
Tefnut, Meshkent, Mafdet
BOTH:
You're playing with
the big boys now
By the might of Horus
You will kneel before us
Kneel to our splendorous power
You put up a front
You put up a fight
And just to show
we feel no spite
You can be our acolyte
But first, boy, it's time
to bow
PRIESTS:
Kowtow!
HOTEP AND HUY:
Or it's your own grave
you'll dig, boy
You're playing with
the big boys now
Playing with the big boys
Playing with the big boys now
(CROWD CHEERING)
(LAUGHS) They love it.
(CHUCKLES) All right, Moses.
I know you.
What's this really about?
Rameses,
look.
What do you see?
RAMESES: A greater Egypt
than that of my father.
That is not what I see.
(RAMESES CHUCKLES)
Moses, I cannot change
what you see.
I have to maintain
the ancient traditions.
I bear the weight
of my father's crown.
Do you still not understand
what Seti was?
He was a great leader.
His hands bore the blood
of thousands of children.
(SCOFFS) Slaves.
My people.
And I can no longer
hide in the desert
while they suffer
at your hands.
So,
you have returned
only to free them.
MOSES: I'm sorry.
Yes.
I had hoped, but...
I do not know this god.
Neither will I let
your people go.
Rameses, please,
you must listen...
I will not be the weak link.
Tell your people, as of today,
their workload
has been doubled,
thanks to your god.
Or is it thanks
to you?
It's Moses.
(GROANS)
Moses.
So, Moses, how does it feel
when you get struck
to the ground?
I didn't mean to
cause you more pain.
I'm just trying to do
as God told me.
God?
When did God start caring
about any of us?
In fact, Moses, when did you
start caring about slaves?
Was it when you found out
that you were one of us?
Don't listen to him.
No, he's... He's right.
I did not see because I
did not wish to see.
Oh, you didn't see because
you didn't wish to see.
Ah.
Well, that makes everything
fine then, doesn't it?
Aaron, you shame yourself.
Miriam.
I'm so sorry.
(SIGHS)
Moses,
hear what I say.
I have been a slave
all my life,
and God has never answered
my prayers until now.
God saved you
from the river,
He saved you in
all your wanderings,
and even now,
He saves you from
the wrath of Pharaoh.
God will not abandon you.
So don't you abandon us.
(CROWD MURMURING)
Miriam, where are you going?
Miriam.
The ball disappears.
Now, where is it?
It's in his hand.
How about that?
(LAUGHING)
Rameses!
Let my people go!
(SCOFFS)
Still gnawing away
at that bone, are we?
Carry on.
You cannot keep ignoring us.
Enough. I will hear no more
of this Hebrew nonsense.
Bring him to me.
Moses!
No!
GOD: Take the staff
in your hand, Moses.
Father.
It's...
Blood!
Blood! Blood!
(GUARDS SHRIEKING)
(GASPS)
Hotep, Huy.
Explain this to me.
Ah...
Rest assured, Your Majesty.
Yes, we were going to
demonstrate the superior
might of our gods.
Uh...
By the power of Ra.
(SIZZLES)
(LAUGHING)
Abandon this
futile mission, Moses.
I've indulged you long enough.
This must now be finished.
No, Rameses.
It is only beginning.
But, Moses,
didn't you see
what happened?
The priests did
the same thing.
Pharaoh still has the power
over our lives.
Yes, Aaron, it's true.
Pharaoh has the power.
He can take away your food,
your home, your freedom.
He can take away your sons
and daughters.
With one word,
Pharaoh can take away
your very lives.
But there is one thing
he cannot take away from you.
Your faith.
Believe,
for we will see God's wonders.
(THE PLAGUES PLAYING)
CHORUS: (SINGING)
Thus saith the Lord
Since you refuse
to free my people
All through the land of Egypt
I send a pestilence, a plague
into your house, into your bed
Into your streams
Into your streets
Into your drink
Into your bread
Upon your cattle
On your sheep
Upon your oxen in your field
Into your dreams
Into your sleep
Until you break
Until you yield
I send the swarm
I send the horde
Thus saith the Lord
MOSES:
Once I called you brother
Once I thought the chance
to make you laugh
Was all I ever wanted
CHORUS:
I send the thunder
from the sky
I send the fire raining down
MOSES:
And even now I wish
that God had chose another
Serving as your foe
on his behalf
Is the last thing
that I wanted
CHORUS:
I send a hail of burning ice
on every field, on every town
MOSES:
This was my home
All this pain and devastation
How it tortures me inside
All the innocent who suffer
From your stubbornness
and pride
CHORUS:
I send the locusts on the wind
Such as the world
has never seen
On every leaf, on every stalk
Until there's nothing left
of green
I send my scourge
I send my sword
Thus saith the Lord
MOSES:
You who I called brother
Why must you call down
another blow
CHORUS:
I send my scourge
I send my sword
MOSES:
Let my people go
CHORUS:
Thus saith the Lord
RAMESES:
You who I called brother
How could you have come
to hate me so
Is this what you wanted?
CHORUS:
I sent the swarm
I sent the horde
RAMESES:
Then let my heart be hardened
And never mind
how high the cost may grow
This will still be so
I will never let
your people go
CHORUS:
Thus saith the Lord
MOSES:
RAMESES:
I will not let your people go
MOSES:
Let my people go
Rameses?
RAMESES: Oh. Let me guess.
You want me to
let your people go.
I hoped I would find you here.
Get out.
(CUP SHATTERS)
Rameses, we must
bring this to an end.
Rameses, please, talk to me.
We could always talk here.
(SIGHS)
This place.
So many memories.
I remember the time you
switched the heads of the gods
of the Temple of Ra.
Ah.
RAMESES: If I
recall correctly,
you were there switching heads
right along with me.
No, it was you.
I didn't do that.
Oh, yes, you did.
You put the hippo
on the crocodile,
and the crocodile...
On the falcon.
Yes.
And the priest thought
it was a horrible omen,
and fasted for two months.
Father was furious.
You were always getting me
into trouble.
But then...
(CHUCKLES)
You were always there to
get me out of trouble again.
(CHUCKLES)
Why can't things be
the way they were before?
BOY: Father.
It's so dark.
(GASPS)
I'm frightened.
Why is he here?
Isn't that the man
who did all this?
Yes.
But one must wonder
why?
Because no kingdom should be
made on the backs of slaves.
Rameses, your stubbornness
is bringing this misery
upon Egypt.
It would cease if only you
would let the Hebrews go.
I will not be dictated to.
I will not be threatened.
I am the morning
and the evening star.
I am Pharaoh.
Something else is coming.
Something much worse
than anything before.
Please, let go
of your contempt for life
before it destroys everything
you hold dear.
Think of your son.
I do.
You Hebrews have been
nothing but trouble.
My father had the right idea
about how to deal
with your people.
Rameses...
And I think it's time
I finished the job.
Rameses.
And there shall be
a great cry in all of Egypt,
such as never has been
or ever will be again.
(GASPS)
MOSES: Rameses, you bring this
upon yourself.
God has come to me again,
saying, "Take a lamb
"and with its blood,
"mark the lintel
and posts of every door.
"For tonight, I shall
pass through the land
of Egypt
"and smite all the firstborn.
"But when I see the blood
upon your door,
"I will pass over you
"and the plague
shall not enter."
(RUSTLING)
(EERIE WIND BLOWING)
(DOOR RATTLING)
(EERIE BREATH)
(POT SHATTERS)
(EERIE WIND WHISTLING)
(EERIE BREATH)
(CACOPHONY OF PEOPLE SOBBING)
RAMESES:
You and your people
have my permission to go.
Leave me!
(PEOPLE SOBBING)
(SOBBING)
(WHEN YOU BELIEVE PLAYING)
(SINGING)
Many nights we've prayed
With no proof
anyone could hear
In our hearts a hopeful song
We barely understood
Now we are not afraid
Although we know
there's much to fear
We were moving mountains
Long before we knew we could
There can be miracles
When you believe
Though hope is frail
It's hard to kill
Who knows what miracles
You can achieve
When you believe
Somehow you will
You will when you believe
TZIPPORAH:
In this time of fear
When prayers so often
proved in vain
Hope seemed like
the summer birds
Too swiftly flown away
Yet now I'm standing here
Now I'm standing here
With heart so full
I can't explain
BOTH:
Seeking faith
and speaking words
I never thought I'd say
There can be miracles
When you believe
Though hope is frail
It's hard to kill
Who knows what miracles
You can achieve
When you believe
Somehow you will
You will when you believe
(CHILD SINGING IN HEBREW)
(CHILDREN SINGING IN HEBREW)
(LAUGHING)
CHORUS: (SINGING)
There can be miracles
When you believe
Though hope is frail
It's hard to kill
Who knows what miracles
You can achieve
When you believe
Somehow you will
Now you will
You will when you believe
When you believe
MIRIAM AND TZIPPORAH:
You will when you
Believe
(SEAGULLS SQUAWKING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(HORN BLOWING)
(NEIGHING)
(CROWD MURMURING)
(RAMESES YELLING)
(SOLDIERS YELLING)
(CROWD CLAMORING)
(THUNDERCLAP)
(HORSES NEIGHING)
(CROWD MURMURING)
GOD: With this staff,
you shall do
my wonders!
(ALL GASPING)
(WIND HOWLING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
MOSES: Leave it!
(GASPS)
(WHIMPERING)
Yeah, me too.
(GASPS)
(HORSES NEIGHING)
(GRUNTS)
(YELLS)
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING)
(YELLING)
Don't just stand there!
Kill them!
(ALL SHOUTING)
RAMESES: Kill them all!
The soldiers! They're coming!
(ALL CLAMORING)
(ALL SHOUTING)
AARON: Moses! Moses!
Hurry! Hurry! I got you.
Look! The shore!
(GASPS)
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING)
(CROWD CLAMORING)
(THUNDERCLAP)
No!
(WAVES CRASHING THUNDEROUSLY)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Thank you.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER CONTINUES)
Moses!
(SIGHS)
Goodbye, brother.
(CHORUS SINGING IN HEBREW)
Look.
Look at your people, Moses.
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
They are free.
WOMAN:
Deliver us
(WHEN YOU BELIEVE PLAYING)
(I WILL GET THERE PLAYING)